Oh I come from a land,
From a faraway place
Where the caravan camels roam
Where it's flat and immense
And the heat is intense
It's barbaric but hey, it's home
When the wind's from the east
And the sun's from the west
And the sand in the glass is right
Come on down, stop on by,
Hop a carpet and fly
To another Arabian night
Arabian nights
Like Arabian days
More often than not
Are hotter than hot
In a lot of good ways
Arabian nights
‘Neath Arabian moons
A fool off his guard
Could fall and fall hard
Out there on the dunes
Got to keep one jump
Ahead of the bread line
One swing ahead of the sword
I'll steal only what I can't afford
One jump ahead of the lawman
That's all, and that's no joke
These guys don't appreciate I'm broke
- Riffraff
- Street rat
- Scoundrel
- Take that
Just a little snack, guys
Rip him open, take it back, guys
1 can take a hint, got to face the facts
- You're my only friend, Abu
- Who?
Oh, it's sad Aladdin's hit the bottom
He's become a one-man rise in crime
I'd blame parents,
Except he hasn't go ‘em
Got to eat to live, got to steal to eat
Tell you all about it when I got time
One jump ahead of the slowpokes,
One skip ahead of my doom
Next time, going to use a nom de plume
One jump ahead of the hit men,
One hit ahead of the flock
[ think I'll take a stroll
Around the block
Let's not be too hasty
Still ! think he's rather tasty
Got to eat to live, got to steal to eat,
Otherwise we'd get along
Wrong
One jump ahead of the hoof beats
One hop ahead of the hump
One trick ahead of disaster,
They're quick but I'm much faster
Here goes, better throw my hand in,
Wish me happy landing
Alf got to do is jump!
Riffraff, street rat
! don't buy that
If only they'd look closer
Would they see a poor boy?
No siree
They‘d find out
There's so much more to me
Well, Ali Baba had them 40 thieves
Scheherazade had a thousand tales
But, master, you're in luck
‘Cause up your sleeves
You got a brand of magic never fails
You got some power in your corner now
Some heavy ammunition in your camp
You got some punch, pizzazz,
Yahoo and how
See, all you got to do
Is rub that lamp and I'll say
Mr. Aladdin, sir,
What will your pleasure be?
Let me take your order, jot it down
You ain't never had a friend like me
Life is your restaurant
And I'm your maitre d'
Come on, whisper what it is you want
You ain't never had a friend like me
Yes, sir, we pride ourselves on service
You're the boss, the king, the shah
Say what you wish,
It's yours, true dish
How ‘bout a little more baklava?
Have some of column A,
Try all of column B
I'm in the mood to help you, dude
You ain't never had a friend like me
Can your friends do this?
Can your friends do that?
Can your friends pull this
Out their little hat?
Can your friends go...
Hey, looky here
Can your friends go
Abracadabra, let her rip
And then make the sucker disappear?
So don't just sit there
Slack-jawed, buggy-eyed
I'm here to answer
Alf your midnight prayers
You got me bona fide, certified
You got a genie for a chargé d'affaires
! got a powerful urge to help you out
So what's your wish?
really want to know
You got a list that's
Three miles long, no doubt
Well, all you got to do is rub like so
Mr. Aladdin, sir,
Have a wish or two or three
I'm on the job, you big nabob
You ain't never had a friend
Like me
Make way for Prince Ali
Say hey, it's Prince Ali
Hey, clear the way in the old bazaar
Hey you, let us through,
It's a bright new star
Oh come, be the first
On your block to meet his eye
Make way, here he comes,
Ring bells, bang the drums
You're going to love this guy
Prince Ali, fabulous he, Ali Ababwa
Genuflect, show some respect,
Down on one knee
Now try your best to stay calm
Brush up your Sunday salaam
Then come and meet
His spectacular coterie
Prince Ali, mighty is he, Ali Ababwa
Strong as ten regular men definitely
He faced the galloping hordes
A hundred bad guys with swords
Who sent those goons to their lords?
Why, Prince Ali
He's got 75 golden camels
Purple peacocks he's got 53
When it comes to exotic-type mammals
Has he got a zoo, I'm telling you
It's a world-class menagerie
Prince Ali, handsome is he, Ali Ababwa
That physique, how can! speak?
Weak at the knees
Well, get on out in that square
Adjust your veil and prepare
To gawk and grovel
And stare at Prince Ali
He's got 95 white Persian monkeys
To view them he charges no fee
He's got slaves,
He's got servants and flunkeys
Proud to work for him,
They bow to his whim, love serving him
They're just lousy with loyalty to Ali
Prince Ali
Prince Ali, amorous he, Ali Ababwa
Heard your princess
Was a sight lovely to see
And that, good people, is why
He got dolled up and dropped by
With 60 elephants, llamas galore
With his bears and lions,
A brass band and more
With his 40 fakirs,
His cooks, his bakers
His birds that warble on key
Make way
For Prince Ali
} can show you the world
Shining, shimmering, splendid
Tell me, Princess, now when
Did you last let your heart decide?
! can open your eyes
Take you wonder by wonder
Over, sideways and under
On a magic-carpet ride
A whole new world
A new fantastic point of view
No one to tell us no or where to go
Or say we're only dreaming
A whole new world
A dazzling place I never knew
But when I'm way up here
It's crystal clear
That now I'm in
A whole new world with you
Now I'm in a whole new world with you
Unbelievable sights
Indescribable feeling
Soaring, tumbling, freewheeling
Through an endless diamond sky
- A whole new world
- Don't you dare close your eyes
- A hundred thousand things to see
- Hold your breath, it gets better
I'm like a shooting star
I've come so far
- 1 can't go back to where I used to be
- A whole new world
- Every turn a surprise
- With new horizons to pursue
Every moment red-letter
I'll chase them anywhere,
There's time to spare
Let me share this
Whole new world with you
A whole new world
That's where we'll be
- A thrilling chase
- A wondrous place
For you and me