May the All Mother...
smile upon our first meeting,
Not bad. You sound a little formal.
studied for five years...
...but there is much to learn.
Calrn people, calm.
What are you doing, Tsu'tey?
These demons are forbidden here.
There has been a sign.
This is a matter for the Tsahik.
Bring, him.
Father...
...1 see you.
This creature...
why do you bring, him here?
l was going to kill him...
..but there was a sign from Eywa.
have said...
+N dreamwalker will come here.
His alien smell fills my nose.
Step back!
I will look at this alien.
Awarrior!
t could kill him easily!
I could kl im easily!
This is the first warrior dreamwalker...
1 WE have seen.
We need to learn more about him.
My Daughter. .
+-YOu will teach him our way...
«to speak and walk as We do.
Why me? That’s not fair...
This alien will learn nothing...
wed rock sees more...
.look at him.
Look howbig you are.
You are so pretty.
I see you...
...Brother
..and thank you.
Your spirit goes with Eywa.
Your body stays behind...
...to become part of The People.
That moron's going to die.
Don't be afraid, warrior.
You are now ason of the Omaticaya.
You are part of The People.
Tsu'tey will lead the war party.
Stop please
This will only make it worse.
We will strike them in the heart.
have something to say...
...to all of you.
You see?
It is a demon ina false body.
Father !
Mother !
Eytukan, t have something to say.
Listen!
Speak, Jakesully.
A great evil is upon us...
The Sky People are coming...
sto destroy Hometree.
Bind them.
Leave now!
Have no fear.
Take the ikran...
..attack from above.
Get everyone to the forest.
Father !
Daughte an
take...my...bow.
Protect The People.
Tsu'tey, son of Ateyo...
...l stand before you...
ready to serve the Omaticaya people.
Hear us please, All Mother.
Eywa, help her.
Take this spirit into you...
..and breathe her back to us.
Let her walk among, us...
..as one of The People.
English - US - forced