Little town
It's a quiet village
Every day like the one before
Little town
Full of little people
Waking up to say
- Bonjour!
There goes the baker
with his tray like always
The same old bread and rolls to self
Every morning just the same
since the morning that we came
To this poor provincial town
Look, there she goes
The girl is strange, no question
Dazed and distracted
Can't you tell?
- Never part of any crowd
- 'Cause her head's up on some cloud
No denying she's a funny girl
that Belle
- Bonjour
- Good day
How is your family?
- Bonjour
- Good day
How is your wife?
I need six eggs
That's too expensive
There must be more
than this provincial life
Look, there she goes
That girl is so peculiar
! wonder if she's feeling well
- With a dreamy far-off look
- And her nose stuck in a book
What a puzzle to the rest of us is Belle
Oh, isn't this amazing?
It's my favorite part because
You'll see
Here's
Where she meets Prince Charming
But she won't discover that it's him
Till chapter three
Now, it's no wonder
that her name means "beauty"
Her looks have got no parallel
But behind that fair facade
I'm afraid she's rather odd
Very different from the rest of us
She's nothing like the rest of us
Yes, different from the rest of us
is Belle
Right from the moment
when I met her, saw her
I said she's gorgeous
and I felf
Here in town there's only she
who is beautiful as me
So I'm making plans
to woo and marry Belle
Look there, he goes
Isn't he dreamy?
Monsieur Gaston
Oh, he's so cute
Be stilf my heart
I'm hardly breathing
He's such a tall, dark, strong
and handsome brute
Bonjour.
- You call this bacon?
- What lovely grapes
- Ten yards
- Excuse me
- I'll get the knife
- Please let me through
- This bread, it's stale
- These fish, they smell
There must be more
than this provincial life
Just watch, I'm going
to make Belle my wife
Look, there she goes
A girl who's strange but special
A most peculiar mademoiselle
It's a pity anda sin
she doesn't quite fit in
- 'Cause she really is a funny girl
- A beauty but a funny girl
She really is a funny girl
- That Belle
- Bonjour.
Bonjour.
Bonjour
Madame Gaston
Can't you just see it?
His little wife
No, sir, not me
! guarantee it
! want much more
than this provincial life
! want adventure
in the great wide somewhere
! want it more than I can tell
And for once it might be grand
To have someone understand
! want so much more
than they've got planned
Gosh, it disturbs me
to see you, Gaston
Looking so down in the dumps
Every guy here’d love to be you, Gaston
Even when taking your lumps
There's no man in town
as admired as you
You're everyone's favorite guy
Everyone's awed and inspired by you
And it's not very hard to see why
No one's slick as Gaston
No one's quick as Gaston
No one's neck’'s
as incredibly thick as Gaston
For there's no man in town
half as manly
Perfect, a pure paragon
You can ask any Tom, Dick or Stanley
And they'll tell you whose team
they prefer to be on
No one's been like Gaston
A kingpin like Gaston
No one's got a swell cleft
in his chin like Gaston
As a specimen, yes, I'm intimidating
Oh, what a guy, that Gaston
Give five hurrahs
Give 12 hip-hips
Gaston is the best
and the rest is all drips
No one fights like Gaston
Douses lights like Gaston
In a wrestling match
no one bites like Gaston
For there's no one as burly and brawny
As you see, I've got biceps to spare
Not a bit of him scraggly or scrawny
That's right and every last inch of me's
covered with hair
- No one hits like Gaston
- Matches wits like Gaston
In a spitting match
nobody spits like Gaston
I'm especially good at expectorating
Ten points for Gaston
When I was a lad I ate four dozen eggs
Every morning to help me get large
And now that I'm grown
l eat five dozen eggs
So I'm roughly the size of a barge
No one shoots like Gaston
Makes those beauts like Gaston
Then goes tromping around
wearing boots like Gaston
l use antlers in all of my decorating
My, what a guy
Gaston
Le Fou, I'm afraid
I've been thinking
- A dangerous pastime
- 1 know
But that wacky old coot
is Belle's father
And his sanity's only so-so
Now, the wheels in my head
have been turning
Since I looked at that loony old man
See, ! promised myself
I'd be married to Belle
And right now I'm evolving a plan
No one plots like Gaston
Takes cheap shots like Gaston
Plans to persecute harmless crackpots
like Gaston
So his marriage
we soon will be celebrating
My, what a guy
Gaston
Be our guest
Put our service to the test
Tie your napkin round your neck, cherie
and we provide the rest
Soup du jour, hot hors d'ouevres
Why, we only live to serve
Try the gray stuff
It's delicious
Don't believe me?
Ask the dishes
They can sing
They can dance
After all, miss, this is France
And a dinner here is never second-best
Go on and fold your menu
Take a glance
and then you'll be our guest
Be our guest, be our guest
Beef ragout, cheese souffle
Pie and pudding en flambé
We'll prepare and serve with flair
a culinary cabaret
You're alone and you're scared
But the banquet's all prepared
No one's gloomy or complaining
while the flatware's entertaining
We tell jokes
1 do tricks
With my fellow candlesticks
Und it's all in perfect taste
That you can bet
Come on and lift your glass
You've won your own free pass
to be our guest
If you're stressed
it's fine dining we suggest
Be our guest, be our guest
be our guest
Life is so unnerving
For a servant who's not serving
He's not whole
without a soul to wait upon
Ah, those good old days
when we were useful
Suddenly those good old days are gone
Ten years we've been rusting
needing so much more than dusting
Needing exercise
A chance to use our skills
Most days we just lay around the castle
Flabby, fat and lazy
You walked in and whoopsy daisy
It's a guest, it's a guest
Sakes alive, well, I'll be blessed
Wine's been poured and thank the Lord
I've had the napkins freshly pressed
With dessert she'll want tea
And my dear, that's fine with me
While the cups do their soft-shoein'
I'll be bubblin’, I'll be brewin'
I'll get warm, piping hot
Heaven's sakes, is that a spot?
Clean that
We want the company impressed
We've got a lot to do
Is is one lump or two?
For you, our guest
- She's our guest
She's our guest
No, people. Song's over.
Over here, line up. Not...!
It's been years since we've had
anybody here and we're obsessed
With your meal, with your ease
Yes, indeed, we aim to please
While the candlelight's still glowing
Let us help you, we'll keep going
Course by course
One by one
Till you shout
"Enough, I'm done!"
Then we'll sing you off to sleep
as you digest
Tonight you'll prop your feet up
But for now let's eat up
Be our guest, be our guest
Be our guest
Please be our guest
There's something sweet
And almost kind
But he was mean
and he was course and unrefined
And now he's dear
And so unsure
! wonder why
! didn't see it there before
She glanced this way
I thought I saw
And when we touched
she didn't shudder at my paw
No, it can't be
I'll just ignore
But then she's never looked at me
that way before
New and a bit alarming
Who'd have ever thought
That this could be
True
That he's no Prince Charming
But there's something in him
That I simply didn't see
- Well, who'd have thought
- Well, bless my soul
- Well, who'd have known
- Well, who, indeed
And who'd have guessed
they'd come together on their own
- It's so peculiar
- We'll wait and see
A few days more
There may be something there
that wasn't there before
You know, perhaps there is something
there that wasn't there before
There may be something there
that wasn't there before
Tale as old as time
True as itcan be
Barely even friends
Then somebody bends
Unexpectedly
Just a little change
Small, to say the least
Both a little scared
Neither one prepared
Beauty and the Beast
Ever just the same
Ever a surprise
Ever as before
Ever just as sure
As the sun will rise
Tale as old as time
Tune as old as song
Bittersweet and strange
Finding you can change
Learning you were wrong
Certain as the sun
Rising in the east
Tale as old as time
Song as old as rhyme
Beauty and the Beast
Tale as old as time
Song as old as rhyme
Beauty and the Beast
- We're not safe until he's dead
- He'll come stalking us at night
Set to sacrifice our children
to his monstrous appetite
He'll wreak havoc on our village
if we let him wander free
So, it's time to take some action, boys
It's time to follow me
Through the mist, through the woods
Through the darkness and the shadows
It's a nightmare
but it's one exciting ride
Say a prayer, then we're there
at the drawbridge of a castle
And there's something
truly terrible inside
It's a beast
He's got fangs, razor sharp ones
Massive paws,
killer claws for the feast
Hear him roar, see him foam
But we're not coming home
till he’s dead
Good and dead
Light your torch, mount your horse
Screw your courage
to the sticking place
We're counting on Gaston
to lead the way
Through a mist through a wood
Where within a haunted castle
Something's lurking
that you don't see every day
It's a beast,
one as tall as a mountain
We won't rest tilf
he's good and deceased
Sally forth, tally ho,
grab your sword, grab your bow
Praise the Lord and here we go
We don't like what we don't understand
In fact, it scares us
And this monster is mysterious at least
Bring your guns, bring your knives
Save your children and your wives
We'll save our village and our lives
We'll kill the Beast
Hearts ablaze, banners high
We go marching into battle
Unatraid, although
the danger just increased
Raise the flag, sing the song
Here we come, we're 50 strong
And 50 Frenchmen can't be wrong
Let's kill the Beast
Kilf the Beast
Certain as the sun
Rising in the east
Tale as old as time
Song as old as rhyme
Beauty and the Beast
Tale as old as time
Song as old as rhyme
Beauty and the Beast