Once upon a time
in a faraway land,
a young prince lived
in a shining castle.
Although he had everything
his heart desired,
the prince was spoiled,
selfish and unkind.
But then, one winter's night,
an old beggar woman came to the castle
and offered him a single rose
in return for shelter
from the bitter cold.
Repulsed by her haggard appearance,
the prince sneered at the gift
and turned the old woman away.
But she warned him
not to be deceived by appearances,
for beauty is found within.
And when he dismissed her again,
the old woman's ugliness melted away
to reveal a beautiful enchantress.
The prince tried to apologize,
but it was too late,
for she had seen
that there was no love in his heart.
And as punishment,
she transformed him into a hideous beast
and placed a powerful spell
on the castle
and all who lived there.
Ashamed of his monstrous form,
the Beast concealed himself
inside his castle,
with a magic mirror
as his only window to the outside world.
The rose she had offered
was truly an enchanted rose,
which would bloom
until his twenty-first year.
If he could learn to love another
and earn her love in return
by the time the last petal fell,
then the spell would be broken.
If not, he would be doomed
to remain a beast for aif time.
As the years passed,
he fell into despair
and lost all hope.
For who could ever learn
to love a beast?
Little town
It's a quiet village
Every day like the one before
Little town
Full of little people
Waking up to say
- Bonjour!
There goes the baker
with his tray like always
The same old bread and rolls to self
Every morning just the same
since the morning that we came
To this poor provincial town
- Good morning, Belle.
- Morning, monsieur.
- Where are you off to?
- The bookshop.
I just finished the most wonderful story
about a beanstalk and an ogre...
That's nice. Marie, the baguettes!
Hurry up.
Look, there she goes
The girl is strange, no question
Dazed and distracted
Can't you tell?
- Never part of any crowd
- 'Cause her head's up on some cloud
No denying she's a funny girl
that Belle
- Bonjour
- Good day
How is your family?
- Bonjour
- Good day
How is your wife?
I need six eggs
That's too expensive
There must be more
than this provincial life
- Belle.
- Good morning.
I've come to return
the book I borrowed.
- Finished already?
- L couldn't put it down.
- Have you got anything new?
- Not since yesterday.
That's all right.
I'll borrow this one.
That one?
But you've read it twice.
Well, it's my favorite.
Far-off places, daring sword fights,
magic spells, a prince in disguise.
If you like it all that much,
it's yours.
- But, sir...
- linsist.
Well, thank you. Thank you very much.
Look, there she goes
That girl is so peculiar
! wonder if she's feeling well
- With a dreamy far-off look
- And her nose stuck in a book
What a puzzle to the rest of us is Belle
Oh, isn't this amazing?
It's my favorite part because
You'll see
Here's
Where she meets Prince Charming
But she won't discover that it's him
Till chapter three
Now, it's no wonder
that her name means "beauty"
Her looks have got no parallel
But behind that fair facade
I'm afraid she's rather odd
Very different from the rest of us
She's nothing like the rest of us
Yes, different from the rest of us
is Belle
You didn't miss a shot, Gaston!
You're the greatest hunter in the world.
I know.
No beast alive
stands a chance against you.
- And no girl for that matter.
- It's true, Le Fou.
And I've got my sights
set on that one.
- The inventor's daughter?
- She's the one.
- The lucky girl I'm going to marry.
- But...
- The most beautiful girl in town.
- 1 know, but...
That makes her the best.
And don't I deserve the best?
Well, of course. You do.
Right from the moment
when I met her, saw her
I said she's gorgeous
and I felf
Here in town there's only she
who is beautiful as me
So I'm making plans
to woo and marry Belle
Look there, he goes
Isn't he dreamy?
Monsieur Gaston
Oh, he's so cute
Be stilf my heart
I'm hardly breathing
He's such a tall, dark, strong
and handsome brute
- Bonjour.
- Good day.
- You call this bacon?
- What lovely grapes
- Ten yards
- Excuse me
- I'll get the knife
- Please let me through
- This bread, it's stale
- These fish, they smell
There must be more
than this provincial life
Just watch, I'm going
to make Belle my wife
Look, there she goes
A girl who's strange but special
A most peculiar mademoiselle
It's a pity anda sin
she doesn't quite fit in
- 'Cause she really is a funny girl
- A beauty but a funny girl
She really is a funny girl
- That Belle
- Bonjour.
Bonjour.
Bonjour
- Hello, Belle.
- Bonjour, Gaston.
Gaston, may I have my book, please?
How can you read this?
There's no pictures.
Well, some people
use their imagination.
Belle, it's about time
you got your head out of those books
and paid attention
to more important things... like me.
The whole town's talking about it.
It's not right for a woman to read.
Soon she starts
getting ideas and thinking.
Gaston, you are positively primeval.
Why, thank you, Belle.
What do you say you and me take a walk
to the tavern and look at my trophies?
Maybe some other time.
- What's wrong with her?
- She's crazy.
He's gorgeous.
Please, Gaston, I can't.
l have to get home to help my father.
Goodbye.
That crazy old loon.
He needs all the help he can get.
- Don't talk about my father that way.
- Don't talk about her father that way.
My father is not crazy.
He's a genius.
- Papa?
- How on earth did that happen?
Doggone it.
Are you all right, Papa?
I'm about ready to give up
on this hunk of junk.
- You always say that.
- [mean it this time.
I'll never get this
boneheaded contraption to work!
Yes, you will. And you'll win
first prize at the fair tomorrow.
And become a world-famous inventor.
You really believe that?
l always have.
Well, what are we waiting for?
I'll have this thing fixed in no time.
Hand me that
double-legged clincher there.
So did you have a good time
in town today?
I got a new book.
Papa, do you think I'm odd?
My daughter? Odd?
Where would you get an idea like that?
Oh, I don't know.
It's just that I'm not sure
I fit in here.
There's no one I can really talk to.
What about that Gaston?
He's a handsome fellow.
He's handsome, all right.
And rude and conceited.
Oh, Papa, he's not for me.
Well, don't you worry,
‘cause this invention's going
to be the start of a new life for us.
I think that's done it.
Now let's give it a try.
It works!
It does?
- It does!
- You did it.
You really did it!
Hitch up Philippe, girl.
I'm off to the fair.
Goodbye, Papa. Good luck.
Goodbye, Belle,
and take care while I'm gone.
I should be there by now.
Maybe we missed a turn.
l guess I should have taken that...
Wait a minute.
Let's go this way.
Come on, Philippe.
It's a shortcut.
We'll be there in no time.
This can't be right.
Where have you taken us, Philippe?
We'd better turn around.
Whoa!
Whoa, boy. Whoa. Whoa!
Look out!
Whoa.
Whoa, boy.
Back up, back up!
Good boy, good boy.
That's a good... Back up!
Steady, steady. Now, steady.
Steady.
Whoa, Philippe, whoa.
Philippe?
Help! Is someone there?
Help!
Hello?
The fellow must have lost his way
in the woods.
Quiet. Maybe he'll go away.
Is someone there?
Not a word, Lumiere, not one word.
I don't mean to intrude,
but I've lost my horse
and I need a place to stay
for the night.
Cogsworth, have a heart.
Of course, monsieur.
You are welcome here.
Who said that?
Over here!
Where?
Hello.
- Incredible.
- Well, now you've done it, Lumiere.
Splendid. Just peachy.
- How is this accomplished?
- Put me down at once.
Stop that.
Stop that, I say.
Close that at once!
- Do you mind?
- [beg your pardon.
It's just that I've never seen a...
You are soaked to the bone, monsieur.
Come warm yourself by the fire.
- Thank you.
- No, no, no.
You know what the master
will do if he finds him here.
I demand that you stop right there.
No, not the master's chair.
I'm not seeing this.
I'm not seeing this!
Well, hello there, boy.
- What service.
- All right. This has gone far enough.
I'm in charge here.
How would you like
a nice spot of tea, sir?
- It'll warm you up in no time.
- No! No tea.
No tea!
His moustache tickles, Mama.
Hello.
There's a stranger here.
Master, allow me to explain.
The gentleman was lost in the wood.
He was cold and wet.
Master, I'd like
to take this moment to say...
.. was against this.
It was all his fault.
I tried to stop them.
Would they listen to me? No!
Who are you?
What are you doing here?
I was lost in the woods and...
You're not welcome here.
I'm sorry.
- What are you staring at?
- Nothing.
So, you've come
to stare at the beast, have you?
Please, I meant no harm.
I just needed a place to stay.
- I'll give you a place to stay.
- No, please.
No, no!
Oh, boy. Belle's gonna get
the surprise of her life, huh, Gaston?
Yup. This is her lucky day.
I'd like to thank you all
for coming to my wedding.
First I better go in there
and propose to the girl.
And you, Le Fou,
- when Belle and I come out that door...
- l know!
I strike up the band.
- Not yet.
- Sorry.
Gaston, what a pleasant surprise.
Isn't it, though?
I'm just full of surprises.
You know, Belle,
there's not a girl in town
who wouldn't love to be in your shoes.
This is the day...
This is the day your dreams come true.
What do you know
about my dreams, Gaston?
Plenty. Picture this.
A rustic hunting lodge,
my latest kill roasting on the fire,
my little wife massaging my feet
while the little ones play on the floor
with the dogs.
- We'll have six or seven.
- Dogs?
No, Belle!
Strapping boys, like me.
- Imagine that.
- Do you know who that wife will be?
- Let me think...
- You, Belle.
Gaston, I'm... I'm...
..- speechless.
I really don't know what to say.
- Say you'll marry me.
- I'm very sorry, Gaston.
But I just don't deserve you.
So how did it go?
I'll have Belle for my wife.
Make no mistake about that.
Touchy!
Is he gone?
Can you imagine?
He asked me to marry him!
Me, the wife
of that boorish, brainless...
Madame Gaston
Can't you just see it?
His little wife
No, sir, not me
! guarantee it
! want much more
than this provincial life
! want adventure
in the great wide somewhere
! want it more than I can tell
And for once it might be grand
To have someone understand
! want so much more
than they've got planned
Philippe!
What are you doing here? Where's...?
Where's Papa?
Where is he, Philippe?
What happened?
We have to find him.
You have to take me to him.
What is this place?
Please, steady.
Steady.
Papa.
Couldn't keep quiet, could we?
Just had to invite him to stay,
didn't we?
Serve him tea,
sit in the master's chair,
pet the pooch.
I was trying to be hospitable.
Hello?
Is anyone here?
Papa?
Papa? Are you here?
Mama, there's a girl in the castle.
Now, Chip, I'll not have you
making up such wild stories.
Really, Mama.
I saw her.
- Not another word. Into the tub.
- But...
A girl! l saw a girl in the castle!
See? I told you.
Irresponsible, devil-may-care,
waxy-eared, slack-jawed...
Papa?
Did you see that?
-It's agirl.
- [know it's a girl!
Don't you see? She's the one.
The girl we have been waiting for.
- She has come to break the spell!
- Wait a minute!
Papa?
Hello? Is someone here?
Wait. I'm looking for my father. I...
That's funny.
I'm sure there was someone.
- ls anyone here?
- Belle?
Papa!
- How did you find me?
- Your hands are like ice.
- [have to get you out of there.
- [want you to leave this place.
- Who's done this to you?
- No time to explain.
- You must go now.
- l won't leave you.
- What are you doing here?
- Run, Belle!
Who's there?
Who are you?
The master of this castle.
I've come for my father.
Please let him out.
Can't you see he's sick?
- He shouldn't have trespassed here.
- But he could die.
- Please. I'll do anything.
- There is nothing you can do.
- He's my prisoner.
- There must be some way I can...
Wait!
- Take me instead.
- You!
You would take his place?
Belle, no!
You don't know what you're doing.
If l did, would you let him go?
Yes.
But you must promise
to stay here forever.
Come into the light.
No, Belle!
I won't let you do this!
- You have my word.
- Done.
No, Belle, listen to me.
I'm old. I've lived my life.
- Wait.
- Belle!
Wait!
No. Please spare my daughter. Please!
She's no longer your concern.
- Take him to the village.
- Let me out!
Please let me out!
Let me out.
Please!
Please.
- Master?
- What?
Since the girl is going to be with us
for quite some time,
l was thinking that
you might want to offer her
a more comfortable room.
Then again, maybe not.
You didn't even let me say goodbye.
I'll never see him again.
And I didn't get to say goodbye.
I'll show you to your room.
My room? But I thought...
- You wanna stay in the tower?
- No.
Then follow me.
Say something to her.
I... hope you like it here.
The castle is your home now
so you can go anywhere you like.
Except the west wing.
- What's in the west...?
- It's forbidden!
Now, if you need anything,
my servants will attend you.
Dinner. Invite her to dinner.
You will join me for dinner.
That's not a request.
Who does she think she is?
That girl has tangled
with the wrong man.
No one says no to Gaston.
- Darn right.
- Dismissed. Rejected.
Publicly humiliated.
Why, it's more than I can bear.
- More beer?
- What for?
Nothing helps. I'm disgraced.
Who, you? Never.
Gaston, you've got
to pull yourself together.
Gosh, it disturbs me
to see you, Gaston
Looking so down in the dumps
Every guy here’d love to be you, Gaston
Even when taking your lumps
There's no man in town
as admired as you
You're everyone's favorite guy
Everyone's awed and inspired by you
And it's not very hard to see why
No one's slick as Gaston
No one's quick as Gaston
No one's neck’'s
as incredibly thick as Gaston
For there's no man in town
half as manly
Perfect, a pure paragon
You can ask any Tom, Dick or Stanley
And they'll tell you whose team
they prefer to be on
No one's been like Gaston
A kingpin like Gaston
No one's got a swell cleft
in his chin like Gaston
As a specimen, yes, I'm intimidating
Oh, what a guy, that Gaston
Give five hurrahs
Give 12 hip-hips
Gaston is the best
and the rest is all drips
No one fights like Gaston
Douses lights like Gaston
In a wrestling match
no one bites like Gaston
For there's no one as burly and brawny
As you see, I've got biceps to spare
Not a bit of him scraggly or scrawny
That's right and every last inch of me's
covered with hair
- No one hits like Gaston
- Matches wits like Gaston
In a spitting match
nobody spits like Gaston
I'm especially good at expectorating
Ten points for Gaston
When I was a lad I ate four dozen eggs
Every morning to help me get large
And now that I'm grown
l eat five dozen eggs
So I'm roughly the size of a barge
No one shoots like Gaston
Makes those beauts like Gaston
Then goes tromping around
wearing boots like Gaston
l use antlers in all of my decorating
My, what a guy
Gaston
Help! Someone help me.
- Maurice?
- Please, please, I need your help.
He's got her.
He's got her locked in the dungeon.
- Who?
- Belle.
We must go.
Not a minute to lose.
Whoa. Slow down, Maurice.
- Who's got Belle locked in a dungeon?
- A beast!
A horrible monstrous beast!
- ls ita big beast?
- Huge!
- With a long, ugly snout?
- Hideously ugly.
- And sharp, cruel fangs?
- Yes, yes!
- Will you help me?
- All right, old man.
- We'll help you out.
- You will?
Oh, thank you.
Thank you, thank you!
Crazy old Maurice.
He's always good for a laugh.
Crazy old Maurice?
Crazy old Maurice...
Le Fou, I'm afraid
I've been thinking
- A dangerous pastime
- 1 know
But that wacky old coot
is Belle's father
And his sanity's only so-so
Now, the wheels in my head
have been turning
Since I looked at that loony old man
See, ! promised myself
I'd be married to Belle
And right now I'm evolving a plan
If l try to get her out of there...
- Yes?
- Then we got her out...
Would she?
- Guess.
- Now I get it.
Let's go!
No one plots like Gaston
Takes cheap shots like Gaston
Plans to persecute harmless crackpots
like Gaston
So his marriage
we soon will be celebrating
My, what a guy
Gaston
Will no one help me?
- Who is it?
- Mrs. Potts, dear.
I thought you might like a spot of tea.
You're... You're a...
- Careful!
- This is impossible.
I know it is, but here we are.
Told you she was pretty, Mama,
didn't I?
All right, Chip, now that will do.
Slowly now.
Don't spill.
Thank you.
Wanna see me do a trick?
Chip!
Sorry.
That was a very brave thing
you did, my dear.
We all think so.
But I've lost my father,
my dreams, everything.
Cheer up, child.
It'll turn out all right in the end.
You'll see.
Listen to me, jabbering on while
there's a supper to get on the table.
Chip!
Bye!
Well, now, what shall
we dress you in for dinner?
Let's see what I've got in my drawers.
How embarrassing.
Here we are.
You'll look ravishing in this one.
That's very kind of you,
but I'm not going to dinner.
But you must!
Dinner is served.
What's taking so long?
I told her to come down.
Why isn't she here yet?
Try to be patient, sir.
The girl has lost her father
and her freedom all in one day.
Have you thought that perhaps this girl
could be the one to break the spell?
Of course I have!
- I'm not a fool.
- Good.
So you fall in love with her,
she falls in love with you,
and poof, the spell is broken.
We'll be human again by midnight.
It's not that easy, Lumiere.
These things take time.
But the rose has already begun to wilt.
It's no use.
She's so beautiful and I'm...
Well, look at me!
You must help her to see past all that.
I don't know how.
Well, you can start
by making yourself more presentable.
Straighten up.
Try to act like a gentleman.
Yes, when she comes in,
give her a dashing, debonair smile.
Come, come, show me the smile.
- But don't frighten the poor girl.
- Impress her with your rapier wit.
- But be gentle.
- Shower her with compliments.
- But be sincere.
- And above all...
You must control your temper!
Here she is.
Good evening.
Well, where is she?
The girl. Yes, the girl.
Actually, she's in the process of...
Circumstances being what they are...
She's not coming.
What?
Your lordship!
Your grace!
Your eminence!
Let's not be hasty!
I thought I told you
to come down to dinner.
I'm not hungry.
You'll come out or I'll... I'll...
- I'll break down the door!
- Master, I could be wrong,
but that may not be the best way
to win the girl's affections.
Please attempt to be a gentleman.
But she's being so difficult!
Gently, gently.
- Will you come down to dinner?
- No.
Suave. Gentile.
It would give me great pleasure
if you would join me for dinner.
- Can we say please?
- Please.
- No, thank you.
- You can't stay in there forever.
- Yes, I can.
- Fine.
Then go ahead and starve!
If she doesn't eat with me,
then she doesn't eat at all.
Oh, dear.
That didn't go very well at all, did it?
Lumiere, stand watch at the door
and inform me at once
if there is the slightest change.
You can count on me, mon capitaine.
Well, we might as well go downstairs
and start cleaning up.
l ask nicely, but she refuses.
What does she want me to do?
Beg?
Show me the girl.
The master's really not so bad
once you get to know him.
Why don't you give him a chance?
I don't want to get to know him.
I don't want anything to do with him.
I'm just fooling myself.
She'll never see me
as anything but a monster.
It's hopeless.
- Oh, no.
- Oh, yes.
- Yes, yes.
- I've been burnt by you before.
Zut alors! She has emerged!
Come on, Chip. Into the cupboard
with your brothers and sisters.
- But I'm not sleepy.
- Yes, you are.
No, I'm not.
I work and I slave all day long
and for what?
A cculinary masterpiece gone to waste!
Stop your grousing.
It's been a long night for all of us.
Well, if you ask me,
she was just being stubborn.
After all, he did say please.
If the master doesn't control
that temper, he'll never break the...
Splendid to see you
out and about, mademoiselle.
lam Cogsworth, head of the household.
- This is Lumiere.
- Enchanté, cherie.
If there's... Stop that!
Anything we... Please!
..can do to make your stay
more comfortable?
- lam a little hungry.
- You are?
Hear that? She's hungry.
Stoke the fire,
break out the silver, wake the china.
- Remember what the master said.
- Pish posh.
I'm not about
to let the poor child go hungry.
All right, fine.
- Aglass of water, crust of bread...
- Cogsworth, I'm surprised at you.
She is not a prisoner.
She's our guest.
We must make her feel welcome here.
- Right this way, mademoiselle.
- Well, keep it down.
If the master finds out about this
it will be our necks.
Of course, of course.
But what is dinner
without a little music?
Music?
Ma chere, mademoiselle,
it is with deepest pride
and greatest pleasure
that we welcome you tonight.
And now we invite you to relax.
Let us pull up a chair,
as the dining room proudly presents
your dinner.
Be our guest
Put our service to the test
Tie your napkin round your neck, cherie
and we provide the rest
Soup du jour, hot hors d'ouevres
Why, we only live to serve
Try the gray stuff
It's delicious
Don't believe me?
Ask the dishes
They can sing
They can dance
After all, miss, this is France
And a dinner here is never second-best
Go on and fold your menu
Take a glance
and then you'll be our guest
Be our guest, be our guest
Beef ragout, cheese souffle
Pie and pudding en flambé
We'll prepare and serve with flair
a culinary cabaret
You're alone and you're scared
But the banquet's all prepared
No one's gloomy or complaining
while the flatware's entertaining
We tell jokes
1 do tricks
With my fellow candlesticks
Und it's all in perfect taste
That you can bet
Come on and lift your glass
You've won your own free pass
to be our guest
If you're stressed
it's fine dining we suggest
Be our guest, be our guest
be our guest
Life is so unnerving
For a servant who's not serving
He's not whole
without a soul to wait upon
Get off!
Ah, those good old days
when we were useful
Suddenly those good old days are gone
Ten years we've been rusting
needing so much more than dusting
Needing exercise
A chance to use our skills
Most days we just lay around the castle
Flabby, fat and lazy
You walked in and whoopsy daisy
It's a guest, it's a guest
Sakes alive, well, I'll be blessed
Wine's been poured and thank the Lord
I've had the napkins freshly pressed
With dessert she'll want tea
And my dear, that's fine with me
While the cups do their soft-shoein'
I'll be bubblin’, I'll be brewin'
I'll get warm, piping hot
Heaven's sakes, is that a spot?
Clean that
We want the company impressed
We've got a lot to do
Is is one lump or two?
For you, our guest
- She's our guest
She's our guest
No, people. Song's over.
Over here, line up. Not...!
It's been years since we've had
anybody here and we're obsessed
With your meal, with your ease
Yes, indeed, we aim to please
While the candlelight's still glowing
Let us help you, we'll keep going
Course by course
One by one
Till you shout
"Enough, I'm done!"
Then we'll sing you off to sleep
as you digest
Tonight you'll prop your feet up
But for now let's eat up
Be our guest, be our guest
Be our guest
Please be our guest
- Bravo. That was wonderful.
- Thank you.
Thank you, mademoiselle.
Good show, wasn't it, everyone?
My goodness, look at the time.
- Now it's off to bed, off to bed.
- L couldn't possibly go to bed now.
It's my first time
in an enchanted castle.
Enchanted!
Who said anything
about the castle being enchanted?
It was you, wasn't it?
I figured it out for myself.
I'd like to look around
if that's all right.
- Would you like a tour?
- Wait a second.
I'm not sure that's such a good idea.
We can't let her go poking around
in certain places,
if you know what I mean.
Perhaps you'd like to take me.
I'm sure you know everything
about the castle.
Oh, well, actually, I...
Yes, I do.
As you can see, the pseudo-facade
was stripped away
to reveal a minimalist Rococo design.
Note the unusual
inverted vaulted ceilings.
This is yet another example
of the late neo-classic Baroque period.
And, as I always say,
"If it's not Baroque, don't fix it.”
Where was I?
As you were.
Now then, if l may draw your attention
to the flying buttresses of the...
Mademoiselle?
- What's up there?
- Where? There? Nothing.
Nothing of interest
in the west wing.
Dusty, dull, very boring.
- So that's the west wing?
- Nice going.
l wonder what he's hiding up there.
Hiding? The master is hiding nothing.
- Then it wouldn't be forbidden.
- Perhaps...
.. Mademoiselle would like
to see something else?
We have exquisite tapestries
dating all the way to...
- Maybe later.
- The gardens or the library perhaps?
- You have a library?
- Oh, yes!
- Indeed.
- With books.
- Scads of books.
- Mountains of books.
- Forests of books.
- Cascades.
- Cloudbursts.
- Swamps of books.
More books than
you'll be able to read in a lifetime.
Books on every subject ever studied.
By every author
who ever set pen to paper.
Why did you come here?
I'm sorry.
- l warned you never to come here.
- [didn't mean any harm.
Do you realize what you could have done?
- Stop.
- Get out!
No!
Get out!
- Where are you going?
- Promise or no promise,
- l can't stay another minute.
- No, wait, please.
Please wait.
Here now. Don't do that.
Just hold still.
That hurts.
If you'd hold still
it wouldn't hurt as much.
If you hadn't run away
this wouldn't have happened.
If you hadn't frightened me
l wouldn't have run away.
Well, you shouldn't have been
in the west wing.
Well, you should learn
to control your temper.
Now hold still.
This might sting a little.
By the way, thank you...
..for saving my life.
You're welcome.
I don't usually leave the asylum
in the middle of the night,
but he said
you'd make it worth my while.
- I'm listening.
- It's like this.
I've got my heart set
on marrying Belle.
But she needs a little persuasion.
Turned him down flat.
Everyone knows her father's a lunatic.
He was in here tonight
raving about a beast in a castle.
Maurice is harmless.
The point is, Belle would do anything
to keep him from being locked up.
Yeah. Even marry him.
So you want me
to throw her father into the asylum
unless she agrees to marry you?
Oh, that is despicable.
I love it.
If no one will help me
then I'll go back alone.
Is that everything?
I don't care what it takes.
I'll find that castle
and somehow I'll get her out of there.
Belle? Maurice?
Oh, well.
Guess it's not gonna work after all.
They have to come back sometime,
and when they do,
we'll be ready for them.
Le Fou, don't move from that spot
until Belle and her father come home.
But... but I...
Nuts.
I've never felt this way about anyone.
I want to do something for her.
- But what?
- Well, there's the usual things.
Flowers, chocolates,
promises you don't intend to keep.
No, no.
It has to be something very special.
Something that sparks her interest.
Wait a minute!
Belle, there's something
I want to show you.
But first you have to close your eyes.
It's a surprise.
- Can I open them?
- Not yet.
Wait here.
- Now can I open them?
- All right.
Now.
I can't believe it!
I've never seen so many books
in my life.
- You... You like it?
- It's wonderful.
- Then it's yours.
- Thank you so much.
Would you look at that.
- [knew it would work.
- What?
What works?
It's very encouraging.
- Isn't this exciting?
- didn't see anything.
Come along, Chip.
There's chores to be done.
What are they talking about?
What's going on? Come on, Mom.
There's something sweet
And almost kind
But he was mean
and he was course and unrefined
And now he's dear
And so unsure
! wonder why
! didn't see it there before
She glanced this way
I thought I saw
And when we touched
she didn't shudder at my paw
No, it can't be
I'll just ignore
But then she's never looked at me
that way before
New and a bit alarming
Who'd have ever thought
That this could be
True
That he's no Prince Charming
But there's something in him
That I simply didn't see
- Well, who'd have thought
- Well, bless my soul
- Well, who'd have known
- Well, who, indeed
And who'd have guessed
they'd come together on their own
- It's so peculiar
- We'll wait and see
A few days more
There may be something there
that wasn't there before
You know, perhaps there is something
there that wasn't there before
What?
There may be something there
that wasn't there before
What's there, Mama?
I'll tell you when you're older.
Tonight is the night.
- I'm not sure I can do this.
- You don't have time to be timid.
- You must be bold, daring.
- Bold, daring.
There will be music,
romantic candlelight,
provided by myself.
And when the moment is right,
you confess your love.
Yes.
Icon... 1... No.
- lL can't.
- You care for the girl, don't you?
- More than anything.
- Well, then, you must tell her.
Voila. You look so...
So...
Stupid.
Not quite the word I was looking for.
Perhaps a little more off the top.
Your lady awaits.
Tale as old as time
True as itcan be
Barely even friends
Then somebody bends
Unexpectedly
Just a little change
Small, to say the least
Both a little scared
Neither one prepared
Beauty and the Beast
Ever just the same
Ever a surprise
Ever as before
Ever just as sure
As the sun will rise
Tale as old as time
Tune as old as song
Bittersweet and strange
Finding you can change
Learning you were wrong
Certain as the sun
Rising in the east
Tale as old as time
Song as old as rhyme
Beauty and the Beast
Tale as old as time
Song as old as rhyme
Beauty and the Beast
Off to the cupboard with you now, Chip.
It's past your bedtime.
Good night, love.
Belle...
Are you happy here with me?
Yes.
What is it?
If only I could see my father again.
Just for a moment.
I miss him so much.
There is a way.
This mirror will show you anything.
Anything you wish to see.
I'd like to see my father please.
Papa!
Oh, no. He's sick.
He may be dying and he's all alone.
Then you must go to him.
What did you say?
l release you.
You're no longer my prisoner.
You mean...
.l'm free?
Yes.
Thank you.
Hold on, Papa. I'm on my way.
Take it with you,
so you'll always have a way
to look back...
..and remember me.
Thank you for understanding
how much he needs me.
Well, your highness, I must say
everything is going just swimmingly.
I knew you had it in you.
I let her go.
Yes, yes, splen...
You what?
- How could you do that?
- [had to.
Yes, but...
Why?
Because...
..[ love her.
He did what?
Yes, I'm afraid it's true.
She's going away?
But he was so close.
After all this time
he's finally learned to love.
That's it, then.
That should break the spell.
But it's not enough.
She has to love him in return.
Now it's too late.
Papa?
They're back.
Belle.
It's all right, Papa. I'm home.
I thought I'd never see you again.
I missed you so much.
But the Beast,
how did you escape?
I didn't escape, Papa.
He let me go.
- That horrible beast?
- He's different now, Papa.
He's changed somehow.
- Hi.
- Astowaway.
Why, hello there, little fellow.
I didn't think I'd see you again.
Belle, why'd you go away?
Don't you like us anymore?
Oh, Chip.
Of course I do.
It's just that...
- May I help you?
- I've come to collect your father.
- My father?
- Don't worry, mademoiselle.
We'll take good care of him.
- My father's not crazy.
- He was raving like a lunatic.
- We all heard him, didn't we?
- Yeah!
No! I won't let you.
- Belle?
- Maurice.
Tell us again, old man,
just how big was the Beast?
He was... l mean, he was...
He was enormous.
I'd say at least eight...
No! More like ten feet.
Well, you don't get
much crazier than that.
It's true, I tell you!
Get him out of here.
Let go of me!
No! You can't do this.
Poor Belle.
It's a shame about your father.
You know he's not crazy, Gaston.
I might be able to clear up
this little misunderstanding.
- If...
- If what?
- If you marry me.
- What?
One little word, Belle,
that's all it takes.
- Never.
- Have it your way.
Belle!
Let go of me!
My father's not crazy
and I can prove it.
Show me the Beast.
- ls he dangerous?
- No. He'd never hurt anyone.
Please. I know he looks vicious,
but he's really kind and gentle.
He's my friend.
If didn't know better I'd think
you had feeling for this monster.
He's no monster, Gaston. You are!
She's as crazy as the old man.
The Beast will make off
with your children.
- He'll come in the night.
- No!
We're not safe till his head
is mounted on my wall.
- lsay we kill the Beast.
- Kill him!
- We're not safe until he's dead
- He'll come stalking us at night
Set to sacrifice our children
to his monstrous appetite
He'll wreak havoc on our village
if we let him wander free
So, it's time to take some action, boys
It's time to follow me
Through the mist, through the woods
Through the darkness and the shadows
It's a nightmare
but it's one exciting ride
Say a prayer, then we're there
at the drawbridge of a castle
And there's something
truly terrible inside
It's a beast
He's got fangs, razor sharp ones
Massive paws,
killer claws for the feast
Hear him roar, see him foam
But we're not coming home
till he’s dead
- Good and dead
- Yeah!
- Kill the Beast!
- No, I won't let you do this.
If you're not with us,
you're against us.
- Bring the old man.
- Get your hands off me.
We can't have them running off
to warn the creature.
- Let us out!
- We'll rid the village of this beast!
- Who's with me?
- lam!
Light your torch, mount your horse
Screw your courage
to the sticking place
We're counting on Gaston
to lead the way
Through a mist through a wood
Where within a haunted castle
Something's lurking
that you don't see every day
It's a beast,
one as tall as a mountain
We won't rest tilf
he's good and deceased
Sally forth, tally ho,
grab your sword, grab your bow
Praise the Lord and here we go
We'll lay siege to the castle
and bring back his head.
l have to warn the Beast.
This is all my fault.
Oh, Papa, what are we going to do?
Now, now, we'll think of something.
We don't like what we don't understand
In fact, it scares us
And this monster is mysterious at least
Bring your guns, bring your knives
Save your children and your wives
We'll save our village and our lives
We'll kill the Beast
I knew it. I knew it was foolish
to get our hopes up.
It would have been better
if she'd never come at all.
- Could it be?
- Is it she?
Sacre bleu! Invaders!
- Encroachers!
- They've got the mirror.
Warn the master. If it's a fight
they want we'll be ready.
Who's with me?
Take whatever booty you can find,
but remember the Beast is mine!
Hearts ablaze, banners high
We go marching into battle
Unatraid, although
the danger just increased
Raise the flag, sing the song
Here we come, we're 50 strong
And 50 Frenchmen can't be wrong
Let's kill the Beast
- Pardon me, master.
- Leave me in peace.
But sir, the castle is under attack.
Kilf the Beast
- Kilf the Beast
- This isn't working.
Lumiere, we must do something.
Wait! I know.
Kilf the Beast
What should we do, master?
It doesn't matter now.
Just let them come.
Kilf the Beast
Now!
Yes!
Here we go!
What the devil?
Belle, look out!
You guys gotta try this thing.
Up here, you scurvy scum!
Now!
And stay out!
Get up.
Get up!
What's the matter, beast?
Too kind and gentle to fight back?
No!
- Belle.
- No! Gaston, don't!
Let's go, Philippe.
Come on out and fight.
Were you in love with her, Beast?
Did you honestly think she'd want you
when she had someone like me?
It's over, Beast.
Belle is mine!
Let me go. Let me go!
Please, don't hurt me.
I'll do anything, anything!
Get out.
Beast!
Belle!
Belle.
You came back.
Of course I came back.
I couldn't let them...
Oh, this is all my fault.
If only I'd gotten here sooner.
Maybe it's better...
It's better this way.
Don't talk like that.
You'll be all right.
We're together now.
Everything's going to be fine,
you'll see.
At least I got to see you...
..one last time.
No. No!
Please.
Please. Please don't leave me.
I love you.
Belle.
It's me.
It is you.
Lumiere.
Cogsworth!
Mrs. Potts!
Look at us!
Mama, Mama!
- My goodness.
- tis a miracle.
L'amour.
Well, Lumiere, old friend,
shall we let bygones be bygones?
Of course, mon ami.
I told you she would break the spell.
l beg your pardon, old friend.
But I believe I told you.
No, you didn't.
I told you.
You most certainly did not, you pompous
paraffin-headed pea brain.
En garde, you overgrown pocket watch.
Take that.
Stop shoving.
Are they gonna live
happily ever after, Mama?
Of course, my dear.
Of course.
Do I still have to sleep
in the cupboard?
Certain as the sun
Rising in the east
Tale as old as time
Song as old as rhyme
Beauty and the Beast
Tale as old as time
Song as old as rhyme
Beauty and the Beast