Welcome to the Brave commentary.
I'm your host Mark Andrews.
I'm the director of Brave.
And I'm here with...
Steve Purcell,
co-director and co-writer.
Nick Smith, editor.
I'm Brian Larsen, story supervisor.
We were thinking
that with the Disney castle
we would actually change it into
the Dun Broch Castle.
There was a discussion
but we decided just to go with
the original Disney castle.
We talk about a lot of things.
We talked about a lot of things
over the course of the film.
Wasn't there something you
wanted to do on the Pixar logo?
-Yeah, we wanted...
-The bagpipe thing.
We wanted him to come in
with some bagpipes.
-Or at least give him a kilt.
-And a kilt?
No when he jumped in it would be...
A bagpipe.
-Then a groan...
-Then a... Yeah.
-We should do that.
-It's not too late.
-We just did.
-Yeah.
So, the beginning of Brave
started very differently for a little while.
l had this whole scene where
Fergus was hunting
through the snow to find Mor'du
and we were going to
give the audience this experience of
encountering Mor'du
so that we'd know who he was
and know why Fergus
was missing the leg
and establish his hatred for bears.
Almost this Captain Ahab to Moby Dick,
kind of lust to destroy this bear
which plays into the story later.
We boarded it. We put it through layout.
We animated it.
We started to render it
and then in one screening
we realized that we're too far away
from our main character, Merida.
So there was this idea about
showing Merida when she was younger.
Of showing Merida and her mother
Elinor when everything was good.
So that after the sequence opened
and we flash forward in time,
we pick them up
and now their relationship is strained.
Well, that's what ultimately this scene,
I think, is trying to really set up
is, like, their relationship, family,
Mor'du, the wisps, the bow.
There was so much that this scene
was trying to incorporate
-and like you were saying with...
-Right.
-And Dad's relationship with Mom, too.
-Yeah.
And get it through organically.
We see her and her mom having
this great relationship where
they're playing and loving each other.
Dad gives her a bow for the birthday,
so this creates her love for the bow.
And we establish the wisps here
that lead you to your fate.
And in this case lead her away
from getting eaten by
this big, evil, demon bear.
But then this is that encounter
where we call Mor'du by name
and still get the encounter
between Fergus.
Well, originally we had Merida alone.
Right, sneaking out of the castle.
Yeah, we've had
many different openings.
And actually
it's surprising to think back on
how often we would do scenes that had
only a couple of
the characters together.
And I think there's a lot to be said for
putting all the characters together
right away,
so you can kind of
feel their dynamic from the get-go.
So we had to very quickly
create a brand new character.
That young Merida here.
And to get her right, we were
talking about taking a triplet
-and putting longer hair on it.
-Yeah.
We actually took Merida
and scaled her down to a little girl.
Pulled in the body
and got the proportions right.
Then we really had to
subtly adjust the face.
And we had to have
a whole new hair rig,
our new hairdo done.
And everybody just rallied
and did a marvelous job.
And we have this
super-cute little girl now.
And we also had to find a voice, too.
And Patrick Doyle, our composer,
found this girl to sing the lullaby.
The lullaby, yeah.
And thought that she might work.
And you went over and...
Met her and then we got the song.
And then I said, "Hey, I have this scene
l want you to try."
-What was her name?
-It was Peigi.
And she said, "Sure,"
and she'd never kind of acted before.
But then she did the voice
and knocked it out of the park.
We auditioned a bunch of little girls.
But it turns out
Peigi was the most natural.
And two sessions and she nailed it.
-She had a sweet voice.
-It was unpolished in a really sweet way.
And then we get into the attack here.
So everything is fate.
You can almost say that
the wisps led this encounter to happen
to be resolved
several years down the road.
This is the inciting incident
to kind of bring them all off.
And then to really get this big hit,
l really wanted this.
-Well, it's two great bookends.
-Yeah.
The beginning and the end of the family
coming together to fight Mor'du.
And so this is the opening here,
once we go through
the coming out of the clouds
and going into
the Highlands of Scotland
and coming down to find the castle.
It was my homage to
The Sound Of Music.
And I thought that
getting into the movies...
‘Cause that used to be our opening,
as just starting coming out of cloud
into images of Scotland.
But I really wanted to
transport the audience.
And there's several movies
that really do this well.
I think Braveheart does it well
by coming across the water
and rising up over
the Scottish Highlands.
Which I also do in this sequence.
And then, in Sound Of Music
to just give us a sense of this world
that we're going to be in,
I thought was very important.
This next scene right here,
actually Mark choreographed this
and we filmed it.
This fight scene right here,
Mark was actually Fergus.
You should be able to
find that on the Blu-ray.
-And were you...
-l was in there.
Yeah, I was one of the guys
who gets kicked.
How many guys? Did you actually
do it with that many guys?
I did it with that many guys, yeah.
We choreographed the whole thing.
The animators were really into
all the archery and the sword fighting.
And I was teaching them the swords
and doing all the choreography
and we were filming it.
-So they can really go in there...
-'Cause you're trained in this, right?
lam. But so they could go in there,
‘cause it's those details of
how you move and where you
shift your weight and all that stuff.
And they really wanted to nail it
and get it down.
There we see Merida as a teenager.
But I wanted to,
as soon as the doors opened,
find her doing something wrong.
She's just doing the stuff
that she wants to do,
like eating that apple,
but she's constantly getting in trouble
or being frowned upon by her mother.
Just so that we get that instant
change of dynamics of their relationship
from the beginning of the film.
We want a chance to see Mom
and Merida together.
So we could see,
even in their body language,
how different they are as characters.
Where Mom's pulled in and very formal.
And Merida is always more relaxed
and kind of has her head elsewhere.
We had this idea for just one day.
Ascene for a day in the life of Merida,
which had all these elements in there.
And then we decided to make it
like this mini montage
so we get that she's being kind of
ruled or run by her mom constantly
day after day after day after day
after day
with all these lessons,
and these reasons to be a princess.
So that when she gets her day
it's a real breakout.
We had a big issue because
we had a princess in this movie,
and because this is fairly
familiar ground with Disney films,
and other movies
that have a princess in it,
that we really wanted to define what
everybody thinks a princess is
in the opening,
so that we can break it
in this sequence once she gets out.
I mean, she ends up...
She's riding through the woods
and having this great day.
And we see her skills with the arrow.
How much she's developed
since the beginning of the film
when she couldn't hit nothing.
How capable and athletic she is,
how brave and bold she is.
And, later on,
she's even mucking out her own stall.
You don't really see princesses
mucking out their stalls in any movies.
So, we're visually saying, "This is not
the princess you think she is.
"She is not timid, a faint heart,
waiting for Prince Charming to come.
"She's going to do it all herself."
Well, this sequence in particular
is really a response to
the sequence with her mother.
The camera was very still
and muted colors.
Where here, the camera is very active
and the colors are bright.
So it's kind of comparing what Merida is
truly feeling during both sequences.
Right. Life in the castle is this drab,
boring, restrictive place.
But once she's out on Angus
riding around,
then it becomes
this big, bold free place.
And she's much more in her element,
her environment.
And she's ultimately
exploring who she is.
And finding things that she likes
and are inspiring to her, and risking.
I mean, she almost slips
and falls off of this rock.
We call that the Crone's Tooth.
Those are the Fire Falls
which was inspired by
this natural phenomenon that actually
happens in the United States
in Yosemite National Park
at a certain time of year.
The sun, when it sets,
casts this light on the falls
that makes it catch on fire
and they call that the Firefalls.
There are three songs in the movie.
And this is the first song written by
our very own Alex Mandel
who l asked to do these as temp songs
‘cause we needed something
in these positions.
And we listened to 'em so much
and everybody really liked 'em.
And I remember John Lasseter
and Andrew Stanton saying,
"Who did those songs?
Those are great!"
And so we kept them in the movie,
and got them re-recorded
and found a Scottish singer
and they turned out really great.
One thing that we were
talking about is that
the teenager is
always late to the dinner table.
And they've already eaten usually
or have gotten some snack
and she's always
stuffing her face before.
So it was a bigger thing at one point,
and we just scaled it down to
the couple shots of her
entering the kitchen,
having a couple of bites, and nibbling.
So that she can steal this
platter of cupcakes for her brothers.
What I like about the scene that you,
I think, were trying to establish was
you're setting up
the space of the castle.
You're trying to introduce the castle
and the family as a unit.
So you're trying to get a lot of space
associated for the audience.
So we want to meet these
characters that they're in
this exotic time period for us.
And so we want to see them in a way
that we recognize the situation totally.
And then we can get on board with
the characters much more easily.
It's a typical day.
You want to set up the normal day
before you see the extraordinary day.
It's really hard when you've got
something that's in the round here.
You've got a four-sided table
with characters on each side
to keep 'em straight.
So there is a pattern to
the cutting of who you see
and when and who locks down
on one side or the other.
With Fergus, usually Merida's head's
there on the left side of the screen.
And then with Mom, Merida's
head's on the other side of the screen,
on the right side of the screen.
So we know where Mom is
in relation to Dad.
And where the triplets are.
The filmmaking is all there
to try and lock us down into place.
And it also really illustrates
the difference in the relationship
between Mom and Dad.
Where she has this very
sweet relationship with her father.
And then her mother is barely
paying attention to her at this point.
Right. And we wanted to
switch that old dynamic
of Dad's usually reading
at the dinner table with the newspaper.
It's actually Mom, you know,
she has all of her affairs of state
and the castle,
you know, accounts and things,
so she's the business one
while Dad is engaging with the family.
And here's to set up a dynamic of just
between Merida and the triplets
that they're not antagonistic
towards one another.
They help each other out, and
you'll see that again later on in the film.
Ted Mathot actually had this great gag
when the dogs jump up
and try and start eating Fergus' food,
and he knocks them away.
And I thought that was just hilarious.
Because it just kind of goes to
the whole character of who Fergus is.
But what the air of
everything is inside the castle.
So for the dogs to jump up
and run across the table,
you have this chaotic air.
We had a back and forth a lot of time
of how queenly
or how kingly is this environment.
And I didn't want
a Queen Elizabeth queen
because that's devoid of emotion.
In this time period
kings and queens were just
beginning to emerge
in this kind of class society.
So there weren't established rules
of how one should act.
So we could be a little bit more loose
and relaxed and just made it more real.
And that way we could also
recognize the characters as parents,
even more so than as royals.
So we kind of recognize their behavior
and their issues
that they have with their daughter.
Right. Them being the royals just
created higher stakes in the story.
The larger problem that was
going to come up in the movie
by Merida refusing to marry anybody
and break with tradition.
So this scene is the start of
Merida and Mom's real blowup
in a big way that's coming.
And the crux of it ends up
in the tapestry scene.
Right. We're not that long
into the movie.
And I wanted to establish quickly
exactly what this story
is going to be about.
The main conflict is going to be
between this mother and this daughter.
This whole thing is
to get both of their sides.
‘Cause a lot of the time
what was happening was
Mom would be too stern,
a Mommie Dearest-type,
and we'd hate her.
And we could never hate her.
And then Merida, to go the other way,
would be too complain-y teenager
and we would hate her, too.
So it was to really find that,
and it's a very narrow path,
to dial in to where you like both of them,
and you understand both of them.
But very much this is Merida's picture.
And you have to be on Merida's side
without hating Mom.
Brad Bird had said,
"Nobody was really following
"that message of her
talking about this ancient kingdom."
So we had the idea to have
these little flashes of kind of showing it.
And it did for us, A, it identified this set.
This ruins, this ancient kingdom that
we're going to see later on in the movie,
so we recognize it.
And visually set up who this prince was
who was later going to become Mor'du.
Yeah, in our minds it seemed like
Mom tells these stories all the time.
And for whatever reason,
this one seemed like it stood out
and Merida would pay more attention.
Because the consequences of this story
seemed a lot more dire than
what she had heard before.
We went into this moment
that we called "deep thoughts."
Il had drawn Merida
sitting on top of a castle,
or that she's alone with her thoughts
so that we would get that this decision
or what can she possibly do.
How is that going to affect her life?
Then we also had this sequence where
Mom's got to talk about her daughter
to somebody.
The parents are always talking
about their children.
And we can get the other aspect of it.
And Katherine Sarafian, our producer,
would do this type of thing
to me all the time.
Where she would want to role play
before we'd go into a meeting
or something like that,
where Katherine would be the person
that l was having the meeting with,
so l could kind of
test run my questions and stuff,
or she could ask me questions
and I would fire back.
And I thought that was a great idea.
We could actually put that in the movie.
And Dad could be Merida
and Mom could actually talk to Merida.
But it also illustrates the fact that
they are incapable of actually
having a conversation with each other.
So all they do is talk to themselves
as though they were having
a conversation with the other person.
And it fully gets out there
what their issue is.
Right, yeah, yeah.
So you understand both sides of it,
but neither of them actually
talk to each other.
We knew that we were going to have
these parallel conversations going on
and that's how we scripted it
in the beginning,
but then at some point
we realized we could
feather the conversations together
and make it feel like these characters
are actually talking to each other.
And it's the conversation
you sort of wish they'd have
where they're kind of calm,
they're actually
spilling their guts a little bit
and you kind of see the point of view
of each character.
Yeah, there were two separate scenes
until we figured out,
"This is the same information,
we should put it in one scene.
"Let's just edit these things together."
Then me and Steve went at it
and started writing it as one scene,
playing with the cuts back and forth.
As soon as we had that,
it was really working.
Here's Mom, what Mom wants to hear.
And here's Merida,
what Merida wants to hear.
So you know later on
when Mom's dressing Merida
and they're together that
they have this uncomfortable silence.
It's like, "Now here's the moment where
you guys can speak to each other."
And then they let it go,
‘cause they're incapable of doing that.
We have the introduction of the lords.
We had had it when they first arrived,
but it was nice to see them
arrive by longship,
just to get a sense of who they are,
having their names
announced by the pride of their clan.
Also, get a little sense of who
their characters are in the boat,
but that there's instantaneously
this rivalry between them.
So it doesn't come as a surprise
in the next scene
where they actually get to the castle.
Weren't you playing drums on that?
I was playing drums.
I'm the last guy who's rocking out.
We got that going on, yeah.
When you see them rolling in
on those ships,
you want to feel, "Here comes trouble."
Absolutely. Absolutely.
In this sequence,
we didn't always have the medallion.
We had it in other versions,
but with the medallion,
we needed something later on
to give to the Witch to pay for the spell,
but also to give Merida the spell
in the first place, right?
Why would this witch
come out of retirement
to do these spells if not for something
that's really, really, really valuable.
And we had to go back in
and put the medallion into
all those finished shots.
We wanted to feel that
longing for that connection
that keeps falling away.
They have these moments
where they could,
if they could remember the language,
how to talk to each other.
And like a lot of parents and children,
you can get out of sync with each other.
And you're wishing
they would find a way to do it.
We actually cut this scene
from the movie in one iteration
thinking that it was too much.
But then later on,
once we had the movie together,
we realized
that we needed to put it back in,
‘cause what it showed was
they had this moment that they missed,
as characters.
They could have solved
the whole dilemma right here
if they just talked to each other.
But neither of them do.
Here, all Merida has
as she's dressed up by her mom,
she has one defiant gesture
and that's to pull her hair down
out of that wimple,
so that she's taking
some bit of control that she can be,
not just defiant, but her own person.
And now we're in here,
this is the first time
we're kind of meeting the lords.
Which has always been in the film,
hasn't it?
Yeah, there's always been
this setting up the stakes
of the threat of these guys
that are coming to Merida's fate.
We always had them where
they didn't get along with each other,
so we knew they were always
in danger of spinning off the rails
and going to war at a moment's notice.
So they were always
brewing as this threat.
But the way to introduce them
changed many times
over the course
of the story development.
Well, part of her marriage
is keeping the peace as well.
It's the inter-marriage between clans.
The fun thing about Fergus
setting up as not being
a very good public speaker,
as all kings should probably be
good public speakers,
was again to illustrate
that Mom is there to back him up.
We had always talked about
maybe she practiced with Fergus
of what he was going to say.
And as soon as he starts to blow it,
then she could very simply
just jump up and fill in.
And here's her potential suitors.
We've got
Mr. Captain Arrogance right here.
Which they weren't always
in the film either.
For a long time it was
just the lords themselves.
But we thought it was better to always
have this parent’child relationship.
This is setting up, still,
the competition between
all of the lords
that are introducing their sons,
their stories get more extravagant
and each of their sons
are clearly different characters.
And again, the animators
just blew this out of the water.
Yeah, Young MacGuffin here
being the shy,
afraid of his own powers,
even though he is the strongest,
the most powerful one.
Macintosh, the first guy,
with the sword being
all cocky pants and arrogant.
And then this gag,
which is one of my favorites.
-With Dingwall? Yeah.
-With Dingwall.
He's always kind of
the butt of everybody's joke.
I mean, we even wanted him where
he came in on a little dinghy,
he never had a longboat.
Just 'cause he's so diminished and that
his son is totally diminished, too.
But you have this hulking,
we call him Conan, the big buff guy.
You know, that that is the hero.
He has the hero physique.
But then just to illustrate that these are
totally fish stories and exaggerated.
Also you can completely understand
why Merida wouldn't like any of them.
Exactly.
And Kevin McKidd is speaking
a dialect called Doric
which his mother speaks and he would
send his lines home to her.
And she would give him a translation
and he'd come in all ready
with this incomprehensible
authentic dialect
to do his lines as Young MacGuffin.
Yeah, it was a great character piece.
And to have
that character of Scotland in there,
because there are so many dialects
in Scotland and it's so varied.
And that was another thing
that really impressed me
when we were there researching,
was how varied not only the terrain are,
but also the climates and the people
and the dialects.
And this is clearly setting up
that Mom is the ultimate peacekeeper
between all of the lords.
So this is, again,
exposition through entertainment
so you realize as the film will go on,
this is information
you need to be aware of
-that will happen later on.
-Right.
If they're left to their own devices.
Yeah, I mean,
they're just a big bunch of children,
and how easily they erupt into fighting.
Right? How can you run a kingdom
with these guys being in charge?
But Elinor is able to calm it down.
And that's what
this whole part of the sequence was for.
And there was a lot of talk about
how violent the sequence was,
or how much fighting there was.
And there was actually
more fighting in it
than what you're seeing
in the current thing.
I cut it down a little bit,
but just only a little bit.
A lot of it is still there.
A lot of it is in there.
But again, that, for the story point,
is to pay off Elinor being able to do this.
This one thing, to be able to
calm down everybody,
going into this hornet's nest
and get them all in line.
That's the respect that she commands.
And even the King's walking back to
his seat and sitting down,
cowed like a pet.
Then we learn later what happens when
you take Mom out of this equation.
‘Cause you can guess at it now
by watching this,
if Mom wasn't there,
this would probably go on for days.
In this moment,
we're trying to let the audience know
that Merida has something in mind.
We want to go to the games feeling like
she's got a workaround for this problem.
She's sorted it out
and heard something that Mom said.
And we played with this different ways,
until we just...
We wanted to see the thinking
and the problem solving on her face.
And it cracked us up,
this animation of her
jumping out of her chair,
"Archery, archery!"
And it was pretty late
that we were giving her
the choice of which event
that she could compete in.
But I think it really solidified it
that she now has...
She's in a power position.
Right. And making it work logically
with Mom's statement of,
here are the rules of this thing,
that it is customary for a princess
to pick the competition
for these guys to compete in.
It just kind of lines up
how she's going to solve this problem.
‘Cause she has no way out. Right?
She's stuck in this. How possibly
is she gonna get out of this?
We wanted to feel like
she was backed into a corner.
So you would forgive her for
going against her mom
and trying to solve her own problem.
So we have the games here.
And again, this was part of
the Scottish culture
where the Highland Games were
mostly created so
you could practice war arts
under the nose of the English
without them actually knowing.
So all the games
go back to that kind of thing
versus how they are played today.
Here we see the triplets
being chased by Maudie,
which is going to be a setup
and a payoff for
later on in the film in the third act.
Fantastic atmosphere
in the background,
just to set the depth of those Highlands.
-That is a Carnyx.
-Carnyx, yeah.
Yeah. And that tongue actually moves.
There's a little wooden piece with it.
Yeah, it was
an actual war horn they would use,
usually shaped like a boar.
And so we adapted it to make it a bear.
So it's thematically for our movie.
But they would use that 'cause
it would rise up above the soldiers.
Yeah, it would be
up above the attacking armies
and scare the other army to death.
That predates the bagpipe.
The crowds in this movie
are spectacular.
They're just amazing.
I mean, just the character design.
I don't know how many different people
we actually had
and different hair designs
and different clothes
that they could inter-swap just to
make them this mass of individuals.
It just really works fantastic.
And just again setting up
character through action.
Every one of these archers has
a different way of shooting that bow.
And this guy is just hilarious.
And his little groupie girls behind him.
Long ago we had
a version of this where,
before we had the lords' sons,
there was a version of the games
where Merida just didn't like this idea of
these guys playing for her at all.
And so she just gets in there
and starts a brawl.
-We actually had a haggis toss.
-Yeah, yeah, yeah.
And as the haggis was being lobbed
high in the air
she shoots through one of the haggis
and drenches everybody
and causes this blowup
that turns into a fistfight.
So as we worked on the story
we kind of dialed in
and made it these
very specific characters
that she's showing up
instead of the kind of general crowd.
Right. Which works really well because
we establish in the scene before
that this is part of the tradition.
This is a thing that happens
and that there are
specific rules for this tradition.
And Merida has found, as the
impetuous teenager always does,
the exception to the rules,
or the loophole for the rules.
So, she's actually right.
She's following the rules in her mind.
But at the end of the day
she's taken advantage of the system
and made everybody look like fools
and that's what leads to this big blowup.
But we're wanting to
agree with her at this point.
-We are forcing her into a corner.
-Yeah, we're one on her side.
I mean, what princess would want to be
forced to marry somebody
she doesn't want to?
The idea of the dress ripping
has been there forever.
Because it's, again,
another symbol of Mom
and the way Mom has identified Merida.
And Merida is pushing back against
that in a really visual, tangible way.
And for a long time she was never able
to make the third shot.
Mom was always able
to stop that third shot.
And then Nick here says,
"What if she does win?"
Yeah, it just creates for bigger stakes.
l also wanted to do this in slow motion
to really just put the aspect of,
she is winning herself.
And she has to beat them undoubtedly,
in no uncertain terms,
that she is the best and so
you couldn't argue it away from her.
So, I really wanted to slow it down.
I had a lot more slow motion moments
in the sequence.
And it stayed too long in Nick's terms.
-We overstayed our welcome?
-That's correct.
But we really get to break down and see
the archers' paradox
that happens with the bow.
You guys can
look that up on Wikipedia.
But it actually occurs.
The argument.
This was a scene that we had
done really early on in the film.
And it always remained as
the ultimate fight,
the knock-down drag-out
between Mom and Merida here
that we really wanted to
kick off the rest of the film.
Yeah, Emma Thompson worked
herself up into a froth
when she was doing this scene.
It was amazing,
‘cause she actually had the stool
in the studio
in her hands and her face turned red.
And she had really gotten herself
into a state
to get Mom's rage in this moment.
It's like all that bottled up rage
at her daughter's misbehavior
is coming out.
Well, there's something great
in this scene, too,
that they really go at each other here.
But they both cross the line
and regret it.
Merida chops that tapestry
and Mom burns that bow,
but you quickly see that they
come down out of their tempers.
Right. There's hypocrisy that's going on
in this scene for both characters.
That they're both unwilling to yield,
and, yeah, they cross the line in their
attempt to punish the other person.
And it just all goes bad from there.
Yeah, and Emma dialed up the intensity
even more so than she had before.
And she adlibbed that line,
"It'll be fire and sword
if it's not set right."
We loved when our actors would
give us material like that
that felt really authentic.
I mean, Emma Thompson's
a writer in her own right.
So, it was great to work with her
and get her suggestions
and it was like
watching a private performance
every time we're recording her.
And Mom knew
she was wrong right away.
Like a parent,
sometimes you step over the line
and realize you're acting like a kid.
And she regrets it right away
when she steps over
and hurts that precious bow.
This is the same bow that Dad
gave her in the beginning of the movie.
Merida, in this moment,
we always felt like
she was a teenager that got into her car
and drove out of the driveway
and took off.
And she's just letting Angus
run wherever he wants.
She's just along for the ride
and just wailing.
And this scene here, the ring of stones,
we had debated for a long time
on how to introduce this location.
There was even a time
earlier on in the film
where Merida and her dad
had actually seen this spot before
and now she's going to return to it.
But ultimately we came down to,
"Just let her visit the place
when she happens to go there."
Right. These big standing stones
that are around in Scotland
that were set up by the Picts
or who knows who
and what their purpose was
is still in question.
But there's ideas about fairy rings
and circle rings being magical.
And for our purposes in Brave
this circle ring is magical.
It ends up being a type of portal
that we always return to.
And Angus knows it and Angus...
That animal sense is why
he won't cross into the circle,
is that something is going to happen.
He kind of understands that
on his animalistic level.
We were inspired by
the Callanish stones
which we saw on our research trip.
But there's all kinds of stones like this
scattered around in Scotland.
You could just find a strange stone
in someone's backyard.
Right. Whether they were
stood up by giants, or...
One of our guys
had a great idea, a theory
that they were way markers
for navigating across land.
That you'd be able to see them
and they'd point you in a direction of
where the next stones were,
or where the next town or village
or city was.
And I thought was
a really interesting idea.
l hadn't heard that one before.
But the wisps here are leading her
to her fate or a possible fate.
And she follows them,
like she followed them
at the beginning of the movie,
which leads her to the Witch's cottage.
Feel the lighting going darker.
We know we're getting into
unchartered terrain in here,
and that it's a little more threatening.
A little bit more Snow White
to the forest here.
Yeah, magical going from
the light side into the dark side.
This ancient black house cottage.
It looks like the cottages
that we saw in Scotland as well.
Stone cottage with...
Covered with like grass
and moss on top.
Now this scene was the very first scene
that we ever got approved
to go into production on the film,
but actually turned out to be
the very last scene we actually
got finalized in making the film.
Yeah, there was so many different
versions of who this Witch was.
And how even Merida even entered
or discovered
what was really going on in this set.
Julie Walters does
a fantastic job with the voice.
And we went over a lot of ground,
really nailing down and getting specific
with who this character was.
From a nice old lady to a maniac lady
to a ditzy lady.
She tried it tons of different ways
before we finally
got the scene working right.
And now she's just
kind of a proud salesman.
This kindly old lady who just does art
in the back of her house,
but is very excited about
the prospect of having a customer.
At one point we had her as this
addled lunatic that had cabin fever.
And when she'd see a wisp,
it was like a mouse in her kitchen
and she'd just wail at it with her broom.
We're really fighting
what everybody knows about witches.
We've seen them so much
in films and in literature
that they come with their own baggage.
So how do we make it fresh and new
and super entertaining.
The Crow character is unique
in that we discovered along the way
of building the scene.
We found that the Witch doesn't have
anybody to counter off of.
So, how do you
make this organic scene happen
with just Merida asking questions?
And she was not necessarily
going to ask the correct questions.
Also, how do we find out that
she's actually a witch and does spells.
So, came up
with this idea of having a crow.
You know, like a familiar pet
that can actually talk,
and that would ultimately
give away that she's a witch.
But the Crow had a larger role
in one of the versions of the scenes
where they acted
like an old married couple.
It would antagonize her and
she'd tell it to shut up and everything.
And he would mutter to himself,
"lL was a man. l was a man."
We thought that was fantastic.
And so Steve actually
does the voice of the Crow.
And he does an excellent job.
We knew in the sequence
it was a pivotal moment
for Merida to get the device
that was going to alter her life
and set things in motion.
But we also had to learn that the
Witch and Mor'du had a relationship,
that she dealt out the same type of spell
ora spell for him, too,
that we find out later is the same.
But how do we
get those kinds of exposition
that we absolutely need to have,
and make it entertaining?
Yeah, there are a group of elements
floating around in the story,
the first being Mom's story
about the ancient kingdom,
and then you get
a second set of information
when you're in here about the prince.
And then it's not until the ruins
that you find out the full story.
Right.
We came up with this idea that
when she walks in
it's a wood carver's shop
to throw off the audience to the scent.
And also, Merida, what she's expecting
the wisps lead her to.
So she's entirely confused.
And she's kind of like a witch in hiding.
We kept a lot of these elements
that she was a witch,
she doesn't want to do it anymore
because of...
Well, you deal with magic
and things go bad.
And she doesn't want to do that.
And she finds her true bliss,
which was in carving.
Of course, we had these questions
come up of, "Why a bear?"
Why does the spell
always turn people into bears?
And we went round and around
with a bunch of different ideas.
We finally
just made her this wood carver
and all she carves was bears
because she's just obsessed
and just left it at that.
‘Cause it doesn't really, ultimately,
at the end of the day,
need to be explained.
You know, whether she only knew
one trick out of a book.
So she doesn't want to
give Merida the spell,
‘cause she doesn't want to
go back down those roads
and into her past.
So Merida having the necklace
be an essential part of
getting the spell from her,
being this expensive jeweled thing
that Merida would
buy all the wood from her,
we thought was an element that worked.
And also kept the idea of the necklace.
‘Cause the necklace used to be
another birthday present for Merida
given to her by her mom.
And it had much more
of a significant value
that we kind of took away.
And just had it as part of
Mom dressing her up to be like her.
We see Mom wearing it
at the beginning of the movie,
but we don't go into that kind of value
as deeply as we did.
I love that all the most dramatic
and unusual lighting
is in the sequences with the Witch.
The most, kind of...
The greens and the odd back lighting
and the reds and stuff
are coming out in her sequences.
In the background
Dad is singing this drinking song.
And we just wanted to
keep alive the idea
that there's this dangerous situation
brewing in the castle.
And so, it was kind of inspired by
things like Pirates Of The Caribbean,
where it's this good-natured song
about doing terrible things.
In this case it's about
how many different ways
they're going to kill Mor'du
and slaughter him and make stew
out of him and things like that.
And, Steve, you wrote a lot of that,
didn't you?
Alex Mandel and I wrote a version.
And then Patrick Doyle
wrote a more Scottish version
that has a lot more
Scottish references in it.
We got our loop group together
and taught them the song
and it was like an old drinking song.
It was singing it in rounds,
it was fantastic fun.
Yes, so we wanted to
hit the story notes of,
you know, that Dad's been
looking for this bear for a long time
and plans to hang his head
up on the wall as soon as he can.
There's a little moment of hesitation
in here
where Merida thinks Mom has already
come around to her way of thinking.
And it makes her question whether
she should see this spell through or not.
Merida thinks her mom is relenting
and she's going to get her way,
therefore, no need for the cake.
But then when Mom goes,
"But you still have to
go through with everything,"
then she's going to give her this cake.
Now, Mom is totally misunderstanding
thinking Merida's totally solved
and will go along
with her way of doing things,
not knowing
that she's being had right now.
And we kept talking about this moment
of what does Merida expect
the spell cake is going to do?
Change her right away?
Is she going to just up and eat it and go,
"You know what, on second thought
you don't have to get married."
So, Merida is
constantly staring at her mom
looking for any sign of change.
And we just keep that build-up going
until we get our answer a little later.
Yeah, our big brain trust note
for this idea was,
you wanted to feel like Mom turned into
the worst possible thing
that she could be in this situation,
which was a bear.
Because everybody in this place hates
bears and wants to do away with them.
Right. And just keep that,
it's the fun-naturedness of Fergus
that we have
that, when it actually happens
and there's a bear in the castle,
he is like the Terminator
going after this bear.
So we had that contrast.
For him it's an adventure.
It's like Jaws,
when those guys go after the shark,
it's scary but it's fun at the same time.
It's got this adventure spirit to it.
l remember we used to have
Mom physically change
that she would grow hair,
her fingernails.
And it started in this scene
a long time ago,
the shots still remain the same.
But after a while it was that we were
taking a lot of those elements out
to keep the surprise
as much as possible.
And there was also that idea
that she was changing into
and looking like Fergus,
because he was a bear king.
And so you think
she's going to turn into him,
but then ultimately turns into a bear.
So it was kind of confusing.
"What are we actually saying?
What direction are we going?"
So we stripped that back out
and gave her this tummy ache instead,
which was very entertaining.
But Merida doesn't know
what to expect with the spell.
Is it working or not?
When is Mom just going to turn around
and say, "You know what,
this whole thing is over,
"let me go talk to everybody"?
So, we just keep that idea going.
One of the original concepts was that
she wanted Mom to be more like Dad.
Right.
‘Cause Dad was much more
easygoing on her
and less demanding of Merida.
Right. So, to solve her problem,
"If Mom became Dad
"I'd be done."
But again, we took that back out
because I didn't want the story
to be about parent comparison.
-Competition between parents.
-Yeah.
So, along the way
we just wanted to feel that
Merida is totally obsessed with the idea
that Mom is going to
change into something.
Not necessarily physically,
but just the idea of
coming around to her way of thinking.
Some of this transformation
was inspired by...
We were looking for humor and horror
at the same time.
And so one of the references that
we were thinking about was Pinocchio,
when kids turn into donkeys and
how it's kind of horrifying and shadowy
and there's a strange goofiness to it
at the same time.
So, when she's smashing into the bed
and everything it's funny,
but the size of it,
the scale of the transformation
can be scary at the same time.
Yeah, there's a great contrast
of reality and comedy
that happens in this sequence,
that we know the sequence was working
when we were getting it.
You know, where you were scared
but it wasn't horrific
and you can laugh at the same time.
Then go, "Oh, my gosh,
that thing is huge."
And then laugh because the tapestry
fell over its head, you know?
And that you're bouncing back and forth
between those elements.
And to also make the scene fun,
you can have somebody
transform into a bear and freak out,
but it's not going to
have that entertainment
or the fun that we...
It was really difficult
to find it in that scene.
But once we found it,
it really played well.
Yeah, I mean, getting it in storyboards
and basically composing this
and doing the shots
and finding it,
there's that entertainment value,
but it's not until
you actually get into the animation
where the subtlety of the acting
really transforms the scene
and gives you those subtleties
that you need in character.
And Merida is just annoyed
because this thing didn't go at all
the way she was expecting it to.
And there's no way she's going to
accept any responsibility at this point.
She's just annoyed.
She feels like
she was ripped off by the Witch.
It's still not her fault,
in true teenager fashion.
It's, "Il didn't do this to you,
the Witch obviously did this to you."
We actually played it in certain versions
for a long time
where Merida didn't know
if this was her mom at all
or this fierce, threatening bear.
And we ultimately decided that
the earlier you can perceive
that Mom's personality is
inside the bear, the better off we are.
Yeah, you could just
get right to the dilemma of,
"Oh, my gosh, my mom's a bear.
"How do I get her out of this castle
filled with bear-hating men
"that hunt bears and kill bears?"
And then again, pushing that idea that
Mom doesn't care that she's a bear.
She's going to go out and
she's going to talk to Fergus about this,
or go find that Witch.
And so we have this dilemma of
there's a bear in the castle
and Fergus is already onto it.
Which gives us
this just great entertainment value of
how do you get this huge thing
out of the castle?
Immediately, they have
the worst thing on their tail,
the pressure and the stakes go right up.
Right up. And when we figured this out
we go, "That's a win.
"That's entertainment right there,”
and we could push this moment.
And the other physical devices we used
to illustrate Mom being in there,
she puts her crown on.
In her mind,
she's just the same as she was before.
She puts her crown on and she pulls
curtains up around her as a dress,
because it's not proper
to go out undressed.
-And she stays queenly all through this.
-Totally.
The way that she walks and behaves
and everything.
But she's in this gigantic body
so she's constantly
not used to knocking things over.
And we see, visually, that
she doesn't fit in this world anymore.
Again, keeping that tension up
with the little sound
and Fergus is hunting them.
Photographing this 5'4" redheaded girl
and this nine-foot-tall bear
was a pain in the butt.
The lenses that we used,
the camera angles that we used.
We'd always have to be lower or higher
to get 'em both in frame.
And I like to keep them both in frame
because we had
that sense of environment
that they're there together,
instead of just using singles,
which don't necessarily
give you the value
of the relationship of the characters.
You'd have to rely on eye line.
But to have them both in the shot,
sharing the shot together,
either in a two-shot or in overs,
was just really difficult to keep going
because of
the size change of Mom-bear.
And whenever you don't see the floor,
we're sinking Mom into the floor.
And we're cheating a lot.
And the 2.39 aspect ratio
exacerbated it, too.
It doesn't help anything.
I mean, it is the screen ratio of the gods.
But it doesn't help when things are tall.
We had a whole section at one point
where they go outside the castle
and then they had to make it to the wall.
And so we had
a couple of guards on the wall
and they have to distract one...
It just got too much.
And the sequence suffered from,
when we were building it,
a lot of stop and starts,
stop and starts, stop and starts.
And those kind of moments
where you would run into an obstacle
that you'd have to stop, distract them
or figure out a way to get around them.
Then start up again
to find another obstacle,
it was just slowing down
the pacing of the sequence.
So we had to trim it all down,
keep it in the castle,
because that was a great visual
of inside to outside,
it's just a clearer read
of they've gotten out.
Once they get out,
then I can cross this off
and they could be
anywhere in Scotland.
So, that part of the story
became more action oriented
and less of the time we needed
for them to engage with each other
as characters.
We wanted to raise the stakes and
have them in the castle to be chased.
And so we came up with this idea
that she goes and she gets help
from her triplet brothers
to distract King Fergus and the lords
so that they can get out.
We came up with this idea that
they're chasing this ghost shadow
through the castle.
And it was originally a little puppet,
a little wooden puppet.
And then at some point it got changed
into a barbecued chicken on a stick.
Yeah, we thought that the puppet,
while it worked and while it was logical,
there was just something
way more comedic
about putting
a chicken on the end of a stick.
Was it a wooden puppet?
It was a wooden puppet.
It was a wood puppet.
It looked like a quick carving,
like something
that they can do really fast.
And I don't know if it was
in a review with John or somebody
they said it was just too...
Like they thought about it,
and it had to be
even a quicker decision
like, "What do we use?
What do we use?"
You know, out of your resources.
It's like, "Grab that chicken."
And we all laughed
at the impossibility of it.
It works.
But this is animation for crying out loud.
It totally works.
And it does its job.
You have this great scene.
And they had built this whole castle set
with all these ins and outs,
but it's such a great, great set
inside this castle,
l wanted to exploit that even more and
have these shots inside and outside.
We used to have
Dad go out on the road
hunting Mom as a bear
and putting the pressure
on Merida and Mom.
And what we found is that
it made it more difficult
for Merida and Mom
to have character moments together
if there was always
heat on them from behind.
So, this gave us a comedic way
to let Dad be
the single-minded bear hunter guy.
That's Victor Navone's animation
of the chicken on his head.
He came up with a dozen different ways
of this guy coming down the chimney
into the oven there to scare Maudie.
And one of them was
he came down
with the chicken on his head.
And I'm all, "Bingo, that's the one."
This is also Victor with the snot.
There were so many ways that,
after they came out of their tussle,
he had about six different ideas
and he's all, "I don't know
if you're going to like this one."
And when he showed it to us,
it was the booger coming out.
l said, "Done."
Everybody who has a toddler
sees that six times a day.
Yeah, right, that's right. That's right.
And this is setting up...
When they come over and they see
the cake, "Anything that you want."
We had to, 'cause we're
transforming them into bears later,
we had to leave 'em off
with finding that spell cake
where Merida had left it
from the previous scene.
And it'll be a long time
till you see them as bears,
so we wanted to make it very clear that
you knew what was going to happen
when they ate that cake.
Our first shot of nudity, I think,
in all of animation right there.
-For Pixar.
-For Pixar, nudity.
I'd have to have
animation historians look into that.
Right.
Actually, I think, also one of Kelly's
first line reads was on this scene.
We did a test on this, right?
We did a test on this
which was amazing.
She really knocked it out of the park.
In this travel sequence with
Mom and Merida on the road together,
we were always trying to balance
how upset can they be with each other.
Because you know
there's contention there,
but you want it to be entertaining.
You don't want it to go on so long
that you can't stand to be around them,
but you want to feel like
they're at odds with each other.
Because Merida just did
a horrific thing to her mom.
And we wanted to
hold back Merida's self-realization
-that she had screwed up.
-Exactly.
Yeah, so she's being stubborn
and she wants to do things her way,
and Mom is asserting herself her way.
And they're just not getting along.
But we didn't want to see them
arguing the whole time either.
Right. We had the griping happen
during the walk
and it wasn't working.
It seemed like
she was being really mean.
So then we moved it
and got a different read on it,
like it was under her breath
before they started walking,
let them kind of walk in this silence.
And all of a sudden it totally worked.
In a very old version
of this part of the movie,
we actually had
Merida go back to the castle
and leave Mom in the Witch's cottage.
And Mom was in there getting hungry,
trying to make tea
and she burns the place down
and comes racing through the forest
on fire,
like, her rear end is caught on fire.
The demon hell-bear, yeah.
Yeah, and the villagers see this bear
with a fiery halo around it
and send home the news that
Mor'du is rampaging through the forest.
Which sent Dad out on the hunt.
This had gone through
a few iterations, too,
that the cottage was dilapidated,
it was old.
Right. It was destroyed.
We had weird magic happening
where hundreds of years have passed.
But we had this idea that they return
and there's a note on the door.
Well, a note on the door
is not good enough.
It's not dynamic, a note on the door.
Or that the Witch was there
and packing up and leaving,
and she could tell herself.
But then that's not dynamic.
And we thought,
"Why doesn't she use magic?"
And this idea of this magical
answering machine came up.
One of my favorite lines in here is...
Steve wrote this sequence.
We were really balancing how modern
the Witch needed to sound,
as if this was her shop
and she's leaving this message
of the things that she can do.
"We had wedding cake toppers,"
and "for messages in Gaelic vial two,"
and "to speak to a live homunculus"
is probably my favorite,
one of my favorite lines
in the whole movie.
And then John Lasseter
had this great moment
to make this really impactful
of the spell,
the actual wording of the spell
is that, clunk, we go red
and we put echo on it and all this stuff
and made it kind of sinister.
And she was really
acting the part of the Witch,
which is the only time
she's really traditionally witchy.
Well, there were years
that went into making
those specific words of that spell.
And we used to
include the lords' relics.
The lords' relics,
that she had to gather them all.
-Caldrons, swords...
-Stones...
Right, or we needed their tribal artifacts
to make the spell go away.
Yeah, that was a red herring
because it was talking about the relics
which were physical objects
in the movie.
But when later Merida realizes
the relics had been
sewn into the corners of the tapestry.
Which I think still exists in the tapestry.
Yeah. They're in the tapestry
but they're just an element.
And then we had later used
that they were the physical lords.
It was the kingdom,
this family had to see this apology.
But then we just left that element out
until we found the actual words
that really worked.
And it's a lot of trial and error.
Story, these moments,
everything is trial and error.
Right? Reworking it and watching it.
And you only find that organically,
you know?
That's what makes it alchemy.
So the cottage has blown up.
The message machine blows up.
They overload it accidentally
with the magical spells.
In kind of our homage
to Mission: Impossible.
So, any chance
of getting any kind of concoction
that's going to change Mom back
.
IS now gone.
And we have their low moment.
We had this whole other scene
where Mom freaks out
and she gets caught and choked
by ropes and stuff and lashings
and then Merida calms her down.
But it was just too much,
that they can both realize
there's something about getting
the rug pulled out from under you
that was more meaningful.
It slowed everything down
and brought
the weight of their dilemma to light.
And then Mom is mad at her daughter,
but can't say anything,
and she gives her that one look
and rolls over.
And now Merida...
It's really hitting Merida,
her guilt of what she's selfishly done.
This actually came
before the first scene.
Yes, the flashback.
We had a young Merida here
that we knew we needed to get.
But we were debating
whether we were going to have,
because of the difficulties
of creating a young Merida.
So, as soon as that other scene,
the opening scene,
we said, "We definitely need
a young Merida."
Then I said, "Then this is going in."
Patrick Doyle wrote the beautiful lullaby
that was translated into Gaelic and...
Sung by Emma Thompson and Peigi.
Yeah, it was beautiful.
We had had a temp song in there
that was Gaelic
that was about drowning at sea
or something, wasn't it?
But since we didn't understand
the words, it sounded beautiful to us.
It did, it was totally beautiful.
We couldn't hear
the drowning story within it.
The run up into this area
is like a power struggle
between Merida and Mom.
And Merida has the upper hand
because she's still a human being,
but Mom still tries
to maintain her authority.
And then, of course,
Merida, knowing the woods,
knows that everything Mom has done,
while good-natured and well-meaning,
.
IS wrong.
There's worms in the water,
she picked poisoned berries.
So, they're not going to survive.
She's out of her element there.
She's out of her element big time.
And we're in Merida's world.
And this is where the transition
happens for us in the story
of Merida becomes the parent now
over the person that needs help,
which is her mother,
who's now in the child's role.
It turns out a nightshade berry
will not kill you, but it'll make you dizzy.
-So...
-Just dizzy, not sick?
Sick and dizzy. But...
We said poisonous
and that is poisonous.
‘Cause they're actually
called deadly nightshade, right?
Yeah. I guess if you have enough
of something that makes you dizzy,
-you're going to die.
-Right, sure.
But poisonous,
we're right on the money.
Mom would have to
eat a bucket of them to have any effect.
Well, she's a bear,
she probably could eat a bucket.
To talk about the production design
a little bit,
we go from this very cold, dim,
rain-filled scene of sorrow and misery to
they wake up
still in this kind of blue mood
but it's dawn.
But now,
the light is coming into their lives.
The light is
coming into their relationship.
The dynamics of their relationship
is changing.
It's the first step of them
actually working together.
Yeah. But all of what Mom said before
is now coming back to haunt her.
"Oh, if l never had weapons training
we'd be starving to death."
"Here is food that you need
but you're not going to try it," you know?
And so there's a little push back.
So we go into the fishing sequence,
which had to be locked down story-wise
fairly early on
when we came up
with the idea for this sequence
because of the incredibly long time
it would take to do the water effects.
So, David MacCarthy,
D-Mac and his team
needed to have this sequence
locked down,
which, in animation,
doesn't always necessarily happen.
So, we got it down to its nitty-gritty
and locked it down.
And had to get the song in there,
so we had the length of all the shots
and they started working
on the effects of the sequence
a year before the film was completed.
It takes that long to do the water effects.
And it turned out,
it's breathtaking, that river.
They did an amazing job.
There's so many elements
involved in it, just the water flow,
then there's the foaminess of it,
and the interaction with it.
The splashes, the aeration in the water.
Lighting did a fantastic job lighting it
so you get that gold
and those blue reflections in there.
It's a moving sculpture, is what it is,
and it's gorgeous.
And it's so authentic looking
you just accept it.
You don't actually appreciate it enough
unless somebody tells you to look at it.
Because it feels so natural.
And here comes the song to explain
this new dynamic of their relationship
also written by Alex Mandel.
He and Steve worked on it quite a bit.
And when I heard it for the first time
Il said, "This is beautiful.
"I'm keeping this one in definitely.”
‘Cause it just
summed up their relationship
in this very economical
and emotional way.
I mean, the music just plays into this
where it's not a celebration
and it's not a victory.
There's something still tentative
about it, but hopeful.
And the sim, the simulation department,
to get that wet bear and Merida all wet
and their clothes wet and clingy,
Claudia and her team is just fantastic.
It just all goes together.
‘Cause it's a really memorable,
important moment,
it's one of the brightest
sequences in the movie
with this golden light about them
playing and finding each other again
and seeing each other differently.
So, all these technical aspects
just go in concert
to make the sequence memorable.
What could make Merida's crazy hair
even more complicated to do?
"Let's get it wet now."
If you look in the background on this,
we have bugs
flying around in the sunlight.
All these clouds of bugs
flying around back there
to make that forest feel alive.
I mean, that's something
that Ridley Scott did in Legend
when he filmed all of it inside on stages,
that he can really control
the atmosphere and the debris
that you get for free in the forest.
And we did the same thing. I wanted
atmosphere throughout this movie,
because it's there in Scotland,
in the air,
knocking back the backgrounds.
And you see little clingy clouds and
then there's midges all over the place.
There's bugs all over the place,
so we needed that,
and it just really helps with the texture.
We used to have a version of the story
where the entire set
was covered in snow.
Two-thirds of the movie
took place in a snow cover
which was based
on the effect of the spell.
Kind of having this global effect.
And what we gained
by losing that idea is
we just get a beautiful view of Scotland
that we wouldn't have had if we were
covering up all these great sets.
A lot of work done on the snow
that we decided was not needed
for the movie to tell the story.
No. It was pretty amazing stuff actually.
The tests on the snow were fantastic.
And we had the opening of the movie
which took place
with Fergus in the snow.
So we had it, but then we chopped it.
So, there is only one shot that exists
in the world, that's in the trailer,
is Fergus coming across the snow
in his armor.
We have the flyover with the snow.
Right, we got the snow
in the very beginning of the film
in the montage.
We had a whole sequence in here
that we cut out
of them getting chased by wolves,
which was quite fantastic
as an action sequence goes.
But ultimately
does not serve the story well.
And there were lots of sequences
that we had in the movie
where we thought we needed
to spend the time with them,
so that they can
earn their reward at the end.
They could actually have
a longer journey.
But it's pretty fantastic to see
just editing it down
what exactly do we need.
We get every moment.
And by the end
they still earn this journey.
The wisp sound design is amazing.
To get this kind of whispery effect
that almost sounds like
unintelligible talking whispers.
But from children.
It had this eerie quality,
but nice, too, really.
There's nothing creepier
than children whispering.
-Right.
-Unless it's clowns whispering.
So, this was a key moment
when they find the ruins
and the crossed battleaxes,
the sigil of House Mor'du
that she's seen before
so that we know it's not just a story.
It's on the ring that the Witch had.
These stories are now
coming into contact with each other.
And then the Witch is
one of the hubs of this story.
And that the wisps
are leading them here
so that Merida can find those answers.
And I wanted it to be a very stark place,
just devoid of life and color.
And that's an actual broch.
That's what they look like in Scotland.
Which was the first castle fortresses
done in almost prehistoric ages
and they're insane,
the construction on them is so simple.
What I love about Steve Pilcher's
art design, especially in here,
is Merida is like a target on screen.
And no matter what setting you're in,
you spot her right away
‘cause her hair is so striking
and has that kind of unnatural
cherry red which is... It's great.
You just always know
where she is on screen.
And she's the only color in the room.
And I love how, in this scene,
her face goes white,
and her hair, even though it's red,
it's very pale.
It's like an illustrated book.
Yeah. But seeing this location
colorless, gray, dead.
Yeah. This is the worst place to be,
but she's getting all the information.
Exactly. And we're tying it all together.
And that's why the wisps
ultimately lead her here.
So she can put together
and solve this mystery.
Her flashback,
that was my little ode to Porco Rosso.
-Miyazaki film.
-Yeah.
Porco is a pig and she's looking at him
and he's a man.
And then she looks at him
and he's a pig again.
So [kind of did the reverse
where, in her flashback,
she sees Prince Mor'du,
but then he turns
and it's the face of Mor'du.
So, we lock home
they're one and the same
before she figures it out here.
This is one of the great things
about working at Pixar
is what we're willing to do
to tell the story.
And Brave is the darkest film
Pixar has done.
And that we can go into that
and go into this dark place,
and have this really
intense, scary moment
and come out of it fine, unscathed,
where it helps support the story.
It tells the story that this person needs
to understand these consequences
I think is very important, even
for young children to understand.
It seems like that's something
that's in classic folktales and fairytales
is these kind of big ideas
of life and death and loss
and things that kids and people
are grappling with.
Yeah, and she's there.
She goes to her mother for help.
Her mother is not leaving her there
on her own.
The other important fact of this
is that when you ask for help, it's there.
And we have our magical transition
when they ride out into the fog,
and... They're already
in the standing stones,
they've just done
25, 30 miles in no time.
And that's the magic of the world,
that's the portal.
The stones we kind of used
as this hub, the stone ring.
As in legend, all fairy rings
or magical rings
were portals to the other worlds
or even time.
You would have magic toadstools
that you step into and you fall asleep,
when you wake up you're
in some strange new world,
or time has passed
and you had no idea.
But later on for Fergus, since
he doesn't buy into all this magic,
for him the ring of stones
is a corral to corner his prey.
Right.
So they have the answer of the tapestry,
it's back in the castle.
Which, originally in the scene,
the castle was all...
Everybody was fighting, all the clans
were fighting all over the castle.
It was a hornet's nest.
But then,
in a previous incarnation of this,
they try to sneak back in,
they get spotted, they get shot at,
Mom gets an arrow in the butt,
she turns around
as Merida tries to pull it out of her,
she slashes Merida's arm.
Well, when she pulls it out, yeah,
-she turns into a bear.
-She turns into a bear,
and slashes Merida's arm and then
turns back into her bear-human self,
freaks out and then runs off.
And then we had this whole scene
where Mom has given up.
So, not only do you have to get
back into the castle to get the tapestry,
how do you change Mom's mind
and turn her around
to get her back in the castle?
So Merida had to chase her down.
Chase her down, stop her,
and then convince her to come back.
And then they kind of...
And at that point part of
the convincing process
was Merida's saying
how much she loved her
and that she's the strength behind her
and so forth and so on.
Which felt premature,
because then where we play it now
is in the back to the castle scene.
Right. We solved their issue
before we needed to solve their issue.
Right, exactly.
That Mom doesn't get to
experience her daughter
in the moment becoming everything
that her mom hoped that she would be.
So, by taking all that stuff
that happens outside
into this sequence
and collapsing it into...
They're not yet solved
until after this sequence,
and Mom gets to see her,
and get them to where we need to be.
We wanted to hearken back to that
moment of Mom, earlier in the movie,
kind of striding into the middle
of this chaos and taking control of it.
And Merida is kind of
drawing herself together
to be able to do that in this situation.
Right, and then catching
the ire of the lords
who would never do this to the Queen,
but because she's not the Queen
and then kind of assault her
by visually closing in on her.
That Merida handles it in her own way.
The Queen would never yell at them,
but Merida would, you know?
-Like Fergus would.
-Fergus would, yeah, totally.
And it's a key moment.
When we were going through the film
and plotting out Merida's arc,
this was one of
the big tentpole sequences.
And here, with Mom
being in the room, we knew
it was important for Mom to witness
what Merida was about to do,
but through the many iterations
we had Mom ona balcony,
we had her in a separate room...
A doorway.
Yeah, another doorway.
But the story point was still the same
of she needs to be here
to witness what Merida is about to do.
We spent some time
reminding the audience a couple times
where they're going.
So we drive the camera
right up that stairway.
-The goal.
-So, when they're talking about it.
-Yeah.
-We see that goal in a very real way.
And then sometimes you feel like
you want to remind the audience
where they are
and what Mom's intent is
when she comes in there.
She looks up that stairs,
‘cause she wants to get to
the tapestry room and get out of danger.
Yeah, we have a goal
that kind of gets derailed in here.
‘Cause then we get caught up,
just like Mom gets caught up,
of seeing her daughter
be this fantastic person.
So Merida is pulling out
all this knowledge
that Mom has probably been telling her
all her life and it stuck somewhere.
So she's able to draw on this knowledge
of how these guys got together.
And put it back at them
using her storytelling skills
and kind of make them nostalgic
for how they formed as a group.
Yeah, it plays into their characters
and their sense of who they are.
But that, it's totally organic.
Merida is shooting from the hip here.
And it's just a great read.
Kelly Macdonald just did a fabulous job
not only in the whole movie,
but in this scene.
‘Cause you really get some big
emotional scales here
from kind of being nervous
to then being very confident,
to then being very self-conscious
and feeling guilty
about what she's done.
And that she's caused
this whole problem herself.
And kind of saying
that she's sorry, apologizing.
Each of them is going to put themselves
in the line of fire for the other one.
So, to have Mom explain to her,
"How do I tell my daughter it's okay,
she doesn't have to get married?"
And, "I've got another idea.
"And I can't A,
speak, because I'm a bear,
"but B, if anybody turns around
and looks at me, I'm dead."
So, this was a great time to put in that
almost Cyrano de Bergerac moment
of her being able to communicate
through her gesturing
to have it almost come
as the Queen's voice
through Merida to the lords.
It's also a throwback
to that deep thoughts scene
where now they can communicate
to each other without speaking.
They understand
each other completely,
where before they couldn't speak at all,
and didn't understand each other.
There was a lot of film work
to really get that relationship
between where Mom was standing
and where Merida is standing to work.
Working into those POVs
and out of those POVs
and who's seeing what
so that it was believable, what was
happening here with the pantomime.
Steve and I had written
more in the scene
and we pulled out the stuff
that was just the most essential.
And I think that's a great parameter
for any filmmakers out there.
It's when you get into
how important the editing process is
when you're making a film,
even though, in animation,
we storyboard
the whole thing beforehand
and you have a really good idea
of what you're getting into.
There's still a process of,
"Can I hone it down?" That less is more.
And letting the pacing and the timing
kind of guide you to what
really makes a sequence work.
‘Cause you could get caught up
and just be hanging on stuff.
Merida's argument is,
"You guys all got together,
nobody told you to get together,
"it just happened
because of who you were.
"Can't land your sons
do the same thing?
"Can't we be in charge
of our own lives?"
Everybody was saying,
"Well, how do you convince these lords
who come out of this old school,
"and who were raised
on these traditions to agree to this?"
And when we figured out
it shouldn't be them,
it should be their sons who are in
the same situation as Merida,
who may not want to marry her
and are being forced into this,
that they should speak up.
And that's what ultimately
turns everything around,
was our central argument and kind of
one of our themes of the whole movie.
Being able to be brave enough
to say what you want.
-And make your own choices.
And then live by them.
And Dad acknowledges Merida
as the thing that
she was dreading being,
which is some version of Mom,
but in this case,
it turns out to be this positive message
that Dad sees the good part of that.
And she accepts it
in the same way that he says it.
At the end of the scene, we're good.
Merida has come into her own.
Mom, they both recognize each other,
they've come full circle.
Everything is solved.
The story is now solved.
So where do we go?
All we have is this little hiccup
of turning Mom-bear back to Elinor
and getting her human again
as we go into the next bit.
So now that they're as close as
they've been through the entire film,
we're getting ready to separate them
as much as possible here.
Exactly.
That's why we see the cut,
the thing that started it all.
The thing that's still between them,
things get unraveled,
but now that we want them
to stay together,
we separate them big time.
And this is the red herring,
the tapestry was
a red herring in the spell
that had been going around
and around and around
exactly what the wordings
of the spell was
and how they'd figure it out
and how it could...
Literal interpretation versus
our figurative interpretation
of that what's really torn
is their relationship,
not necessarily the tapestry.
So we were going around
and around about that.
If you sew the tapestry up,
does she turn back into a human?
Or do you have to put it
over the top of them?
Or does Merida actually
need to say, "You're sorry"?
So, we're investing in this one tapestry,
this item to be the solve-all thing,
so that later, by the end of the movie
when she puts it on her and it's
all stitched up, nothing happens.
So that our wording
for the spell still works.
And we're about to separate
Mom from the tapestry.
So we're separating Mom
from the solution,
what Merida perceives the solution is.
Why Mom changes into a bear,
what motivates her
to change into a bear,
l wanted to stay away from,
that it just happens.
Because if you have a trigger,
then you're locked into that trigger
and we really couldn't find
a trigger that worked.
It turns out we already had a trigger,
but we didn't know it.
For Mom to turn into a bear, was food,
was this primal sense,
this animalistic sense of just hunger.
So she's eating the fish,
she turns into a bear.
When she's sniffing the apples,
And then whenever
the human side of her came out
was always about compassion.
She was about to hurt somebody
or she has just hurt somebody.
And we tend to think of Mom
when her personality is there
up on her hind legs,
‘cause that's
when she's trying to maintain
what she was when she was a person.
So, when she draws
out of that bear mode
and comes up on her hind legs,
we recognize it right away
as Mom's body language.
This was also interesting that
we've taken probably,
the jolliest character in the film
and now he's in total revenge mode,
which is adding to the stakes of,
and the complications
that Merida now has to deal with.
It's like her father and her closest ally
is now her biggest enemy at this point.
Right. The thing that you fear the most
from the beginning that we see
as just this kind of comedic clown
is now the Terminator
by the end of the movie.
And he's not going to stop
regardless of whether this animal
actually killed his wife or not,
he's going to kill it.
And we needed to go there,
again, to drive up those stakes
and get into this very serious dilemma
of her problem is still not yet solved.
And now Merida is fighting
to get back to her mother,
while, at the beginning of the movie,
she was running away from her mother.
And now you've come
full circle in their arc
about how they feel about each other.
Even visually going
from the red-red warms
into the super-super cools.
That we get as much contrast
as possible in the lighting.
When she breaks a window,
it blows out a light,
so it could be even darker
on one side of the room,
and lighter on the other side
of the room.
Again, there's that duality that's in play.
That just kind of supports the story
whenever we can.
Now, we haven't seen the triplets
and there was a scene where
we cut back to them eating the cake,
where Maudie finds them
eating the cake, half-transformed.
Because earlier on, when Mom's
going through the transformation,
we had one shot
where she pops up
from behind the bed half-transformed,
looking kind of like a were-bear
or a werewolf.
But ultimately we didn't need that,
and we cut it out as we were watching it
and reviewing the reels
and looking at the story as a whole,
which was a great exercise, to go,
"You know what?
We know that when last we left them
"they were looking at the cake,
the spell cake."
So to look and see them
coming out of the shadows
with these little glowing eyes and reveal
that they're bears, that was enough.
It was more of a surprise than
leading the audience down that path.
I think this scene was the first time
we used Maudie early on.
And as we developed the story
we kept finding ways to use her
and establish her
as the governess of the triplets
or give her reasons to exist
in the movie beforehand.
And I think that helps,
so once you get here
you know her as a character by the time
you see her go through this trial.
Yeah, she's always
fabulous to work with.
We kept just bringing her back.
And also kind of just
broadening this universe
that we're creating of these characters,
of the castle life and everything.
And then just the mixture here
of chase after chase, right?
Yeah, we liked the idea
of feathering the two,
the comedic chase
against the dramatic chase,
‘cause it was a fun way
to cover ground in two places
but you still have time to laugh
as well as be worried.
Yeah, so you're
on the edge of your seat
because two things
have to get resolved.
There's two goals that are happening
at the same time.
As Mom gets further and further away,
the chase with Maudie goes on inside.
Well, they're kind of
paying Maudie back
from all the previous times
that she's been chasing them.
Well, we know how
they get around the castle
by the little ins and outs
and their little secret passageways.
So that Maudie could ever think
that she could outrun them,
to the audience, was kind of ridiculous.
But they can just show up
out of nowhere,
and that just adds to the whole moment.
I love this little bit here,
one of the triplets just trips.
The animators asked me,
"Why? Why do you want to do that?"
I'm all, "Because it's funny.
One of 'em has got to eat it.”
It's just one of those little aspects.
It's just a little detail that... Yeah,
does it serve anything for the story?
No, but overall, it just gives
a little entertainment into the shot.
The whole concept of her sewing
while she's riding
-has been in since the beginning.
-Yeah.
Brenda was all over that.
She loved that idea.
And I love that little red lantern
on that blue background, it's beautiful.
-Yeah.
-All the red firelight in here.
It's gorgeous to look at.
Yeah, Danielle Feinberg
and Steve Pilcher
talked about the very
theatrical lighting of this movie.
And any sequence we can go
to really push it, l was all for.
And it turns out great.
It's just so striking.
And in the early version,
this whole scene took place in snow.
It was like the thickest part
of the snowfall that we had.
So he was plowing through snow drifts.
Ropes are not easy in animation
and to coordinate
how they're going around Mom
and who's holding them
with the Crowds Department,
with Paul Mendoza and Paul Kanyuk
and the crowds team was just fantastic
in this whole sequence.
It just made it.
It's like a cat's cradle game to look at
that diagram of how to arrange.
And which one is going to what horse
and how they pin it down.
And the wisps lead her to her fate,
lead her back to her mom,
so they can resolve this thing.
But also,
steer her away from Mor'du.
And there's great acting
from Billy Connolly in this
to get that rage out of him.
Because he's been
the jolly Scotsman the whole time,
to really get him to yell and roar,
and Billy was all game for it.
And to be fierce, he was terrific at that.
This took a really long time to block.
Yeah, well this was
one of the first things
-when I came on that we worked on.
-Right, right.
That we kind of reboarded and set,
and then it went away
and then it wasn't until almost
near the end of the process
where we came back into it
with Rob Anderson and his layout team
and got it all situated and set.
Well, we didn't have
all the characters either.
-Exactly.
-We were waiting for character design
and to be realized.
But we were already thinking about
what it needed to be.
We had the dogs in the beginning
of this sequence and they disappeared.
And I'm all, "Oh, my gosh."
It's already being animated and
we're already lighting it
and I'm all, "Where are my dogs?
Wouldn't they do anything?"
So we managed to sneak them
into a couple of shots
and see 'em get walloped by the bear.
So, that explains
why they're not around.
Because, back in the day,
the dogs would be all over that bear.
So many plates to spin that
you forget about certain elements.
-But they will come back to haunt you.
-Yeah.
Sometimes you don't want to
draw attention to something.
You don't want the audience
to worry about either.
Like the audience is hardly worrying
about where the dogs are at this point.
They're totally caught up
in Mor'du, so...
But if we could balance it just right
to cheat them that
we've explained why they're not there,
why there are no horses there,
that everybody's backed off
without showing it,
then it doesn't pull you out
without having any questions.
Gary Rydstrom and E.J. Holowicki
did an amazing job
with the bear vocals in this movie.
Oh, yeah, hearing the very
different aspects of them.
Yeah, there was a huge amount of
design work that went into their voices.
-And it's not all just bear sounds.
-Right.
And there was a version in this
where Mom was turning back and forth
between herself and a bear
during this fight.
Right. From bear mode to Mom-bear,
to bear mode to Mom-bear.
And it just, all these ideas
which were kind of great ideas on paper
that we would try,
and we'd try everything
to find that right concoction,
that right chemical explosion
of all the right things.
And we end up throwing out
a lot of stuff.
It becomes too complex.
And I wanted to catch the audience
by surprise with this,
where you know they were finished,
but then, it was Mom ultimately
and her kind of smarts.
She couldn't beat 'em physically,
but getting the help
from this huge stone column
to crush the bear actually did it.
That she recognizes that crack
and she could make it bigger.
It doesn't work
when she wants it to work,
but eventually there's a slow give away.
That's kind of almost my homage
to Force 10 From Navarone
when they blow up the dam
to save everybody,
but then the dam doesn't
break right away,
and then it breaks later
and washes away all the Nazis, yeah.
And we wanted to resolve Mor'du
instead of just kill him.
So we had this idea
of Mor'du gets killed,
and that releases his spirit to then,
how apropos, to become a wisp,
to then warn others or lead them away
from these negative fates.
Yeah, I really liked the idea
of resolving his story,
so he's not just this dead
carcass under the rock.
He's like the soul of that guy,
however nasty he was,
gets redeemed, somehow, just by being
released by another enchanted bear.
-Yeah.
-He started out being purely a bear.
There were different versions.
There was versions where
there was less magic around him.
And we weren't being as clear
in different versions.
We wanted there to be lore
around him like Moby Dick,
but that we didn't know
where he came from.
And then as the story developed,
it became more obvious
that he was somebody.
And I liked that more because
it feels more like a magical world
that we created.
It's a great storyline to help parallel
what Merida is about to go through
and what the possible outcome
for Mom is going to be.
This was probably, for me,
one of the hardest sequences to do,
was this end moment to kind of tie up
how the magic actually
works with the words and the tapestry,
making the second sunrise happen.
When does Mom turn into the bear
so that you know the game is over,
so that we can be sad and crying?
That no matter how hard Merida tried,
even though she's learned her lesson,
she wants her mom back,
she still kind of failed.
Which I think is a great thing
for kids and adults to understand
that there are consequences
to our actions.
And we can't just be selfish.
We have to think about
what's going to happen a little bit more.
But getting this to work just right
was really difficult.
Getting the second sunrise in there,
putting it back in the ring of stones
as the focal point.
We would go around and around
about how that actually worked.
But I think,
once we finally figured this out,
and that we actually
had the ticking clock,
the visual ticking clock of the sun rising
and the sunlight coming down
the stones and across the ground,
really gave it this extra little bit of kick
in the sequence
to realize when it was actually over.
And when she says, "I love you,"
just before the sun hits her,
and then once it hits the tapestry
that changes Mom back
instantaneously
and, again,
we don't see that magic happen.
We don't see that scene,
it just happens.
Yeah, we wanted to
mute the magic though.
We didn't want to see
a giant spectacle of special effects here.
We wanted to just feel like this moment
was very personal and very small.
Yeah, it's unexplained,
and it makes it more intimate,
instead of just something that happens
that's fireworks or blue swirly lights
or anything like that,
that everybody can witness and see.
It's just... Blink! She's back to normal.
The ending is all about the balance.
We have all these strings
that we have to tie up.
So it's really tricky.
The ending of a film is always really
one of the trickiest things
there is in filmmaking,
‘cause there's always
these emotional qualities to it
that you have to just arrange just right
to have the effect that you really want.
So there was a lot going on
here that we had to navigate,
and how much of what to make it work
and not just seem overbearing.
It seems like near the end of a movie
the audience's perceptions speed up.
And so, you're kind of
weighing this idea
of how long does it take you
to get to the climax?
‘Cause they're kind of maybe
ahead of you at this point.
And so you want to make sure
you're dishing it out at the right pace
for the audience to be receiving it.
And sometimes we find we lag too much
and we want to get to it a little sooner
than we thought we did.
This was, technically, one of
the hardest shots we had in the movie
because of the rate of the camera move
and the pan that was in it,
and you're shooting
24 frames a second,
you get a strobing, this stutter.
And, to work that out,
we had to slow down the move,
make it not as long,
pan slower or faster.
But I wanted to see all the stuff,
so we did some magic tricks
and worked it out.
But that's one of the things
that you run into in film.
And then I like getting into...
Merida kind of starts off the movie
with her narration,
and here she ends her narration
with that moral of the story.
And I think it works great with
Mumford & Sons' song in this moment,
that there's this little hole cut out
for Merida to say her piece,
and then you go back into the song,
which kind of sums it all up.
I'm really glad that
Mumford & Sons came on board
and agreed to do the final song,
our final song moment in the movie.
-And Birdy.
-And Birdy, she sings it great.
It just encapsulates the whole story
in this nice kind of 1-2-3 bit.
Even their emotional arc,
Merida's emotional arc of where she is,
just sums up everything perfectly.
For me, it's very satisfying.
And I don't know that I've seen it before,
but it goes to the original heart
of Brenda's story that
the resolution is a love story
between a mother and daughter.
And I don't know that
we've seen a lot of that in movies.
-Yeah.
-Especially family movies.
Well, you bookend that
Merida was having her favorite day
with Angus at the beginning of the film.
And now Mom has joined her
in her world,
I think wraps their characters up
quite nicely.
We had this one idea that I really loved
and I wish we could have kept.
You're back to the archery tournament.
And Merida fires an arrow
and makes a bull's-eye,
and then Mom picks up the bow
and splits her arrow.
And she says, "You didn't get
everything from your father."
-Yeah, we had that for a while.
-We had that for a while,
but ultimately it went back to
that it's this competing thing
and what are they
out there competing for?
Are they still competing for her hand?
And it was just kind of
the wrong resolution.
But that, again, it went back
into that comparison,
and the suitors were hanging around.
So it was just muddy.
It was a great moment,
but it was a can of worms
and it opened up all these questions.
So that doing it this way,
not having everything resolved,
it's resolved.
And Merida and Mom have changed.
Merida is wearing a nicer dress.
Mom's hair is down.
But that you have that resolution
of their characters,
and in the song,
the song's words are basically saying,
"We are what we are, and that's okay."
Getting to see them riding together,
even without that archery moment,
you sort of feel like...
I think we all believe that Mom
was quite a bit like Merida
when she was young.
So, you get to see a touch of that
when they're riding together.
And Mom's hair is flowing,
and, of course, she can ride on a horse
fast across the countryside,
‘cause she used to be Merida
when she was a kid.
Totally. And they're having fun together.
Which I think is at the heart
of all relationships
that, when they're working, is that
there's not a hierarchy
in the relationship.
You're just who you are and
you see each other on this equal level
and play is a big part of that.
I know as a parent, for me,
when I'm playing with my kids
there's no parent’kid thing,
we're just having fun.
With my friends,
when we go out and see movies,
that's just another form of play.
Well, the last part of the film
is we had this great idea
of ending a movie.
-Oh, it's coming up, not yet.
-It's coming up.
You got to wait 'til the very end.
Well, hold on, there's one other one
that you wanted to end on.
-It was the hawk...
-Oh, yeah.
-... that came in.
-We had this thing...
Yeah, we had that. It was...
When they ride out
and the wisp disappears,
we kind of panned up and you see
the ships going off into the sunset.
l had that hawk or an eagle come down,
which represented Merida,
just dive right at the screen and tear it.
And then I would go into the most
awesome heavy metal soundtrack
at the end of the movie,
which was fantastic.
With some bagpipes?
Yeah, it was great.
-Which was fantastic.
-We did that for a couple screenings,
-or one screening we did it for.
-Yeah. And it was great,
but they said, "No."
So to keep the integrity of the piece,
we didn't go that way.
l thought you were kidding around
and I didn't realize you really meant
that to be in until a few weeks later.
It's drawn and it's been archived.
Yeah. But what we did settle on
for the very, very end of the movie
is just to have this little button
at the very end, where...
What happened to all that junk that
Merida bought in the Witch's cottage?
.. bought in the Witch's cottage,
and we came up with this great idea.
And you guys are going to see it
and we thought that's
just kind of a nice little button
at the end of the movie.
Well, that's it, gang.
Thanks for watching Brave.
l hope you enjoyed it.
I'm the director, Mark Andrews.
Co-director, Steve Purcell.
Editor, Nick Smith.
Story supervisor, Brian Larsen.
And I couldn't have made it
without you guys.
It was fantastic working with you
and the rest of the crew.
-l love you guys.
-Thank you.
Thank you and good night.