TOKUMA SHOTEN presents
© 1986 Nibariki - Tokuma Shoten
Pirates!
It's a raid!
Hold them off!
Get down on the floor.
It's tear gas!
What are you waiting for!
Break it down!
Where'd she go?
She's hera!
She's hiding out here.
Well, get her!
Mama, I'm falling!
There's the stone.
Quick, go next door!
The crystal.
There goes the crystal.
LAPUTA: Castle in the Sky
Executive Producer
Yasuyoshi TOKUMA
Music by
Joe HISAISHI
Production
Studio Ghibli
Producer
Isao TAKAHATA
Original story written and directed by
Hayao MIYAZAKI
Two meatballs, please.
Working late?
We're finally busy again.
Still working?
What's that?
A person!
Pazu!
What are you up to?
Where's my dinner?
Boss!
A girl fell from the sky.
Boss, she fell from the sky.
Darn old clunker.
Boss! A girl...
Close the second valve!
Ouch!
Pazu, toss me a wrench.
l can't let go. You do it.
Don't make them wait.
Keep a steady hand.
Brake!
Any luck?
No silver, no tin even.
All that wasted work.
Should try the east vein.
That's riddled with old holes.
Have to start over.
Time to go home...
Shut down the boiler.
Call it a day.
I'll go under at this rate.
Oil the clunker, Pazu.
Mama, I can't see a thing.
It's too dark.
l hope you really looked!
All right. We'll wait for daylight.
Hi. How are you feeling?
Hold on there...
I'm Pazu. I live by myself.
They eat after I play.
So you are human after all.
l was afraid you were an angel.
Thanks for helping me.
I'm Sheeta.
Sheeta. nice name. You fell
from the sky. A bit scary.
That's right. Why am I still alive?
I fell from the airship...
Don't you remember?
Say, can see that?
This?
It's been in my family forever.
It's beautiful...
Wait...
Watch this!
So it wasn't the stone after all.
Oh, no! Pazu!
Are you OK?
Yeah. Are you?
I'm fine. Sorry, did it hurt?
No, my head's harder
than my boss's fists.
The pot's still boiling.
Hungry? Let's eat.
Wash up over there.
There's a towel.
Thank you.
Laputa...
Sheeta!
Where are you?
My father took that picture.
Laputa, an island in the sky.
An island in the sky...?
They say it's only a myth...
But my father saw it...
That's when he took it.
There's a Laputa in Gulliver's
Travels. but Swift made it up.
Dad drew this.
He said the abandoned palace
was full of treasure.
But nobody believed him.
Until he died, they called him a liar.
But my father never lied.
I'm building a real plane.
I'm going to find Laputa...
A real automobile...
They're pirates!
They attacked the airship.
Are they after you?
Quick !
Morning!
Hey, wait!
We're in a rush.
Have you seen a girl?
Sure. yesterday...
The boss's kid, Madge...
Go away!
They're looking for you.
Louis, a girl's dress!
What! She was disguised!
Tell mama!
No, I haven't.
A cute little girl
...brown hair, braids...
Boss!
About that age.
That's her!
They're pirates, chasing her!
Pirates! Lemme see!
Not one step closer.
Hand her over.
Dola's clan.
Go home. Just poor folk here.
Ma'am?
Scoot out the back.
] want to fight.
They've got weapons!
What a nice girl. Protect her.
You refuse to step aside?
Use your fists.
Could be interesting.
Get him, brother.
Show your stuff.
Wow...
Who's going to mend that shirt?
You can beat him!
Go! Go!
Think you can fool me?
After them!
Climb on!
There you go.
Playing hooky for a date?
Bad guys after us...
The Dola clan.
Pirates?
Take us to the next town.
The police!
You're on. Stoke the fire.
Mama!
You idiots! Hurry up and get on!
What? But the girl's...
She slipped out the back door.
Get moving!
Brother!
Wait!
They're catching up, more steam!
Can't you go any faster?
She's an old-timer.
Move over!
Mama, I'm falling!
More steam!
Here we go!
Sheeta, over here.
Stoke the fire.
Don't give up!
Push! Push, ! tell you!
Not so fast!
Don't let them escape!
Dump this over the side!
Go, go, go!
I'll do it.
No, let me.
Wait!
It's them... what'll we do?
l refuse to give up. Move!
This is a surprise. If it isn't the army.
These kids need help!
They've got pirates after them.
Sheeta?
Good bye.
Wait!
Sheeta!
Halt or I'll shoot.
An armored train.
Who cares! Smash it!
What is it, Sheeta!
Stay away!
They're gonna fall!
Quiet. Watch closely.
We're floating!
Look! It's that crystal!
It was the stone after all!
Amazing!
We'll float all the way down.
Amazing! 1 want it!
Shoot!
lI have to get that amazing stone!
It's fading...
Hey, wait!
Just like when you landed.
The opening looks so tiny.
I hope the Boss and the engineer
aren't in any trouble.
Aw, don’t worry.
Miners aren't exactly wimps.
Let's find the way out.
These mines are ancient.
Tunnels everywhere.
I'm so happy. I was starving.
I've still got an apple and some candy.
It's like you have a magical bag
that holds everything.
Gondoa? That's so far north.
Yes. Both my parents died,
but they left me
the house and the fields.
sol was getting by alone...
The guys with dark glasses
kidnapped you.
That guy was one of them?
Who can they be,
calling in the army?
The Dolas and the other guys.
all want the stone,
But I had no idea it
had mysterious powers.
It was always in our family.
Mother left it to me when she died.
She warned me never to show it
or give it to anyone.
We're both orphans, aren't we?
I'm sorry I dragged
you into all of this.
When you fell from the sky
my heart was racing.
I knew something
wonderful had begun.
Little demons... little demons.
Uncle Pom! He's really great.
Uncle Pom.
We've lost our way.
Now that little demon
sure looks like Pazu...
with a little girl demon beside him.
Pirates are after us.
And the army,
How very extraordinary...
Drink up.
Thank you.
Have you always lived underground?
Why no, no. The rocks have
been astir...
That's when I like to be down here.
The rocks astir...?
Rocks speak very softly...
Wonderful...
Look up.
They were ordinary rocks until...
How pretty...
Here, let me show you...
It's gone.
These rocks contain Volucite.
Volucite?
As soon as it's exposed to the air,
it becomes ordinary stone.
It's glowing...
Oh. my gracious!
That's a Volucite crystal, my dear.
I've never seen one before.
That's why the rocks were stirring.
This stone has mysterious powers.
] thought only Laputans knew
how to make Volucite crystals.
Laputans...
They used Volucite to send
a magnificent island aloft...
Laputa did exist, Sheeta!
It really did!
Does the island still exist?
Uncle Pom?
Dear. would you mind covering the
stone? Its power overwhelms me.
What's wrong...
My grandfather told me...
the rocks shift when
Laputa floats overhead.
If you went up to the sky then,
you'd find Laputa!
My father was telling the truth!
Young lady...
Your stone is most powerful...
know it as one who has
spoken to rocks all my life.
A stone so powerful brings happiness,
but it can also bring misery.
What's more,
your stone is the work of men.
I just thought I should...
It's not true!
That stone's already
saved Sheeta twice!
Amazing! Laputa really does exist!
It's gone.
Let's go back to the ship.
When it’s this quiet,
it's best to stay put.
I'm hungry...
It's all clear, Let's go.
Thank you, grandpa.
Look after yourselves.
Look at those clouds!
Beyond those clouds is an island
we've only dreamed of.
Here I come! I know
I'm going to find Laputa!
Pazu...
I haven't told you everything.
My family had a mysterious
ancient name which came
with this stone.
My name is Lucita.
Lucita Toelle Ur....
Laputa...
So you mean...
It's the army! Run!
Underground!
Don't move!
How dare you!
Pazu!
Let me go!
Pazu! Pazu!
We've apprehended them.
So much trouble.
Open up, open up!
Sheeta...
Company, fall in!
Shape up!
Squeeze the brat!
... she'll talk!
Spoken like a man in uniform.
In your haste,
you risk everything.
If we'd mobilized the army sooner,
Dola wouldn't have had a chance.
She managed to decipher
your third-rate code.
How dare you!
My organization will handle this.
You concentrate on mobilizing
the troops when the time is ripe.
Muska! Remember, I command
the search for Laputa!
Of course. But ! have my
orders from the government.
That pencil-pushing upstart!
Have a nice rest?
Where's Pazu? Let me see him!
No interest in pretty clothes?
Don't fret about Pazu. His
stubborn head is harder than mine.
Come, I have something
to show you.
Enter.
What is it...
A mechanical soldier with vast
destructive power.
Had he not fallen from the sky.
no one would have believed in Laputa.
He's not of this earth.
Our science can't even identify
what material he's made of.
Look...
Don't be afraid.
He's long dead.
Look at that.
This insignia was carved on
your fireplace.
It's on this stone, too.
The stone works
only in your hands.
It will protect you and
guide you back to Laputa.
I know nothing of this!
Take it if you like.
Just leave us alone...
You imagine Laputa’s
like Treasure Island...
Fearsome powers
thrust Laputa into orbit.
Their dreaded empire
once ruled the earth!
Even you can appreciate
that when such an entity
roams the skies.
it threatens Peace.
l need your cooperation.
You must know how to make
the stone guide us to Laputa.
l really don't know!
Please let me see Pazu!
l intend no harm,
but his fate rests with you.
The boy goes free
if you assist us, Lucita...
... Toella Ur Laputa.
But how...
Ur means ruler in Laputan,
Toelle means True,
Queen Lucita. rightful heir
to the Laputan throne.
Out!
Sheeta.
Pazu, are you hurt?
I'm fine. You? Did they
do anything horrible?
My dear Pazu. we misjudged you.
Accept our apologies.
We didn't know how gallantly
you protected her from the pirates.
Sheeta, what did you...
Pazu, I beg you,
forget about Laputa.
What!
Sheeta will aid us in our
search for Laputa.
l understand how you feel,
but forget about her.
Is this true, Sheeta? But we...
I'm sorry for all the trouble...
I'll never forget you.
l can't believe it...
Sheeta, we swore!
Good bye.
Sheeta!
Wait. Sheeta!
Be reasonable. Act like a man.
Sheeta!
Here's a token of our gratitude.
It's yours.
Only you can recall the words
that will waken this stone...
If you keep your promise.
you, too, shall be free...
Pazu...
Mama. it's Pazu! He's back!
Pazu.
We were so worried.
You just disappeared.
And the girl?
Forget it.
Pazu!
Let me go!
What are you doing!
Put a lid on it!
Nice place you got, kid.
Get out!
This is my house!
Oh, come off it.
Can't even protect a little girl...
He's got gold!
Sold her for money, huh.
No! I wouldn't do that!
You let them pay you off...
Sheeta told me to...
So...
So you gave in and crawled home.
You call yourself a man!
You talk big.
but you're after Sheeta too.
But of course. we're pirates.
Pirates hunt for treasure.
They're the strange ones.
What's the girl to them?
You think she'll get out alive?
Sheeta told you to leave?
They threatened her.
so she tried to save you.
How do you know, mama?
50 years of being a woman.
She steels her heart
to save her man. How touching...
Reminds me of my youth...
You boys want to marry,
look for one like her.
So... that girl...
will grow up to be mama?
Don't even bother switching codes...
Calling the battle cruiser...?
They'll pack her up and take off.
Time is short.
Dinner's over. Move out.
Yes, mama.
Going after Sheeta?
l want the crystal, not the girl.
The stone's no good
without her.
Can't I go with you, Ma'am?
l have to help Sheeta!
Not so fast. Do it on
your own nickel.
You're right. if ! was clever
and strong, ! could’ ve defended her.
Please, ] don't care about treasure.
Listen to him...
Shut up!
But you could probably
help us with her.
Leave all this behind?
I know,
You sure?
Yup!
You've got 40 seconds.
Be well.
Tie this to your belt.
You boys wait on the ship.
A magnificent vessel.
Has the girl come through?
I need a littla more time.
Forget it! We'll squeeze
it out of her up there.
We depart at dawn, with the girl.
Hurry up, it's almost dawn!
Sheeta!
Whatever shall we do...
Sheeta. listen. I'm going
to teach you
a magic spell for trouble.
A magic spell?
Yes. These are old, old. old.
secret words.
They mean
help me rekindle the light.
Perfect.
Just as the ancient books described.
This is the sacred light.
Sacred light...?
What are the magic words?
Tell me.
It's moving!
The robot. it's alive!
Hello!
Help!
It's alive!
It's the robot!
The robot?
It's coming this way.
Run!
Retreat! Retreat!
Incredible!
I see!
It's the light!
The sacred light broke his seal!
This is the way to Laputa! Come!
No!
He's going to fly!
It's pointing to the sky...
It's showing the way to Laputa.
Hurry!
Use explosives!
But don't blow up the ship!
Hello, hello, hello! What is this!
Good.
We're connected.
This is Colonel Muska.
The robot's cut our lines.
I've assumed emergency command.
It's after the girl on the tower.
Take it down on sight.
Prepare to fire.
Hurry!
Hurry up!
Fire!
Hurry!
We did it.
Get the girl.
Is she dead?
Get up!
She just fainted.
Stand!
It moved...
What's that! Must be a battle.
Let's go, Ma'am!
Captain, to you!
Lower, Charles.
Stop! Stop it!
Please!
Mama, Goliath's moving.
We're going directly into
the crossfire. Regroup!
Look, there's Sheeta!
Where?
Straight ahead. she's
on top of that tower!
This is a job for a woman!
Cover me.
Sheeta!
I'm coming, Sheeta!
Pazu!
Fly closer, lady!
Let me go!
Sheeta!
Ma'am!
Pazu.
Pazu!
Climb !
Last chance! Grab her on the fly!
Pazu!
Here goes!
Move!
Darn!
Sheeta!
What's Goliath up to!
A smoke screen...
Where's the robot!
Destroyed. The girl went that way.
What!
Put out the fire!
Organize a search party!
We haven't lost the sacred stone.
Its light points to Laputa..,.
Inform the General, we'll depart
for Laputa as planned.
How nice...
can't believe she'll
grow up to be just like mama...
There's your valley...
Back where we started.
Lady, please take us aboard.
Call me Captain! What use
are you without the crystal?
We'll work.
I want to see Laputa
for myself.
Don't want any treasure, just
to see Laputa? Suspect motives
for boarding a pirate ship.
Are they coming with us, mama?
One false move and
you're shark bait!
Excellent! No more laundry
or cleaning duty!
Or dish washing!
Or potato peeling!
Can you make pudding?
Yas...
l like mincemeat pie.
leat, um, um... anything!
Enough out of you!
When will you boys ever grow up!
Get off!
Canvas. It's made of cloth.
And don't tear it.
Hurry up, it's crowded in here!
Hurry, this way!
l hate dawdlers.
You're with me!
Pazu!
I don't bite. Come.
You're not here for fun.
What an engine.
Now where'd he go?
Pops! Pops!
Got you an assistant.
Don't holler. 1 hear you.
He's tougher than mama. Be careful.
My hand doesn't fit.
This gasket?
Name?
Pazu.
The crystal pointed
nearly due east...
You sure about that?
l could see the sunrise from the tower.
It's the harvest season now,
so the sun rises just south
of due east.
The light pointed to the left
of the sun rose.
Good answer.
Any luck?
Not a peep.
Blocking their radio transmissions...
Mama, Goliath's faster than us.
We're upwind of them. If we get
a lift on the trade winds...
This is an Asian calculator.
Windspeed is 10... and...
I think it'll work.
OK. listen up!
Goliath's on its way to Laputa.
We're on their tail.
With these winds,
I expect contact tomorrow.
Ten gold pieces
to whoever spots her first!
Ten!
Whatever we find. I'm sure Laputa has
riches enough for any pirate gang!
Earn your keep, boys!
Course 98. speed 40.
You're useless in that get-up.
Wear these.
Your station.
Sweet...
You serve five meals a day.
Go easy on the water.
Get to work, you idiots!
Yes.
I'm sorry, dinner isn't ready yet.
I've never cooked on an airship...
What is it...
Sweet...
I thought I'd give you
a hand in my spare time.
Why thank you. Can you
put those dishes away?
Happy to obli...
You said your stomach hurt...
I've got some free time. Canl...
Move.
Some stomach ache, jerk!
Hey, can I help...
You've changed. chasing the likes
of Goliath... But it's pointless.
It's Laputan treasure l'm after.
They're certainly nice kids...
Get to the point, you crank.
They're too upright and honest
to aver respect you.
What's that!
No, ] mean... Check...
Good... good...
Seconds anyone?
Seconds! Seconds!
Seconds!
Hey. shake a leg.
It's your watch,
Take it, it's cold.
Watch?
Darn cold!
Go on up.
My turn.
Great.
Sheeta!
That was scary!
Beautiful.
Sheeta.
Get in.
Can't sleep?
Nice and warm...
Look out behind.
Pazu.
I'm really, really, scared.
l really don’t want to go to Laputa.
l hope we never find Goliath.
The light really did
point that way.
About the robot?
Poor thing.
I never dreamed that
little spell could...
I learned lots of other spells.
To help find things. cure the sick.
And one must never, ever use.
Never, ever use...?
A spell of destruction.
I had to learn bad ones so the
good spells had power, But not to use...
l was so scared, I couldn't sleep...
That stone should be locked away.
They hid it in the fireplace.
Only wore it for weddings.
My mother's and grandmother's and
great. great grandmother's.
l should have thrown it away.
You're wrong. We only met
because of the stone.
Throwing it away won't
change anything.
Airships are improving.
Someone will find it.
(don't know what to do, but if
Laputa is so dangerous,
it's sure not
for the likes of Muska.
Besides,
if we run now,
they'll hunt us forever.
But don't become a pirate for me...
[ won't become a pirate.
Dola understands.
She's nicer than she looks.
Once things are settled,
I'll take you to Gondoa.
l want to see where you were
born, the valley, the yaks...
Pazu...
What's that!
Below us, look!
Goliath, right below us!
Come about!
Do we have to hurry?
l hate to lose them.
We can't catch them in this fog.
We'll get them. Thay won't go far.
Steady as she goes.
Farther north than I thought.
There's no time, so listen.
lf we lose Goliath,
it's all over.
Follow them in the crow's nest.
What do I do?
It turns into a glider.
See the crank?
Yeah.
Turn it clockwise.
Once it's locked. the upper
laver spreads the wings.
Use the wire to stabilize them.
Figure out how to steer as you go!
Sheeta, you there!
Get back down here.
Why?
Because you're a girl!
But so are you! Besides, I'm
a mountain girl with sharp eyesight.
Sheeta!
Please, Pazu agrees.
Once you're aloft. the voice tube
won't work. See the head set?
You mean this...
Wow...
OK. I'll give it a try. Release us.
Here goes.
They're gone.
Slipped behind clouds.
Stay alert. They could be anywhere.
Hold on tight.
What's wrong!
We're fine.
Ran into a gust of wind.
We'll keep watch.
Scared?
No.
I'm getting the hang of it.
Rough skies ahead.
Get the rope from my bag, Sheeta.
Tie yourself to me.
The mercury's sinking. mama...
Lousy luck. Storm coming up...
How long 'til dawn?
One more hour.
It's dawn.
Strange that the sun's
rising on that side...
I know! We're supposed to
be heading east. Bridge!
What! We're heading north?
The compass is pointing east.
The shifting winds must have
put us off course.
Look!
What is it? Goliath?
It's a cloud. A huge one...
A cloud?
It's headed for us!
A castle in the sky...
We're headed into
a low pressure system.
Turn her away, full speed!
It's sucking us in.
Hold tight, we can’t help!
l can't steer!
Where's your brute strength.
Engine’s burning up.
Stop whining! Do something!
We're clearing the clouds!
Sheeta, the ocean!
The Dragon's Lair!
So this is the Dragon's Lair...
Dad said, that wind
blew in opposite directions.
Look out, a wall of wind!
Help! It's sucking us in!
Don't give up! Be a man!
Bridge! Laputa's inside!
What was that!
Dad saw Laputa inside
the Dragon's Lair.
Ridiculous! It'll blow
you to smithereens!
Pazu!
Look.
Just what we need.
Let's go! It's the path dad took.
He made it back.
Into the Dragon's Lair we go!
Got ‘em!
Our ship's in danger. Retreat.
Stay the course.
The light's pointing
right for the clouds.
Laputa's in there.
Stay the course.
We'll find a way in.
Here we go, Sheeta!
Sheeta. Sheeta!
Are you all right?
Look...
Laputa...?
Oops.
Wait... I tied it really tight.
My hands are shaking...
We did it!
Birds...
Where is everyone...
Coming to greet you?
But I don't have the stone.
I'll use a knife.
What are you doing!
Wait.
Please don't break that.
We need it to get home.
A flycatcher's nest!
He's protecting the nest.
I'm glad no eggs were broken.
The birds aren't afraid.
- Follow.
- You understand?
! feel it.
It's a city...
But we're inside...
You can see the sky...
A city so advanced...
Why did it...
A grave...
l wish 1 could read the writing.
Flowers...
Do you tend them?
Another robot!
It broke a long time ago...
Must've been the gardener...
...who protected this place ever
since the people went away.
You picked flowers for the grave.
Thank you.
Are you all alone? Are there
any other robots here?
He doesn't seem to be lonely.
He's got friends and
birds' nests to look after...
This way!
This section's been destroyed.
They got Tiger Moth.
l hope the pirates are OK.
Look!
They're prisoners!
They hang pirates.
We must help them.
Let's go!
We found a way in.
Mountains of treasure.
Wow...
Want some?
I'll give you plenty... of rope.
Have you reported we found Laputa?
Just about to.
Make the code good and complicated.
Hey! No looting!
The perfect distraction for those idiots.
What amazing roots.
Can you climb trees?
It looks safe.
How horrible...
If they reach the garden...
The only way to save this...
is to get the stone back.
l see why the clouds parted.
Otherwise they never
could have landed.
Was it my spell...
Muska was right.
The seal's broken, and
the kingdom's waking up.
It's welcomed the visitor
with the stone.
But Muska will become the king.
He's got much worse in mind.
But what do I do with the stone
when I get it back...
That spell...
Spell... you don't mean...
l see a way.
I'll go first.
It's here somewhere.
Please God...
This is it!
It's that kid.
Oh, no!
Don't shoot, capture her.
Well if it isn't the little princess.
Sheeta! Shoot!
What is it, Colonel?
The last of the pirates.
There's one right under you.
Yes sir! Search!
Wait for me, Sheeta!
Pazu!
Grenades!
Must be Pazu.
What was that?
No, it wasn’t.
The General is over there.
Militia, assemble!
On the double!
Ma'am!
They've got Sheeta. I'm going after her.
I'll cut your ropes, Escape.
Get out of here.
Hey, wait!
Take this.
Thanks.
The boy has become a man.
What's that!
Muska destroyed
the radio equipment.
Yes. while the ship
was short-handed.
Some of the guards
are badly wounded.
The Colonel is in a
black sphere down there.
There's a witness.
That upstart's finally
showing his colors.
Hunt down the spy!
Company assemble!
Hey! Hurry!
Shoot if he resists!
Find the entrance.
Where are we, Colonel...
Laputa's core. The castle
above is just a trinket.
All of Laputa's knowledge
is crystallized here.
You two wait here.
Colonel!
Only royalty may enter
the sacred area.
What is this!
The roots come this far...
Eventually, we'll burn it all.
Come, this way.
Ow!
I found it!
This is it!
Here, too!
Found it!
Behold the giant crystal!
Source of Laputa’s power.
Fantastic. It has awaited
a king for 700 years.
700 years...
Your family even forgot that?
The black rock!
As the epics described!
l can read, I can read it!
Just who are you?
I, too. have an ancient.
secret name. Lucita.
My name is Romuska Palo Ur Laputa.
We are descended
from the same royal family...
...that split in two down on earth.
Not even a crack.
What's the catch?
Deploy all our explosives.
Force won't be necessary.
Your Excellancy.
Muska, where are you!
Why hesitate. General?
Please enter.
Darn it! Follow.
Follow His Excellancy.
Follow.
What is this! Muska, where are you!
Silence.
What on earth!
Watch your tongue. You're in
the presence of Laputa’s king.
Are you insane...
Let's celebrate Laputa’s resurrection
with a display of its power.
Sheeta!
Behold, Laputa’s thunder.
Sheeta.
It's the heavenly fire that
destroyed Sodom and Gomorrah.
It's the Ramayana’s Arrow of Indra.
The world shall bow down
before Laputa once more!
Wonderful. Muska. You're a hero.
A monumental achievement.
I've had it up to here
with your stupid face.
Run, everyone!
Die!
It's those monsters!
Run!
Check our Flaptors.
They're ready to fly!
Let's hurry!
Quiet. Keep your voice down.
What are you two doing!
I'll have to leave you behind.
l advise you not to anger me.
We'll be alone together here.
They should've escaped.
You think you can fight me?
Robots!
Sheeta!
Fantastic!
A marvelous display, no?
Aha, some human garbage.
How dare you!
Be a good girl, give it back.
Please, open!
Just where will you go?
Open it!
Sheeta!
Pazu!
I'm coming.
Get back!
Take this. hurry!
Muska's coming, quick!
Throw it into the sea.
Hold onto that stone.
I'll trade her life for it.
Stand up! No time left for hide and seek.
How delightful that it should end
in the throne room, Come here!
The throne room?
This will be our grave. Ours...
What is a king when his
country lies ruined.
l won't give you the stone.
You'll die, trapped here with me.
There's no escape.
This is why Laputa died out.
There's a song in my valley...
Put down your roots in the soil
Let us live together with the wind
Pass the winter with the seeds,
sing in the spring with the birds...
No matter how powerful your weapons,
or numerous your poor robots,
you can't survive apart from the earth.
Laputa will not die. It will revive.
Its power is the stuff of
humanity's dreams.
Next, ! shoot off your ears!
Beg for your life. Make the kid
hand over the stone.
Wait!
The stone's hidden. You can shoot.
but you won't get it.
Stay away, Pazu.
He'll kill us both.
I'll spare her life if you tell me
where the stone is.
Or do you intend to conquer me
with that cannon of yours?
Let me talk to Sheeta alone.
Don't come.
Throw it away and run!
3 minutes.
Sheeta. calm down and listen.
Repeat the words of that spell.
I'll say them with you.
Put your hand in mine.
[ cut the pirates’ ropes.
Time's up. What do you say?
My eyes, my eyes...
Mama, it's collapsing!
We've no choice, escape!
Hurry!
Look, the bottom's falling out!
Sheeta was such a nice girl...
They used the spell of destruction.
Those kids saved Laputa
from those idiots.
It's stopping!
A crystal! A humongous one!
It’s rising.
The tree... it's carrying
it away, Chase it!
You're heavy. get off.
You're crazy!
The roots protected us.
We can still use this.
Here goes.
What are you doing.
we're not moving.
Of course not, we're overloaded.
It's Sheeta!
She's alive!
Ma'am!
Thank God you're alive!
You guys OK?
Oh, no! My galleon's wrecked...
Oh. stop blubbering.
We'll make a better ship!
You poor child. the worst is
having your hair hacked off...
That hurts, Ma’ am.
Pathetic. All that work.
and only this to show.
Ran out of time...
Voices
PAZU Mayumi TANAKA
SHEETA Keiko YOKOZAWA
DOLA Kotoe HATSUI
MUSKA Minori TERADA
UNCLE POM = Fujio TOKITA
English translation by
Linda HOAGLUND
English subtitles by
AURA and Sony PCL
Production
Studio Ghibli
Producer
Isao TAKAHATA
Original story written and directed by
Hayao MIYAZAKI