Chief!
Where is everyone?
Jiu
Anybody alive here?
lam Niu Er!
Everybody...
It can't be...
All dead..
“Judging from this cow's size,the bulls must be really big!"
Shame on you!
Let me see!
What some grass?
What grass?
Foreign cattle eat grain.
Chief
"Uncle,"
the 8th Route Army offers him the first taste.
Already two buckets...
The milk flows like a river.
Chief!
Do cows have parents?
Idiot!
It's the law of nature!
Think you were born out of a stone?
Impossible!
Animals make milk only if they can reproduce.
“Niu Er, why are you here?"
Aren't you embarrassed? Look!
"See how big the foreign cow is? Next to it,"
yours is nothing.
Go to hell!
My cow is good!
That thing... It's a monster.
She's still going! What a cow!
So much milk.
This cow is worth more than us!
Absolutely.
It only gives milk for a few months each year.
We milk it with restraint.
“Comrade, could 1 have some milk?"
My baby is hungry.
Sure! Children shouldn't go hungry.
What are you doing?
Hard work never did anyone any harm
People from other villages
are overrunning us!
"As a newcomer, you don't understand!"
Milk is needed for the wounded of the 8th Army.
So newcomers should starve
It hasn't been easy for m to marry into your village.
Widows should keep quiet!
"Chief, 1 want justice!"
Must newcomers starve in your village?
The old saying goes...
“Women who bring bad luck to their husbands"
Severe punishment
Nonsense!
Your wife
is not from this village!
Let her bring you bad luck!
He wants me to die!
"See, Niu.."
That girl Jiu needs discipline.
Then she'll be as tame as a cow.
Have you ever touched udders?
Not such big ones.
Big talker! Not even small ones.
“If you dare touch those udders,
then you can look at my gun sight."
I rarely show it to anyone.
Silence!
Japanese troops are coming!
Run!
Hide the grain and run!
Those demons are coming!
Hurry!
Listen! An approaching plane!
It trips me every time!
What are you doing?
You want to die?
You could detonate that bomb!
It's been here for two years.
Can a kick make it explode?
Can't you read the sign
“Men and Animals, Keep Away."
Can't you read?
“l was told this was ""eight""."
"You're 8th Army, didn't you know?"
You're funny!
I'll show you...
“Two separate strokes make "eight""."
“Two connected strokes make "man"™."
“Add one stroke to make ""big""."
“Add two to make "'sky""."
"What happens to "eight" now?"
I don't know.
“Anyway, separate strokes make "man",
connected strokes make ""eight""."
That's wrong.
“Separate stokes make “"eight"",
connected strokes make "man"™"."
“See, you don't know either."
Wow!
Your breakfast is much richer than mine.
Here you go.
What a big cow!
Hide in the cellars what we can't take.
The cow is a real problem.
Let's leave it in the village.
The army will give you funds to feed it special grain.
“Comrade, give me a hand."
“In a couple of weeks, our army will strike back."
I'll return for the cow.
We must make a contract.
"You know, the cow is a donation from foreign friends."
The milk is for our wounded.
Hiding the wounded is easy.
But the cow is too big.
It's different from our local cows.
"The village is a "stronghold". You'll manage.”
We'll do our best
The cow will be returned to you unharmed.
Not to me .
To the Army.
How could this happen?
“Everyone dead, except the cow. "
Move!
What are you doing?
Damn you
Who do you think you are?
You should have been roasted long ago!
What?
Let me see.
Are you mute?
Line up!
Time for bean lottery!
We follow the rules of our ancestors.
He who picks the red bean tends to the cow.
Patience to those who pick green beans.
Heaven will determine who will bear this duty.
Understand?
So?
Exactly 128 beans.
Fine.
Here's the red bean.
Pour them in.
One bean per man!
No women!
Why not?
Aren't we liberated now?
Women are free!
Keep quiet!
This is a dangerous task!
How can you hide such a big cow?
So conspicuously foreign!
The Japanese are not stupid.
Loan me your cow for grinding.
No!
Everything clear?
I have an idea.
I have lots of dyes.
I can turn this cow yellow
to resemble a Chinese cow.
The Japanese would not notice.
No!
Why not?
I'll do it myself.
I would give my life for the cow!
I have an idea.
I have been a doctor for many ears.
I have a potion to make it mute
without harming it.
Niu Er!
Why are you with the women? Come here!
He is busy!
l already have a cow. Leave me out.
You're not a woman!
Come here!
I'l do it!
What are you doing?
Here lam.
Not you.
You'll take all the milk for yourself!
I'll take Niu's place
“Niu Er, tell them"
Don't look.
Eat this.
It tastes bad because it's good for you.
Then do what you want.
Stay mute.
You're very contrary.
Just like Jiu.
Jiu?
"Call me "dear."
Eat up and moo for me.
Go on.
Niu dear!
Here you are.
You pest!
You want to kill me?
“Jiu, what bean did you get?"
No bean at all!
Who got the red bean?
Show your hands
Let's see!
Who is hiding it?
Niu Er has it!
Let me see.
It's in hs mouth!
That's a lie!
Spit it out!
He swallowed it!
Don't listen to their nonsense!
What?
Jiu...
l wanted children and a happy life with you.
All clear.
One of our units passed here already.
Exactly.
This is a stronghold.
Anti-Japanese.
Our troops already cleared the area.
A big favor... We should thank them.
"Check the village, eliminate any danger."
We'll head out tomorrow morning.
"Yes, sir."
Forward march!
I heard you... It worked.
The antidote was good.
Let's go.
We can't stay here.
A wolf is a bad sign. What will happen now?
What's your problem?
Don't start...
I'll show you.
So many wounded...
What now?
Sir!
All clear ahead.
Good. Get some rest.
So?
No sign of the enemy in the village.
Good. Get some rest
“Excuse me, Captain."
I want to fight with the others.
Stay and take care of the wounded.
But I can fight!
That's an order. Understand?
"Yes, sir."
Commander...
We must advance...
The torches!
Otsuka
Go and see!
“It's your fault.
By leaving, we could have avoided this."
I'll roast you yet!
"OK,1 won't."
The torches!
Otsuka!
Go and see!
Where is the noise from?
Over there.
Damn cow!
Trying to get me killed?
Then stay there.
I won't come back.
l almost forgot...
"l lost my old cow and my home,
deserve this money."
Over and done
Heaven's will.
Where could this foreign cow have come from?
Really strange.
They aren't native to China.
It's not a Chinese cow.
Anybody know how to milk a cow?
Excuse me...
We raised cattle back home.
Really?
Can you milk a cow?
Let's sing for the cow!
"We will win"
Without far of death!
“A pretty girl in the orchard"
Picking pretty peaches
"Sees tomcat doing tabby"
Meow meow here
Meow meow there
“Squad Three, assemble!"
Conserve the rations.
We return in two days.
Wait here for us.
Your mission is to protect the wounded and the cow.
Don't worry
The Chinese are sneaky.
Don't retaliate in case of attack.
Understand?
Drink.
Be strong.
They return in two days.
The pain!
Ikeda!
Hold on!
Let's go home alive!
“Kuroki, your post is crucial!"
Defend it with your life!
“Shibuya, did you feed the cow"
Do it!
Shibya! Enough!
Watch the gate!
So cunning!
Damned Chinese!
“Shibuya, the gate!"
The cow is gone!
Dumb-ass!
What are you doing?
"Sorry, sir!"
What destroys a country?
I don't know.
Frivolity and irresponsibility
I stumbled on it by accident
The war isn't in that jar!
Be serious.
Could you see?
Yes.
All wounded. Three still standing.
Let's go.
Where are you going
To report To Captain.
Why?
They have a machine gun.
“If we get it, we'll be heroes. "
Damned Chinese!
Come out!
What are you waiting for?
Save your ammunition
“Shibuya, watch the door!"
It's only an ambush!
No use mooing. I won't go back.
“You want me dead, killer cow!"
Everyone is dead. You know it.
! did what 1 promised.
Two people... Pow! Pow! Killed.
“If 1 go back, the village would become extinct."
Enough with your damned moos!
Go to hell!
I don't care
I must have eaten it in a past life.
So
Place these land mines around and bury them well.
“Shibuya, not too far fram the entry.”
Remember the positions.
“Protect me, bodhisattva Guanyin."
“Bodhisattva of Mercy, protect me. "
How strange
l remember stealing grain this way as a child...
the tunnel seemed wider.
Don't make noise.
Keep quiet.
I'm back
Come here!
There' no one here.
No fooling around.
Stop eating.
Otsuka!
Someone's there!
We're not armed!
Beast!
He's running away!
“Kamada, where did he go?"
In the well!
Step back!
The Chief was right: it takes is discipline!
VIL Kill it
That treasonous cow!
TI kill you right now!
The cow seems hungry. Feed it.
“Kuroki, keep watch. 1 need sleep."
Damn!
“Otsuka, what did you do in Japan?"
“Anything I could, to make a living."
l was a student.
I don't know much about life.
A clear shot.
I can't miss.
You still have a lot to learn.
Your fingerprint is a promise.
Niu Er swears on his life...
Yours is the last remaining cow.
Protected from the Japanese.
Where did he hide it?
I know where!
That bastard dug a big cave in the mountains.
I discovered it
when I was hunting
Always
0:46:35:05 00:46:40:10 keep their
promise. I didn't promise anything!
You must!
Everyone must sacrifice for the revolution.
"Fine, he'll do it."
Your fingerprint now!
I don't want to!
Niu Er is stronger than you!
Whoever loses takes the cow!
"l say that first,"
we must find a man to train you!
Fine.
Let's do as the Chief says
“Niu takes care of the cow,
the village appoints Jiu as his wife."
Why?
These are two totally different things.
“Today, marriage is a personal choice."
Nonsense!
I decide!
Let it be done!
I won't!
Heaven knows that I already have a grandfather!
I deserve a real marriage!
“I'm your grandfather's grandfather,"
lam Heaven here!
"Who would marry you, widow"
“Refuse, and we'll banish you."
You'll get three bucket of grain as dowry.
Convince Niu Er to accept the cow.
That's not enough.
I want his silver bracelet.
As a memento.
Or l won't marry him.
Fine.
No!
It's a family heirloom!
Too bad
Everyone bear witness!
No!
“Good morning, Otsuka."
I told you not to go out.
"Sorry, but a healthy cow needs to walk."
Don't be long.
"1: Loyalty is second nature for a soldier."
2: A soldier respects the rules of proper etiquette.
3: A soldier cultivates the art of weaponry.
Who are you?
What's going on?
It's the enemy!
How many are you?
“How many are you?
Speak up, damned Chinese!"
Bastard!
What happened?
He attacked me from behind.
Who is he?
The enemy!
Should I stab him?
Consider him target practice
Stab him
“Stand up, Shibuya!"
You are not a student!
You are a soldier of the Empire!
That's an order!
Go!
Call Otsuka!
“Shibuya, water!"
It's just a flesh wound.
Shut up and look at me.
"You oaf... And you, act like a man!"
Lower your head.
VIL kill you
Don't shoot
“Shibuya, the rifle."
I'll show you how to use a bayonet.
Watch!
“Come on, Chinaman!"
NIL kill you!
“Captain, here's a dead villager."
Jiu...
"Oh Momma..."
Let's head south
"Where roads are wide"
And money is high
Oh Momma
The village has decided. So we'll obey.
“Such a good life, you have."
Easy and plentiful. That's why you're so big.
You've never had grain before.
Life with me is tough.
Communist cows are so lucky!
"This is home. We eat what we want, nothing to fear."
What are you looking at?
You are a cow of the 8th Army.
You should act like one
The Communists stress quality for all men.
But not for cows
“I'm poor, so you'll have to eat hay."
Peasant food.
"Yellow Cow, eat up."
But net so much that they'll notice.
Wow...
How did they get so big?
What's wrong?
Don't 1 have the right to some milk?
“Like Jiu, you need discipline."
Be good or I'll give the rest of your grain to Yellow Cow.
“l can't touch Jiu's, but 1 can touch yours."
"See, how I'm touching them."
“Of course, 1 can touch them."
What's up?
Shame on you!
Scratches to your face!
And slaps to the mouth!
Aren't you ashamed?
Give me the silver bracelet.
You'll get it
after we're married.
Give it to me or I'll report you.
You fed the village grain
to your yellow cow
And you're abusing the Communist cow!
I'm not!
"Yes, you are!"
No!
You touched her udders!
Stop and listen to me!
"Villagers, come out and hear!"
Disgusting news!
Don't believe this nonsense!
He fed the village grain to his own cow
and let the Communist cow go hungry!
The very cow entrusted to us
And he even touched her udders!
Only the 8th Army has that right!
Jiu...
Go away!
Leave me alone!
Where are you going?
Don't come back if you run away.
“A pretty girl in the orchard"
“Picking pretty peaches"
Sees tomcat doing tabby
“Meow meow her"
"Meow meow there!"
Shameful cow!
“If l were you, I would kill myself."
So insolent!
“From now on,"
you will obey me.
Do as I tell you and give me milk.
OK?
Don't I feed you right?
Enjoy yourself while you can.
Refugee?
From where
The smell brought you here...
Have some.
A real mother...
Milk again!
Where're from the other valley. I'm a doctor.
"Well, you know how to remove corns.”
“treat diseases, too."
Our village was raided and burnt down by the Japanese.
We fled for our lives.
We haven't eaten for days.
Human life isn't worth much
“Thank goodness, your cow saved us."
“It's like our mother, right?"
The poor beast is doing badly.
It eats very little grass
and it gives too much milk.
It's no surprise that it's sick.
We won't be able to milk it for a while.
Don't worry.
It can give you one last bucket.
No one will milk her anymore!
Look at her!
Feeding you made her this way. Go away!
Where to?
We'll slaughter it.
“Big as it is, there will be enough meat"
for 20 days.
Go to hell
You're re a beast!
Why?
Tell me!
Did you kill your mother after she breast-fed you?
lll kill you first!
It's not his fault.
We all need to eat.
"Go, all of you."
You can see what's left of the cow.
! did what I could for you.
Don't ask for more
“Please, just go"
“Listen up, everyone..."
Maybe we'll meet people in the next village.
Let's go.
"If we find food, children eat first!"
Think of our hungry children!
That poor man nearly killed his cow for us.
I'll stay and try to cure it with some kind of medicine.
Blood is clogging its heart and lungs.
High internal temperature.
It will take the right kind of herb.
“Please, you must cure her"
“l want to, but 1 don't have the medicine."
Come with me. The Chief had all kinds of medicine!
The cow shouldn't be left alone! You go!
What?
You're up to something bad!
Is this how you thank me for feeding you?
Bad people!
I'll be back!
I'll get you!
Can a corn-removing scalpel be used to slay a cow?
To protect the cowhide
you must start from the muzzle.
Bastard
You don't have a heart!
Think to kill the cook after the meal?
Come here!
“Don't touch that cow,"
or I'll skin you alive!
Fight like a man!
Enough!
"Once it is done, we'll calm him with some meat."
Everyone
happy!
The cow's gone mad
Bad-tempered like Jiu.
Where have you been hiding?
I've been looking for hours!
What did they do to you? Those bastards...
How did you get up here?
Can you fly too?
It's fine. Those bastards won't come here.
That son of a bitch!
He wants to kill us.
The cow must be inside.
Of course.
“Gousheng,”
“Er Qiang, capture him now"
Go away
The place is covered with Japanese land mines! Stop it!
Or you'll all end up dead!
Coward!
We only wanted to eat your cow.
And you killed my two brothers!
NIL kill you!
There's another one!
Go away...
There are land mines!
Leave my cow alone!
You can't come in.
The explosions will attract bandits.
Save yourself
“The mines are everywhere,
I don't know exactly where!"
Just go!
“Doctor, just hurry and go!"
Liar!
Why would I lie?
Are you blind?
You're trying to trick me!
Mangy mongrel!
You're crazy!
People aren't for eating!
Bastard!
Go away
Let's et out of here.
Man ad beast have gone mad.
“Let's go to the mountains, to the cave."
We'll never return.
What do you say?
Tell me.
“Niu Er, dear!"
I need your help!
Go away!
Come here!
You broke your promise.
Come here
Hurry and dig the hole.
The Japanese are coming.
I'll feed your cow.
I will send it back to you soon.
“If the mountain bandits come, we're finished."
Just give them the yellow cow.
Save yourself.
Come on.
Who's there?
"So you like killing, you Japanese dog?"
Don't want to kill anymore?
Didn't you kill everyone here?
"We were living peacefully, without harming you. "
Come here!
and you? Not unruly anymore?
“l was a student. I just arrived, I never killed anyone.”
This Japanese knows some Chinese!
He writes well.
Eight.
I'm 8th Route Army.
You're a dead man!
There's no reason to kill each other!
What kind of gun is this?
Almost forgot...
Open your eyes.
I'll do this your way.
My mother...
My younger brother
They are waiting or me.
Give me my photo
Don't show me that.
It won't work.
Your family?
I used to have a family too!
You murdered my pregnant aunt with a bayonet.
So shut up! You must pay.
For everything.
"Uncle,"
Chief!
Help me!
“Today, 1 avenge you all!"
"Oh Momma"
Let's head south
“Where roads are wide And money is high"
“So many mountains to climb..."""
Wait here. I'll check out the cave.
Halt!
Who are you?
You scared me. Where are you from?
Are you 8th Army
I'm from the Nationalist Army. Who are you?
I found that stuff on the way.
I'm not a soldier. Stop threatening me!
What's that?
You were smart to hide here. This is my cave.
That cow...
It's so big!
“Careful, she's very bad-tempered!"
Fraternizing with the Japanese? Traitor!
They're killing the Chinese
Put that gun down
Do you want to get killed?
My brothers...
What kind of gun is this?
I will avenge them!
It's not how it looks!
Listen to me!
“Uncle, Chief..."
Help me!
“Today, I will avenge you!"
Don't touch her!
Crazy Japanese
Bullshit
Don't take me for a fool!
He cured my cow!
Collaborator!
Tell him to put the gun down!
Or I'll shoot you too!
Guns down both of you!
What kind of gun is this?
Two...
Three!
Get down!
Jiu
Where are you?
Everything's fine.
We're lucky.
All together!
Push!
What is this about?
A foreign cow mating with a Chinese cow?
Sure it can! They're both cows.
Reproduction is possible.
I'll get you all!
We'll never go down again.
Men till the land and women weave cloth.
This is how life should be
So you wanted to kill me
Then we'll all die together.
lL kill you all!
Jiu!
Momma!
“Picking pretty peaches"
“Sees tomcat doing tabby"
Get up
I forbid you to die
Do you want to freeze to death?
Then get up!
Listen...
I want to know something.
You...
In your foreign country...
How are you called?
Do they call you Jiu?
What's the name of your village?
Do you miss your parents?
“Captain, land mines ahead!"
We can't advance
How could there be landmine here?
Query headquarters.
Are you the 8th Route Army?
Yes. We're now called the People's Liberation Army
Have you come for the cow?
I don't understand.
"You were supposed to return in 10 days,
seven years ago."
Wait a minute.
She belongs to you.
We are the People's army.
We don't take from the people!
Hold on!
What is it?
This was written when the troops evacuated.
All the villagers died.
1 brought the cow to the mountains.
And there's this...
I don't know who wrote this.
My unit can't take this cow.
“Listen, I'll make a military decision."
The cow now belongs to you.
The cow... She's mine?
And the seal?
What kind of gun is this?
Your seal of agreement.
How about a fingerprint?
I'll give you my fingerprint.
How's that?
Let's go.
What now?
The cow and I...
We'll stay in the mountains.
We'll never go back down.
You... do me a favor.
Write something for me.
What?
Some characters...
“For a tombstone, on a grave."
“In memory of Niu "Er" (two)"
Which is which?
“In memory of Two "Niu" (Cow)"
It's the same.
Don't be afraid.
Everything will be alright.