Stop
"May 2002. Six months before Yan's death”
Know what "screwed up" means?
The first masseuse came in
She looked like Sam's dog
So I asked for a replacement
The new one was worse
She's the dead ringer of Sam
Just imagine
I simply couldn't swallow that
She dared to ask if she's pretty
Of course I said no
And she clawed me. So I called you
That's what's screwed up
And you wrecked the whole place
That's gonna cost me a fortune
So if a masseuse is ugly
you're screwed
How dare you swear at your boss?
Ouch
Yan
It's a small gig. Don't give me shit
You bitch that I give you no work
But crooks don't need to work
If you want work, why not be a cop?
Know why I only
take you under my wing?
It's because you're focused
It pays to be focused. Look at Sam
He's so focused, no?
As for what happened today
Don't let Sam know
After his wife died
he hates us horsing around
Gimme a break, would ya?
Are you done talking? Go inside
Hey, stop pushing me, officer
One shouldn't be like that. You're a cop
So are you gonna tell on me?
Enough
Go to hell
Cut it out
How dare you beat up your boss?
"October 2003. Ten months after Yan's death"
File number 10143
Regarding the deaths of officer Yan
and officer Billy
IA has made the following report
On November 26, 2002
Sr. Inspector Ming of IA
contacted undercover officer Yan
Tipped off by Yan
Ming toppled Sam's drug operation
together with the OCTB unit in West Kowloon
$60 million worth of cocaine was seized
On November 27, 2002
Ming met with Yan again
on the rooftop of FSC Center
Yan supplied intel on triad moles
You can't get away
Just wait and see
So you're planning to whack a cop?
know all about you and Sam
You've no choice. Come back with me
Drop your gun
What are you planning to do?
I just wanna get away
The foregoing testimony
was provided by Sr. Inspector Ming
The independent investigation
committee
unanimously believed the testimony
Ming's killings of Billy and Yan
have been ruled legal
It has been confirmed that
Billy was a mole sent by Sam
It's over at last
You guys believe me?
Anyway it's all over
Stay in Admin for now. OK?
Wait
Got it. Your parking space
Wait 3 more weeks. Yes
Bye
Sergeant Chan
Your uniform is ready
Drop by when you're free
If not, 1 can send it to you
Sure, no problem
Good. OK
Too bad Billy destroyed the CCTV
Or it wouldn't have dragged so long
Our bosses harp on accountability.
Lucky that we work together. So no red tapes
You can come back to IA next month
Exhausted?
Take a vacation with Mary
Hello
I'll sign the documents tomorrow
Sure
Yes
Everything can be separated
Everything except the baby
Sergeant Chan, your uniform's ready
If you're not free, I can send it
I can do that too
OK, wait for me. Bye
Have I done something wrong?
I feel like beating people up today
Why make such a scene, SP Yeung?
These Taiwanese are arms dealers
My appointment didn't show up
They're bored so I kept them company
Nothing wrong, huh?
Sure
work in the Security Wing
l hate guys coming here all spiffed out
You got so many men. Lend me a hand
Don't give me a hard time
That should make it easier
You wanna set me up?
Is it better now?
We've already written the report
Half a kilo. Minimum 8 to 10 years
Ask two kids to come back with me
That's what they're gonna say
They saw them take out some drugs
As good guys do, they beat them up
l'l give them
Good Citizen Awards
How about that?
Sounds good
Take them in
Be gentle
Sir. Sir, you can't go in
Yeung, don't go too far
All these years, you and me
You want me dead?
If I fall, you'll go down with me
Give me a chance, would you?
"One Month Later"
Delivery from OCTB?
I was transferred to IA yesterday
together with the coffee
Sit down
I've stopped drinking
I need pills to sleep lately
If take coffee, 1 can't sleep
Life is so unpredictable
l used to hate IA the most
And now I have to work here
You don't seem to like it here
I can transfer you elsewhere
Are you kidding?
I moved here because of you
The files are on your desk
The first file
This sarge killed himself in front of his ex-boss, Yeun:
IA is working on several big cases
Security deals with politics
Everything is classified there
They won't answer any questions
We found an envelope on the sarge's desk
There's a tape inside
It's a chat between him and Sam
It turns out he was Sam's mole too
Besides Chun
several officers also committed suicide or vanished
They are proved to be Sam's moles
After Sam's death
SP Leung suspects one of the moles
wants to clear his ass off
and kill everybody else
SP Leung ordered to dig out this guy ASAP
It's a close shave this morning
A package was delivered to SP Leung
Guess what's inside
Tapes of us supplying intel to Sam
Lucky that the sarge is one of us
How many more of us are there?
Including you, there are five
Ronald, this is Inspector Ming
I've left something at Admin
I've dug up something about Chun
He was in the Police Bowling Team
Wait
Inspector Ming, that's what you need
Good
I'm off to lunch now
Thanks
Go on
He used to go to SCAA for practice
He rented his place from JJ Investment Co
This company owns 3 big units
The owner is Shen, a Mainlander
I'l email you the info later
No, send them to me now
Inspector Ming
I'm Yeung from Security Wing
I applied for a parking space
Let me check
I waited a whole month
I don't wanna push you
But how much longer will it take?
Sorry, but I've moved back to IA
l know
But Admin asked me to contact you
It's approved last month
Your parking space is at B3A6
We couldn't reach you
I've taken a month off
IA was investigating me. You should know
I do
Well, investigating Admin today?
No. Just picking up a uniform
It's a sarge's uniform, Inspector
belonged to the sarge who killed himself in front of y«
I'll take it back for investigation
Wasn't the case closed already?
True, or your break isn't over yet
Thanks
You're welcome
B3A6
Have we met before?
I dunno
D'you know Shen?
Mind your own business
Inside Chun's locker
we found these photos
This guy is Shen
He used to be Sam's business partner
This other guy is SP Yeung
I think he is responsible for sarge's death
SP Leung could be Sam's man we're searching for
OK
OK. See you in an hour
You're so nice
You see him as soon as you're back
You're a nice guy too
Thanks to you
he could die as a cop
That's my duty.
I don't know why I helped him
I only knew him for 5 months or so
I've seen him 21 times in total
He's a good cop
Everyone would've helped him
Where're you going? I'll take you
I'm back
Let's start
There're no triads in China
What China needs is wealth
Triads are all life-and-death
Today, we're here to talk business
But I'm a real triad
No
To me, you're the best businessman
My brother said so too
We have a hundred mill to spend
We wanna invest in your business
We'll ask no questions
It's one country, two systems
As long as money breeds money
we'll let you run the show
You still believe in that?
We believe in our Mainland ties
You think a Hong Kong triad
can outlive a Mainland businessman?
Without my brother's connection
your business in China won't last
Sam, you're a Buddhist, right?
Glory to Amitabha
Is the feng shui good here?
The best in Hong Kong
I want a longevity tablet here
For which member of your family?
For my wife
She died half a year ago
And also for myself
Such a small gig, I'll handle it
A small gig?
A small gig
If it's so small, let my men do it
We'll see how they'll handle it
Goodbye
Bye
Keung
You'll deal with his men
Are you kidding, Boss?
I'm an idiot. 1 will mess it up
What does this smile mean?
Excuse me
So loaded?
Jealous or what?
Is it legit? Be careful
Don't worry, Boss
You should know how much cash I have
Want a loan?
What's this?
Your daughter's pocket money
You're a dad. Spend more time home
You sure look thinner lately
None of your business. Thanks
Who're these two guys?
Only know they're Mainlanders
Anything else?
Shen was born in Taiyuan, Shanxi
An entrepreneur who was drafted
Dealt in antiques and transport
Started from scratch, he's loaded
He came to Hong Kong a year ago
His bro Liang joined him recently
and involved in shady businesses
Sam's been eyeing the Chinese market
He wants you to talk about what?
Co-operation
Liang
Yan
Sit down.
By yourself?
You too, Liang?
We have lots of nightclubs in China
All protected by local big shots
Big shots
Your goods can ride on our network easily
We have businesses in eleven cities
I'm sorry
Well, how's the talk so far?
Not bad
See an ashtray in front of you?
Pick it up and smash it in his head
Smash him
I'm screwed
What happened?
Mary is pregnant
Congratulations, Boss
But we're not married yet
Get married then
Huh, is it necessary?
Or she can have an abortion
We're already engaged
Got it
We can go now
OK, let's go
Long time no see
But I saw you last week in China with a broad
You don't have to shout
Security people are full of secrets
Time for a break
Hey, what's going on?
What are you guys doing here?
Sorry, SP Wong
We're asked to take some mug shots
I don't know what's going on either
l asked CIB to open a file
and take a picture of everyone, anything wrong?
Officers, are you done?
Wow, everybody's here
We were on the trail of Mr. Shen
But that led us to Sam by chance
We even busted Sam's man
I'll let CIB handle the triads
Sam, long time no see
What brings you here?
Just accompanying some friends
You HK Police is so inefficient
I'll speed it up then
He beat you up. Wanna press charges?
If not, then sign here
I beat you up. Wanna press charges?
You're out of your mind
Stand there
3G
Keung, let's go
Wait
Do you recognize me?
But I recognize you. Be careful
SP Wong
They're all yours
No need. We know each other so well
The CIB colleagues, you can go now
Thanks, Ming
It's my duty
Let's go
What's your game?
You think it's a game?
It's life-and-death
I'm glad you know that
Hurry up and thank me
For what?
Look what you're doing now
Just eating
You're eating shark fin
Boss took me to Thailand last time
l had shark fin and then I moved up
You have shark fin. You'll move up
Boss is mean but he buys you shark fin
Just think about it
Take him
Let go of him
Boss
You let them take Yan to China?
Ask him why he smashed his head
He smashed his head?
It's no big deal. On the street
either you smash me or I smash you
Yan has smashed his head, right?
How about this?
Is that OK now?
Liang
Are you here to make a scene?
Or are you here for business?
Scram
We are even now
Let's talk business
Il heard your arms business is huge
If you can let me chip in
then the blood they have spilled
will not be in vain
Boss
So what about it?
You have a grudge against me?
No
Ever met a guy who seems nice
but might whack you any moment?
I've met someone like that before
So what's your conclusion, Boss?
I'm wondering
Why he didn't whack you
You look after them from now on
Take this
Shen's not what he seems
Security is on his trail
Could be related to arms smuggling
Sam stopped all his deals in China
They're gonna work together soon
That's big shit
What should I do?
You're not at the shrink yet?
Why should I see a shrink?
You beat people up
l persuaded Department of Justice
to send you to a shrink instead of jail
It's fine if you don't wanna go
See you in jail
Hello
What's the address?
l have an appointment with Dr. Lee
Over there, please
Planning to spend the night here?
I can't fall asleep in my clinic
Unlike him
He said since he's an undercover
he could only fall asleep here
I still remember
He told me that night
Everything'll be OK after tomorrow.
And then he died
You're a doctor
You still keep his file?
He's dead, but he's still a patient
Let's go
OK
"Three Hours Later"
We found an envelope on sarge's desk
There's a tape inside
It's a chat between him and Sam
After Sam's death
SP Leung suspects one of the moles
wants to clear his ass off
and kill everybody else
I think he is responsible for sarge's death
SP Yeung could be Sam's man we're searching for
Do you understand what ! said?
Sorry
I won't sign if she doesn't show up
Got it?
OK
My wife is divorcing me
Did I scare you? I'm sorry
Be careful
Of what?
Your car's next to mine. I drive badly
If l scratch your car, look for me
I'm a good driver. Don't worry
The Taiwanese will be discharged next week
Taiwan authorities have no comments
Mainland's police will come for repatriation
Their boss is a good friend of mine
So stick to the plan
When those big shots arrive
banquets and shopping are inevitable
Make sure they feel welcomed
How about the nightclub?
[ think Macau is better
You're not afraid of paparazzi?
I'l just bag them
OK, you bring the bags
SP Yeung
It's Chun's memorial next week
We wanna hire some monks for a service
Make sure it's decent
Yes
Back to the Taiwanese police
Talk to the Macau guys tomorrow
Let them plan the evening
I'll talk to them about security
Without planning, it'll be a mess
Then we won't have a good time
Any addition to your testimony?
No
Call us if you got extra information
Thanks
All set?
Yes
Can I touch this?
OK, thanks
Is everything OK?
It's like that when I came in
They stole some cash and watches
And the computer is gone
Might as well start from scratch
But the computer's useless to them
I locked it with my password
They won't know it's my license plate number
Your eyes are red. You didn't sleep?
Been working on several cases
You should get some sleep
Everything'll be OK after tomorrow
Il have to go. Call me
Mr. Chan
"2002.8.16. The First Session"
Mr. Chan, I'm Dr. Lee
lam obligated to tell you
You're ordered to undergo treatment
In the coming 6 months
you should complete the treatment
I'll then submit a report to the Court
The Court will base on this report
and decide if you should go to jail
Jail?
Isn't the treatment all there is?
You should follow the doctor's orders
Or the Court can revoke the sentence
And detain you for handling
Got it
Excuse me
Damn you, SP Wong
You don't need to call the cops
Just give me a call
You have my number, right?
Or I'll become a wanted criminal
"The Second Session"
Mr. Chan, I'm Dr. Lee
lam obligated to tell you
You're ordered to undergo treatment
In the coming 6 months
you should complete the treatment
You'll then submit a report to the Court
The Court will base on this report
And might put me in jail. 1 got it
Please sign here then
We think you have a violent streak
We'll use hypnotism for treatment
Hypnotism?
You signed the papers
You can refuse
But the Court can revoke
And lock me up, right?
Go ahead
Hypnotize me then
Let's begin
Please introduce yourself
Talk about your family
Mr. Chan?
Mr. Chan
Can you co-operate?
I was practicing
In case you can't hypnotize me
I can hypnotize myself for you
You know
willis particularly strong. It's not easy to hypnotize r
l haven't started yet
Not yet
You wanna know my story?
My surname wasn't really Chan
I was an illegitimate child
My dad was a drug pusher
I had to work since I was little
l earned two hundred grand a month
I brought a Porsche at seventeen
I hired two drivers coz
I didn't have a driver's license
This shrink thing is useless
Shrink or jail time. You choose
She wants to hypnotize me
If I spill the beans
don't blame me
It's not that easy to be hypnotized
Don't concentrate and she can't
It's tough not to concentrate
Dr. Lee is nice
Nice person
You won't understand
"The Third Session"
You are looking at the sky with lots of cloud
You are enveloped by warm water
You feel weightless
You're floating on water
You slowly open your eyes
The sky is so close
What're you doing?
I'm hungry
Gotta eat something
Are you done?
Yes, kind of
Let's start again
Can you see the sea?
The water is so warm
It envelops your whole body
You feel
What now?
Nothing really
I might oversleep during hypnosis
Better set my alarm
It's not difficult to remember
"The Fourth Session"
One Mercedes to Zhanjiang
One Land Cruiser to Zhuhai
Write it down if you can't remember
The cabin cruisers need new motors
Pink?
We are smuggling, not sailing
My fax number:
21918125
No fax machine?
Why ask my fax number then?
E-mail?
E-mail address?
No e-mail
Sorry, but I've been really busy
So are you done with your business?
Let's talk about your family
You said your dad had 3 wives
You have 16 sisters
Let's talk about your twelfth sis
Heh, I haven't
Are you OK?
Get away
Why so impulsive? I haven't listened
Better now?
The report for the Court
doesn't matter to me
I'm a doctor. I only wanna cure you.
You can leave any time if you like
But I've been trying to tell you
If you keep lying, I can't help you
"The ... Session”
Dr. Lee
What did I do besides sleeping?
You don't remember what you did?
I do but I'm not sure
Forget it. Bye
Dr. Lee
I find you particularly nice to me
You've got a crush
Delusion
Delusion?
No wonder
Bye
What's with you? Looking so smug
The doc said you're dying tomorrow?
You won't understand
You think [ have delusion?
Delusion?
Yes, you do
Maybe hypnotism makes me delusional
That can't be helped
Hey, watch out
So many cars
I'm a normal guy
But she makes me all confused
So I'll spill my guts
It has to do with Sigmund Freud
According to psychoanalysis
hypnosis gets to your subconsciousness
Once it reaches your subconsciousness
it can reach your darker side
Then it can heal your traumas
And then with symbolic memories
It's so deep. Are you showing off?
I can't help it
It's written in Shen's Reader's Digest
Are you buddy buddy with Shen now?
Not at all
He tries to buddy buddy me instead
Mr. Shen
Let me apologize for Yan
I'l apologize for him
Pal, ever heard the saying
Men are changed by events,
not events by men?
Without the past, there's no present
I'm sorry
What?
Great speech
Where's Sam?
He sent the two of us
Sam
Reading?
Any recommendations?
How about you?
How To Become Rich In One Day
I'm not short of cash
l helped you a lot over the years
You speak first, Chief Inspector
You know everything I know already
Cut the spiel. Will you help me?
You help me. I help you
We help each other
Good
What are you doing here?
lam here to
He is gone
Who's that guy?
A pimp
Why are you following him?
Actually, I'm a pimp too
l wanna know if he's dating my gals
Actually, I'm short of cash
How about hiring me?
Be serious, doc
Be serious, pimp
Hello, Internal Affairs
Boss, I saw Yeung with Sam today
He may be a mole. Run a check on him
Sam's deal with Shen may start soon
Uncle Chan, why so late?
Refill the water dispenser
You're good
You know when we run out of water
Don't just talk. Give me a hand
Damon, help
Why said nothing just then?
Yan just sent me a tape
Yan sent you a tape?
Wait for me
What's the matter with you?
I got something important to do
Wait
What?
You've been back for two days
You haven't seen anybody but me
Am I supposed to greet everyone?
Did I scare you?
I'm sorry
I dunno why you
locked yourself up for two days
Don't take everything on yourself
Everything'll be OK after tomorrow
Ming
The door is over there
Let's give it to OCTB
Did you listen to it?
No
vam and Shen's transaction will take place in two day
There'll be lots of arms and coke
I'll contact you before take-off
So Sam doesn't trust you fully
Beware of Yeung first
I will
Can you bust him?
You saw them together. That's not enough
How can I bust him?
Boss, I'm risking my life for you
So don't run that bullshit on me
I'll take care of Yeung
It's you?
Don't worry. Ming's a great help
Do you know what you're saying?
You won't die if it's not for him
It was an accident
Didn't you want us dead?
l only wanna be a good guy
Can you give me another chance?
Sorry, but I'm a cop
Are you OK?
I'm fine
I'm OK
Do you know what you just did?
I know. What about it?
Can you take me back to the clinic?
Sure. Are you OK?
Ok. Let's go
Good morning, Dr. Lee
Your hypnosis is great
I'm so relaxed
I guess I won't need to go to jail
Hypnotherapy is a two-way process
If you don't tell the truth
[can't help you
I'm already very co-operative
You don't talk about the triads
That's OK. But even on matters
like your favorite food and films
You still have to lie
Well, that beats me
You're not me. You won't understand
The brain is not
made for keeping secrets
l remember when I was a kid
I stole a candy bar in a supermarket
It's a foot long
The manager caught me
l was so scared I cried
The manager finally let me go
Later I went there with my mom
And I saw the manager
I felt he's staring at me
I was very uneasy
My mom asked me what was wrong
said the manager had molested me
My mom called the cops
So the cops took the manager away
He never told on me
But I never saw him again
Then I went to college
I finally told this to a classmate
After I finished telling the story
I felt like a new-born
Can I really start over again?
Do you trust me?
I do
As long as you trust me
When did you join the triads?
[ didn't wanna join the triads
l wanna be a good guy
But then I met Mary
Your wife?
She's Sam's woman
Why do I have to talk about this?
You gotta trust me for hypnosis to work
Then we can solve your problems.
You can't solve my problems
My job is to betray folks around me
I dunno when I can stop
To survive
I have to betray others
I'm actually a cop
I'm a cop
I don't wanna be Sam's mole
Did I scare you?
I'm sorry
Everything'll be OK after tomorrow
Where were you? Today is D-Day
Today?
Yeah
I forgot
Take out your phones
Distribute them
Yan
You take the boat. There're arms
If anything goes wrong
l know
You drive me to the dockyard
D-Day of Shen and Sam's deal
will be tonight
They probably have heavy armories
We should wear bulletproof jackets
The marine is standing by
Team A and B get ready at the slopes
Wait for my order
The operation is called off
What are you saying?
That's an order from the top
An order from you or from the top?
I don't need to explain to you
I've been on Sam's trail for years
Explain your ties with Sam
It's Security's top secret
ou can make formal inquiry to the Asst. Commission
Call IA
Yes, Sir
Sir
Just do what Yeung said
No way
It's not as simple as you think
It's very simple for me
My man is risking his life out there
Everybody in OCTB stays put
You're under disciplinary investigation
What kind of disciplinary issues?
You don't follow orders. That's a disciplinary issue
Where are you going?
Back to my room, Sir
Let's go
Turn back
Ask everyone to follow our car
But Yan is in the transaction
Your wife agrees to meet you this afternoon
Is that OK with you?
Thank you
The people will come in today for repatriation
Make sure nothing goes wrong
Damon and Fai, you stay here
Set the channel to 34879
Tell Transportation we can go now
Thank you
Ming, having fun in my office?
Everyone, get ready and follow me
What's the matter, Ming?
We'll bring Yeung in
Those police are chatting inside.
They'll be meeting our boss in fifteen minutes
Don't make any mistake
Damon and Fai, get the documents ready
Yeung
You're under suspicion for collusion with Sam
Please come with us to IA
Ming, you know what you're doing?
l know
l found a cassette tape
What tape? I don't get it
Listen and you will
Where's Mr. Sam?
He's not here yet?
They're empty
Shen
Boss, the arms cost over ten mill
Please give them back.
Those Mainlanders are animals
What if they're here to set me up?
Which bitch told you that?
My life told me so
What if you're wrong?
Then I'll co-operate with them
But Yan's gonna die either way
We're all risking our lives here
l almost died twice
Boss, no more jokes
Boss
l have only one henchman
Don't do this to me
Tell me
Where are my goods?
Go ask Sam yourself
Why didn't you shoot my head?
I didn't aim
Stand up
You guys are together?
You guys are together
Sorry, I'm a cop
Go ahead and shoot
Save me a bullet
What kinda cop are you?
I got an "A" for writing reports
After I kill you, l can write anything
He's not Sam's man
Then you're not Shen
You're in time
Come join us. It's entertaining
So you don't wanna help me, Ming?
I do, but they're watching me
So you're not worried about me
You're worried about yourself
Whatever you say
You'll deal with him
Give me three days. I'll run a check
Ming
Ming, this is your last chance
Ming, you're under arrest
What're you doing? Ming is over there
We agreed to bust him. Why you help him?
Yeung found this tape in your room
Why did you make such a big mess?
He is chasing after me. I have to kill him
I'm taking charge now
I'l look after your deal
I've got it when we killed the cop today
I'll talk to you later
Cuff him
What're you doing?
Get away. Sit down
Sit down. Get away
Get away
Get away. What're you doing?
I told you to be careful
Why should I be careful?
I'm a good guy. Why should I be careful?
Why?
l worked so hard
Helping you guys
killing all of Sam's moles
Why can't you give me a chance?
l wanna be a good guy too
Why don't you give me a chance?
Why? Answer me
Sorry, I'm a cop
I'm a cop too
Sure you won't go to the hospital?
People like me can't see the light
Same here
More blood, more credits
Will that cause you trouble?
It's just a report
You trade intel with Sam. Be careful
You should be careful. Sam set you up
You won't bump into me every time
Will we see each other again?
I'l pass
Speak Mandarin
I'll go to Beijing next week. Join me
I'll quit after this.
And you?
I'm a snitch
We don't have holidays
OK
See you
You haven't told us
What's your name?
Name?
I dunno
Just call me "Shadow."
How corny
About time for me, too
You haven't answered me
l asked if you remembered me
At the cadet school in 1991
If you hadn't left, 1 couldn't get the award
Ming is in critical condition at the hospital
The bullet penetrated his upper jaw
and has entered his brain
The doctor says even if he can survive
his brain will be seriously damaged
Stuff about him and the moles are all over the walls
in his room
The whole IA has been covered with CCTV
all connected to SP Yeung's computer
Mary
He won't make it
Ten Days after Yan's Death
He's dead. What's the point?
There're things we've gotta do
Hey pal, you're right
Everything'll be OK after tomorrow
I'll arrest Ming myself
One Month Later
Take it back
He made me a limper
Is he Yan's friend too?
They were in cadet school together
Twelve Years Before
Now that you're in the cadet school,
you should follow the rules
Those who break the rules will be like him
They will be expelled
Who wants to trade place with him?
Yeung, congrats for the Award
If he weren't kicked out, it should have been his?
Perhaps that's fate
Destiny is destiny
Men are changed by events, not events by men
But these two men
They have changed certain events
Let bygones be bygones
Tomorrow is another day
Seven Months Later
You're here?
The baby can say "papa"
November 2002. Seven days before Yan's death
He shot me so I shot him back
I was just a punk at that time
Stop bitching and learn from Yeung
Learn what?
How to write a report
Did you kill anyone? It's big shit
So it's small shit if 1 got killed’?
Send me a report
I'll send you shit
What did you say?
Scram
What do you mean?
Time for lunch
I've hardly finished breakfast
Do you wanna eat shit instead?
Excuse me
Can I help you?
I'd like to try this stereo
Ksitigarbha Sutra:
"People of the like shall be cast
into the Avinci Hell
and will continue to suffer from Kalpas to Kalpas
with no means of escape."