The Infernal Affairs screenplay
is rich in content,
so we could have many,
many sequels if we wanted.
But that all depends on the box office,
since that's what lets you
go on making sequels.
ANTHONY WONG:
It's very seldom
that you get to do
a monologue for over a minute.
You talk to yourself like a fool.
That actually takes a lot of skill.
Because...
you want the audience to see--
you want a kind of intensity.
I'm talking to this other guy, describing
something I saw the other day.
I'm speaking calmly,
but what I'm saying needs to be scary.
To make the audience feel
that scariness is a real skill.
Anybody can speak.
You just spit out the words.
You can just read
whatever's on the page.
SIU FAI MAK: In the beginning,
Wong Chi Shing and Han Sam
are good friends.
Han Sam is a polite man.
Sure, he's a gang leader,
but he's content, not too ambitious,
and he never worried much about
committing atrocities in his line of work.
He pretty much joined the triad
just to make a living.
It is his destiny.
As for Mr. Wong, everyone thinks
of him as a loyal father figure.
He hates bad guys,
and he stays pretty calm.
By contrast, we wonder why
Officer Wong changed so drastically.
He never used to be calm
by any means.
In fact, he was downright
cruel in the past.
Actually, he always meant
to be a good man,
but he chose to ignore proper procedure,
to do things his own way.
ERIC TSANG: Sam is the least
ambitious one in infernal Affairs.
He is a person with a traditional mindset,
a common person in the world.
A gang leader is always
a gang leader, period.
He should never have considered
usurping the gang leader's position.
SIU FAI MAK:
We don't learn everything there is
to know about Sam in Infernal Affairs.
Sam is a very emotionally reserved
character in Infernal Affairs.
Whenever he appears, he presents
himself strictly as a gang leader.
He shows authority, gives orders,
and breaks a few eggshells when needed.
At one point,
I thought of having a scene
where Sam has to pick up the eggshells!
When you finish a meal,
somebody has to clean up the mess!
As an audience member, ! want to
find out what kind of person he is.
Not just as an audience member--
I myself want to know too!
In real life,
there are real gang leaders,
and it's understandable we would be
curious how they behave.
Does he do his own laundry?
You know, that kind of mundane stuff.
CARINA LAU: Mary is a clever lady,
but she's also very traditional.
She always follows her husband.
She takes it for granted that if
her husband is good, she will be happy.
For any such lady, her life typically
revolves around her husband.
She does whatever her husband says.
She concludes that, since her husband
is so great, "Why should he be a follower?
My husband should
be the gang leader."
In my opinion,
that's what you'd expect of a woman.
In infernal Affairs tl,
I pictured the first scene
showing Lau Kin Ming walking
down the street
from Monkok to Tsimshatsui.
Then he shoots.
I don't know why, but for the whole movie,
it's the first scene I always remember.
We have Lau Kin Ming taking Mary's
clothes--Mary being played by Carina Lau.
Ngai Kun, gang leader in Ngai families.
This whole circuit that Edison Chen
walked, I wanted it perfect.
Whatever he was doing--walking,
making expressions, holding a gun--
l wanted Lau Kin Ming to do
everything perfectly.
The manner of firing the gun,
the manner of walking--
both needed to be perfect.
I feel every scene has a characteristic.
EDISON CHEN:
I feel Lau Kin Ming had
many good scenes to perform
in this second installment.
I can't say no one ever cared
for my character,
but he had the feeling of being
a lone wolf during his childhood.
After talking with Felix,
the screenwriter,
l would go home
and ponder these things.
was thinking how I could incorporate
my own experiences into the role,
so that I would remember
the feeling when I was acting--
I could feel the emotions
and invest them into the performance.
I find that really helped me a lot.
Before I ever read the script,
I made a point of telling myself
everyone considers Mary to be
someone with authority and presence.
But after seeing the script,
I concluded that
Mary should be a person
who is graceful and polite.
She would speak differently
when facing different people.
She is a woman of taste.
Since she runs her own
music and electronics store,
she knows a great deal
about music and about stereos.
She's a woman who knows
a thing or two about life.
I think that Mary's attitude towards
Lau Kin Ming is pure and direct.
She just appreciates
this boy very much.
She felt that he was clever,
ambitious, and loyal.
Carina Lau is a nice lady.
Most of the girls
l know are young and lovely.
Working with Carina Lau,
I cannot just be myself
because the feeling is different.
The way Carina Lau smokes,
the way she carries herself--
all she has to do is look at you,
and you want to sit up straight
and speak clearly.
So even walking should not be done
the normal way Edison Chen does it.
He should be more mature,
to match her mode of conduct.
CHAPMAN TO:
In infernal Affairs lil,
we assume that Crazy Keung
is in his 30s.
That puts Crazy Keung in his 20s
in Infernal Affairs It.
At the beginning,
the director of movie thought that
I needed to look like
a young Crazy Keung,
so he wanted me to lose weight.
Then I lost about 20 pounds
for the part.
I lost weight and took care
of the outward appearance,
but now I had to take care
of my internal state, my behavior.
We had in mind from the start
the sort of person who never grows up,
who never grows in his intelligence.
No matter what he goes through,
he never learns anything.
We took Crazy Keung
to be such a person.
So we let Crazy Keung
be the kind of guy
who never polishes his behavior,
who never grows in his understanding.
In fact, Chan Wing Yan and I
had a complex relationship,
because many people don't realize
that Crazy Keung was a show-off
who liked to flash his stuff.
You can tell by his constantly
changing styles during the movie.
Maybe you can pick up on the fact
that this ordinary valet
has a very flashy ponytail.
If anything, he's overdressed,
probably because Crazy Keung
is obsessed with looking handsome.
And you do realize,
Chen really is handsome.
Crazy Keung wants to look good,
and he sees that Chen looks good,
so he naturally feels good about that
and becomes good friends with him.
Chan Wing Yan is a complex person.
How can we say that?
Because there are many things
he refused to do.
But he has no choice--
he has to do it.
In fact, it's very simple--
he's undercover.
He pretty much hates the gangs,
but he has to rub shoulders with them.
That's the heart of the conflict--
"Il don't like you,
but I can't let you know that."
JUN HU:
Shawn Yue, he was my subordinate.
He was just a student who
hasn't graduated from police school.
I like him very much.
But once I know the relationship
between Ngai Wing-Hau,
played by Francis Ng, and him,
I start to be cautious of him.
Wong Sir just took advantage
of this relationship to help Yu
to get into Ngai Wing-Hau's "family."
Shawn Yue was very studious.
Whenever we were setting up lights,
or whenever he was free,
he would ask me questions like
what should he do as an actor,
what should he study,
should he go to school?
He asked me about that kind of thing--
what should he be paying attention to.
We had good communication,
so I didn't treat him like an idol.
I still think he is
a hard-working person.
In fact, Chan Wing Yan's background
is very complex. He's a gang member.
But he followed his mother's name
because he didn't want to have
any relationship with the triads.
So he came out with his mother
and became a policeman
because he wanted
to escape from the triads.
However, he is a triad,
unfortunately, so he could not do it.
Moreover, he had blood ties
with these people in the triads,
which was beyond his control.
FRANCIS NG:
Wing-Hau was a nice person,
but he was a member of the triad.
Members of triads
fall into two categories--
people with family ties to the triad,
and people without family ties.
He had a blood relationship
with these people.
He was graceful,
calm, peaceful, and generous.
I think he could easily have been
an entrepreneur or a politician,
but he was tied to the triads.
I guess it was a sensitive matter
in society.
We wanted Francis Ng for
the first picture, but he couldn't do it.
But we got him for the second.
But then, if we had used
Francis Ng in the first picture,
he would have had no place
in the second.
Francis Ng is very much
a recognizable actor.
This time, I expressly wanted him
to play a second-generation triad.
He used to be an accountant,
but the family has changed.
His father died. There was no one
to take over the family business.
So he had to take it, but he faced
a lot of pressure from everyone else,
because the family business
had many branches.
To put it simply, it's a big family.
Sam looks after a certain branch,
and others look after other branches.
When Ngai, the old gang leader, died,
the four leading families wouldn't
necessarily toe Ngai Wing-Hau's line.
Not so Sam, who was very loyal.
When Ngai Wing-Hau took over
the business, he had to consider
how to use strategy and his own
intelligence, and how to face the triads.
We needed just the right person
for the role of Ngai Wing-Hau.
In fact, Francis was our best choice.
I knew he could handle this role.
This role was unusual
in the annals of Hong Kong cinema.
For example,
he was a real intellectual,
and he had a lot of plans in mind,
but he never got nervous
in the face of emergencies.
He knew how to persuade
several other gang leaders
in a phone call
at the beginning of the movie.
How many things did he have in mind?
Hard to tell.
So we needed an enigmatic person
to take the role,
and Francis Ng was
Ngai Wing-Hau in the movie.
l would use him to indicate
what kind of person Ngai Wing-Hau is,
and how he could possibly persuade
all the triad members in one night.
And then came the second phase,
when he finally annihilated them.
We see him play both ends
against the middle--
the police versus the Ngai family--
and how he balances them
one at a time.
Francis Ng had prepared for that.
In fact, he was
an easily excited person,
but he had to establish
the proper pitch for the role,
and therefore he tried to be a person
who never got too excited.
For him, it was a challenge
with a certain degree of difficulty.
He always kept an even keel.
He always gave us
a pitch-perfect leader, every time.
He wanted to read the script
before deciding how to play the part.
"You guys need to start shooting fast,
or else I'll forget what I've prepared!"
Actually, Francis Ng
is a supremely capable actor.
He's very selective.
He doesn't take just any role.
A poorly qualified actor always talks
about how he should play his role well.
But Francis Ng--
and Andy Lau, and Tony Leung,
and Anthony Wong--
I never heard any such thing
from them.
They just talked
about making choices.
This refers to the fact that they have
their own little corner on the role.
They didn't worry about the role,
just that little corner.
Take Francis Ng's role, for example--
"l want to be a leader
in the triad from now on."
It'd be easy to fall back on the same
old approach, talking very authoritatively.
And that is a true fact.
It's very easy--there are ways
of getting things done.
He speaks with absolute authority.
At his word, ten thousand people
are ready to act.
But he didn't want to act that way,
and I didn't want it either.
But it was the same as always
in the script.
He would stop and think,
"Where was my choice?"
Ngai Wing-Hau's still learning
to take on these huge responsibilities.
That is his choice.
He insisted on acting it this way,
right down to the line readings.
l admire one of his sayings very much.
He said, "I play the role by ‘subtracting.’
"We actors often say
we act by ‘adding'--
that is, you find out the way
of speaking of this role,
then you add the body actions
of another role--
for instance, hand gestures,
holding a cigarette. That's typical.
But Francis Ng said, "No, I can't
do it that way. I'll do it by subtraction."
Take his lines, for example.
He spoke the lines in a reserved tone,
perhaps even a bit shy
and modest tone, which was unusual.
That is to say, he even issues orders
in a shy and modest tone.
What does it look like in the end?
This is what actors of Francis Ng's
caliber bring to a role.
It's very unusual.
If an actor of lower caliber
played the role,
he would speak the lines out loud,
open his eyes wide,
and say, "Very good."
He's a new edition.
I think it's really unique.
After l watched it,
after ! and Wai Keung Lau watched it,
we wondered,
is this the leader of a sinister gang?
Not hardly. However, if he plays
the leader of a sinister gang this way,
he's making it something special,
something unique.
He's a good guy, basically.
FRANCIS NG:
I don't think I calculated the role this way.
I just delivered the performance
the script called for.
To me, it's meaningless.
l imagine other people
would play it another way.
But to me, that's the only method
that would allow me to take the role.
l accepted the role for the challenge,
because it doesn't fit my usual image.
l was interested, and I think
other people were also interested.
I don't think that everyone
would play the role in this way.
l felt a bit worried when I was acting,
because ! would not revise his lines.
It's like looking at a famous painting.
You look at it for a while, then you can
close your eyes and trace it mentally.
Other people will trace it
accordingly. It's different.
For me, I watch it and think that,
"Oh God, I'm afraid I can't trace out
the things in my mind."
So basically, I didn't create anything.
I just projected the images
in my mind literally,
and ran them over to the audience.
After we began shooting, they asked me
how I could decrease the vigor
of the role to such a degree.
A cultured man would not put all
his energy or talent on constant display.
As for "adding," I didn't add anything.
But there were some scenes
where suddenly, like gifts from heaven,
l felt very happy about them.
Like the toast. It wasn't in the script
and would not be very interesting to read.
Wai Keung Lau's way of shooting
is quite open too.
Towards the end of shooting,
there arose a kind of mood
which affected
every single actor on the set.
Even bit players and extras
could feel the sad atmosphere.
It was like a funeral.
It's interesting that usually
we toast and shout hooray--
"Long live Big Brother"--
a group of fellow sufferers.
But I remember that day,
after I raised my toast,
the man opposite me raised his,
and then everyone raised theirs, slowly.
They were all invested in the moment,
not just wandering souls before a camera.
So it was very moving to record
this scene on film, and very unusual.
Usually, those bit players
will not act until you ask them to.
But this time they communicated
such feeling, which is very uncommon.
Wai Keung Lau, shooting a film--
I think I'll act according to
the script for the first time.
In infernal Affairs, there was a scene
about my drilling in the Cadet School.
He thought I didn't drill well enough
to be a convincing cop, so he beat me.
I thought he was being too strict.
He beat me, so ! said to him,
"You beat me one more time,
and I'll beat you back."
I'm pleased to accept his advice,
because he has shot
even longer than Andy Lau,
and he has known more players
than others.
So I respect his opinions.
Nevertheless, I think he should
also listen to my opinions,
since I'm the one playing the role.
Even if I didn't follow his directions,
he couldn't do anything about me.
But I respect both of them,
because they're very experienced.
You can see from Infernal Affairs
that they've written and directed the film.
WAI KEUNG LAU: Keung, since
he himself liked the role very much,
I didn't have to give much input.
He could emote
and act it naturally from his heart.
He had already caught the sense.
Before the second picture,
I let him know I had no doubts
about his acting,
but I did have my doubts
about his physique.
"If you can't lose 20 pounds,
I'll drop this role."
He certainly met my requirements.
It was like seeing Chapman To
ten years ago.
SIU FAI MAK: I've planned
SP Wong to be such a bad guy.
Actually, I felt like planning
a guardian angel around SP Wong.
We believe there is an angel
around everybody.
The problem is whether
you pay attention to it or not.
SP Luk is the angel around SP Wong.
The difference between
SP Luk and SP Wong
is that SP Luk believes in the law,
while SP Wong is a cop
who does not believe in the law.
SP Wong will do anything,
by fair means or foul, to arrest criminals.
However, SP Luk believes
in "live and let live."
If you don't break the law, no problem,
but if you do, he's ready to pounce.
He's such an upright cop.
In the beginning, we didn't
specify which actor would play him,
until one day
someone mentioned Jun Hu.
I thought that was a good idea,
because I quite like him.
Then I began to talk it over with Jun Hu
and showed him the script.
He liked it very much too.
So it was done,
and we began to shoot.
SIU FAI MAK:
As for Shawn Yue's performance,
I didn't want to talk much with him.
It's terrible to talk through the creation
of a role from beginning to end.
It'll take you three months
to explain it clearly.
So Wai Keung Lau and !
found an easy way for him--
Why not start with imitation?
That is, imitating the performance
of Leung, CW Tony in Infernal Affairs,
including his way of walking, speaking,
even the expressions in his eyes.
Leung's eye expressions
were the most difficult part to learn.
This method is doable,
but it may be not a good one.
But after watching Infernal Affairs
about 100 times,
he gradually formed an image
of Chan Wing Yan in his mind.
SHAWN YUE: I started to cooperate
with Francis just from this film.
Honestly speaking,
in the beginning when we were
not very familiar with each other,
I found it a bit daunting,
because I thought it would be
hard to get to know him,
while at the same time
I knew very clearly
that we had an intimate
relationship in this film.
What was I to do?
So, during shooting,
whenever we'd take a break,
I'd sit beside them off-camera
and listen to them talking.
By being near them, I hoped I could
muster more feelings during shooting.
CARINA LAU: In fact, I already
knew Edison Chen personally.
I've known him for several years,
because knew his dad.
I think he's changed
a lot during these last few years.
He used to play around a lot.
He was a bit of a wild boy.
After these years of working,
he's become more mature.
During shooting, he'd like to find
chances to be close with me,
just chatting.
He said he's watched all my films.
I said, "Stop exaggerating!"
He said he would find an angle
to love me.
I discovered my young friend
was serious about his craft.
WAI KEUNG LAU: Ever since we wrote
the script, there were many characters.
How can we help the audience
distinguish the family members
from the bodyguards?
Take Roy Cheung,
for example, in the role of Law.
It's clear to see he's the bodyguard
for Ngai Wing-Hau, and very special.
He has no dialogue,
which makes him even more special.
Let me borrow an expression
from SARS--
Why should we select
such atypical characters?
Because the selection of the cast
is very important for the film.
The selection of the cast
is very helpful for the film.
Is it really necessary for us
to select such atypical actors?
Atypical actors
are not the usual players.
We thought,
why don't we find some directors?
We happened to have a list of
directors on the table.
We had a list of directors
in the meeting.
Many of these directors
have acted before.
Why don't we use their experience
and acting skills?
So we picked out four famous directors.
Arthur Wong plays Wah,
Henry Fong plays Gandhi,
Peter Ngor plays Negro,
and Teddy Chan plays Ching.
It's suitable to place them in the film,
perhaps even according to age.
Some of them are elder,
while others are young,
and this gave the film some texture.
Of course, we showed them the script,
for a movie that might be
a little pricier than others.
We asked them whether they wanted
to accept the challenge or not.
l exaggerated to them
that Peter Ngor is my master,
and Arthur Wong
is Peter Ngor's master,
so Arthur Wong
is my master's master.
That's subtle, and very intimate--
the master and the master's master.
Teddy Chan and Henry Fong are
directors of two different generations.
Such a combination is funny
even in real-life.
When you see it in the film,
it will be just wonderful.
As soon as he sat down, Francis said,
"This is bad.
How can I out-act these guys?"
SHAWN YUE: In fact, SP Wong,
that is Anthony Wong,
has a significant impact on me.
I'm not sure whether it's
because our personal relationship is...
From my first meeting with him
to our collaboration on this film,
it's been really wonderful.
I've already worked with him on my
first film, and here we are together again.
He he's very kind to me.
He teaches me a lot of things.
So he plays the part
of SP Wong in the film,
which makes me feel really,
really intimate.
I'm so familiar with him, I don't have to
give communication a second thought.
Our relationship
has long since been established.
On this film, I feel
we are very well-acquainted indeed.
ERIC TSANG: In my opinion, Carina's
role epitomizes most of the female race,
since women cannot do
many of the things men can.
Therefore they pin their hope
on their husbands.
So, if someone's looking to find
what makes a woman tick,
look for something
she's hoping to achieve.
Let's say she can't be an executive,
but she has hope her husband can.
She can't be the leader of a sinister gang,
but, hey, maybe her boyfriend can.
Carina is a such person.
To some degree, she's
pushing me to achieve something
without me knowing it.
Carina and I are lovers
who love each other deeply.
In fact, she's the one
who changes my whole life.
My growth, my life process,
is split into two phases.
Sam has had a character arc
from one picture to the next.
Sam is transformed
because of Carina's character.
CARINA LAU:
What's fun is when you act,
especially with really professional
actors like Anthony Wong.
It was quite a challenge.
There was no problem
with rehearsing the script,
but when it actually came time
to perform the scene,
he suddenly goes like this, and my
first thought is, do I need to stop?
Do I go on playing like this?
Because at that time there were
too many things on my mind.
There were many ways
l could have played this moment,
but I hadn't thought it through carefully.
I gave an in-between response.
I thought I could do better...
and later on, I realized
I could have responded differently.
Like, when I stand up, I needn't
go away and shy away from him.
Because we're equal.
We're just using each other.
I needn't go away. I can just look
at you and see if you agree or not.
That's exactly my purpose today.
Everyone has his own idea.
The director wants it his way--
is there any possibility that Mr. Wong
and I have a love affair?
This is for the audience to guess.
Actually, this is good.
The charm of cinema lies in the fact
that everyone sees it
from his own perspective.
If you see it, you see it.
If you don't, you don't.
ANTHONY WONG: In that scene,
the relationship between the two
is very ambiguous,
and you can think of it any way you like.
This kind of relationship is
for the audience to imagine--
how are those two connected?
Because Carina and I have
only one scene where we meet.
WAI KEUNG LAU: Ever since
the first draft of the script appeared,
the approach to the character
of Luo Ji has been tricky.
The first draft gave him only one line.
How could we find an actor willing
to do one line and one line only?
This role was supremely hard to cast.
We thought long and hard
and decided we needed a special actor.
And we finally picked Roy Cheung.
Originally when we were
presenting the script to him,
he felt strange and went,
“Are you sure you want me?"
To put it bluntly, it's a walk-on.
It's just kind of set in place.
There isn't a lot of leeway
for him to bring out anything.
He listened to my explanation
that sometimes an actor doesn't need
any lines to show off his charm.
"l want you for this role because
I think you've got what it calls for."
1 don't know whether he knows it or not,
and he said, "I'll follow you."
I think this is a sign of trust
between actors and directors.
When the film was halfway finished,
I cut his one and only line.
And he accepted that.
All he said was, "Okay, take it out."
But this film let his characteristics
have their full play.
SIU FAI MAK:
The character of Lu Qichang
is actually like the role played by
Wong in Infernal Affairs 1.
We need a character like that.
When you're first watching the film,
you won't foresee this.
You won't think that he's gonna die,
and you don't imagine
any accident will befall him.
This guy must be a good man,
a lovely man.
Actually, if you ask me,
l wouldn't think it was fair,
that for no good reason you must
sacrifice in order to change another man.
The man who has changed
is Wong Chi Shing.
Hu Jun has worked with Wong Chi Shing
for many years in the police station,
on the same team.
He is much more direct than Wong.
He thought the best way to treat
criminals is to arrest them directly,
and this is the way
that a policeman should be.
Wong does not agree
with him on this point.
During his career, Lu Qichang has risen
through the ranks faster than Wong,
but he doesn't look down on
or give up on Wong for what he is.
He keeps supporting Wong,
keeps working with him,
hoping he can change
his thinking one day.
At least he would never kill
his own brother for no good reason,
like those gangsters!
Such a person, if he hasn't died,
can be promoted to assistant general,
or commander, or things like that.
FRANCIS NG: There are
no 100% righteous people,
but there are 100% evil ones.
It's hard to say, but I don't believe
people know how to look
through others' appearance.
Good or bad is just
the superficial packaging.
Anyway, anything that is helpful
for the family is right.
So I have been strange,
a gentle, refined, and calm person
who can put away his hatred
for ten years.
Revenge is a dish best eaten cold.
But for Ngai Wing-Hau,
right or wrong is always so simple.
In the film there are many
conflicts among the four big families.
In real life, you have rivalries
with bona fide actors
like Anthony Wong,
Eric Tsang, and Hu Jun.
It's much the same, since in the film
I have to beat the big families,
and in real life ! have to rival
these three award-winning actors.
It's very much the same
in and out of the movie.
We think of a method--
he read the first script
and saw how Anthony and Eric acted
so he could take the advantage.
At the same time,
he has done a lot of preparation.
Look at his glasses.
Look at his hair--does it need pomade?
We have checked
the make-up carefully.
As for acting, there are interior
and exterior aspects.
The actors use body language
to express themselves.
Every expression of the eye,
from the stern look to the weak gaze--
we consider every detail.
Actually, we spent
a lot of time on Francis.
SIU FAI MAK: This time Uncle Chi
is in it, and I really appreciate that.
There is one scene about killing people,
which is rather long
and involves a lot of killing.
Uncle Chi is responsible for killing
the leader of one of the families.
Once this person is killed,
the cycle of assassinations is finished.
There is not much special depiction,
except for some actions and plots.
When we were shooting
the scene that night,
Uncle Chi was playing
the harmonica on the set all night long.
When we were filming,
we felt a little strange.
We looked at him
and called Wai Keung Lau.
Lau asked me what was going on,
and I said, Chi was able
to play the harmonica.
I figured he was hinting we shoot
footage of him playing the harmonica
after he killed those people.
And I went to ask Uncle Chi,
"Do you often play the harmonica?"
And he didn't say anything!
So we went on shooting.
After finishing the scene of the killing,
Uncle Chi watches that person die.
And I said, "Uncle Chi, how about
playing the harmonica now?"
Actually, this is very interesting.
This is a kind of atmosphere,
and [ want to say just now
how to create
an atmosphere for a character.
He won't come to you and say,
"l will play the harmonica after the killing.
I will play ‘Friends Forever."
won't say it out, but he will do it,
and it creates an atmosphere
at the scene.
This is a kind of soft promotion
of atmosphere, which is very interesting,
with the playing of
"Friends Forever" at his own pace.
In the end we filmed two versions,
one with "Friends Forever"
and the other without.
The one with "Friends Forever"
is really fantastic.
And this is an actor.
He does a lot of preparation
and chooses the suitable role,
and he keeps on adding things.
This is a good actor
who cooperates with others.
SIU FAI MAK: We were
looking for a bodyguard character
beside Ngai Wing-Hau.
This bodyguard
has been working for years,
and he has to be strongly built,
the kind of guy who can take you
by the throat with or without guns.
When we were designing this role,
we tried to give him a few lines,
but they turned out to be
almost always the same--
"Luo Ji has a covetous eye."
After having written this same line
maybe five times,
you'd finally just go,
"Just give him a line!"
Like when Ngai Wing-Hau
asks him, "How about that?"
He says, "Okay!"
Things like that.
Later on, when we approached
Yiu-Yeung Cheung, we said,
"We have this role. Do you want it?"
Of course the role has its appeal.
He is an undercover cop,
undercover for many years.
When we cast
it with Yiu-Yeung Cheung,
after the first day's shoot,
Yiu-Yeung Cheung stood there quietly,
which was a little scary
and made me kind of worried.
Wai Keung Lau knows him well,
so he didn't care a bit.
He just kept saying, "You stay here.
Don't move, and no talking.”
And he kept saying this all day long.
When we saw him standing there
motionlessly looking at us,
we wondered if he was getting mad.
Do we need to write more lines for him?
If he cannot stand it and decides
to beat us, there would be problems.
We declined to add any lines for him,
but we found
this role really needs no talk.
When Yiu-Yeung Cheung is playing it,
there is no need for him to talk
throughout the movie.
This is when you begin thinking about
why this person is so strange.
What the hell does he do?
When we reach the middle part
of the movie, we all know who he is.
At some point,
the expression in his eyes
tells us there is something
he wants to tell Chan Wing Yan,
whose undercover identity he knows.
He wants to caution his young friend
about the danger.
On the other hand, this character
wants Chan Wing Yan to know
this is the fate of those
who go deep undercover.
WAI KEUNG LAU:
If were to tell some professional actors
l had a character for them,
but without so much as a single line,
I think most of them would take this
as a formidable challenge.
Yiu-Yeung Cheung thought so too.
At first he actually had one line,
and he asked us if we could add another.
I said yes, with much thought.
Actually, I didn't want there to be
any lines for him.
But this seemed unfair to him.
With just one line, we had him in.
Later on, he kept asking for lines,
and I gave him one that was absurd.
That is, right before his death, he says,
"Mr. Ngai, you are not
like this, are you?"
He said, "I can't do this."
I said, "I know, so why don't you just
try not speaking when you play it.”
And in the end,
he even didn't say this line.
CARINA LAU: Actually, for Mary,
she doesn't need to look at
Lau Kin Ming when talking with him.
They are boss and underling,
senior and junior.
When talking to him,
she will treat him like a child
and not care much
what his inner feelings may be.
Because she brings him up,
she never thinks
about the possibility of
a love affair occurring between them.
But when Lau Kin Ming grows up,
he begins to take notice of her,
which goes totally unnoticed by Mary.
Whenever Mary looks at
Lau Kin Ming, he shies away.
ERIC TSANG: Actually,
from the character Crazy Keung,
you can see, as [ have mentioned,
that lam a very traditional man.
Besides, there is always
one person like Crazy Keung
standing by the blood brother,
who is loyal but lacks moral sense.
He acts on the gang leader's orders.
If the leader tells him to hit
his head against the wall, he will hit it.
If he is told to smash his head,
he will smash it.
His only thought
is what he's ordered to do.
That's the nature of Crazy Keung.
But he is very happy, because
he doesn't need to think. Why bother?
If all l think about is waiting
for orders, then why think at all?
If l don't think, ! can be happy.
This is why he is called Crazy Keung,
because he is stupid.
He doesn't need to think.
The scene where
he and I go to Thailand,
he only says he wants a threesome,
a massage, and some shark's fin soup.
He is so simple.
When there is an accident,
he takes a potshot with two guns.
And he says, "Brother,
you go and I'll handle it.”
He doesn't think of
whether he can actually handle it.
I think, on some level,
in the gangster movies,
there are some people
who just give suggestions
and are always
planning things for you.
These people
will always remain in the background.
In the front,
there will always be a person
who blocks the bullet
for you with his body,
as if he is your shield.
Moreover, the assault is done
by his own gun.
The gang leader is always
planning things behind the scenes.
There are many soldiers,
vehicles, and guns at his disposal.
Crazy Keung is one such foot soldier.
SIU FAI MAK: Because every action
is initiated by somebody,
I think there should be a game for
them to decide who takes the initiative.
And I thought of drawing lots
using playing cards.
Jun Hu lost the game
almost every time,
so it's Mak who has been
in charge all these years.
Even after Jun Hu has been promoted,
when Mak has to
follow his orders, if there are any,
he keeps on
playing the card game with Mak.
This involves the brotherhood
between the two.
And we hope everyone can see
the love between them.
JUN HU:
That scene impressed me deeply.
I finished shooting early that day.
My part was in the can.
Then I was waiting to see
how Anthony Wong
would act out his feelings,
his crazed grief when he sees me dead.
And he acted well, really well,
and it was worth waiting.
You know what?
l had been waiting a long time,
and it wouldn't stop raining.
And in the end, Wai Keung Lau said,
"We have to shoot it in the rain.
When the bomb killed Lu Qichang,
even the sky cried."
It was very funny.
During the whole process, I think
Anthony Wong performed very well--
that kind of passion,
that feeling when you are so helpless
and cannot turn to anyone.
And the feelings between brothers--
one minute you had your brother,
the next minute he's gone.
This made a significantly
deep impression.
Another deep impression is,
Wai Keung Lau has very good technique.
Consider the scene
where Anthony Wong
goes about
in a very special barnyard.
He fetches a fire extinguisher
and cloth to smother the fire.
And he goes down to the ground,
kneels down,
keeps going about, goes for
the cell phone but cannot reach it.
It's that kind of feeling again.
And everything was shot
handheld by Wai Keung Lau,
from beginning to end, and there
were no shots blowing the cover.
And there are all
the necessary shots,
which cover the scene
from far and near.
I think this impression, and the two
impressions I have are most...
CARINA LAU: My first scene is when
my husband Sam is in Thailand.
The underworld was in disorder.
I got hijacked and he rescued me.
Then when we are taking sanctuary
in a village which is safe,
Lau Kin Ming confesses his feelings
to Mary in word and deed.
"Has it ever occurred to you
that you would be with me?"
"Since we don't know
if Sam is alive or not,
why don't you consider
our relationship?"
Then Mary is totally freaked out,
because this is impossible.
EDISON CHEN:
I know that scene is very important,
so [ read the script
many times beforehand--
to know what to say,
and with what kind of expression.
What my expression
should be when I am hit by her.
There's no shame in her hitting me,
because it proves that she cares
and that she is upset.
CARINA LAU: Actually,
in the movie I have told him clearly.
I told him seriously,
"Don't even think about it.”
I think she will give him a chance,
after returning from Thailand,
but that's not in the script.
Because at that time they were
in such a hurry, rushing to Thailand.
She said that to Lau Kin Ming
and then went away.
Lau Kin Ming
was heartbroken, of course.
Edison is a born actor.
For an actor, the most important
part of his body is the eyes,
and Edison has this kind of talent.
Whenever his eyes appear in front
of the cameras, they project his charm.
Even in silence,
there are words in his eyes.
I think this is a very uncommon talent.
CARINA LAU: At the airport,
Lau Kin Ming
watches the woman he loves.
He knows what will happen,
but he can do nothing to save her.
Actually he is willing to save her,
and he has gone to the airport
and has called her.
But Mary won't answer the phone.
Maybe Mary doesn't know
what to say to him at that time.
What needs to be said has been said.
What remains can be left for
when they have returned from Thailand.
WAI KEUNG LAU:
When it comes to 1997,
the story undergoes
a great change,
because of an important character,
Ngai Wing-Hau,
played by Francis Ng.
In 1997 he makes a great decision,
that's when Hong Kong
returns to China,
the history of his family
can be changed too--
change from black to white.
Keeping this in mind,
he tries to do many things.
He doesn't realize, however, that
he's about to reap what he has sown.
This includes Sam, Wong Chi Shing,
even Chan Wing Yan and Lau Kin Ming.
Before the dawn of a new era,
people are eager
for the promise of the future.
But this story takes place
in the darkest part of the society.
After all, at that time,
a big change of the era
has made everyone realizes his wish.
Now Lau Kin Ming and Chan Wing Yan
know that their work hasn't been done.
Hong Kong has returned to China,
but everything is sill going on.
Their work is continuing,
but they cannot be turned into
what they were before
because of the change of this era.
Impossible.
ERIC TSANG: Actually, friends are
mutually making use of each other,
though it's a win-win situation.
Police and gangsters, they are
like movie stars and paparazzi.
The paparazzi
covers the star's story,
and the star needs the paparazzo's
report for exposure.
The star says he won't be cooperative,
but the paparazzi still follows him.
Stars often say that
the paparazzi are problematic,
but some stars are good
friends with individual paparazzi.
They even touch base: "I'll give you
photos to print after my vacation!
Hey, my news is on the front page!
Tell me how to respond!"
Hence this is someone who tail him,
but also one who solve problems.
This is what it's like between me
and Mister Wong.
When I have troubles,
he will handle it for me.
But sometimes there are occasions
where it's not convenient for him
to show up among the gangsters,
I will handle it for him, and vice versa.
These two are watching each other,
and they discover this only in the end--
using others is not a help,
it's taking advantage of the other.
And naturally they break up
as soon as they realize that.
This is how they became hostile
towards each other in the first picture.
Actually, this is inevitable.
Not a few things in this world are like
this kind of police-civilian cooperation,
and in the entertainment circle there
are always some people
with an underworld background
supporting behind.
In The Godfather, that's how
they describe Frank Sinatra.
In Japanese movie, the Yakuza
is controlling many actors’ lives
in the world of entertainment.
Gangsters cannot broadcast
their fame in the "normal" way,
so they have to promote their fame
by other, crooked methods.
They figure this way they can
make a quick buck,
and among this milieu
they can launder money.
So even in civilized, open areas,
there will be corruption
and red-light districts.
FRANCIS NG: Shawn Yue
is very interesting.
He does things in very direct ways.
He would ask Anthony Wong,
Jun Hu, Eric Tsang, me--
he would ask anybody how to act.
He cannot wait to possess
the acting skill.
I think many have been astonished
by his performance in this film,
but I think even after the movie hits,
he should be thinking of
how to improve, and that's only right.
Because when I think about a film
that has been finished,
l always believe I didn't do well enough.
l keep on thinking, and I come to
an understanding at some point.
But there is no chance of doing it again.
This is how people should be--
even though the facts
of a given circumstance are established,
if there's even a chance you can
spin it in your mind, take the chance.
This is the only way
you can improve your skills.
Or several years from now,
when I see Ngai Wing-Hau again,
I may decide my performance
wasn't just right.
But on second thought,
l only played Ngai Wing-Hau once.
So this method is always the right one.
l only photocopy
what I can see in my mind.
If anything, several years from now
I may better understand my performance.
When you're first starting out,
you should watch your films
and improve yourself.
Even if it has become fact,
you should try looking it
from a mature perspective.
SHAWN YUE: I think all actors,
when watching their own performance,
would surely start to see things
that were left undone.
This is how acting is.
It is doomed to be imperfect.
The director also says
there are imperfections in every film.
Every time you complete one,
you go,
"l could do better.
Why didn't I do well enough?"
This is how things go a lot of times.
When you sit down and think carefully
and get your mind clear,
you watch the film and you catch
some error in an otherwise perfect show.
But should I beat myself up over this?
For me, knowing where I need
to improve is at least a step forward.
I naturally assume that,
after seeing this film,
I will think of many areas
where I could do better.
Even before a film is released,
Il can see it in my mind, and I can know.
I did do better, sure,
but I can do better still.
At least I will know,
which is better than being ignorant.
And this time around, I have
collaborated with some excellent actors.
That's already a valuable experience.
I've gained a lot. 1 had to acquire
experience and act well at the same time.
You can't attain every single wish,
after all.
WAI KEUNG LAU: One is set in '91,
one in ‘93, one in '95, and one in '97.
Actually, they play out in real time.
‘95 and '97 are considered
the most wonderful times in Hong Kong.
There was peace and prosperity,
and everything just glittered,
so we tend to think everything
was abundant during this period.
Speaking of color for a moment,
a golden yellow tint
makes everything look better
if you take the time to look.
‘95 and '97 make me feel this way.
The color of '95
is a little lighter than that of '97.
So things are lighter in color,
maybe even kind of washed out.
For '91 and '93, I didn't use much color.
The difference is very evident.
And this time
I tried another innovation.
On the first picture, ! had the film
developed without bleaching it,
but this time I would input
the entire picture into a computer,
adjust its color,
and get a brand-new film.
I think this is
a basic requirement for us--
innovations to give the audience
.
new experiences.
For the soundtrack,
l have used a new system to adjust it,
and hopefully there
can be some special sounds.
ANTHONY WONG:
I don't know how I can play this role,
because I always
think l am kind of childish.
But this guy, I don't know
how I can play him.
After finishing the first film,
l was astonished myself.
Maybe I'm just getting old.
This role is very mature and sober,
unlike me. ] am playful.
lam playful and childish.
I don't know
how I could play Wong Chi Shing.
WAI KEUNG LAU:
l remember one scene
when Eric and Edison Chen
were in a small room.
Eric kept saying, "Sit down.
"l don't think you are Lau Kin Ming.
You do it again.
Lau Kin Ming didn't talk to me this way."
After redoing it, he still said,
"It's still not right.
We need some more feelings here."
We set this kind of requirement for
young actors.
I think they are poor boys.
But we have to set the bar pretty high,
because we expect a lot from them.
The success of our film industry depends
on whether they can succeed this time.
Everybody knows
that they are our successors.
We hone their skills
and foster their talent,
letting them know
how filmmaking works.
It's not only a matter
of dress and appearance.
Looks do count,
but the inner responses
and interactions with other
actors are also very important.
SIU FAI MAK: I remember that scene
where Shawn walked up to Anthony.
He snapped at him and left.
There were two cameras,
and only one take.
I knew that I had finished.
l was confident, because I knew ! did it.
Perhaps when I
put on that black jacket, I got it.
I devoted myself to this scene,
and I was confident.
There were a lot of scenes where
Anthony Wong and Tony Leung
were alone together.
It brought me back to Infernal Affairs 1,
and they were so intimate.
Not intimate--
they knew each other so well.
So at that moment, ! felt that
l had become the role I played.
SIU FAI MAK:
Just imagine you were Shawn Yue
and you were expected to play Yan.
You were in his shoes.
What would you do?
He did a lot of homework,
did a lot of thinking,
and then he gradually grasped the idea.
l was already aware
that he had prepared very well.
As he stepped out,
I knew that he could totally do this.
There was no problem whatsoever.
For audiences who had seen Shawn
before, it comes as a big surprise.
They would think that Shawn
knows how to act now.
In the first days of shooting,
he couldn't help coming over asking,
"How am I doing?"
l answered,
"It's not bad, it's very good."
And he said,
"] just don't think that guy is like me."
Il said, "You are acting. When you act,
you have to be like Yan, not Shawn.
Yan is unlike you, and that proves
that you've done a good job."
WAI KEUNG LAU:
The first day of shooting,
Il sent the script to Kwong Wing Chan.
l wanted him to think about the music,
to feel the atmosphere generated
by the screenplay and the footage.
Having Chan doing the score
spared me any worries.
We had achieved
a mutual understanding
about the movie and my intentions.
Whatever you do,
you should endeavor to have the music
complement and amplify
every scene in the film.
We had known each other so well
after years of cooperation.
Say I wanted a piano
or a symphony,
I would talk with him
before we ever shot that scene.
That way he would have a better grasp.
SIU FAI MAK:
Here we see the sparkle
between Eric Tsang and Francis Ng.
When we were doing it the first time,
everybody's timing was just right.
Because Wai Keung Lau is a director
who doesn't like rehearsals.
He wanted the rehearsal over with
before the lighting was done.
Sometimes once the set was lit,
he wanted no rehearsal. "Let's shoot!"
Eric and Francis
were servant and master.
You could see that from their costumes.
You take a look at them, and you know
that Eric is Francis’ servant.
When they walk together,
it just feels right.
Their physical appearance,
their costumes--all very natural.
It's all so natural,
and they even had chemistry.
Especially in that last scene,
where Francis invited Eric for a drink.
We didn't have that in the script,
but they acted it out.
That's amazing.
For example, Francis poured wine
for Eric, but Eric pushed the glass away.
Then Francis handed the phone to Eric.
Those things happen at the table, but
the tension ripples to Hawaii and Thailand.
I think what they brought to their roles
was greater than what was in the script.
ERIC TSANG: I love that scene too.
The rhythm of acting is important.
I do not necessarily respond
to a line at once.
Take that scene.
He raised the glass, but I silently
watched him, then pushed the glass away.
Actually, by pushing away the glass,
I was letting him know I didn't agree.
Then he handed me the phone,
suggesting I'm under his thumb.
But what he didn't know
was that I had him well in hand.
When we exchanged the phone,
we had made everything clear.
Just like I said,
I enjoyed the interaction between us.
Actually from infernal Affairs !
to internal Affairs Il,
l had been enjoying the process
of collaborating with fine actors.
l had been going around saying
l regained my acting bug last year.
l had fun, so now I'm producing.
Everybody is waiting for a good story.
A good cast of actors.
Everybody worked well together.
What we used to do
were mostly comedies.
The comedians got together
to play something funny.
This time it's a serious movie,
and we were serious about details,
about eye contact, about mannerisms.
You gave me this role,
so [ had to bring my best into play.
Francis wanted to talk about the scene
where he died at the hawker stand.
Actually, we wanted to do
a trial before that.
See what each of us
has brought to the movie.
Put everybody's performance together,
and you have a good movie.
Everybody had different ideas.
We saw what's best.
Francis felt that way too.
Everyone shared their ideas.
Everyone got new ideas for acting.
It may be different from
what you came up with.
You just act it out.
And it is different from a stereotype.
FRANCIS WOO:
l have tremendous respect for Eric.
As a matter of fact...
One day we had a few drinks,
and he said something
that gave me the confidence
and determination to portray this role
without "acting" that much.
He told me, "You look
quite aggressive yourself.
Don't act. Get another day job."
So I didn't act.
I dealt with him in my own way.
It's interesting, I think.
It's a rare thing to have such intimate
acting with a male actor.
We had a tacit understanding,
and it's terrific.
It's like we fell in love
with each other,
since we had
such good communication.
ERIC TSANG:
Il told him not to act,
because his role was already
in the right place.
He didn't have to deepen the role.
This character was already very
dramatic, so he just played it casually.
If you portrayed a dramatic
character in a dramatic way,
it'd become a stage play.
You can't play too hard.
What pleases me most
is that we talk everything over.
l offer some advice,
which you could just ignore.
But for me, I speak it out, ! am happy.
You don't have to accept that.
We exchanged our opinions,
but we didn't impose ourselves.
Everybody was willing to offer advice.
It's not like we hid what we had
and pulled it out to show
only during the performance itself.
People did that in times past,
but in this movie, we were
all open and willing to share.
Even in the last scene,
between Anthony and me,
he said, "You have screwed up
everything I have tried to do."
He's supposed
to act out his inner world.
I think he should take
the credit for that scene.
l wanted him to succeed
in ways I never could.
Acting is like playing football.
You have to pass the ball.
If l can't score,
at least I can pass the ball
to a teammate who has a chance.
I'd rather do this.
After all, it's a game.
It's a matter of teamwork,
not individualism.
I think that infernal Affairs
is that kind of a movie--
a great piece of teamwork,
not a showcase for loners.
The audiences just love the movie.
SIU FAI MAK: Why end the story
on the night of Hong Kong's
return in 1997?
It's an important historical moment,
for every person in Hong Kong.
Since that night,
everything has changed.
That moment fits this story.
A background befitting the theme
of the movie was selected.
We were attracted to this.
After the script was finished,
I told everyone about the actors.
I said that Infernal Affairs Il
was a stand-alone script.
It would be a wonderful script
even without Internal Affairs I.
But it might never have been shot.
There are many elements
that you can't just weave
into a sequel that easily.
lam not talking about
the commercial elements.
I don't think so.
It's a really long story, and a lot
of people are concerned about this.
Then you can put these things
in the story.
That's the way it is.
Without infernal Affairs 1,
Infernal Affairs tl
would ignore the times for sure.
It would only deal with changed people,
a simple story of people.
Being able to do this
has made me grateful.