Hi, I'm Mark Osborne. One of
the directors on Kung Fu Panda.
I'm John Stevenson,
the other director on Kung Fu Panda.
And welcome to the commentary!
It's been a long four years.
We were really inspired by anime
in making this film,
so we wanted to start the film
not only as an homage to anime,
but we wanted to find a new way
to create a 2-D look
for Kung Fu.
And we're really,
really excited with what
Ramone and Jen came up with
for the look of this sequence.
Also, I like the idea of starting
a computer generated movie
with a traditional 2-D sequence.
We love traditional animation
and hope it comes back.
We particularly love it when
it's very stylized,
as it is in this dream sequence here.
We also thought it would be the perfect
way of showing the biggest contrast
between Po's dreamlife, where he's free
to do all these crazy, heroic things.
And contrast that when we go into
our computer-generated images
with his more gravity-based reality.
We should also talk about James Baxter,
who is the fantastic animator
behind this sequence.
We were lucky
to have him involved in this.
It was a combination
of wanting to be limited,
look like anime,
but we wanted fluid animation.
They came up with a great style
that was fluid,
at the same time had the
pose-to-pose limited quality of anime.
Also, we've got hugely vibrant,
saturated colors,
‘cause we're going to
make the contrast once we go to
what's reality in our film.
Where we're using computer graphics
of a more muted palette
when we first see Po.
It's really a Technicolor dream
that goes to a more subdued...
...color palette
when we go into reality.
It's worth pointing out
that this is the first CG movie
at DreamWorks to be shot
in CinemaScope.
So here we are coming up on the great
reveal that this has all been a dream.
And we find Po in the reality that
now he has weight.
And we get to meet Jack,
the real Po, for the first time.
We meet him in his environment,
it's very different, very quiet.
It was something we wanted
to show the contrast between
the dream life and the reality
as much as possible.
The other thing worth noting,
because it's a visual motif we will
be revisiting throughout the film,
our first real look at Po,
he's upside down.
Po being upside down
is something we'll see a few times.
I'll point them out, the each have
a particular significance to us.
Dan Wagner did a lot of this animation
we're seeing here.
He's really the master
of the Po animation
and established what Po
would look like early on.
The subtlety of his acting,
I think Dan did an incredible job
of establishing the sensitivity
of the character.
That shadow of Po's father,
we put that in the category of one of
our way-home type jokes.
- Nobody laughs at it.
- Nobody gets it.
Hey, can't win them all.
It's supposed to be a misdirect
that that shadow is
the shadow of a panda.
So, next time see if that works for you.
It certainly doesn't work
for most people the first time.
That's one of our failures, I think,
in trying to make an interesting reveal
that's Po's father is a goose.
Why? Why is Po's dad a goose?
A lot of people come out of screenings
asking that question.
For us, it was a hilarious thing that
one of our story artists came up with.
Alfred Gimeno, he always threw out
these big, wacky ideas.
At one point he had Po's dad as a goose,
it was hilarious, we loved it
and ran with it.
Originally, Po was working,
had a mean goose boss,
when he was working
as a short order cook.
Alfred said, "He's not his boss,
he's his dad."
He was a caring dad, putting his hat
on him, putting his apron on him.
We should make a big shout out right now
for Mr. James Hong,
who does an absolutely wonderful job
as Po's dad.
He brought a lot of warmth and heart
and comedy to Po's father,
who is a very simple character.
He has only got room in his head
for two things.
There are two things in the world he
loves, his son and noodles. That's it.
And he can't possibly imagine
why Po would ever want
to do anything other than noodles.
People say why doesn't Po tell his dad
about his love of kung fu?
It's because he doesn't want
to break his dad's heart.
In the early days of exploring this,
trying to figure out who Po was,
at one point he lived with his mom
down at the Bamboo Forest.
He worked at a chime factory.
There used to be loads of other pandas
that lived in a panda village.
We tried everything
until we settled on this idea
that he works in his dad's noodle shop.
And it makes him the outcast,
.
In a sense,
there's no other pandas in the film.
This is our first glimpse of kung fu,
with the Furious Five attacking Shifu.
This was actually one of the last
kung fu sequences we did on the film.
At this point,
animation knew how to make
these characters do all the
cool things we see throughout the movie,
We wanted to start our introduction
of the world of kung fu
with a huge, explosive bang.
Have the Five attacking
this little old man.
It's also the first time that we show
how our camera work is different
for our kung fu scenes.
It's our rule, when we're just shooting
dialogue and character scenes,
the cameras are pretty restrained,
pretty formal.
When we go to our fight scenes, the
camera gets more active and dynamic.
It's a really important contrast,
to make sure you guys get
a rich experience.
Many ups and downs.
This is the first time
we're seeing Dustin Hoffman.
We wanted to give you the misdirect
that he's the wise, old master.
And then we reveal him to be the least
Zen Zen Master ever.
And we also have the amazing
Randall Duk Kim as Master Oogway.
We were very lucky to find him.
He has such warmth.
Every time we played
any sequence with Shifu and Oogway,
even Dustin was like,
"That guy's amazing."
We went for a very
abstract version of Tai Lung,
and processed the animation
so that it felt almost flat
and 2-D.
But, it's also the introduction
of our evil color.
We have a complex color theory
in the film.
Blue is our negative color, associated
with Tai Lung, he's a snow leopard.
That's the first very blue sequence.
And the petals that
are on the moon pool,
which will tie into Oogway's peach tree,
and it's also the introduction
of the circle motif.
And we elected to have,
basically, not a common villain,
but a scary, driven,
in his mind,
an emotionally justified villain.
But we were making the pact that
Walt Disney made with his audience,
for all the classic films, which is
there is going to be scary stuff
and dangerous stuff in this movie,
but it's going to work out OK.
I was in the first
recording session with Jack.
He started to reveal his more insecure
and vulnerable side,
something that has been in
all of his performances,
to mitigate some of the abrasiveness.
But he really was
bringing that to the floor.
That was a huge gift
that he brought to the film.
And once we saw that, it really made Po
a much more appealing character.
A guy who was very self-aware,
who knew his limitations and...
And would often feel
very bad about them.
We went back and tried to retool
the whole film
to support that idea
which Jack had brought to us.
Then we have to shackle Po
to this noodle cart,
as much as he dreams about kung fu,
he just can't get away from this
noodle burden that his father
puts on him.
And we see how that plays out
at the bottom of the staircase
of 1,000 stairs.
That becomes a big, running gag
throughout the movie.
Po and stairs. People laugh.
Ours is probably the most stair-centric
movie we could think of,
we're always having Po
run up or fall down the stairs
throughout the film.
There's a reason for it in the end. But,
there's a lot of stairs in our movie.
In this gag, we wanted to be
as dramatic as possible
in setting up this whole
Po climbing up the stairs.
We wanted to make it in the hot sun,
like he's crawling across the desert.
Then we get this great reveal.
It was one of the earlier jokes that
we tried 1,000 different versions of,
and finally settled on this version.
Let's give a shout out
to the Shaw brothers,
Jack's Tenacious D brothers,
Kyle Gass and J.R. Reed.
J.R. Reed... it's amazing. We got all
of Tenacious D in our movie.
The Shaw brothers,
a tip of the hat, obviously,
to the legendary kung fu film studio
that came up with some of the greatest
martial arts movies ever made.
There's all these great mechanisms
the Furious Five are going to battle.
You see them just for a split second.
One of the earliest versions
of this sequence,
you saw the Five battling
these giant mechanical beasts,
and all these really cool things.
Buy the game, you'll get to see
what they look like.
It was better, story-wise, to stay with
Po and to be trapped outside with Po
in the shadow of this great event
that's happening inside.
It gave us a much better stage
for the comedic beats
of Po struggling to get in,
to see that stuff.
There's a couple of lighting choices,
everything inside the auditorium
is lit with bright sunshine.
Po's outside and he's kept in shadows.
So he's away from his dream,
from everything he wants,
We also, unapologetically, decided this
was going to be a very broad
slapstick, Tex Avery, Chuck Jones
kind of sequence with those
kind of visual gags,
to establish that we could do that.
This is also one of the most
technically complex of our sequences.
There are so many crowd characters,
they're all wearing incredibly
complicated clothing.
We also have other effects.
The shots of the crowd
would take...
They would be
on the render farm for days.
Even when they're out of focus,
in the background,
they're just specks of color.
They still have to have
all their cloth, and everything proper.
And it's pretty frustrating.
Once we get all those details are right,
it really gives
a nice realistic setting.
I think this sequence
took 18 months to light.
It was incredibly difficult.
We the audience can't see what's
happening inside.
And we know it's really cool because
we've seen the Furious Five in a dream.
So these little glimpses
we get here are
supposed to tease the audience
as much as Po gets teased.
This sequence came up,
our story artists teamed up
and did a jam on this sequence.
We had every story artist
in our whole crew
working on coming up with ideas
of how we keep Po outside.
Because we wanted to riff on the idea
that he keeps trying crazier
and crazier things to get in.
And it was Phil Craven who brought up
the idea of using fireworks.
That Po would finally
strap fireworks to a chair.
And that's based on an urban legend,
a myth of a low level Chinese official
from the Ming Dynasty,
who tried to go to the moon
by strapping rockets to a chair.
So the legend goes, and disappeared.
He obviously blew up.
That was sort of a funny story
we thought would actually make sense
for Po to try and emulate
in his desperate attempt to try
and get in to see his heroes.
He's such a fan.
He's the ultimate fan boy.
And so this is an expression of
how much he cares about the Five.
How much he cares about kung fu.
He's willing to blow himself up
to get in there.
It's the thing he does that causes him
to get into the right spot.
He creates his own destiny
by being a fan.
Sometimes people say
"He landed by accident."
But, as Oogway says,
"There are no accidents."
Early in story, Po was going to land
directly on top of Tigress.
We wanted to make it clear
Oogway was choosing Tigress.
That pointing finger was landing on
Tigress when Po landed on her.
It was a little bit too much,
story-wise,
to have him land on her.
She's a kung fu master, she should be
able to have her wits about her.
It became better to have him land
directly in front.
It's something we tried
a few different ways.
But, it's one thing we didn't
clarify as much as possible.
That Tigress is Po's favorite.
Tigress’ fairly cold treatment of him,
is more painful, that was the idea.
All those scenes of celebration are
incredibly difficult and elaborate.
Sequences involving tons of effects.
But the effects crew
pulled it off beautifully.
I think when we first
suggested confetti,
everyone was like,
"Do we really need confetti?"
We were like, "Yes!"
We really need confetti.
Markus Manninen and Alex Parkinson
were hugely responsible
for handling all
the technical challenges,
from clothing to confetti
to all the difficult aspects.
We wouldn't have any of the cool stuff
without those guys.
So this is the first time
we get to hear Angelina Jolie,
in our film as Master Tigress.
And she really did an incredible job
of creating a very rich character.
We wanted to have really interesting
scene transitions.
We worked hard on finding creative ways
of getting from one scene to another.
This change of locale to Mongolia,
which is where the prison is set,
was very critical.
Again, it's the introduction
in the body of the story.
The blue presence of Tai Lung.
The whole scene
is lit primarily blue for Tai Lung.
With contrasting red,
which became our power color.
But it was very important to do
as many things as possible
to tell you that
you're in a different world.
No longer in the Valley of Peace,
which is sunny,
you were in a somewhat far away,
somewhat hostile...
We wanted to feel not only the threat,
and to feel like
he was this villain
that was kept far away,
but we needed to establish Tai Lung
as a ticking clock.
We needed to feel like he was as far
away from the Valley as possible because
we have all this story
that we need to tell of Po,
and that needs to happen
in the Valley of Peace.
We needed to have a psychological
separation between those two locations.
Another of our story artists,
Rob Koo, who came up with the idea
of taking the Great Wall of China
and wrapping it around the interior
of a hollowed out mountain.
So, those two visual ideas became
the basis for Chorh-Gom prison.
And "Chorh-Gom prison" means
"sitting in prison,” or"in prison."
So that's one of our little in jokes.
Commander Vachir,
which is a Mongolian name,
which means "thunder bolt,"
played by Michael Clarke Duncan, the man
with the biggest voice in the world.
A voice so deep you can rearrange your
internal organs as you listen to it.
We wanted somebody hugely powerful,
which Michael is.
Everything about it,
like the rhino commander,
his guards all had to be...
It takes 1,000 of these guys
to keep Tai Lung in place.
We should point out the armor he's
locked in was created by Rob Koo.
He came up with this
great idea that Oogway
designed this tortoise shell armor
that encased Tai Lung
and had acupressure,
these dragon-headed pins poking...
To screw up his chi flow.
And basically paralyze him
and keep him absolutely...
Plus, he's anchored to two huge rocks.
Apparently chained to his cuffs.
Something you'll see later
when he escapes.
This feather has been falling for quite
some time, gently floating down.
And then when we come back,
we contrast back to good times,
happy times.
A great moment to shout out
to John Powell and Hans Zimmer,
who did an amazing job with our score,
in helping us to create that contrast.
The contrasting feel
we wanted to get from the prison
back to the Valley of Peace.
We wanted to use all
the story-telling tools we could
to make sure we were getting
the contrast between
the darker moments in our movie
and the lighter moments.
This Yin and Yang balance
between aspects of the film.
John and Hans gave us
what we always
dreamed of having in this movie,
which was a great orchestral score.
We were trying to create
a self-contained universe
and a timeless story,
we didn't want to have
contemporary songs on the soundtrack.
We were very lucky that
Hans and John wanted to work together.
They gave us more score
than we could ever dream of.
It's a score we love deeply.
It has many very beautiful cues.
I'll just say this sequence
is very special to me.
We took inspiration from...
l was up at the Skywalker Ranch once.
A friend of a friend got me in,
I'm a huge Star Wars geek,
and I was creeping around
inside the main house,
and looking at all the artifacts:
The lightsaber, Indy's hat.
l remember being terrified that at any
moment someone was going to come in,
"What are you doing?
You're not supposed to be here!"
Carefully wanting to soak up
as much as possible,
and I think it's funny that I'll
see that played out as a panda.
It was a great way of showing
Po the giant fan boy.
In the home of the most
sacred artifacts of kung fu.
He knows everything about this stuff.
He's read everything, knows the history.
And that's why it was important
for Po to run in
and be spouting out stats about this
stuff. He doesn't have to read the card,
he knows exactly what this stuff is.
And then, when he knows
what the Wuxi finger hold is,
that, of course,
is the ultimate total minutiae,
as far as kung fu is concerned.
He actually knows all about it.
Knows who created it,
knows when it was developed.
That actually, you can see,
it slightly impresses Shifu.
But Shifu has much more
hatred for Po at this moment,
he can't appreciate the fact that
this guy actually knows his stuff.
The Wuxi finger hold
used to come later in the movie,
when Shifu was trying
to restrain Po from leaving.
And it originally started
as a Chinese finger trap.
And then Derek changed that to this
thing he made up, the Wuxi finger hold.
And we love the idea
that the most scary thing,
the most scary kung fu move,
in our world of martial arts,
is this tiny thing
of holding your finger.
- Holding your finger up.
- How ridiculous.
Now we come into, Po gets to witness
the coolest thing
he's ever seen in his entire life.
He didn't get to see the show earlier,
now he gets to see the Five.
It's his own private viewing
of the Five doing kung fu.
And we wanted to make this
really intense, really hardcore.
We wanted to make it very dramatic,
like he was stepping into
a torture chamber.
These guys can
avoid all the torture,
but we know what's coming for Po.
We spent a lot of time looking at movies
like The 36th Chamber of Shaolin,
and any of those great movies
that have rigorous training.
Training halls, things to
make kung fu heroes work.
All our training devices
are based on animals.
No human beings in our world. We took
all things, like Shaolin Wooden Men,
even those spiky things
that swing over...
we call them pork swings,
.
or porcupines.
Those snakes that go over the water.
They rotate and
you have to balance on them.
Those are actually based on snakes.
The rings hanging from the ceiling
are snakes as well.
There's tiger claws.
Originally, the Five Floor,
we used to see cutaways of
palace geese, underneath the floor,
- operating the mechanism.
- Pedaling bikes and starting fires.
But it was just
too distracting to do that.
Jack really found Po in this sequence.
And in the previous sequence
when we were recording early on,
we had a more abrasive version of Po.
And in this sequence is when he really
brought the more
insecure character out.
The real vulnerable character
and the sweeter character.
The character that doesn't think
he's going to just walk in
and show everybody how it's done,
but the character who's terrified
to reveal that he doesn't
know how to do kung fu.
This was actually the first sequence
we put into production.
We called it our "panhandle" sequence.
It was the first scene
that had character acting and action
and kung fu and slapstick comedy.
So it was a very good sequence to try
and see the technical problems
we were going to be faced with,
and acting problems.
It was the first scene that was lit,
as well.
We ended up, many months later,
going back and relighting it.
In a more aggressive style.
It was too conservative
the first time around.
So we went with a red sky.
We asked Ramone to really take a chance
and make a bold statement.
And he was doing amazing bold statements
in other sequences,
that we said let's hit this again.
Something that happens when
the very first things you start with,
even the animation
often gets more sophisticated
or more subtle or more pushed.
So we revisited it to make it stronger.
To use our color theory,
once we decided red was our power color,
we hit the scene with red
to reinforce the power
of the Furious Five.
This is their home, contrasting to
Oogway's home, green in knowledge.
This is all about strength and power.
And just in case anybody wonders
what the words are
on the hanging tapestries
around the training hall,
the words say, "Focus. Harmony. Honor.
Sacrifice. Courage. Power.
Agility. Speed. Grace. Balance."
This is our great Dewey Finn moment.
We wanted to have Po react
to overhearing the Five.
He's a self-aware character who knows
that he's out of place.
Also, another shout out
for matte painting,
most of that exterior
is all matte painting.
There's very little stuff
that we actually built there.
The whole bunkhouse
and all the background
is matte painting.
It's also the reinforcement
of the negative blue color.
This is not a good time for Po.
So, just as we'd use blue for
something overtly evil, like Tai Lung,
we also use blue
for when Po is having
a negative emotion.
The earliest version
of this sequence was done by
our storyboard artist, Paul McEvoy.
He came up with this idea that Po
would just be in their bedrooms,
without them even knowing it. It started
with Po face to face with Mantis.
It was just Po being
the creepiest fan ever.
You know, kind of lurking around.
A huge shout out
to David Cross, as well.
He plays Crane so perfectly, dry,
in contrast to Jack's nervy energy.
A lot of what David did was adlib, too.
There wasn't much on the page and
he kept adding bits here and there.
We wish there was more
Furious Five in our movie.
One of the things we're sort of sad is,
they don't get more screen time.
But, we love the Furious Five.
Everybody who was a member
of the Furious Five,
which were about the five deadly venoms.
But David Cross and Lucy Liu
and Angelina
and Seth Rogen and Jackie Chan,
we loved them all and wished they had
a chance to have more screen time.
We used to have a bunch of vignettes.
Po sneaks down the hall,
he's trying to get to an empty room.
We used to have things where
we would see into Mantis' room,
Viper's room and we would see
that they would hear him coming.
And they would do anything to avoid
having him come into their room
and talk to them.
We had silly stuff like
Lucy pouring tea on her...
Trying to look like
she was in the shower.
Mantis hiding under the bed,
rubbing those things...
To sound like a cricket, so it sounded
like nobody was in there.
We cut it out.
Probably for the better.
Po eats when he's upset.
And the peach tree, we'll talk about it
more when we get to that sequence,
in the scene we call "Oogway departs,"
but that became the key location
for that sequence.
We realized, once we knew that Oogway
was going to have this
very beautiful death scene,
that we had to introduce
the peach tree earlier.
We changed the kitchen location
to be Oogway's peach tree.
The peach is a symbol of immortality
in Chinese culture,
peach blossom and peach tree leaves
are used in Taoist magic.
The wood of the peach tree
is said to ward off evil.
So, in our mythology,
it was Cogway
who planted the peach tree...
..a thousand years ago
when he first came to China.
And his staff is made
from the wood of the peach tree.
The peach tree is the place
that overlooks the valley,
and is this very significant place.
One other thing to mention
is that Oogway brings light.
It's a moment of enlightenment
between Oogway and Po.
So it was a really cool visual thing
to have him bring the lantern
and leave light behind.
It also was a good transition.
He's in the same color language,
blue and a bit of orange.
We go from the blue of the night sky
and the orange of the lantern
to the golden orange of Tai Lung's eyes
in the cut to our first
big action set piece.
While we're in the land of color,
this whole sequence was designed
to be a battle between
blue, Tai Lungs color,
and red, the power color.
If you watch the scene
a couple of times, you'll notice that
as Tai Lung wins each level,
‘cause the thing is designed
like a video game with levels,
as Tai Lung wins each level, he
extinguishes all red light behind him.
So that was one of the big,
overriding conceits for the sequence.
And hopefully, if we make you believe
the physics and the gravity
of all the stuff with Tai Lung
in the hand-to-hand,
you'll accept that he can defy
the laws of gravity in the end,
when he starts to run back up
the falling debris.
Which is obviously a complete
and utter cheat,
but it is designed to show
how amazingly skillful he is.
We should call out sound designers
who did an incredible job.
Ethan Van der Ryn and Erik Aadahl.
They approached this like King Kong,
Transformers and Lord of the Rings.
Gave us a really amazing,
huge, epic soundtrack.
We really wanted to bring them in,
as we did with many of our other
creative people on our team,
to say let's make this a real movie,
let's try to push the boundaries
of what a family animated film can be.
The first time we get to hear lan
McShane's voice come out of Tai Lung,
and we realize he's actually a thinking,
a very smart, and real being,
not just a feral beast.
That was a conscious choice,
to have him not say anything
until he's beaten his challenge.
The only thing you would hear
would be actual animal sounds,
you might think he was just bestial.
lan is one of the most amazing actors.
He made our joke completely redundant.
"Could I get a cup of tea, love?"
He comes in as
the nicest guy in the world.
And then, every single take,
from A through Z,
he'll find every single possible way
of delivering a line.
And when he's finished he just looks
at you through the control room glass,
and goes, "Did I miss anything, love?"
And you'll go, "No. No, that was great.
Let's move on."
Nails it every time. Brilliantly.
Halfway through production, we were
really trying to find Tai Lung.
l was looking back at
The Hero with a Thousand Faces,
and it talks about
a villain is the hero of his own story.
And that's perfect for Tai Lung,
because he thinks he's been
unjustly imprisoned for 20 years.
He wants that Dragon Scroll,
that's his third act.
In his mind, he's going
to get that scroll,
everything's going to be great
and people will understand.
And finally, he'll be able to be
the hero the way he wants it to be.
Reconciliation of the father,
Shifu is the father figure.
And I think that's
not interesting unless...
Unless there's a human component
to the villain
that makes you understand
why they believe they're justified
in their villainy.
We actually freaked people out.
Then we kept getting the note:
"He's too dimensional. Too human.
There's too much going on."
I've got too much sympathy
for Tai Lung.
There's a balance we had to strike.
We wanted you to engage with him.
And believe him as a villain.
At the same time, we didn't
want him to be totally sympathetic.
That's why we ended up putting in
an abstracted version of a massacre
in the flashback scene,
which will be coming up.
Because people felt bad for Tai Lung.
He wanted something
and he was denied it,
locked away in
this hideous prison for 20 years.
So we realized we hadn't
done a good enough job of
justifying why Tai Lung
had to be incarcerated.
So we put in this abstracted version
of him running amok
in the Valley.
So, we wanted Tai Lung
to cast a literal shadow
over the second act of the movie,
and also the Valley.
We weren't going to cut to him
traveling back from the prison,
so we worked on the transition
from his escape
into this next sequence.
So that subliminally,
his shadow burns
over the landscape of the Valley,
to indicate his coming threat.
Another moment with the Five,
just a little bit of glue
for Po's story,
to get us back into his story.
There was a great gag
where Po was asleep.
He had been trying to do splits all
night, and ended up falling asleep,
‘cause he got stuck.
We changed it, it was too confusing.
Too much story going on.
Obviously, he took
OCogway's words to heart.
And decided to take the next day
as a challenge and come.
This is where it's dawning on him
how much of a fan this guy is.
He's not going to quit.
He keeps trying to turn up the heat,
to scare him away,
trying to raise the intensity
of his attack on Po.
He can't do it overtly, because that
would be going against Oogway's wishes.
And this sequence is all about Shifu
turning up the heat
and this gag right here,
when Po hides the piece behind his back.
I think that was something Rodolphe
had boarded early on.
- It was a Rodolphe gag.
- It made us laugh.
We got the hugest crew laugh every time,
we worked hard to make sure
we maintained that
all the way to end.
In the land of reincorporation,
seeing Tigress do
that combat split kick,
and hearing Shifu say,
"It takes years to perfect a split,"
obviously is going to
payoff later in the movie.
So, here we get some more kung fu
coming from the Five.
Just snippets, but we continue
to establish the slapstick...
What happens whenever
Po tries to do kung fu,
we get this slapstick result.
But, Po's indomitable spirit
keeps freaking Shifu out to no end.
That thing where Po
is being flipped around,
that comes from Atom Ant.
An old Hanna-Barbera cartoon,
where bad guys would get beaten up
by this ant that was too small to see.
We just used that for Mantis
beating the snot out of Po.
One of his special abilities
is he's almost invisible.
We tried it with a green smear,
We talked about it.
- It was less interesting.
- It's very funny to not see him.
And this moment is
a pretty intense moment for Po.
This starts our
bouncing down the stairs.
It's a running gag
that we see later in the film.
It should be pointed out,
this moment was heavily scripted
over and over again.
We finally figured out
what we needed to do here,
when Seth Rogen
adlibbed that amazing line.
Seth ended up rewriting
and adlibbing all of his lines,
to the betterment of the movie.
He's hugely responsible for...
Mantis doesn't have a lot
of screen time, unfortunately,
but Seth made every moment count.
Just his big throaty laugh
coming out of a little insect would
always make us crack up every time.
But, when he adlibbed,
that was when the pieces fell into place
around his great adlib
about Po bouncing on the stairs.
This sequence was storyboarded
by Rob Koo,
another continuation
of his acupuncture idea.
We've got the acupressure on Tai Lung
in the tortoise shell armor,
and this was a continuation
of that same idea.
We thought it would be
perfect for Mantis.
Initially, he was going to use
his thingies to do acupuncture,
but we felt it was better to do needles.
We're laying the pipe for the fact that
Mantis can't reach his pressure points
with his acupuncture needles,
for how he's going to stay
invulnerable to Tai Lung.
Will Tai Lung's Nerve Touch
work on Po?
Well, we'll have to find out.
Angelina's fantastic in this scene.
This is her big acting moment
where she reveals she's this
fairly tough, stern,
unforgiving presence in the film.
But you find out she's nursing a wound.
She has a psychic wound of her own.
We had this back-story,
that Shifu raised Tai Lung,
we didn't want the characters
talking about it.
So we came up with this idea
to actually show it.
And to go into...
Tigress is a very
one-dimensional character,
two-dimensional character,
to give us all this rich back-story,
and by accident,
she's defending Shifu in this moment,
but by accident she ends up revealing
all these deep secrets about herself.
It's also Po's awareness of himself
is starting to
cause these other characters
to have more awareness of themselves.
It's brilliant, the one-to-one
correlation between
when Tai Lung is a kid
and being trained by Shifu.
So, again, in the land of visual motifs,
just wanted to point out that
the Nerve Touch
that Oogway does to Tai Lung,
is based on the water ripple.
We saw an energy version
of the water ripple
when he used his staff to still
the waters in the moon pool.
And that same energy ripple
will be something that we use again ina
very different way towards the climax.
Which I'll point out when we get there.
We wanted a mirror of Tigress
and Tai Lung as children,
as closely as possible.
She hits the dummy in the same way,
but Tai Lung actually knocked a weapon
out of the weapon rack,
whereas Tigress just caused it to spin.
So Tai Lung's actually
a little bit better than Tigress.
Coming up here we have some great subtle
animation between the two of them.
This is a subtle moment
that gives way
to a very slapstick and ridiculous
moment, boarded by Rob Koo.
This is probably
the biggest laugh in the movie
where we reveal
the pin cushion on the back.
And then we segue into a very
different moment with Shifu.
We wanted to show him,
the disruption in his life,
and how he is not a Zen Master,
he's trying to be.
And Alessandro Carloni
did an amazing job
of animating the subtlety in this scene
of Shifu's amazing kung fu hearing.
Disturbing his meditation.
Also, in that opening shot, you'll see
the pressure of blue on negative color,
pressing down on Shifu's
little bubble of warmth,
which is about to be popped
by the news from Zeng.
It's a big thing in a movie,
.
any movie,
but particularly in a family film,
to make the decision
to kill off a character.
When we knew that it was going to be
good for the story to do that,
it actually changed
a lot of the tone of the film.
It meant that we were going
to have to be...
- It got deeper, it got richer.
- You can't do that in a trivial film.
But he knows Shifu's struggling, he's
seen Shifu struggling for many years.
Like a great therapist,
he doesn't ever give the answers.
He's always gently guiding.
I think this is a moment where
we like to think it's very clear
that right here Oogway
makes his decision to leave,
because he knows that Shifu
isn't going to be able to do it
as long as Oogway's around
to be a crutch and to be relied on.
Oogway knows "It is my time."
Oogway chooses this departure time,
I'm getting goosebumps.
It's a beautiful, emotional moment.
A significant moment in the story.
I think it was one
of those sequences early on that
was a real proof of concept for how deep
and emotional a movie could be.
And how we wanted to make something
that was taking the story seriously.
We didn't want to be a parody, a spoof,
we didn't want to be jokey,
we wanted to be significant
and deep and rich.
And our actors,
Randall Duk Kim and Dustin
we really asked them to dig in
for the sequence,
to make it heartfelt,
to make it believable.
Dustin had to be anguished
and conflicted.
- And Randall had to be...
- Calm. At peace.
.. accepting of...
For Oogway this is an adventure,
it's not a bad thing,
that he's moving on.
There's a more interesting
adventure awaiting him
on some other plane of existence.
He's OK with it.
It's Shifu who's very not OK
with losing his mentor, his master,
and his safety net, really,
for everything that's about to come.
And also, there's some back-story where
Oogway knows that Shifu's destiny
is to be the next Oogway,
and I think Shifu spent
a lot of his young career
probably hoping to be
the Dragon Warrior himself.
It wasn't until
he believed he failed, he wasn't good
enough, didn't believe in himself,
which is thematic to the film,
that he became a teacher.
And he thought "I'm going to raise,
create the next Dragon Warrior,"
Shifu's been on this track of
"l failed at my mission."
Oogway's known, "No, there is a
greater mission for you."
Which is where Oogway
gives him his staff and says...
"You're now me.
You need to take over the role of..."
Which Shifu doesn't get.
Shifu doesn't understand.
He's using it as a weapon.
He'll actually go on to use the staff
in a forceful way that is
very strange.
And now we come to the sequence
we cursed early on in production,
by naming it "Fun in the Kitchen."
The sequence is not fun.
It actually is fun now.
For many years it was
the absolute opposite of fun,
It was the least funny sequence
you've ever seen.
The core idea of Shifu,
after the death of his master,
finding Po doing something ridiculous,
that was the core idea, to have Shifu
coming from this horrible thing
into everybody laughing,
the Furious Five with their feet
up on the tables, eating,
they're breaking their kung fu diet.
We wanted to have the reality
come slamming into Po.
And actually, I think it was Phil Craven
who first boarded the idea that Po
makes fun of Shifu.
And we expanded on that.
So, Po starts imitating Shifu.
I think it's brilliantly animated.
It's mocking, but if
you listen carefully,
he's making fun of himself.
He's using Shifu as the vehicle,
but he's actually being
self-deprecating.
And I think that's one of
the great things about Jack
and Jack's performance in this. He's
never lashing out at anyone but himself.
It's this consistent thing that he does.
And because we needed this to be fun,
we have the famous joke:
"The boob bowls."
The biggest laugh
in the movie usually is...
Back in the day!
It used to be this sustained laugh
that would just go on and on.
- Much to our surprise.
- We test screened to kids,
and kids went nuts, they laughed
for a minute straight.
And actually we should put that
soundtrack on the DVDs as an Easter egg.
They laughed for a minute straight,
the craziest thing.
They were climbing over the seats,
talking to their friends about it.
And Jeffrey Katzenberg
was at that screening.
l remember him turning
and looking at us.
There was no way
we were cutting that scene.
It's there forever.
This next sequence was
the hardest one to get right.
We knew we had this big comedic laugh
coming when we see Po running away.
But the drama between these guys
and what gets said,
in this moment of sheer panic
on Po's part,
and truly it's panic on Shifu's part,
he's made this commitment to Oogway,
and he doesn't know how
he's going to pull it off.
We did many versions of this sequence.
This scene existed as a card.
There was always a scene
we had to have in the film
called "Po and Shifu have it out."
Jed Diffenderfer did the earliest
version when it involved a punching bag.
It was more of a training sequence.
We went through so many versions
of trying to get this scene right.
It was the last sequence
we put into production.
We knew that because
we were having such trouble
trying to get the balance right,
it would be the last thing we did.
We recorded it more times
than any other scene,
with Jack and Dustin.
Jack was always like,
"This one again?"
"Didn't I do this great already?"
And he always did.
And it was us, we kept monkeying
with it, changing the writing
and trying to change the status.
Shift is the status transaction between
these two characters.
Po, who was desperate to stay,
who now is desperate to leave,
he knows his life's in danger.
Shifu, who's made this commitment
to his master,
who is committed to having Po stay
and trying to believe in him,
and so they've flipped places here.
Getting the actual chemistry and
balance right was very challenging.
And also finding this no-man's-land
to set this in.
It's not the dojo, it's not the palace,
it's this area near the peach tree,
so we're reminded of Oogway
in this spot,
but, really it's a moment
where these two characters
bare their souls and reveal their
deepest, darkest flaws.
Po reveals that he doesn't
believe that he can do it.
That this was all just a lark and...
Shifu reveals that
he doesn't know how to do it,
even though he has
committed to believing...
These characters need each other
to complete their journey.
They need each other so bad...
But they don't know how
it's going to work at this point.
- So this is their...
- It's a giving up.
ina sense, emotionally,
this is their darkest point.
And then Tigress will
pick up the charge.
And that is always
what we wanted to have.
That we saw the fracture
earlier in the kitchen,
when the Furious Five know...
And she makes a plea to Shifu,
"Come on, give me my shot.
Let me do it. I'm your best student,
we're all trained.
You equipped us to do this."
I think she's completely shaken
when he rejects her
‘cause of his promise to Oogway.
She's defying her master,
she's defying Oogway,
going against everything
she's ever learned.
She's the most disciplined,
honorable of all warriors,
and also at this moment
we get to see how amazing she is.
And so we want the audience
to believe that
- Tigress is going to do it.
- She's going to succeed.
- They're going to join up.
- Like a team of superheroes.
We want you to think, obviously,
this crack elite force going out
to take down the bad guy,
has got a huge chance of success.
This location and moment
is affectionately known as
"Mopey Mountain" to our crew.
Mike Mitchell coined that term because
we used to have one more instance
of Shifu sitting upset
and not sure what to do.
And we pared it down
and went for the simpler one moment
of despair before enlightenment.
And that comes in the sound.
Talking about the sound, yes, Shifu has
kung fu hearing, we established that,
theoretically he should know
where the sound is coming from,
and not go to the room
to see if Po's there,
he should know where it's coming from,
but it worked better
for him to go to the place
he expects it be,
which is the training hall, and then to
find that Po's actually in the kitchen.
It's actually very symbolic
for Shifu because
he's spent his whole life
thinking he knows the answer,
he knows the right way to do things.
He thinks those sounds should be
coming out of the dojo,
this is the beginning of Shifu starting
to look at things a different way.
Starting to think outside his box.
His box is the training hall.
He had to hit rock bottom in order
to be able to be aware enough,
have his eyes open enough, to see that
Po can do things in a different way.
This moment right here,
when he sees Po in the splits...
Harking back to that split
that Tigress did in combat,
Shifu says "It takes years to get
that right." Po can get that right
when he's not thinking about it,
if he's thinking about something else.
Po has this internal ability,
this natural ability,
because of his love for kung fu,
his obsession with it.
And it only can show itself
when he's distracted.
Now we get to see him
distracted by food.
This is part of Shifu's rebirth,
and re-inspiration as a teacher.
He takes him outside of his box,
the training hall,
to our equivalent
of Wudang Mountain in China.
Avery mystical place,
home of many Taoist monasteries,
and often the home
in martial arts movies,
and stories of the place
where kung fu reaches
its highest level.
But it was really important for us
to take Shifu as a character,
out of his normal, everyday life,
and he is now changing,
it's a rebirth.
He goes back to this place,
This is the birthplace of kung fu.
It's where Oogway invented it,
taught Shifu,
Shifu went and created
the box, the dojo,
and started creating
a fabricated version of this.
This is a very significant moment
for Shifu,
to start turning this corner,
becoming more like Oogway,
more open to the possibilities
of the universe.
Then we get to see Oogway doing kung fu,
which is so cool.
You'll see there's a lot
of lighting stuff in here.
The scene starts
with being pretty misty,
‘cause Po's in the fog,
he doesn't know where this is going.
And then it transitions to
the sun breaking through.
Which is back to our use of gold
as a heroic motif
for the flashback to Oogway
at the point where he invented kung fu.
Also for Shifu's symbolic rebirth
and his declaration
that he is Po's master.
That he is invested and invigorated,
committed to making Po a success
on the same place
where Oogway created kung fu.
This is a great example of...
we didn't try to reinvent the genre.
There's a training montage
in every sports movie,
and every great kung fu origin film.
A great hero training.
So we're going to find
our version of that.
We're not going to reinvent it,
we're certainly not going to do
a really long one 'cause
we wanted to show you this unlocking
happened over a long period of time,
that it's believable, that at the end,
Po has unlocked all these abilities.
We don't know exactly how long
it takes, it doesn't really matter.
- Don't do the math, people.
- It doesn't make sense.
It's just the idea that they went away,
and they took as long as it took
for Po to get where he needed to go.
We're coming to the chopstick fight,
which is, hands down, the audience
favorite at every screening.
It's the concept sequence that,
when we first executed it,
everybody knew that this
was the film in a nutshell.
The great relationship
between Po and Shifu.
And this sequence actually started
many years ago.
Rodolphe Guenoden had boarded it
as a fight between Tai Lung and Shifu.
It was a contained fight
at a dinner table.
It was a James Bond meets
the supervillain thing,
They were being polite to each other as
they talked about their back-story,
but trying to dominate
each other as they...
...tried to steal food out of each
other's chopsticks.
Then we realized that Po's training
was going to be food-based,
we remembered and brought
that sequence back,
a story artist named Phil Craven,
who was trained by Rodolphe in story.
- How very apt.
- Yeah.
He took the sequence and made it new,
and actually exploded it
and made the epic version.
So it starts very small and goes big.
Phil did, I think, an amazing job.
He boarded the previous sequence, too.
The training montage.
Giving us this believable arc
from the panda who doesn't
know how to do anything,
to the panda who manages to figure out
how to unlock and use his abilities
by the end of the sequence.
What was really cool, was when Jack saw
the finished movie he pointed out
he didn't realize how layered and
significant some of these moments were.
So the "I'm not hungry" moment
really resonated and plays great.
We get applause in some of
our audience screenings.
Again, the chopstick fight
had a lot of very careful thought
in the visual design of that sequence.
Again, it's lit with gold light.
We don't have any
conventional skies in our film
until our very last sequence,
the end with the credits.
A very deliberate choice, every sky
is there for an emotional reason.
That one was a bright yellow sky
because it's Po's becoming a hero.
Also, there's a lot of red in the trees.
Again, our power color.
So, the mix of those color elements
became a significant thing
in the visual design of that sequence.
And now we're coming up to one of the
biggest set pieces in our film,
one of the coolest, most ambitious...
This sequence took forever
to figure out,
not only how to do
this particular sequence,
but what this sequence was going to be,
it was another one of those scenes
we knew we had to have the Five
fight Tai Lung.
So, love the way lan McShane
plays Tai Lung
when he's talking to Tigress.
Here, the bridge is being cut.
Basically they're both in danger
of being plummeted
into this bottomless abyss.
And he's so nonchalant
and self-possessed.
The artists did a great job
of just having him lean.
Jed came up with that image.
There he is, he doesn't care.
that he's thousands of feet
above a bottomless precipice.
He can afford to be comfortable
and relaxed,
he's cool enough to even
walk along the tightrope
without blinking
or breaking into a sweat.
And lan just plays
this moment perfectly.
That Tai Lung hears Po's name
for the first time
and conjures up
this, obviously, completely
incorrect image in his head,
that he's got a worthy opponent
waiting for him at the end of his road,
which will be the completion
of Tai Lung's hero story.
That Tai Lung actually bests this guy
who's worthy of his skill.
Certainly, this is
the most technically challenging
and complex sequence.
The dynamics of figuring out
the rope bridge moving constantly...
The breakage of the boards.
Characters adjusting their weight
on the bridge as it's moving.
The mist is also super-complicated.
Hopefully none of this is self-evident.
You should be caught up in the action.
But when we were brainstorming about
what was going to be the venue
for this epic fight
between the Five and Tai Lung.
When the idea was proposed to the
special effects people,
that it was going to be on a shifting,
crumbling, breaking rope bridge,
they all went ashen and white
and looked really scared.
And we thought, "Great! Perfect.
We don't know how to do that."
- So that means it's worth trying.
- Nobody's ever done it before.
It's obviously really hard
to figure out.
And really, just to give you
an idea of how complicated it is,
Viper, which is the most complicated
character in our film,
just because she has
so many points of articulation,
she's a very complicated rig to work.
And the bridge is,
essentially, four Vipers.
Because there's four major ropes
to the structure of the bridge.
Just to give you an idea of how
complicated it is
for the animators to deal with.
Love Jen's idea
of not seeing Tai Lung
as he flips off the rope.
The rope kind of like attached to
the shark in Jaws
plowing through the mist.
Tai Lung is so good, he's so quick,
that you don't even see him
when he does his kung fu spring.
So, in keeping with
the idea that Tai Lung is the hero
of his own story,
even though he's mostly in cool colors.
We've kept his eyes golden,
our hero color.
And we used the transition
from the gold of his eyes
to the gold of the sunset here,
because Tai Lung
has beat these five masters.
In his eyes,
he is on his journey to be
the Dragon Warrior.
And this is another step in his story,
where he is the hero and he has
defeated the overwhelming odds.
We wanted to play the drama of they've
been paralyzed and defeated by Tai Lung,
but we wanted the comedy as well
of the fact that
these guys are now incapacitated.
And Po has to figure out
how he's going to...
Now he's left, he's the only solution
to this problem.
We wanted to basically freak Po out
as much as possible
by seeing the evidence of what Tai Lung
has done to the Five.
So, we go into
a very, very difficult
and lengthy scene,
that was very hard to get right.
There was a lot this scene
had to accomplish.
There were a lot of story points
that had to land,
a lot of emotional turns,
a lot of things that had to happen.
And so we knew we were
trying to pack it all in.
The movie's been building up to this
moment of Po getting this Dragon Scroll.
The opening of the Ark of
the Covenant, it's this huge moment.
It's the moment that Shifu and Po
believe is actually going to make
everything turn out OK.
Po thinks he's going to be transformed.
Shifu is taking steps towards
becoming more like Oogway.
By using the staff, he's showing that
he's using Oogway's staff to get
the Scroll in this way,
That shows he's changing from being the
harsh taskmaster, the kung fu trainer,
to being the more enlightened
and involved character.
He's still hardcore,
the thing we wanted to have.
This contrast, this combination of Shifu
doing something in a hardcore way
with kung fu,
but he's redirecting these petals
just on wafts of air.
Also worth noting, not something most
people would register,
but it is actually the first time Shifu
calls Po by name.
As opposed to calling him Panda.
Which indicates how far
their relationship has come.
He's no longer an object,
he's a person.
He's a friend,
that there is genuine affection.
This is the key scene for Shifu's arc.
Here's a guy who was almost trying
to kill this guy in the beginning,
drive him away, beat him up, detested
him, wanted him out of his sight.
And in this scene he actually
has come so far that he's prepared
to lay down his life
to give this guy a chance
to fulfill his destiny.
It's where a lot of
the elements of the film come,
also, it's got a big reversal,
obviously when the scroll
is revealed to be blank.
We've been building up the entire movie,
it's been a thousand years
of history in this world
that this scroll contains a secret,
The secret to limitless power.
The thing throughout production,
we tried many things.
Early on in the story we had
the scroll was, at times,
the Dragon's sword,
locked in a room we never saw.
It was a box that had something in it.
"The greatest power
in any of us is within."
You open the box, it's empty.
We put a mirror in it.
We tried many different versions
knowing that
this was the philosophical idea
we wanted to deliver.
But it took us a while
to find the exact means to deliver it.
And then once we figured it out,
everything fell into place around it.
It's also worth noting, this is
a particularly lovely run of music
from this sequence into the next,
through the end of the movie.
This little ramp of music
that Hans and John did
is particularly gorgeous
and supports all the emotions
in the scene.
We love the way the music works.
And then we go into
the big transition into our exodus.
Brilliantly done by Yong Duk,
this use of succession of cuts
through the long lens.
‘Cause we don't want to make it
feel like there was...
We wanted to find that...
Not too much panic. We didn't want
bloodcurdling screams.
We wanted there to be
an intensity and energy.
There's definitely
an imperative to get out
before the bogeyman returns.
Most of the energy comes from camera.
The handheld camera.
Especially in contrast to how stately
the previous sequence has been.
It really worked well.
That's the Shaw brothers there,
two other members of Tenacious D,
- they're stealing a foo dog.
- Our favorite dumb joke in the movie.
Nobody sees it and it goes by quickly.
Little red wagon
with a giant stone foo dog,
that's the thing they've chosen to try
and rescue as they get out of town.
They're morons.
One of our way-homers.
It always made us happy.
And then, when we get into
Po reuniting with his dad,
this sequence was done
by Alessandro Carloni
he came up with the joke of the dad
putting the apron back on Po.
It's a brilliant piece
of visual storytelling.
For Po's dad, nothing has changed,
everything's back where it should be,
Po's going to come back
to the kitchen, he's oblivious,
he's tying Po back into his old life.
But then, when we get into
the emotional content later,
you notice the dad
isn't oblivious, he is aware.
That was really important for us to not
continuously play the dad for comedy,
but to let there be
a significant relationship here.
That doesn't always get talked about.
His dad really does love Po.
I think the very nice piece of
storytelling that's very sweet
is that the dad's only way
of trying to heal his son,
make him feel better is to use
the thing the dad loves the most,
he loves noodles more than anything.
He hopes that by
expressing that to his son,
that this will make his son better.
He's trying to heal his son
by giving him...
The only thing he's got left.
.. the most amazing thing in the world,
the secret of the soup.
Truly it's great, he is coming from
a place of being noodle-obsessed.
And that, he's being himself,
but he ends up, inadvertently,
giving Po the secret.
It's brilliantly played by James Hong.
James did a magical job
with the delivery of these lines,
making them warm and heartfelt
and sympathetic.
And also, one of our favorite moments
that we're very happy with,
one of our biggest laughs in the movie,
when it looks like the film
is going to explain
why Po has a goose for a father,
- and...
- We skip right past it.
.. since it has absolutely
no importance to Po's story,
we completely don't do it.
Shifu waiting at the stairs
for Tai Lung
as a sort of a Sergio Leone
echoing Once Upon a Time in the West,
the flapping door of the tournament
grounds, waiting.
And then literally,
in the blink of an eye,
since we've established
that Tai Lung can appear
like the bogeyman out of nowhere.
And we think Tai Lung waited
until Shifu blinked
in the lightning flash,
to choose to make his appearance there.
We wanted to create
tension in this moment,
This very still, static camera
face off moment.
The electricity in the air
of the building storm
before the storm breaks.
With these two guys, everything
is subtext in this conversation.
Twenty years of... everything, actually.
There's not just a lot of hatred there,
there's also love and regret.
There's a great amount
of depth in this story.
This is when all the pieces come
together, now we get the last flashback.
There's a significant,
emotional turning point
that exists in this sequence.
It used to be much longer
and more significant.
If you notice, if you look closely,
Shifu is defending in the whole
beginning part of the fight.
Defending, defending and
it's not until Tai Lung finds
Shifu's staff,
finds Cogway's staff over at his shrine,
over near the candles,
that Tai Lung realizes
that Oogway is gone.
That it truly is between him and Shifu.
He asks Shifu, "Give me the Scroll,"
basically is the subtext.
This is the first time Shifu goes on
the attack and attacks his son.
Because he's defiled the memory
of Oogway by touching his staff.
And the breaking of the staff
became a significant one,
in the land of Shifu's journey
to becoming Oogway,
and the staff becoming a symbol
of Oogway's wisdom and benignness,
but is now used as a weapon
with Tai Lung trying to kill Shifu.
So it's being used in
this completely negative way.
And we made the choice to make breaking
the staff a somewhat magical event.
There's a life-force inside that staff.
It's the last part of Oogway,
when that staff is broken
and that light is snuffed out
within the staff,
we see the last echo of Oogway,
the petals that are left
around the moon pool blow across,
and that distracts Shifu long enough
for Tai Lung to get in this sucker kick.
Not a sucker punch, but a sucker kick
that pounds him into the wall.
Shifu's running for his life
for the rest of the sequence.
When they breakout through the roof
of the palace,
there was some discussion about
whether we needed to do that.
Maybe that was more fight
than was necessary.
But, Mark and I fought
very hard to keep it in.
We felt it added a legendary
and epic quality to the conflict
between the father and the son,
to have them burst out into the sky
against a crack of lightning.
It was a very important part
of the fight,
to take it outside for
the final drop back into the fire.
And I think it's all about
going more and more epic.
We wanted this to increase...
completely turning up
the volume of this battle.
So that we could, in contrast,
get the funniest battle
to come on the heels of it.
Yeah, they sort of become
Greek gods at that point.
Shifu and Tai Lung fighting in the sky.
And then when Po returns,
like we were mentioning,
the new light coming back in,
and the likeness tonally
to the story comes back,
Po knows the secret, he understands
but he has no idea
how he's going to win this fight.
He just knows he has to save Master
Shifu by distracting Tai Lung.
The one thing Tai Lung wants
is the scroll.
The thing Tai Lung wants more
than anything in the world
is the power he believes
is in that scroll.
Which we all know is nothing.
But, Tai Lung doesn't know that.
What's interesting here
is Po is using the scroll,
he's relying on an artificial...
he's still relying on
an external thing to gain the advantage,
so Po hasn't become enlightened yet.
We save that for later.
He's still relying on Tai Lung's
desire for the scroll
and using that against him. But that
gives us somewhere to go in the fight
so we can have more shape to it.
This conceit for the fight,
with the using of the scroll,
was a little
Muhammad Ali‘Cassius Clay,
Joe Frazier,
the rope-a-dope, where Po's
wearing Tai Lung down,
as Tai Lung renews his efforts
to try and get the scroll.
He's using his weaknesses against him.
- He knows Tai Lung wants the scroll
- Emotionally, he wearing Tai Lung down.
He knows the clincher is going to be
when Tai Lung opens the scroll.
And understands that Po doesn't have
any special magic powers,
he's been bested by a panda.
That's the most humiliating thing.
This Panda is standing up to him.
This whole sequence now is the ultimate
callback to the chopstick fight.
We've seen the game of keep away
and how effective that was.
So Po is using that training
he got from Shifu,
to do the ultimate game
of keep away with Tai Lung.
We spent a lot of time wondering what
the shape of this battle would to be.
We'd had epic fights, the Shifu-Tai Lung
fight, the bridge fight,
and so we were wondering
how big and crazy
does this final fight have to be?
Do we set it in a volcano or
what's the legendary setting that we're
going to have for this final battle?
We realized Po's journey has
taken him from his noodle shop
up to the world of kung fu
in the Jade Palace.
And so what we needed to do
was retrace his steps.
Take him back from the palace,
in fact, the fight ends up at the door
of the noodle restaurant.
So we took it back through all
the places that Po had been,
and re-incorporated ideas
we had seen in the film,
now being repurposed by Po
in a different way.
To use them as an effective battle
against Tai Lung.
Whether it was the fireworks or
the idea of the chopstick battle,
now used with woks.
And we're coming up
on the most dramatic...
Tai Lung has taken out
his aggression on Po,
and is desiring the scroll,
he practically kills Po.
He creates a crater around him.
A circular crater,
circular language again.
Tai Lung gets the scroll.
The most important thing for us is,
this battle could have
gone on for decades,
we joked at one point
this would go on for two years...
- The legendary battle.
- ...across the mountains of China.
And we decided it was more significant
to end the battle here
outside the noodle shop.
Give this moment,
which was a truly heroic moment,
as Po, the noble warrior,
offers the answer to Tai Lung.
If Tai Lung were
to accept that answer...
A shot at redemption if Tai Lung had
listened to Po's wisdom,
he might not get...
into oblivion at the end.
This is also the moment when
the playing field has been leveled.
Now the secret is out,
the scroll is meaningless.
And Po has to stand back up again
and fight without any advantage.
Truly use only himself
and what he has within himself,
to see how this fight's going to work.
It was important for the shape
of the fight to have that change occur,
where Po is now fighting with nothing
but his own skills, his own wits.
Everything he's learned from Shifu,
his body...
A lot of people have said
"Po's overweight."
He's not overweight. Po is exactly
the right weight for a panda.
And that's why he beats Tai Lung.
Po is the peach.
The soft, squishy peach
that Oogway was talking about.
His soft and squidginess,
his bounciness,
his absorbency, all the things we've
seen, where he bounces down stairs,
and can absorb all those things.
His ability to redirect Tai Lung's hard
force back against him,
using a martial art principle,
that allows him to win.
A mixture of some real martial arts
and some very Tex Avery stuff.
His most Tex Avery moment
in the whole movie,
the cookie cut-out hole
that Tai Lung has smashed into.
And what's great is we earned
the ability at this point
to be as silly as that,
as ridiculous as that, all the final
battle stuff we're doing,
because we've been
so grounded throughout.
And we allow ourselves
to get to this point
where Tai Lung can climb out of
that hole and be messed up
and be still on the attack to Po
and Po can get the advantage.
We had a lot of discussion about
what is the final thing
that's going to get...
How do we get rid of the villain?
We knew we had this
big fight Po would win,
but we didn't know how he was going
to win, what he was going to do.
We had a belly blast that
sent Tai Lung through 15 buildings
and he ended up in Po's bedroom.
And he looked up and saw all of
Po's fan stuff all over the walls
and was completely confused.
That didn't seem enough,
we were questing around
for the definitive final thing
that will get rid of our villain?
And we found the answer
was already in the movie.
Derek Dryman's Wuxi finger hold,
which we had implanted as
this formidable, ultimate, who knows
what happens when you drop your pinkie,
in the scene where
Shifu and Po first meet.
It was obvious,
or became obvious,
it wasn't obvious for a while,
it became a thing we discovered.
That we should see what happens
when you drop the pinkie.
And what happens when you drop
the pinkie is a mysterious,
and obviously somewhat magical event.
It harks back to
the circle language of the ripples,
and also to the Oogway energy
that he used in the nerve touches.
It's actually, in some versions of it,
when we were planning it, it ended up
looking like an atomic bomb explosion.
We made the choice that,
since this is probably
a really masterful kung fu technique,
it shouldn't look that destructive.
It should look magical and benign.
So we used golden light
and rings of energy
to hark back to
the water ripples in
Oogway's nerve touch.
Just on a gigantic scale.
We have no idea
what happened to Tai Lung,
it's one of the mysteries of the movie,
whether he's atomized,
or what actually happened to him.
Now we're coming up on my most
favorite part of the whole movie,
and it definitely gets
the best audience response,
this interchange between the dying Shifu
and the returning hero.
It's another cliched moment
that everyone expects.
The master's going to die.
Everyone expects that
we're going to follow suit with what you
would expect with this kind of movie.
And we get a great moment from Dustin
when it's revealed that even
in this moment of enlightenment,
he's the same guy,
he's still the same character,
and a character can only grow so much,
can only have so much insight,
and it's a really touching moment...
...emotionally, because not only
do we feel like he's dying,
but we get this great reversal and
it's such a joy that he's still alive!
We cheat unapologetically.
We told Dustin,
play it like you're dying.
So we make the audience think that.
Every time we've seen the film,
we've heard the audiences go, "Oh."
A little kid behind me said,
"Mommy, is Master Shifu dying?"
The mom said, "Yes he is, honey."
And then, when he was still alive,
there was a huge laugh.
The mom was shaking the kid,
"He's alive!"
He's still the same. So, just to go back
to the first time we saw Po,
he was upside down.
Here at the end of the movie,
he's back upside down.
In a mix of gold for heroism
and green for wisdom.
He has completed his journey,
under his own terms.
And that says "Kung Fu Panda"
behind in the logo there.
The Chinese characters.
The idea here was we wanted
to bring back the 2-D
as a call back to
the dream sequence.
We wanted to give
the characters a curtain call
in this great graphic environment.
Book end the film
with the language we've established
for heroes in Po's mind.
The graphic, 2-D language.
Now Po has earned
his place in that world, too.
Plus, there's a lot of credits
in an animated film.
There's almost ten minutes of credit.
That's a lot real estate in the film,
which has a brief running time
like our film has.
So, we figured if we have
all that time,
we might as well use it to try
and do something fun and artistic.
Anybody who's watching the credits
they should be seeing
something beautiful.
Our 2-D animators, certainly our
3-D animators, on the show
actually got the chance
to do some 2-D animation.
All the shots you see of the characters
are done by a lot of our animators
who worked on the film.
So it was a great way for them
to return to their roots.
Flex that old 2-D muscle
that's been a little bit
underused recently.
But I think everyone
loves traditional animation.
It was great to not only get the movie
in there, but to have
our animators return
to their roots like that.
We also wanted to honor everybody
who worked so hard on this movie.
We wanted white type scrolling
against black for ten minutes.
Which was not interesting to look at.
We wanted to make sure people
were looking at the credits.
Seeing the names of everybody who worked
on the film and made it great.
And actually enjoying doing that.
‘Cause it was beautiful art.
We worked with a great company
called Shine,
who helped to execute
these end credits.
Working with Ramone and Tang, our
production designer and art director.
That combination of those guys
and Shine.
The sense that the story of our world
continues after this movie.
We didn't want to have
the storytelling end.
We have a definitive end to the movie,
but we wanted to give the audience
a little bit more time
with the characters.
And hint at some call backs.
We just wanted people to
enjoy the continuation.
Something Amir Zaki does
in a lot of his films
that we've found inspirational,
that sense that you just drop in
to see a story at a particular moment,
that world was there
before you got there,
and will continue afterwards,
we love that.
We thought it would be
an interesting thing to do
to try and indicate...
Those are these little vignettes, where
Po is still working in the noodle shop,
and his father is playing
mahjong with Shifu and winning.
Or that Tigress is having
a moment with Shifu
so that her story has improved.
Shifu's laughing.
And Tigress is able to have
a bit more sense of humor
than we've seen in the film.
All these little moments indicate
the world has changed
for the better.
It continues the way it always was.
Because that is what is so nice
about Po's story.
Is that he is basically the same guy
that he was in the beginning.
He's a little bit more of that guy.
Because he's allowing himself to take
his internal and make it external.
He is the Dragon Warrior, but
working at his father's restaurant.
serving noodles when
he's not saving the world.
And Shifu is still a little bit on edge.
He's trying to learn
to be like Oogway every day,
but he's still going to snap at Po.
His dad is still going to care
about noodles and love his son.
But everybody is hopefully... their
lives are just a little bit better.
A little bit more relaxed, they know a
little bit more about each other.
And hopefully we feel this world
that we're leaving
is left with everybody
knowing more about themselves.
That makes their lives better.
Po, the thing we want people to feel,
the thing we don't necessarily show
is that the world truly has changed
by Po's example.
Because everyone has seen
this most unlikely character
become a kung fu master.
Now they all hopefully will go back,
whatever they believe or want
for themselves, they can pursue it.
He's enlightened everyone.
Whether you're trying to be a chef
or an artist, whatever it is,
that Po's example
is the most extreme example.
And the most enlightened example.
If you look, there's a shot of Po
showing the children of the village,
these little rabbits,
the blank scroll,
so they can see their reflection.
For a thousand years
that secret has been withheld.
And it's for the world to see.
Po is not going to withhold it,
he's going to let everyone see it,
he let Tai Lung see it.
That was the lesson,
that Oogway had to wait
for somebody like Po
to come along to understand,
that a warrior wouldn't have
necessarily got there.
Po, not being a warrior,
but Po just being himself,
he does understand.
He's allowing everybody to see
their true potential.
And hopefully believe
that they can accomplish
whatever their dream might be.
Let's thank our editorial department.
it's not just post-production.
They truly are editing the movie
from the very beginning
and they are the last ones
to leave the project.
They're like the Marines.
First in, last out.
It's amazing.
There's never a break. We're always
building towards a screening,
some important deadline,
so they're always working around
the clock and on weekends.
I don't know how they do it.
So, to Clare Knight,
and CK Horness,
and Jeremy Shipp,
and everybody in editorial,
thank you.
There's no movie without you guys.
You worked like champs
to make this film happen.
And, of course, the other departments
that we should have mentioned,
that we didn't talk about,
we have Alex Parkinson,
he wore many hats on our show.
He did an amazing job of coordinating
many painstaking aspects of our film,
to make sure that
when we wanted a crowd scene,
we'd be able to have a crowd scene.
We'd have those details
and bits and pieces taken care of.
A lot of what those guys do
is invisible to most people,
because you just accept it
as being right and natural,
but, getting the cloth
to fall over the fur or
to get the crowd
to interact with each other,
and not collide or go through
or any of those things
that would totally break
your belief in the world,
were handled by Alex and his team
completely invisibly.
So you could just enjoy the story.
But they were incredibly difficult.
For the most part,
the clothing system was designed
to follow the characters and allow the
characters to move a lot.
There was so much hand animation
that had to occur
to make all the cloth look perfect.
I love this little moment where Po
has got an action figure of himself.
He's now carved his own action figure.
He's now, he really is
the theme of the movie,
which is: he is his own hero.
He's his own fan boy.
He's got his own model of himself
to prove it.
So, 1 want to talk about the cookie.
We didn't want it to be a joke.
We wanted it to be
an end of the story between
Po and Shifu.
Beautifully animated by Ben Willis.
They're friends and Po's question,
"Do you want to get something to eat?"
Well, yes they do and they're doing it
under the peach tree,
which is returning to life.
Weill see the new peach tree
is starting to sprout.
And we leave our heroes,
looking over the valley
as two friends,
under Oogway's peach tree.
For me, John Stevenson,
one of the directors of Kung Fu Panda.
- And...
- Mark Osborne, the other director,
we say thank you.
- Be your own hero.
- Yes.
And always, always,
look within for the answer.