Here come the balloons.
We chose balloons
because we were thinking
of an airy and lighthearted movie.
I'm Eric Darnell.
And I'm Tom McGrath.
We're the co-directors of this movie.
They say talking about film
is like dancing about architecture,
but we'll do our best.
Comes Marty, the voice of Chris Rock,
doing a Tarzan yell.
We actually found some
original Tarzan yells
and played them for Chris.
Even the original Tarzan yells
were manufactured.
- Nobody could actually do that.
- Not even Johnny Weissmuller.
I think he might have,
but it was all edited.
Chris did his best
and it came out pretty funny.
Very funny.
Ben also does it a little later on,
which is quite a challenge to do.
It's always fun doing slow motion
in computer animation
because it has to be
animated in slow motion.
It's not like we animated at
normal speed and then slow it down.
Here comes the lion.
Ben Stiller, of course,
is the voice of Alex.
And we wake up right
in the heart of New York City.
Kendal Cronkhite and Shannon
did a great job
of kind of simplifying and idealizing
the Central Park Zoo,
which is a great location for us,
because it's smack dab
in the middle of Manhattan
and surrounded by
these wonderful skyscrapers.
If you look closely
at the environment,
it does look like New York City
.
In many ways.
It is stylized and modified somewhat,
but on a more detailed level
midpoint of not having any
parallel lines in New York City,
something we called
the whack factor,
which gave everything
just a bit of a style.
A little askew.
Sort of matched the style
of the design of our characters.
Plus we wanted to have
this opening in the fall.
And the art department
used this great muted palette,
kind of showing the city and
romanticizing it at the same time.
So when we went to Madagascar,
it'd just explode with color.
So it's sort of... we start the film
with this talky sequence
as we introduce these two characters.
And Ben and Chris
just both did a great job,
energizing this dialogue and giving
the animators material to work with
so we could keep it interesting.
Here goes Alex up on the wall.
It is great.
The animators had a great time
just pushing the movement like this
and finding these strong poses,
hitting them and sticking them
and staying on these poses
to kind of really push the attitudes.
Here comes the people.
There's the lion chasing the zebra,
a little joke on the clock.
So we go around the horn here.
We meet everybody,
just trying to set up their routine
and how Alex loves the routine
of performing for the crowds
and he's the most energetic
about the whole idea of being a star.
You see something
very normal and simple,
at least it looks simple, when you
look at that water that Gloria's in.
Every time we have
some organic thing like that,
water, wind, particles of dirt
or sand or whatever,
it's a big task for the effects
department to put that in.
Nothing's for free.
Crowds were very much
a huge challenge
and having all the variations
of people.
Here's our monkeys.
Conrad Vernon...
..actually the voice of
the gingerbread man in the Shrek film
is the voice of our monkey.
Mason, we call him.
Sounds like James Mason...
After James Mason, yeah.
A spit, just that water coming out.
Big task for some effects animators
to pull that off.
And they have to do spits
a lot in this movie.
We have about 50 spit takes,
I believe.
So here's where Hans comes in.
Hans Zimmer, our composer,
gave us some great music.
He found a theme for our characters
that he, you know, was playing here.
And he found a large number
of variations on that theme
that we could use later,
emotionally,
to really kind of hit the friendship
between Alex and Marty.
Masses of people,
huge challenge
for our crowd guys.
So this is really... we tried
to take a point of view
from the people
looking at the animals,
to set up the lives our characters
go through every day.
This is their normal routine.
We wanted to show that.
One of our best actors.
The highly trained Tom McGrath
as the voice of the Skipper.
Just kind of fell into it.
I'd voice it in pitches
and we actually wanted
someone like Robert Stack,
this tough guy
in a little penguin body.
Weill often do the voices
just to fill in
until we can get the actor in
and record them.
And Tom did the voice of the Skipper.
When it came time to cast,
we just figured Tom sounds good.
Let's keep him in there.
So Marty tried his best
to get into the routine,
find something different,
but it didn't quite do it for him.
Beautiful afternoon lighting,
almost magic-hour lighting here.
Nice warm glow
in the afternoon, fall feeling.
Originally, Marty was inspired
to go to the wild
by just his mural alone,
and then we found out
we could use these little guys,
these penguins escaping,
to plant the seed in his head
that there was something else
out there besides the zoo.
And it's just one
of the cases we found
we could use the penguins
throughout the film
to kind of be a little mirror
of wanting to find your roots,
the same thing
Marty's going through.
They go through
their own version of it.
He's explained it,
very clearly now, laid it out.
Chris Rock, very excited.
l always liked that joke.
Marty's got some new ideas
to think about.
So you know, it's interesting.
To think that every time
you see anything on-screen,
somebody had to go in
and figure out how to make it,
get it up onto the screen,
what it should look like,
how it should move,
how it should feel.
With animation of, you know,
in any medium, nothing is for free.
Everything that you see is on-screen.
It's like those fireworks,
those cheering crowds,
are all positioned and designed,
even these little elements
you see on-screen.
Obviously, for just seconds,
whether it's Gloria's fruit bowl
or Melman's medications,
are all designed from scratch
by artists and technicians
and put in place by animators
and given surfaces,
so that they reflect
the light properly.
And then lights are applied to them.
It's a huge undertaking
for just, you know,
every moment,
every second of film,
in a process like this.
It's one of the reasons that we do have
two directors for a movie like this,
or at least why we like
to do it that way,
is because there are just so many
decisions to be made every day,
not just about what
the characters say and do,
but what those bars
look like on that cage
or what the surface
of that tree should be.
Originally, with that monkey,
the teacup build,
originally we had a martini glass.
We decided we needed
to take that out.
- Make it more universal.
- More universal.
- Tea is much more universal.
- It works with his character too,
having a tea and
a teacup and saucer.
But, everything on, including
that whipped cream is a big ordeal
because it has to move with Marty's
mouth and feel like it's connected.
Marty just dropped the bomb
on his friends.
So this is a point in the film,
you know,
this scene, rewritten many times,
and how to best show
Marty's love for the wild
and what his dream is,
and we wanted to have it
in an intimate conversation
from all the noise in the zoo.
The art department put this light
right in the center
and made this little table
so that it felt like
they're just sitting around
a dining room table as friends would,
just to try and get that feeling.
And Marty's kind of pushed aside
as his friends downplay his ideas.
One of the goals of this
is how we portray the city
and we try to tell the movie
through their point of view,
to have them know only the things that
they would see or perhaps hear about.
And so we try to always see
the film unfold from their eyes.
We wanted to keep them very naive
and have, you know,
their knowledge
kind of play into
what is believable
- with animals in a zoo.
- Right.
And yet, from their perspective,
they consider themselves New Yorkers,
which is what this premise
is all about.
Take four New York City zoo animals,
New Yorkers to the core,
and dump them into the wild.
How would they survive?
For a lot of that New York sensibility,
we worked with Peter Mehlman,
who was a producer‘writer
for Seinfeld for many years.
He helped to sort of find
that New York
sensibility and rhythm.
And language too.
Came up with some
great dialogue.
- That helicopter joke.
- The helicopter joke was Peter's.
And of course,
Mark Burton and Billy Frolick,
writing partners on this,
did a wonderful job
laying this story out for us
when we first began.
Really focusing on the story
between a zebra and a lion
that you wouldn't expect to be friends
and they really kind of
honed in on that idea
as kind of the centerpiece
for the story,
this kind of fable about these animals,
this predator‘prey
that should never be friends.
So that's the heart,
and this scene here
is purely to show how close
and what kind of history
these guys share.
You know, originally, this was
a big song and dance number
and it went into a huge fantasy
musical kind of Busby Berkeley thing,
you know, to show Alex's viewpoint
against Marty's viewpoint.
But we felt at this point in the story,
we've already said that
in many other ways,
so it seemed kind of
a redundant kind of idea.
So it just came down to a few bars
of New York, New York.
l always liked this scene
where, classic...
.. apartments, buildings, New Yorkers
yelling at each other to be quiet.
The process for writing
and developing a film like this
is perhaps a little bit different
than a live action film.
We do try to start with a script.
It's flexible.
We can modify and change it
and do by design,
by a process,
continue to develop ideas
as we take them into other parts
of our production process,
which include storyboarding,
where we basically draw out
a comic book version
of every scene of the film.
And the story artists
can put a lot of new ideas
into the process that way,
both on how they stage things.
They may come up with new gags
and lines of dialogue
that help inform the scene.
And it's a very iterative process.
We just do it over and over again,
refining and redoing sequences,
looking at them together
and seeing how they play out,
rewriting scenes,
and that goes on
throughout the production process,
which in this case
was about four years.
Not enough credit
can be given to storyboard artists.
Like this light that he claps on and off
came out of a storyboard artist.
They're writers themselves
and actors
and they really come up
with a lot of the great things you see.
Plus the animators
really add little nuances
and little things that kind of make
the characters even more believable.
It's a great example here.
As Marty looks at his wall,
I think it was Manu
who animated this,
put this little scratch
on his ankle in there
and it just makes you feel like
he's a living thing, you know.
Originally in the first version
of the script,
all the animals
were darted by activists
and shipped away from the zoo,
unbeknownst to our characters,
they had no idea what was happening.
Then as the story evolved,
we found it stronger that Marty
would be so obsessed
with seeing the wild
that he would actually escape,
and cause the others to be worried
and follow after him.
It's a little bit more active
on Marty's part.
Plus we got to bring
the characters out into the city
and see how they interacted
and how much of a fish out of water
they are in their own city.
And they're completely oblivious to it.
We have these three neurotic sort of
New York males in the film
and with our one female lead,
the hippo,
voiced by Jada Pinkett Smith,
we wanted a tough,
strong character,
and you wouldn't think of Jada
necessarily off the bat,
because she's so petite
and nowhere near a hippo.
But when you hear her voice,
it's so commanding and strong
and it's just the thing we needed
to sort of help keep these
three neurotic males in line
and Jada just did a wonderful job
as the voice of the hippo.
We did something different
with the camera here,
give it a handheld feel,
which adds to the frenetic nature
of the sequence.
Something you and Johnson
threw in there
just to add that hectic
kind of nature to it.
Great expressions.
Another gag here added
by a story artist,
just break it off and throw it.
I think that's the only food joke
from Gloria in the whole film.
Which we kind of tried to avoid.
We wanted Gloria
to be big and robust,
but to be a beautiful hippo
and not have to worry about...
make her a character where she's worried
about eating or has a weight problem
because hippos are 800 pounds
and they're proud of it.
A great pose when Gloria
busts out that brick wall.
So we wanted to get the monkeys
to be transferred as well,
so they became part
of this little escape,
with their own agenda,
to go see Tom Wolfe.
Rockefeller Center.
Getting some of these icons in here.
We thought,
what better way to put...
push these characters through
New York better than on a subway?
That's one of the things,
being in the city,
that every New Yorker
is well familiar with
is the subway.
So we just tried to capture that
as best we could, that experience.
When Marty is traveling through the city
he's in wide open space
and these guys are cramped
and claustrophobic
and in smaller spaces,
just to kind of contrast
Marty and his friends.
Melman has these
Kleenex boxes on his feet,
the little tip of the hat
to Howard Hughes.
Classic shot of New York City
landmark, Times Square.
There's a lot of animation
in those signs.
That "What are you going to do,"
is another Peter Mehlman thing.
It always makes me smile.
It's such a little thing
but such a nice touch.
Now, that is actually a model
of Grand Central Station,
a beautiful set that they built
inside the computer,
so you can shoot it from any angle.
And it's one of
those things as before,
a little bit whacked out,
a little whack factor.
It's identical but things have been
simplified and kind of caricatured.
But all to make you feel
like you're actually there.
A little bit over the top with the...
And had some fun with the audio,
sound effects, of some of this stuff.
It was a fine line, you know.
Where do you go, way over the top
and have those kind
of cartoon-y sound effects.
We tried to find
the best balance we could.
But that old lady is great,
and that's, for even little kids,
they just love seeing
a lion get hit with a purse.
And that was fun to be able
to do slapstick.
That was part of our conceit,
to have a lot of
the action and motion
be entertaining as well.
And just like, you know, years
of traditional animation has done.
So we've sort of reached a place now
with computer animation technology
where if you've got
the talented people,
and the time and resources
you can really do just about
anything you can dream up.
There was a reason why
the first computer animated films
were toys and insects,
things with exoskeletons,
because it's really hard to get
that sort of furry fleshy feeling
with computer animation.
Well, it's still hard,
but it's certainly possible today.
So we could really push that
and make these characters organic
and squash them
and stretch them in ways
that we've seen in traditional
hand-drawn animation,
but perhaps not as much
in computer animation.
That's a great joke.
At least I think so.
This is so tremendously difficult to...
A huge number of crowds.
Even they have to keep breathing
and moving even subtly
so they don't just freeze up and...
Here she comes again.
That was Elisa, her name was.
She was one of the loop group
voice people
who just threw a great voice
on that side character.
One of the rare times here where
we go for the human's point of view.
One of the things we discovered
when they transfer animals,
they use very heavy drugs.
It kind of inspired a way
to do our version
of Pink Elephants On Parade,
to have this little
fantasy thing
that only animation can do,
that brings out just
a little something special
and we thought it was very funny
that he would have
this kind of a hallucination.
And twice, by the way.
So this is our
"guilty of exposition" scene,
where we really needed
to find a way
to explain what
the people's motives were
and why they were
transferring these animals,
because they didn't think they were
happy and 'cause they escaped.
We thought it'd be funny to
show it through Alex's point of view.
And then get darted again.
One thing people ask
about the characters,
are they designed
after the actors?
‘Cause they look like them
in some cases, but they're not.
They're designed well in advance
of casting in some cases...
in most cases, in our case here.
But the thing is, when they're
performing behind the mike,
we do videotape them.
And it's something we don't copy,
but we give it to the animators
to inspire them.
They're also inspired
by other performances.
And they add these
little nuances in the faces,
these little facial expressions
the actors give.
So it really makes these characters
look sometimes like the actors.
But that's how that
kind of gets in there.
They find an essence somehow.
So this was one of the first shots
that we animated on the film,
because they're just
essentially on stage.
It gave the animators a chance
to really find a style and a tone
for the way we want to move
these characters around.
Six animators
had worked on this shot,
and the time on the shot is incredible.
It's close to 30 seconds, I believe,
and so it's a very long shot.
Different animators would work
on different characters.
This is one of the...
just a flat graphic moment
we could take, cinematically.
And we thought it'd be interesting
to shoot it all as a single shot
with all these characters
.
coming on-screen,
and a few times in the movie
where we have
this kind of proscenium staging,
to take a break
from the cinematics of it.
Always enjoy watching this and watching
the characters that aren't speaking,
see how the animators have chosen
to keep them alive and thinking.
You always feel like there's
something going on in their heads,
even when they're not speaking.
Pretty amazing for a first shot
and it really set the tone
for some of the nuances in how
these characters move and react.
Here's Tommy.
Originally we didn't have
a lot of the sets built too,
so this was a great choice to flex
the muscles of the characters
and they can build
these crates relatively easy,
so that's why it was one of
the first scenes to be animated.
I've always enjoyed this reveal.
We kept trying to think
of a name for the boat.
We had Lollipop
for "It's A Good Ship Lollipop."
We had SS Act Two.
We put names on the boat
and it just drew your eye
tight to the name instead of the scene.
Those are cans of root beer,
just in case,
if anybody was wondering.
Root beer, not beer.
This was one of the first scenes
that was boarded in the film,
and originally it was a storm at sea
that washed the crates overboard.
But so many films
had been done,
castaways, at the time, you know,
and there was so many storms,
that we decided...
and Gilligan's Island
had been out for quite some time.
So we decided it'd be fun to use
some of these characters,
when the entire zoo
was being transferred,
and have them do
a little jailbreak.
So this was really the scene
for these penguins
and for a while this was
their only moment in the film.
And we kept it in our screenings
and people just liked them,
so we just decided to put them
elsewhere in the film,
and found really good
storytelling places for them.
It's a great addition, the sound
of that breaking coffee cup,
which was designed
by the sound effects folks.
Yeah, those guys, you know,
even with the little foley they did,
moving hay and everything,
add so much to the storytelling,
and a lot to the comedy.
A lot of the sound effects really made
some of these jokes play really well.
It's just like the picture,
the sound,
everything you hear
has to be invented.
‘Cause there is no real place
where you can record penguins
slapping each other like this,
so every sound,
every step on a keyboard,
every handshake or wave
or slide across a deck.
That was a little something Rex Grignon
added there, that penguin sliding.
Also on that map on the wall
behind the penguin when he shrugs,
it said "Madagascar,"
and that was one of the only times
we ever wanted to see
Madagascar originally in the film.
We never even wanted to mention it.
We didn't want anyone to say it,
but we caved in.
- We caved in.
- We did, we caved in,
and, I think, Julien the lemur
introduces it later.
You want to talk about
the genesis of this?
This sequence, my brother's wife,
her father was in the Navy
and they were doing war games,
and he was repainting a deck
and got washed overboard.
And he always described the story
about being caught in these swells
as when he dipped down
50 feet and came up
the boat was just a little further away.
It was so graphic and visual,
we thought maybe
from Alex's point of view
he would go through
the same experience.
And we had Marty in his box
and water was spraying out
of different holes
and he was using all his hooves
to cover it, but it was very funny.
But then it looks like Marty
was dead after it
for a long time, so we decided
to keep it with just Alex.
Well, even this here
is a dramatic moment.
Alex arrives on the beach all alone
and he's scared and worried
about himself and the others.
And yet we still try to find ways
to keep it fun and visual,
as he holds onto his tongue
or as he rolls up onto the beach
and the sand is coming out
of his mouth.
Or this joke here, that he's
heading down towards the horizon.
- Cats hate water.
- Dan Wagner, he animated this,
and was finding ways
to push Alex even farther.
During the making of the film
it was always a challenge.
How far can we push these characters,
and see how far we can
take our animation?
It's easy to be reserved and...
it was great that Jeffrey Katzenberg
was So supportive
of the animation style
we all wanted to do
that he was even a big advocate
of pushing it as far as we can,
see what we could get away with.
Another place here
where the story artist
was given this idea of Alex
coming across Melman
and was asked
to figure out a way
to make it fun
and physical and visual.
And so all of this action here,
pulling on Melman's neck
and grabbing this log,
was all invented
by the story artist
who drew it up
and presented it to us
ona big bulletin board,
like a comic book.
And you figure
if you're laughing at that
when it's a black and white drawing
on a bulletin board,
then chances are
you've got something.
And a car screech sound there
when Alex comes to a stop.
Coconut.
There are great little added sounds
that, you know...
There's only certain moments in these
where we really went over the top.
Like that clown horn.
That's always cracked me up.
We wanted to just keep
the action going
and get all our characters
reunited quickly,
and try to hide the fact
that it's so convenient they're all
showing up at the same time.
But, you know, each little beat,
each little character gets his moment.
We have our pair, back to back
musical jokes here,
with Hawaii Five-O
and now Chariots Of Fire,
and we thought about,
can we really get away with those
just running up against each other?
We decided yes.
We can.
This is our little twist
on the little love affair,
which goes sour.
Again with the slow motion,
even all of those little lips
flapping around,
all hand-animated
to appear like slow motion.
So that line "sugar honey, ice tea"
that Marty says when he turns
and runs the other way,
is something that Chris Rock
came up with.
We have a lot of opportunity
to play around and be inventive
when we get into the studio
to record these actors.
There's a great shot
of our jungle for the first time.
A lot of times we just had exclamations.
"Wow, this is great"
or, you know,
something really ordinary,
and Chris and all the cast
were really great
at finding the language
for their character.
And Chris would come up
with funny exclamations.
Dagnabbit.
He'd say sugar honey ice tea.
And right here.
That's Chris Rock all the way.
But that's part of the process
that's so great,
is we... these actors just aren't
names on the marquee for us.
l mean, there's a reason
why they're famous,
it's because they're so good
at what they do.
And so when we get
into the studio with them,
we let them fly.
If they've got ideas,
you know, we go.
We get it. And often
it just is... it's just gold.
Like Ben running after Marty.
Ben standing behind a microphone.
He's jumping up and down,
acting out of breath.
We say, you're chasing Marty telling him
how many ways you can kill him,
Ben would just put his heart into it,
and it looked...
The performance is great.
It really is convincing...
. that they're running
or moving or getting hit.
This is the first shot
of the jungle interior,
absolutely beautiful images.
The art department created
these environments for us.
The lighters who gave it
this wonderful glow,
not too bright, 'cause
the sun is going down,
but it's just absolutely beautiful.
And again, it's always fun
to have Alex get beat up.
But we needed to detain him
for later.
He had to be out of the loop later on.
Most of the plants
are derived from real plants
you would find in Madagascar,
although they are stylized.
But, at least as important to that
is how they're placed in the jungle.
The art department
looked at a lot of reference,
especially like Balinese gardens.
These are gardens
in very tropical climates,
and they use the plants that
they have in that sort of climate,
and yet create these very
manicured, groomed spaces.
And we use that idea
to give this jungle...
...a sort of structure.
It wasn't supposed to be
a literal version of Madagascar
but kind of stylized,
using plant designs.
But to make it kind of an innocent,
naive version of a jungle,
a kind of childlike view.
To place 900 dancing lemurs
in a jungle
is quite an undertaking for a computer.
This is one of the scenes where we
really wanted to show the wildlife
and one of our editors,
Clare De Chenu,
found this piece of music
called Move It, that would...
And to kind of give these
characters a personality
we thought, like, ravers at a party.
That's how they like to live.
And this Move It song
is from the ‘80s.
And Sacha, who is playing Julien,
heard this music
that was just in the background
and decided he'd like to sing it.
So he went home and practiced it.
Came back in and
he just blew the doors off it.
Plus he danced on videotape,
which the animators referenced.
And really gave the introduction
to the locals a great flavor.
And we introduced the foosa.
Yeah, it was a stroke of genius
to cast Sacha Baron Cohen
as our lemur king.
Leslee Feldman and her crew
suggested him to us.
And we'd actually never
heard of him before,
but then saw the work
he'd done on HBO with Ali G.
- And he could create characters.
- Yeah.
He came in and played around
with some voices,
kind of this Indian,
came up with a French,
kind of Indian accent.
And then after a few sessions
really gave it it's own kind of flavor.
We don't know what it is,
what that accent is.
So this was hard to set up,
a challenge for us to set up.
You know, the locals
and what they're like,
and their enemy,
the foosa,
and kind of their situation.
And to introduce the New Yorkers
to the locals as well.
Mort, he's one of my
favorite characters.
We've been told
he's very popular in Japan.
- Andy Richter.
- Andy Richter as the voice of Mort.
He's so funny.
Cedric The Entertainer
is the voice of Maurice,
sort of the second in command.
He's a kind of lemur called an aye-aye,
this very bizarre exotic creature
that lives in Madagascar
and nowhere else.
Cedric just has this wonderful
warmth to his voice.
You know, when we began,
we thought we might
try to get Malagasy accents
for our characters
that live in Madagascar.
But we soon realized
that the best thing
is to use these beautiful voices
that our actors can bring to the table.
Cedric just has all of this warmth
and this mellow tone to his voice.
It's a great contrast to King Julien,
which is what we wanted,
these two to kind of be a contrast.
And, yeah, we needed that,
someone who had brains
in the organization
who could play against this child king.
The locals,
because of these guys,
were very small characters
in the original version,
and their parts just grew tremendously
because of Cedric and Sacha
adding so much to them.
In some of these scenes
we had a lot of dialogue
between Maurice and Julien
in the bushes that was really funny.
A lot of it was improv.
Some of those things, for time,
you have to lose.
The animators having fun with how...
Sacha used to hold his hands
in all these crimped shapes
when he'd perform,
and the animators tried to
add that to his character.
There was a waterfall
actually behind them
that we didn't have the water
quite ready for yet.
And so we didn't turn on
the water for the shot.
So all the things
weren't quite built yet,
but enough to have
the scene come across.
So we had to plan out
what scenes
were best to animate first
with what sets are finished.
So cute. This is great.
Jada turns on her
motherly charms here.
Originally the joke for Mort was...
..that he was the most
annoyingly cute of all the lemurs.
Remember, you always
thought it was great
that he was 37 years old in reality,
and that's why it was so annoying.
Act your age.
We had a joke,
where they called him
on his age,
and he just giggled.
And we lost that.
Had to cut it for time, I think.
You know, when we started this film,
putting five furry lemurs
on-screen
was the most they could do.
And there you see,
there's a few more than five.
And so that was the challenge
to, you know,
how to get all these characters
on screen at once with all their fur.
Every one of these characters
has millions of hairs on him.
And every one of those hairs,
and its associated data,
has to be pumped
through the computers
to create these images.
So it just becomes monumental,
the amount of information
that has to get calculated,
to create these furry guys.
- This is a...
- Ad-lib.
- It's always challenging in these...
- Yeah "ripping our limbs off."
This is a little bit
that Sacha had done
where to punish Maurice
he calls everyone to prepare
the spanking machine.
They all cheer and...
But before the spanking machine,
they ask them their names
and it's a little funny bit
that we ended up losing,
again, to keep it moving.
So it's always a challenge
with these,
like a nine-foot-tall lion
or a 15-foot giraffe...
...to be in the same scene
with an 18-inch lemur, you know.
Cinematically it's very
challenging sometimes.
It was hard enough just keeping
Melman in the shots with his friends,
much less adding
these little guys to the mix.
That's why it was fun
to have Melman's head
kind of drop into the frame
from time to time.
It sometimes came off
pretty funny.
That's another adlib,
“fuzz bucket," very funny.
Beautiful sunset lighting here.
When we started the film, a lot of it
was going to take place on a beach.
We didn't think about things
like kicking sand and footprints
and the history of footprints
and all these little things
that add so much to the realism of it.
l mean, these guys,
a lot of the artists
just really invented ways to do this
that it really adds so much.
And make you feel
like you're on a beach.
That was an ad-lib from Chris Rock.
He just started singing that song
and he really didn't know the words,
so he starts going...
..and inspired that little acrobatic
gymnastics that Marty does.
This scene actually came
after the crates went overboard,
and, in the film,
with the penguins celebrating.
The characters are overboard,
it's dramatic,
and you cut back and the penguins
are having champagne.
We found a better place
for that little penguin celebration.
It was a great image, I think, with
Melman in his grave, sort of giving up.
His giraffe crate is a headstone.
A little thing about the will
in the sand is that
the art department had researched
a New York State will
and all the legalize
and how it's written
and actually wrote it,
modeled it in the sand.
Yeah, that's a legal,
binding document there.
It's legit.
This little Melman ad-lib here.
David Schwimmer just came up
with that. It's very funny.
It just gives the animators
so much material to work with,
these great performances.
David made Melman
just such a wonderful character.
He's so appealing, you know,
even with his phobias
and weaknesses.
We didn't want him
to be a downer,
- we wanted him to be a lot of fun.
- A loveable hypochondriac,
which he did so well.
When we tested it, they asked kids
who their favorite character was,
and this little boy raised his hand
and said,
"l like Melman, because he's too tall."
He's too tall!
Which is great,
‘cause he is too tall, poor guy.
So the kid was really
empathizing with him.
And this is where we start to go
into the survival montage.
We tried so many
different types of music,
songs that would underlie it.
We were really stuck on it, and then
Hans decided he wanted to take a shot
at just composing something
and it really hits
every beat of this
and the attitudes of the characters.
He really did a great job,
building it to this climactic,
monumental moment
with the Statue Of Liberty.
It was a great idea Tom
came up with,
that they construct their own version
of the Statue of Liberty,
that they could use
the Liberty's torch as a beacon.
Which led into
another storyboard artist's
Planet Of The Apes reference,
which kind of just seemed
to work right into this.
We do have a lot of shameless
film references in Madagascar
and we just think they're funny.
And usually, though, what
we'll try to do is give it a test
that, if it works even if you
don't get the reference,
if it makes sense
to some degree,
within the context, then it's OK.
Yeah, we had him doing
the Tom Hanks bit here,
but we just thought
it was too much Cast Away.
So we kind of took out
the "I make fire" bit.
- Fire is very difficult.
- In computer animation.
This was a monumental task to do
the effects here of this right here.
And breaking apart like this.
We had a lot of extra material
in this sequence.
Some of it was animated, I believe,
between Marty and Alex.
Mireille was great.
We had... this sequence was probably,
you know, felt like 15 minutes.
And Mireille was really good
about saying,
this bit's good, this bit's good,
you could really tighten it up.
It was like pulling teeth, but we're
so glad we did tighten that sequence.
- Thank you, Mireille.
- Mireille Soria, our producer.
We always wanted to have this scene
in the plane, which is good,
and the comments like maybe
the skeleton hand would be too dark.
But we just thought it was funny,
and hopefully it ended up funny.
So we put smiles on the skeleton's
faces so it wouldn't be...
There's one right there.
So it wouldn't be too gruesome.
We wanted it to be like
a little tree house kind of scene.
It's great that the skeleton hand
sort of does the right poses.
There's Teemo
that goes into the ball.
l wish we had used Teemo more.
- It's a tenrec.
- I's an actual animal,
all these animals are,
but Teemo was funny.
He used to have this French accent
and had a bigger role early on,
but it was reduced to
popping into a little ball now.
We had a bigger role for Masacoro,
which is that chameleon
that you see occasionally.
She was a psychic and
she would stick her tongue out
onto people's forehead
and change colors like a mood ring.
And she read their fortunes to them.
Again, Sacha, just going off.
He would go off for minutes.
There'd be one line of dialogue
and he'd go off for ten minutes,
having imaginary conversations
with other lemurs,
and we'd just be in tears,
just laughing.
Sacha, there's certain words he would
say that Julien wouldn't know,
he's not smart enough to know,
so he came up with a language
tailored to someone
who wasn't so bright,
and it added a lot to his character.
That was the second place
we say Madagascar.
And that's about all we wanted
to mention originally.
So wouldn't you know,
this is one of those moments,
Alex and Marty connect,
you know, kind of intimately.
It felt like it was
a good point in the film.
Hans Zimmer brings this
friendship theme back in here.
Yeah, which really helps out
moments like this.
This is a long shot.
The animator took a lot of time.
Some subtle performances.
Another story artist idea
that just kind of adds to the shot,
that help sign falling.
So even though they're in the wild
and Marty, you know...
We wanted to have them
live like, you know,
like New Yorkers
even though they're in the wild.
So we thought it was funny
to have this apartment door scene,
with the chains and everything.
This kind of reuniting moment,
and then just have a free-standing door
it was funny.
Again the sound effects guys
adding extra locks
and so Marty has like
20 locks he undoes,
and that adds a bit to it.
He's using sort of a Tiki lounge
concept as a reference here.
Marty has this sort of
‘60s bachelor pad, I guess.
And then Hans goes,
“] must do that music."
And he really nailed
that genre of bachelor pad.
Here come our spit takes.
So this is one where we had a few
and thought they were funny.
The problem was
we didn't have enough,
so we added more.
In the issue of food,
they're so pampered in a zoo,
we're like, well how can we...?
They wouldn't know what to look for
to find food, you know.
They didn't even know
food grows on trees.
So they're kind of helpless
in this environment
being naive about the wild.
And this is a good way to show
the herbivores
are OK with this stuff,
but Alex needs his steak.
So it was a moment we could put in
where Alex really starts
to get hungry here.
And Alex is hungry for steak.
It was always thought...
It was always a moment
for him to have this dream.
We tried different versions
of these different dreams.
One was based off Jurassic Park
where there are steaks running around
in flocks and herds
on a big savannah. And then...
We had a big dance number,
with all the steaks sort of...
Another Busby Berkeley musical,
and again,
the story artists had come up
with this idea,
based off the movie.
But it was just a real simple
quick way we could convey
and have a little joke about it,
that Alex loves steak.
Rob Koo, one of our board artists,
added him doing a steak angel,
which he then added to that.
We actually added these cutbacks
so that we could extend this moment,
make it very uncomfortable.
It sort of cracks me up
that Marty kind of buys it.
Yeah.
Hey, what do you know?
Just the cadence of Sacha's voice
make me laugh.
Yeah, it's the Greek chorus up there
commenting on Alex.
The locals are desperate.
They need some kind of help.
Just blabbing on.
This was quite challenging
to do this.
It's really funny on paper
when it's a drawing,
all these lemurs pulling into this tree,
but to actually do it is very difficult.
In traditional animation all you
need to do is draw it and paint it.
In the computer world though
you have to build it.
And on that gag and this one
coming up here,
we adjusted the timings on those
over and over again
trying to find the perfect rhythm.
The one time we could say suck.
The gag really is credited,
that little bit, to Bob Saget,
who was actually
in the studio at the time.
We showed him the penguin stuff
and he goes, "At the end
you have them on an icy shelf
just looking at each other
and says, 'Well this sucks."
That was going to be
after the credit roll.
And we found a better place.
Well, yeah. As the penguins
became more a part of the story,
we couldn't end with them in Antarctica
so we could just move that gag up.
One of the underlying themes here
is that these guys are all...
Everybody's looking for a place
that will tell them who they are.
Ultimately they all have to look
inside themselves
to find who they are, and
it doesn't matter where they are.
They don't have to be where
Mother Nature tells them to be
or New York or anything else.
So the penguins again
are a parallel to that idea.
Here Marty finds
the real version of his mural
and thinks that that's all
he needs to be happy.
But Alex is a good enough sport
to go along
after their reconciliation
on the beach.
This was a challenge too.
Alex is hungry now.
How do we get... We wanted Marty
to bring this kind of wild side out.
We thought if we could get him
into that chase kind of situation,
a game of tag, that Alex's instincts
would somehow kick in,
between the hunger and
just the act of chasing his friend.
We didn't necessarily have
that dream sequence
at the beginning of the film
until we were sort of working
on ideas for this sequence.
We found that there's this opportunity
to set up that idea at the beginning,
and then allow this
to sort of resonate
with what we saw
when the film started.
There's a similar shot
to Marty's fantasy.
So now Alex's pupils
have changed.
He's transitioned into something
closer to a wild cat,
something's flowing inside of him
that he's never felt before.
We wanted to have something
for Alex that would show
like when he's a little bit crazed
and more wild,
so his pupils shrank
as his irises grow.
And then there's three wigs also
to kind of show
how he would progress
and get a little wilder.
Here's the next version of his hair,
which isn't quite as
blow-dried as normal.
And his whiskers start to get
little kinks in them as well.
Look how he just throws this lemur.
Animators having fun.
This is a great example of Sacha
coming up with alternate wording.
"In a very good working..."
It was something like,
"My plan is working excellently,"
in the script, and he turned it
into words that Julien would say.
We used to have this long scene
where Alex was sniffing Marty,
with that wild look on his face
and didn't know what smelled so good.
Thought he smelled steak and he...
His nose kept leading him to Marty.
Sort of a variation on the song
that we heard
when Alex was at the zoo,
with kind of a crazy,
marching band feel to it.
And once Julien's character
was, you know,
challenged by another king,
he became kind of bitter about Alex.
And there was a lot more of that,
but then we kind of pulled back
on that, because...
A beautiful waterfall back there
through these scenes
that we had turned off earlier.
So it was how to show Alex
going nuts, and his point of view.
And, you know,
gotta give credit to older cartoons
that would turn someone
into a sucker,
you know,
and cross-dissolve.
Although it would've been great
to see little steaks dissolve.
Kind of visually could show it.
Originally the steaks were realistic,
and looked kind of creepy,
so we had to stylize those a little bit.
So a moment of lucidity there
as his eyes go back to normal briefly.
Yeah, as Tom was saying,
these steaks allow us to do this,
to present this idea comedically.
It could be very dark,
this idea that Alex
wants to eat his friends.
Which isn't something that we all can
necessarily relate to in a way,
so we had to play it kind of light,
that part of it,
but hopefully play that it's a real
emotional heartbreak for these guys,
‘cause they don't think
they can be friends.
Everything's coming out in the open.
There was a scene
that we actually took out.
It was Maurice like a car salesman,
showing all the attributes of a lion.
The teeth, the claws,
built for speed, four-wheel drive.
It was a very funny scene,
but at this point in the film,
you kind of knew what a lion was about,
and so it just kind of
slowed down the sequence.
It was great working
with this layout team
to find really inventive ways
to do the storytelling
and to emphasize certain emotions,
where you put the camera.
And you try and think of it
like a live action film.
You have these miniature sets built
and these performers within that,
and it's all a virtual world, but you do
have cameras and lenses and lights
and there are creative people
working those elements
like you would in a live action film.
So it's a really neat
and challenging process
and there's a lot more to it creatively
than most people imagine, in animation.
There's an entire department that
just constructs all the models for us.
What makes these films interesting
is every film can have its own style,
and we wanted to definitely have
our own style.
Kendall pushed a lot of the design,
you know, so it's very unique.
So in a way we couldn't borrow
a coffee table from the Shrek universe
because it's a different style
of how it's made and graphically.
So, every little thing you see,
every prop, every blade of grass,
everything has been made
from scratch for this movie alone.
We have this Wonderful World song
you've seen in many films,
to contrast what the characters
are going through.
We'd used it for such a long time
we couldn't find anything better
to play with this montage,
which is virtually created
from Rob Koo, I think.
He storyboarded all these characters
kind of walking through
and each one getting picked off
by a different predator later on.
So it was pretty funny.
It just kind of grew from there
and then we added Alex
building his cage,
because he was so afraid
about hurting his friends.
With the foosas
it's very difficult, you know,
‘cause we went back and forth.
Do they talk?
What do they say when they talk?
And for a while they did.
We found that we didn't need them
to communicate so much,
but just to be savage,
and to reflect where Alex
would actually go to,
this non-speaking,
guttural, savage creature.
Little ducky.
We were going to have him say,
"Are you my mommy?" to Marty
before he gets eaten,
but that just went a little too far.
We reveal what Alex was constructing.
The Tsingy,
it's actually in Madagascar.
It's a really unique place
of limestone spires
we thought it would be great
to play out the scene there.
Jada again being the strong female
and she's just great.
l mean, she has this kind of...
When she walks into a room,
her presence is there.
Jada is very petite in reality
but she has this great
presence about her.
Animator had fun again here.
We always try to give them a lot
of freedom to go crazy with this stuff.
It's one of those things
that worked out
with our friends
coming back from Antarctica.
We wanted to have the boat
come back,
so they see their opportunity to leave,
but it was nice to be able to bring
the penguins back at this time.
Every shot just has ocean
in the background.
One of these shots
coming up right here
has 15,000 trees, right here,
with four million blowing leaves
that they created
just for that one shot.
And the effects team was just like,
"We want to do this shot,"
and we're so grateful to them
for pulling it off.
That was a line that Tom
just invented on the fly as a joke.
We never thought
we'd use it at the time,
and then we were listening to takes
and we said, wait a minute,
- we should try and blend this in.
- Can we say that?
Kill them and eat their liver?
We decided we could say it as long
as we were sure he was joking.
The skipper is barking off these orders,
and the scene was animated.
They get the locals to help them.
That's why that skipper line
was still in there.
The hearts and minds of the natives.
But we changed the sequence
and they're no longer part of it.
These signs really helped us.
You know, it's maybe cheap to do that,
but we knew which side of the island
was which, in a way.
It's in our tone still.
Here it kind of borders on creepy
with all these smiling steaks.
l remember the sound guys put in
the sound of goats and little children,
and we were going, wait a second,
this isn't Silence Of The Lambs.
They were really fun to work with,
these guys. Really creative.
Chris and Ben did a great job
with the performances here.
This is a scene though
where we went,
we changed the dialogue
in subtle ways,
and Chris at the time
was doing the Oscars,
and he was really cramped for time.
And I remember we actually...
He let us come to his hotel
and we set up a suite
and recorded this stuff.
And he did a really
brilliant performance.
But there was a technical problem
with the audio,
and we had to animate this scene,
we had to go back in with him
after the Oscars.
The day after, I think.
He said everybody else
was calling to congratulate him.
DreamWorks called to say, hey,
can we get you back in the studio?
How he was great, you know,
and it's hard for the...
They have to recreate
their performances, you know,
and, luckily, our actors were
really patient to the process,
which can be very difficult
and sometimes that happens
where you have to redo stuff.
We see all these
beautiful images on screen
that the art department
helps us realize.
But the other side of that equation
is the work that Philippe Gluckman
and his team do,
to bring these artistic ideas
to the screen in three-dimension.
Managing how all the effects look,
how the surfaces look,
how the light reacts with these objects.
It's a huge task. Philippe and his team
have just done an incredible job,
sometimes recreating
almost exactly
what was conceived
in the artistic development process.
And then taking things
to new levels too,
often in ways
that surprised us sometimes.
We didn't think that maybe
some things were possible.
We'd ask Philippe and he'd scratch his
head and say, "Let me think about it,"
and come back the next day
and say, "Yeah, we can do that."
Beautiful backgrounds here,
dark moody lighting
and the plants blowing gently,
all help contribute to the tone.
And the animation here,
it isn't as broad and whacky
as it is in some other scenes
and has a little more subtleties.
I think the animators did a great job
of just pulling off
these subtle moments.
And we launch into action.
This is another little bit
we had to shorten for time,
but Marty was pleading
to the foosas not to eat him
because he had mad cow disease
and other Chris Rock
kind of standup routine
as these foosa
were encircling him.
But it ended up slowing down
the action a little bit.
Again one of the things we discovered
which was very difficult, whipped cream.
Let that be a lesson to everyone.
Massive undertaking again here.
All these individual foosa
have to be animated by hand.
You can't tell the computer to move
them around. It doesn't look natural.
The Whac-a-Mole gag.
An amazing roar designed
by the sound effects folks.
It was very hard to get a real lion's
roar, we've discovered,
because they don't really roar
for very long.
They do really short little blasts.
So the sound guys
had to create one for us.
You know, one of the things
that made Alex savage visually,
his teeth used to turn sharp.
We had this second set of teeth
for him.
But it really, really looked like Alien.
So we decided not to use
those kind of teeth
and keep him with his normal ones.
Usually teeth don't change anyway.
You know, in the end,
just the sound editing,
what H and those guys did,
it's really amazing technically
how this all works.
With all these guys
screaming on top of each other,
and, you know, they're all
recorded separately
and it takes a large amount
of patience in editing
to string all these vocal
performances together
and make it sound like everyone's
working with each other.
A little funny nunchucks bit
that the animator put in.
Really shows off what we can
do with the characters
and how we can move them
.
In a sequence.
Our character TD's or technical
directors are the ones that set these up
so that they can be sort of
pushed and pulled to such extremes.
Robyn, Alain,
and the others did a great job,
giving the animators
the handles they needed
to do this kind of
over the top animation.
And Rex Grignon was fantastic
as an animation supervisor
who really pushed the animators
and helped set the tone
of the style of animation
we were after.
You can't thank those guys enough.
You never can,
because there's so many.
There's probably 50 animators.
that contributed to this film,
whose work is seamless.
Every animator has his own shot,
and they'd run right next
to each other.
So it's amazing how continuous
it all feels afterwards.
We decided Alex could eat fish,
since fish don't talk in our movie.
- They're not.
- You can eat all the fish you want.
Because a lion really can't...
it's impossible for them to really
live off vegetables and fruit.
Have to have protein some way,
so fish was our
serendipitous solution for that.
Marty actually had
teeth marks on his butt
from where he was bitten.
In the computer it never looked right.
It always looked really gruesome,
with little blood specks
or a little pink thing.
It didn't look right.
The ultimate solution they came up with
was a Band-Aid, which works out great.
The story artists bring a huge
amount of creativity to the table.
They don't just get the script and draw
what's on the page necessarily.
They use that as a guide.
Catherine Rader and Rob Koo
are our two lead story artists
and contributed so much
original material.
Much of what you see on-screen
was actually never
in the original script sometimes.
And Rob and Catherine are very much
filmmakers in their own right
as they take these script pages,
just the written word,
and turn it into cinema,
along with their team of story artists.
And the first performance
is in the drawings as well.
So that's how you visualize this,
and from there everyone else
is inspired by the storyboard drawings.
The crown is so small in Alex's hand.
"Go, Stevie, go!"
He went to town on that so we
put that in, the gecko on his crown.
Yeah, to fit that crown
on Alex's head was...
..and do some funky things
with it, little tricks,
to make him be able to wear it.
You can barely see it,
it's so tiny.
But you know how big Julien is
compared to Alex's head.
We got to this point and realized
we needed to let everybody know
the monkeys were still out there.
They're still OK.
They're back there toasting
with tea and root beer,
until Phil smells his armpit
and is down for the count.
We've heard that we may be
telegraphing a sequel here,
by saying it's out of gas.
We thought it was a really funny joke.
We had the boat sail off into the sunset
at one time, but it seemed very typical.
So this is something
at the end of production,
they're sundries animation,
but a lot of it was just...
A lot of animators
had some time and said,
"What's your favorite character?
You want to make him dance?"
You have seven seconds of dance time,
so these guys really worked extra hard
and did these little great
dance numbers with the characters,
which kind of helps you
through the titles.
The titles on an animated film
can be exhausting
because there's so many people
deserving of credit
and so many people working on it
that's it's an amazing process.
As Eric said, that's why
we have two directors.
We could each work
on separate teams.
But Eric and I could always
get together, and with Mireille
and kind of know
the film we wanted to make.
So it was easy for us to split up
and divide and conquer in that way.
And it sort of worked that way
with producers as well.
Mireille would often be in one location
and the co-producer
Teresa Cheng
would be up at the production facility
in Northern California,
managing the production
and all the folks
and the schedules
that were necessary.
We did it in two locations.
We have a DreamWorks campus
in Glendale, California,
and then one
in Redwood City, California,
about an hour plane ride apart,
and a lot of high end technology
and video conferencing systems
that allowed us to bridge
that gap a little bit.
Often Tom and ! would find ourselves
in different locations,
or Mireille and Teresa would be.
Which was probably
in a total of, like,
a four-year process,
four-and-a-half-year process
of working on this film,
the last third of it
is actually in production
with all the animators.
All these people come aboard
and help create this thing.
So it takes a long time
to do one of these things.
But when you see it all done,
and the work everyone else has done,
it's really fantastic to see.
Every one of these names that
you're seeing is actually someone
who contributed a great deal of time
and creative energy on the film,
so that's a lot of them, yeah.
And any one of them is
a tremendous artist in their own right
who could go out
and do beautiful work
without Tom and myself
telling them what to do.
Our job really is
what the name says,
direct people
all in the same direction,
so that everybody's
telling the same story.
We're caretakers
of the story in that sense,
to make sure all this great creative
work is servicing that main idea.
Ultimately it doesn't matter
how many polygons you have
or how many people are in the crowd
or how beautiful the images are,
if you don't have a story behind it all
that people care about
and the characters that people love
and care about what's
going to happen to them next.
We get to feature some
of the great score work
that Hans Zimmer and his team
did here in these credits too.
It was great to bring
some of that music back in.
This is a great piece.
A lot of it underscores the film,
but it's nice to hear it
just clean like this.
This is when they were
escaping from the zoo.
Hans was trying to do
New York-sounding material.
Looking at Gershwin,
trying to do his own version,
and then finally he said,
"What am I doing?
Anything I do will just be
a cheap imitation of Gershwin.
I'm going to come up with my
own sound for New York City."
When he played this for us,
it just gave us chills.
We thought it was a great piece,
a great way to underscore,
quite literally, what they're doing
when they're escaping
in the streets of Manhattan.
I think there's a montage
of penguins music
.
coming up soon.
That was fun to work with too,
to find that tone that sort of...
These guys have this
black and white mentality,
this sort of '50s sensibility.
And to find music that
kind of helped sell that...
Originally we had crime jazz,
which had a lot of bongos in it,
and so they latched onto that
kind of retro, detective music
and added their own bit to it.
A lot of people.
A lot of people,
doing a lot of things.
Here's some more.
You do these things on computers,
but there's so much support for that,
and these guys don't get,
you know...
They invent ways to do new things
and make it
so the art of computer animation
can just keep expanding.
Much of the software we use
is all written in-house
and maintained by computer artists
and programmers in-house,
which makes it possible
for us to do things
that frankly would be impossible
if we had to depend upon
off-the-shelf software.
So a lot of those names
you see here
are helping us achieve
those sorts of things.
Helping the departments
communicate with one another.
It's all about the pipeline
in something like this.
The last thing you want
is to have teams of people
sitting, waiting
for inventory to work on.
So it's a monumental task
to keep that flowing
and a lot of these people
help with that as well.
Here we come with our final
little goodbye from Gloria.
Well, it's been a lot of fun.
Hope you guys enjoyed it.