Good night, sweetheart.
Good night, Mom.
Sleep tight, kiddo.
Whoa!
Oh! Aye! Oh! Oh!
Simulation terminated.
All right,
Mr. Bile, is it?
Uh... my friends
call me Phlegm.
Uh-huh.
Mr. Bile, can you tell me
what you did wrong?
I fell down?
No, no, before that.
Can anyone tell me
Mr. Bile's big mistake?
Anyone?
Let's take a look
at the tape.
Here we go.
Uh, right...
puh-puh-puh-puh...
Ah! There, see?
The door.
You left it wide open.
And leaving the door open
is the worst mistake
any employee can make
because...?
Um... it could let in a draft?
It could let in
a child!
Oh! Mr. Waternoose!
There is nothing more toxic
or deadly than a human child.
A single touch could kill you!
Leave a door open
and a child could walk
right into this factory!
Right into the monster world!
I won't go in a kid's room!
You can't make me!
You're going in there
because we need this.
Our city is counting on you
to collect
those children's screams.
Without scream,
we have no power.
Yes, it's dangerous work
and that's why I need
you to be at your best.
I need scarers who are
confident, tenacious
tough, intimidating.
I need scarers like... like...
James P. Sullivan.
Hey! Good morning,
Monstropolis.
It's now five after
the hour of 6:00 A.M.
in the big monster city.
Temperature's
a balmy 65 degrees--
which is good news
for you reptiles--
and it looks like
it's going to be a perfect day
to maybe, hey,
just lie in bed, sleep in
or simply... work out that flab
that's hanging over the bed!
Get up, Sulley!
I don't believe I ordered
a wake-up call, Mikey.
Hey! Less talk, more pain,
marshmallow boy!
Feel the burn!
You call yourself a monster?
Scary feet, scary feet,
scary feet!
Oop! The kid's awake!
Okay, scary feet, scary feet,
scary feet, scary feet--
kid's asleep!
Twins! In a bunk bed!
Ooh! I thought I had you there.
Okay, Sulley, here we go.
You ready? Follow it.
Oh! It's over here!
Oh, look over there!
Don't let the kid touch you!
Don't let it touch you!
I don't know,
but it's been said
l love scaring kids in bed!
Come on, fight that plaque!
Fight that plaque!
Scary monsters
don't have plaque!
118... do you have 119?
Do I see 120?
Oh, I don't believe it!
I'm not even
breaking a sweat.
Not you!
Look! The new commercial's on!
The future is bright
at Monsters, Incorporated.
I'm in this one!
We're part of your life.
We power your car.
We warm your home.
We light your city.
I'm Monsters, Incorporated.
Hey, look! Betty!
Carefully matching every child
to their ideal monster...
to produce superior scream
refined into clean,
dependable energy.
Every time you turn something on
Monsters, Incorporated,
is there.
I'm Monsters, Incorporated!
We know the challenge--
the window of innocence
is shrinking.
Human kids are harder to scare.
Of course, M.I. is prepared
for the future
with the top scarers...
the best refineries
and research
into new energy techniques.
Okay, here I come.
We're working for
a better tomorrow... today!
We're Monsters, Incorporated!
We're M.I.--
Monsters, Incorporated.
We scare because we care.
I can't believe it.
Oh, Mike...
I was on TV!
Did you see me? I'm a natural!
Hello.
I know!
Hey, wasn't I great?
Did the whole family see it?
It's your mom.
What can I say?
The camera loves me.
I'm telling you, big daddy
you're going to be seeing this
face on TV a lot more often.
Yeah? Like, on
Monstropolis's Most Wanted?
You've been jealous
of my good looks
since the fourth grade, pal.
Have a good day, sweetie.
You, too, hon.
Whoo!
Okay, Sulley, hop on in.
Nope. Uh-uh. Uh-uh.
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey!
Where you going?
What are you doing?
Mikey, there's a scream
shortage. We're walking.
-Walking?!
-Yep.
No, no, no, my baby.
Come on. Come on.
Look, she needs to be driven.
Bye, baby.
1... I'll call you!
Hey, genius,
you want to know why
I bought the car? Huh?
Not really.
To drive it!
You know, like, on the street?
With the honk-honk
and the vroom-vroom
and no walking involved.
Give it a rest,
will you, butterball?
Come on, you could
use the exercise.
I could use the exercise?!
Look at you.
You have your own climate!
How many tentacles
jump the rope?
Morning, Mike!
Morning, Sulley!
Hey! Morning, kids.
Hey, kids.
How you doing?
Bye, Mike! Bye, Sulley!
Ow! Hey!
Ah, nuts.
Hey, hey, hey! Fellas!
Hey, Tony!
Tony! Ba-da-bing!
-Tony!
-Hey, Tony!
Pow, pow, pow, pow, pow!
I hear somebody's close
to breaking
the all-time scare record.
Ah, just trying
to make sure
there's enough scream
to go around.
Hey! On the house!
-Hey, thanks!
-Grazie!
Ba-da-bing!
Oh, great.
Hey, Ted!
Good morning!
See that, Mikey?
Ted's walking to work.
Big deal.
Guy takes five steps
and he's there.
Monsters, Inc. Please hold.
Morning, Sulley.
Morning, Ricky.
Hey, it's the Sullster!
See you on the scare floor,
buddy!
Hey, Marge.
Hey, how was jury duty?
Morning, Sulley!
Hey!
Hey, it's still leaning
to the left.
It is not!
Hey, fellas.
Hey, Jerry.
Hey, Mr. Sullivan!
Guys, I told you,
call me Sulley.
I don't think so.
We just wanted to wish you
good luck today.
Hey. Hey, hey, hey, hey!
Come on, get lost, you two.
You're making him lose
his focus.
Oh. Sorry.
See you later, fellas.
Go get ‘em, Mr. Sullivan!
Quiet! You'll make him lose
his focus.
Oh, no. Sorry!
Shut up!
Monsters, Inc. Please hold.
Monsters, Inc.
I'll connect you.
Ms. Fearmonger is on vacation.
Would you like her voice mail?
Oh, Schmoopsie-poo.
Googley Bear!
Happy birthday.
Oh, Googley-woogley,
you remembered!
Hey, Sulley-wulley.
Oh, hey, Celia...
weelia.
Happy birthday.
Thanks.
So, uh... are we going
anywhere special tonight?
I just got us
into a little place
called, um... Harryhausen's.
Harryhausen's?!
But it's impossible to
get a reservation there!
Not for Googley Bear.
I will see you
at quitting time
and not a minute later.
Okay, sweetheart.
Think romantical thoughts.
You and me
Me and you
Both of us together!
You know, pal, she's the one.
That's it. She is the one!
I'm happy for you.
Oh, and, uh,
thanks for hooking me up
with those reservations.
Oh, no problem.
They're under the name
Googley Bear.
Oh, good ide...
You know,
that wasn't very funny.
What the...?
Wazowski!
What do you know?
It scares little kids
and little monsters.
I wasn't scared.
Il have... allergies.
Uh-huh. Sure.
Hey, Randall, save it for
the scare floor, will you?
I'm in the zone today,
Sullivan.
Going to be doing
- -
some serious scaring.
Putting up some big numbers.
Wow, Randall.
That's great.
That should make it
even more humiliating
when we break the record first.
Ha, ha!
Shh, shh, shh, shh, shh.
Do you hear that?
It's the winds of change.
“You hear it? You hear
the winds of ch...?"
Oh, what a creep.
One of these days,
lam really...
going to let you
teach that guy a lesson.
Chalooby! Baby!
Good morning, Roz
my succulent
little garden snail.
And who would
we be scaring today?
Wazowski, you didn't file
your paperwork last night.
Oh, that darn paperwork.
Wouldn't it be easier
if it all just blew away?
Don't let it happen again.
Yes, well, I'll, uh...
I'll try to be less careless.
I'm watching you, Wazowski.
Always watching.
Whoo! She's nuts.
Always!
All scare floors are now active.
Assistants, please report
to your stations.
Okay, people, eastern seaboard
coming on-line.
We got scarers coming out!
Ooh, they're
so awesome.
Hey... may the best monster win.
I plan to.
We are on in seven... six...
five... four... three...
two...
You're the boss.
You're the big, hairy boss.
Oh, I'm feeling good today,
Mikey!
Yeah!
Whoa!
Attaboy.
Another door coming right up.
You're still behind,
Randall.
You know, maybe I should realign
the scream intake valve.
Just get me another door!
A door! Yes, door!
Well, Jerry,
what's the damage so far?
We may actually
make our quota today, sir.
Hmm. First time in a month.
Huh?!
What happened?
The kid almost touched me!
She got this close to me!
She wasn't scared of you?
She was only six!
I could've been dead!
I could've died!
Keep it together, man.
Hey! We got a dead door
over here!
-We're coming!
-Coming!
-Look out!
-Out of the way!
-Coming through!
-Excuse us.
We've lost 58 doors
this week, sir.
Oh, kids these days.
They just don't get
scared like they used to.
Let her rip!
Uh, sir?
What?!
Look.
Attention.
We have a new scare leader:
Randall Boggs.
Slumber party.
Whoo!
Never mind.
Hey! Watch it!
Well, James, that was
an impressive display!
Oh, just doing my job,
Mr. Waternoose.
Of course, I did learn
from the best.
If l don't see a new door
at my station in five seconds
I will personally put you
through the shredder!
Hey, Wazowski, nice job!
Those numbers are pretty sweet.
Are they?
You know,
I hadn't even noticed.
And, uh...
how is Georgie doing?
He's doing great!
Il love working
with that big guy.
Keep the doors coming,
Charlie.
I'm on a roll today.
George and I
are like brothers.
2319! We have a 2319!
Red alert! Red alert!
Red alert! Red alert! Red alert!
George Sanderson
please remain motionless.
Prepare for decontamination.
Get it off!
Duck and cover, people!
Oh, not the CDA.
Move! Move! Move!
Coming through, please.
Stand aside.
Clear the contaminated area.
This is a 2319 in progress.
Keep the area clear.
Coming through. Watch yourself.
Stand back.
Careful.
All clear.
Situation is niner-niner-zero.
Ready for decon.
Hey, thanks, guys.
That was a close one.
Okay.
Okay, people, take a break!
We got to shut down
for a half-hour
and reset the system.
An entire scare floor
out of commission.
What else can go wrong?
Oh... what a day.
We're just going through
a rough time, sir.
Everyone knows you're going
to get us through it.
Tell that
to the board of directors.
James, this company
has been in my family
for three generations.
I would do anything
to keep it from going under.
Oh, so would I, sir.
Well...
Say, I could use your help
with something.
Anything, sir.
You see, we've hired
some new scare recruits
and frankly, they're...
they're, um... uh...
Inexperienced?
Oh, they stink!
Uh-huh.
And I thought maybe
you might come by tomorrow
and give them a demonstration.
Show them what it takes
to be a top scarer, huh?
I'll start out with the old
Waternoose jump-and-growl.
Ha! Oh, oh, yes!
Now, that's my boy!
Let's go, everybody!
All doors must be returned!
No exceptions!
-Oh, yeah.
-Whoo!
I've never seen anything
like you today.
You were on a roll, my man.
Another day like this
and that scare record's
in the bag.
That's right, baby!
Uh-huh.
So get this--
as if dinner wasn't enough
I'm taking her to a monster
truck rally afterwards.
Nice.
What's on your agenda?
I'm going to head home
and work out some more.
Again? You know, there's
more to life than scaring.
Whew. Hey, can I
borrow your odorant?
Yeah. I got, uh...
smelly garbage or old dumpster.
You got low tide?
No.
How about wet dog?
Yep. Stink it up.
You know, I am so romantic
sometimes I think
I should just marry myself.
Give me a break, Mike.
What a night of romance
I got ahead of me.
Tonight is about me
and Celia.
Ooh, the love boat
is about to set sail.
‘Cause I got
to tell you, buddy
that face of hers,
it just makes my heart go...
Yikes!
Hello, Wazowski.
Fun-filled evening
planned for tonight?
Well, as a matter of fact...
Then I'm sure you
filed your paperwork
correctly... for once.
Your stunned silence
- -
Is very reassuring.
Oh, no. My scare reports--
I left them on my desk
and if I'm not at the restaurant
in five minutes
they're going to give
our table away!
What am I going to tell...
Schmoopsie-poo?
Hey, Googley Bear.
Want to get going?
Do I ever!
It's just that...
What?
Uh, you know,
there's a small...
I don't understand.
It's just that I forgot
about some paperwork
I was supposed to file.
Mike was reminding me.
Thanks, buddy.
Whoo.
Il was? I mean, I was!
Yeah, I was.
Oh, okay. Let's go then.
We're going!
On my desk, Sulley.
The pink copies
go to Accounting
the fuchsia ones
go to Purchasing
and goldenrod ones
go to Roz.
Huh!
Leave the puce.
Pink copies go to Accounting,
the fuchsia ones go to Roz.
No, the fuchsia ones
go to Purchasing.
The goldenrod ones go to Roz.
Man, I have no idea
what puce is.
Oh, that's puce.
Hmm?
Uh, hello?
Anyone?
There's a door here.
Hmm.
Hello?
Hey.
Psst.
Anybody scaring in here?
Hello?
Yo!
Hmm.
Whoa! Ah! Ah!
Oh!
Here.
Gotcha!
Eh!
Oh!
Yeow!
Eww.
Whew.
Kitty!
No, no-- stay back.
Hmm.
And hold it.
Get a paper bag!
Mmm.
Oh, Michael, I've had
a lot of birthday...
well, not a lot of birthdays
but this is
the best birthday ever.
Hmm.
What are you looking at?
I was just thinking
about the first time
I laid eye on you--
how pretty you looked.
Stop it!
Your hair was
shorter then.
Mm-hmm. I'm thinking
about getting it cut.
No, no, I like
it this length.
l like everything about you.
Just the other day
someone asked me who I thought
the most beautiful monster was
in all of Monstropolis.
You know what I said?
What did you say?
I said...
-Sulley?
No! No, no.
That's not
what I was going to say.
Mike, you're not making sense.
Hi, guys!
What a coincidence,
running into you here!
Uh, I'm just going
to order something to go.
Michael...
Sulley!
I wonder what's good here.
Get out of here.
You're ruining everything.
I went back to get
your paperwork
and there was a door.
What?
A door?!
Randall was in it.
Wait a minute. Randall?
That cheater!
He's trying
to boost his numbers!
There's something else.
What?!
Ook-lay in the ag-bay.
Look in the bag.
What bag?
Oh!
They don't have
anything I like here.
So take care, Celia!
Excuse me, sir.
What's going on?
Celia, please try
to understand.
I have to do something!
Michael?
On three.
One... two....
A kid!
Boo!
There's a kid here--
a human kid!
Oh!
Googley Bear!
Come on!
Let's get out of here!
Please remain calm.
This is not a drill.
We have an 835 in progress.
Please advise.
Michael? Michael?
Oh, Celia.
-Please come with me.
-Ow. Stop pushing.
Hey, get your hands off
my Schmoopsie-poo!
Building clear.
Ready for decontamination.
Well, I don't think that date
could have gone any worse.
If witnesses are to be believed
there has been
a child security breach
for the first time
in monster history.
We can neither confirm nor deny
the presence of a human child
here tonight.
Well, a kid flew right over me
and blasted a car
with its laser vision!
I tried to run from it,
but it picked me up
with its mind powers
and shook me like a doll!
It's true!
I saw the whole thing!
It is my
professional opinion
that now is the time
to... panic!
Oh-oh.
Oh, it's coming!
It's coming!
Boo!
No, no, no, no, no!
Come here, kid.
Whee.
No, don't touch those,
you little...!
Oh, now
those were alphabetized.
It's okay, it's all right.
As long as it doesn't
come hear us
we're going to be okay.
Wanna ride on it!
Da, da-da.
Da-da-da.
Oh, y-you like this?
Fetch!
Hey, hey, that's it!
No one touches little Mikey!
Mike, give her the bear.
Oh, no.
Make it stop, Sulley!
Make it stop!
Look! See the bear?
Ooh, nice bear.
Sulley!
See?
Ooh, bear, ooh.
Oh, he's
a happy bear.
He's not crying,
neither should you
Or we'll be in trouble
‘Cause they're gonna find us
So please stop crying
Right now.
Good, good, Sulley.
Keep it up.
You're doing great.
Ooh, the happy bear,
he has no...
She touched me!
Sulley, the bear!
The bear!
Give her the...
Whoa!
What was that?
I have no idea
but it would be really great
if it didn't do it again.
Shh, shh, shh.
Shh...
Shh.
Ah!
How could I do this?
How could I be so stupid?
This could destroy the company.
The company?
Who cares about the company?!
What about us?
That thing is
a killing machine!
La-la-la-la-la-la
I bet it's just waiting
for us to fall asleep
and then wham!
Oh, we're easy prey,
my friend-- easy prey.
We're sitting targets.
Okay, look, I think
I have a plan here.
Using mainly spoons, we dig
a tunnel under the city
and release it into the wild.
Spoons.
That's it, I'm out of ideas.
We're closed.
Hot air balloon?
Too expensive.
Giant slingshot?
Too conspicuous.
Enormous wooden horse?
Too Greek!
No plan. No plan.
Can't think. Can't think.
Flatlining.
Uh, Mike?
I think she's getting tired.
Well, then
why don't you
find someplace
for it to sleep?
While I think of a plan!
Are you sleepy?
You want to sleep?
Is that what you want?
Huh?
Okay, all right.
I'm making a nice little area
for you to...
No. Hey, hey, that's my bed!
You're going to get
your germs all over it.
Fine.
My chair is
more comfortable anyway.
What?
It's just a closet.
Will you go to sleep?
Hey, that looks like Randall.
Randall's your monster.
You think he's going
to come through the closet
and scare you.
Oh, boy, how do I explain this?
Uh, it's empty.
-See?
-Ah!
No monster in here.
Well, now there is
but I'm not going to scare you.
I'm off-duty.
Okay.
How about I sit here,
until you fall asleep?
Go ahead.
Go to sleep.
Now.
Now... go.
Uh, you...
go...
to...
sleep.
Hey, Mike,
this might sound crazy
but I don't think
that kid's dangerous.
Really? Well, in that case,
let's keep it.
l always wanted a pet
that could kill me!
Now, look.
What if we just put
her back in her door?
What?
Mike, think about it.
If we send her back,
it's like it never happened.
Everything goes back to normal.
Is that a joke?
Tell me you're joking.
Sulley, I'd like to think
that, given the circumstances
I have been extremely
forgiving up to now
but that is a horrible idea!
What are we going to do?
March right out into
public with that thing?
Then I guess we just waltz
right up to the factory, right?
I can't believe we are waltzing
right up to the factory.
Sulley, a mop, a couple of
lights and some chair fabric
are not going
to fool anyone!
Just think about
a few names, will you?
Loch Ness, Bigfoot,
the Abominable Snowman--
they all got one thing
in common, pal-- banishment.
We could be next!
Don't panic--
we can do this.
Hey, how you doing, Frank?
Hey, guys.
Everything's going
to be okay.
Number One wants this place
dusted for prints.
Careful with that.
I got a good view from here.
A little lower.
This was recovered
at the scene.
Don't panic. Don't panic!
Don't tell me not to panic.
Just keep it together.
Everything is not okay!
Boo.
..could be contaminated.
Gentlemen, safety
is our number one concern.
If there's anything that...
not now, not now.
Oh, hello, little one.
Where did you come from?
Mr. Waternoose!
Ah, James!
Is this one yours?
Actually, that's my, uh,
cousin's sister's daughter, sir.
Yeah, it's, uh...
“Bring an Obscure
Relative to Work Day.”
Hmm, must have missed the memo.
Well, listen, James
why don't you stop by
the simulator after lunch today
and give us
that scare demonstration
we talked about, huh?
Oh, oh, sir, uh....
Excuse me,
Mr. Waternoose?
Yes, yes, I'm coming.
All right then, I'll see
you this afternoon, James.
That is, if these gentlemen
haven't shut us down.
Oh, boy.
Oh, a scare demo.
Well, that is great.
Why am!
the last to know?
We can bring your cousin's
sister's daughter along.
She'll be a big hit!
Halt!
Stop him!
Hold him down.
Come on, the coast is clear.
Okay, all we have to do
is get rid of that thing.
So, wait here while
I get its card key.
But she can't stay here.
This is the men's room.
That is the weirdest thing
you have ever said.
It's fine. It's okay.
Look, it loves it here!
It's dancing with joy!
Uh, uh, uh, uh.
I'll be right back
with its door key.
That's a cute little
dance you've got.
It almost looks
like you've got to...
Oh.
Uh, are you done in there?
Ah! Sorry. Sorry.
Okay, you
finished now, right?
Hello?
Boo.
Where did she go?
Oh, did she disappear?
Did she turn invisible?
I just have no idea.
Gotcha!
Boo.
Hey, you're good.
Be relaxed,
be relaxed, be relaxed.
Roz, my tender, oozing blossom
you're looking fabulous today.
Is that a new haircut?
Come on, tell me.
It's a new haircut, isn't it?
That's got to be a new haircut.
New makeup? You've had a lift.
You've had a tuck.
You've had something.
Something has been
inserted in your skin
that makes you look like...
Listen, I need a favor.
Randall was working
late last night
out on the scare floor.
l really need the key
for the door he was using.
Well, isn't that nice?
But guess what?
You didn't turn in
your paperwork last night.
He didn't... I... no paperwork?
This office is now closed.
Ready or not, here I come!
I'm getting warmer.
Any second now.
Fee fi fo...
What are you doing?!
I-I'm looking for the kid.
You lost it?!
No, no, she was just...
Here she is.
Hey, what's the matter?
l already told your buddies
I haven't seen anything.
All right, carry on.
Randall!
Thank goodness!
What are we going to do
about the child?
Shh!
Shh, shh, shh.
The front page!
It's on the front page.
The child--
the one you were after.
Will you be quiet?!
Don't you think I'm aware
of the situation?
I was up all night
trying to find it.
I did a simple
calculation
factoring in the size
of the sushi restaurant.
The child may have escaped!
Yeah, well, until
we know for sure
we're going to act like nothing
happened, understand?
You just get the machine
up and running.
I'll take care of the kid.
And when I find whoever
let it out, they're dead!
Oh!
Why are you still here?
Come on, go!
Move! Now!
Ow, ow! I'm not here.
They're gone.
Eww.
This is bad.
This is so very bad.
What were they talking
about a machine?
Who cares? Oh!
Look, don't panic--
all we have to do
is call her door down
and send her home.
You're right, you're right.
We're just two regular joes
on our way to work.
We will blend right in.
Top of the mornin’, fellas!
Hey, what's shakin’, bacon?
Did you lose weight?
Or a limb?
You have her card key, right?
Of course
I have her card key.
I told you
I'd get her card key.
I went and got her card key
and now I have her card key.
Okay, here we go.
Take care of yourself.
Try not to run
through any more closets.
Mike, that's not her door.
What are you talking about?
Of course it's her door.
It's her door.
No, her door was white
and it had flowers on it.
No. It must have been
dark last night
because this is its door.
Hey, you hear that?
Sounds like
fun in there!
Okay, send me a postcard, kid.
That's Mike Wazowski, care of
22 Mike-Wazowski-
you-got-your-life-back Lane.
Mowki Kowski.
Very good. Now bon voyage!
Bye-bye!
Come on.
Look at the stick.
See the stick?
Go get the stick! Go fetch.
Mike, this isn't Boo's door.
Boo? What's Boo?
That's what I decided
to call her.
Is there a problem?
Sulley, you're not
supposed to name it.
Once you name it, you start
getting attached to it!
Now put that thing
back where it came from,
or so help me...
Oh, hey!
We're rehearsing a scene
for the upcoming company play
called Put That Thing
Back Where It Came From
Or So Help Me.
It's a musical!
Put that thing back where
it came from or so help me
Bom-bom, bom-bom,
bom-bom...
So help me, so help me.
And cut!
We're still working on it.
It's a work in progress
but, hey, we need ushers.
Sulley, I've had enough.
Now say good-bye to...
where'd it go?
What'd you do with it?
Where is she?
I don't believe it.
She got away from you again?!
Well, that is just...
Wait a minute.
The sun is coming up.
This is perfect!
She's gone!
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
Where are you going?
Sulley, please,
don't blow this.
Not when we're so close
to breaking the record.
Somebody else
will find the kid.
It'll be their problem,
not ours!
She's out of our hair!
What are you two doing?
They're rehearsing a play.
She's out of our hair!
Can it, Wazowski!
So, what do you think of that
kid getting out, Sullivan?
Pretty crazy, huh?
Oh, yeah, crazy.
Word on the street is the kid's
been traced back
to this factory.
You haven't seen anything,
have you?
Uh, well, uh...
No, no way!
But if it was an inside job
I'd put my money on Waxford.
Waxford?
Yeah, the one at station six.
You know,
he's got them shifty eyes.
Hey, Waxford!
Sulley!
Michael Wazowski!
Last night was one
of the worst nights
of my entire life, bar none!
I thought
you cared about me.
Honey, please.
Schmoopsie, I thought
you liked sushi.
Sushi? Sushi?!!
You think this is about sushi?!
Wazowski!
Michael! Mike...
Men.
Breathe. Keep breathing.
Whew.
Yikes!
Where's the kid?
Kid? What kid?
It's here in
the factory, isn't it?
You're not pinning this on me.
It never would have gotten out
if you hadn't been
cheating last night!
Cheating?
Cheating. Right.
Okay, I think I know how
to make this all go away.
What happens when the whistle
blows in five minutes?
Uh... I get a time-out?
Everyone goes to lunch!
Which means the scare floor
will be...?
Painted?
Empty! It'll be
empty, you idiot!
You see that clock?
When the big hand
is pointing up
and the little hand
the kid's door
will be in my station.
But when the big hand
points down
the door will be gone.
You have until then
to put the kid back.
Get the picture?
Boo!
No.
Hey, you! Halt!
He's the one.
The one from the commercial!
Affirmative. That's him.
Can we get an autograph?
Oh, oh, sure. No problem.
You can make that out
to Bethany, my daughter.
Yes. Let's see...
“From your scary friend
best wishes..."
So I said,
“If you talk to me
like that again,
we're through!"
What'd she say?
You know my mom.
She sent me to my room.
See you guys later,
take it easy.
Bottoms up!
No!
Whoa!
Hey.
Oh, well, hello, there.
What's your name?
Mike Wazowski!
Sulley!
Oh, Sulley.
Okay, Sulley, come on, enough.
Hey, you guys seen
Sulley anywhere?
Nope. Sorry.
Oh, Sulley!
Boy, Wazowski looks
like he's in trouble.
2319!
We have a 2319!
Oh, dear.
Get him!
Sulley? Sulley!
Sulley!
Oh, great news, pal.
I got us a way out of this mess
but we got to hurry.
Where is it?
Sull, that’s a cube of garbage.
Uh-oh.
I-l can still hear
her little voice.
Mike Wazowski!
Hey, I can hear her, too.
How many kids
you got in there?
Mike Wazowski!
Kitty!
Boo!
Boo, oh,
you're all right!
I was so worried!
Don't you ever run away from me
again, young lady!
Oh, but I'm so glad
you're safe.
My, what an affectionate father.
Actually, she's
my cousin's sister's...
Okay, Sulley.
That's enough. Let's go.
Mike Wazowski!
Yeah, yeah.
Step aside, kid. We're in a...
Will you stop
making Boo laugh?
I didn't, so come on!
I still don't understand.
You've got Boo's door?
I'll explain later.
Run.
Okay, let's move,
let's move, let's move.
Come on.
Oh, please be there, please
be there, please be there.
There it is!
Just like Randall said!
Randall? Wait a minute.
Oh, hey.
One, two, three, four!
Get the kid back
through the door!
Hey, hey.
We're going to get
our lives back.
The nightmare is over.
Hey, it's okay, Boo.
What's the matter?
Come on, it's time to move!
Mike, what are you thinking?
We can't trust Randall.
He's after Boo.
Who cares? Let's go.
This is a limited time offer.
No, no.
I don't like this.
Look, Sulley, you wanted
her door and there it is.
Now, let's move.
No, Mike.
You want me to prove
everything's on the up-and-up?
Fine! He wants the door,
I get the door...
Mike, wait!
He's a paranoid delusional
furball.
Mike!
Shh, shh, shh.
Hey, Sulley,
where you been all day?
Sulley? Sulley?
Huh?
Mike?
Where are you?
You in there?
Where are you, buddy?
Mike?
Hey.
Boo, way to go.
It's okay.
Yes! I got the kid!
Oh, huzzah!
That's great news.
Not that I was concerned,
of course.
Just get over here and help me!
Come on, come on, come on.
While we're young here, Fungus!
Kid needs to take
off a few pounds.
Wazowski?!
Where is it,
you little one-eyed cretin?
Okay, first of all,
it's cree-tin.
If you're going to threaten me,
do it properly.
Second of all, you're nuts
if you think kidnapping me
is going to help you cheat
your way to the top!
You still think this is about
that stupid scare record?
Well... I did, right up
until you chuckled like that
and now I'm thinking
I should just get out of here.
lam about to revolutionize
the scaring industry
and when I do, even
the great James P. Sullivan
is going to be working for me.
Well
somebody's certainly
been a busy bee.
First, l need to know
where the kid is
and you're going to tell me.
Yeah, I don't know anything.
Uh-huh, sure.
I don't.
I mean, I don't.
Oh-oh.
What's that?
Come on. Wait, wait, wait.
Oh-oh. Oh-oh. Oh, come on.
No, no, no, no, no.
Come on, hey, hey, hey.
This thing is moving.
I don't like big...
moving things that are
moving towards me.
No! Come on!
Hey, Randall!
Say hello
to the scream extractor.
Hello.
Come on, where you going?
We'll talk.
Come on, we'll have a latte!
Come on.
We can talk about this.
What's that thing?
What is that thing?
Wait, wait, wait!
Stop, stop!
No, no!
Come on, hey!
Help! Help! Help!
Help!
Oh, for...
What did you
do wrong this time?
I don't know.
I calibrated the drive...
Go check the machine!
There must be something wrong
with the scream intake valve.
That's the problem
with these 3250 units...
Huh?
Hmm.
Psst!
Fungus. Fungus.
You like cars, huh?
‘Cause I got a really nice car.
If you let me go,
I'll give you...
a ride in the car.
Please, Fungus?
I'm sorry, Wazowski,
but Randall said
I'm not allowed to fraternize
with victims of his evil plot.
Hmm...
What happened?
Where's Wazowski?
Where is he?!
Come on!
This is crazy.
He's going to kill us!
Careful. That could be
contaminated.
We got to get out of here now!
We can start a whole new life
somewhere far away.
Good-bye, Monsters, Inc.!
Good-bye, Mr. Waternoose!
No, Mike, wait!
Hey, what are you doing?
Follow me. I have an idea.
No! No, no, no, no,
no, no, no, no...
Simulation terminated.
No, no, no, no, no.
What was that?
You're trying to scare the kid,
not lull it to sleep.
I was going
for a snakesninja approach
with a little hissing.
How many times
do I have to tell you?
It's all about presence!
About how you enter the room!
Mr. Waternoose!
James! Perfect timing.
No, no.
Sir, you don't understand.
Ah, now, show these monsters
how it's done.
What? No, no, I can't...
Sir... sir, you have
to listen to me.
Pay attention, everyone.
You're about to see
the best in the business.
Reset the simulator.
But-but, sir!
Good night, sweetheart.
Night, Mom.
Kitty!
No, Boo, no, no!
Now, give us a big, loud roar.
Mr. Waternoose,
there's no time for this.
Come on. What are you
waiting for? Roar!
But-but-but, sir!
Roar!
Well done.
Well done, James.
Boo?
-All right, gentlemen,
I hope you've learned...
-Right this way, everyone.
..a valuable lesson
in scaring today.
Boo.
Boo?
Boo, it's me.
The child!
Sir, she isn't toxic.
I know it sounds
crazy, but trust me.
Boo?
No, no, no, no.
It's okay.
I was just...
No, no, no, no, no,
don't be scared.
That wasn't real.
It's just a...
I was just...
No...
Boo.
..and he was going
to test it out
on that sweet, little girl.
-Boo.
-Now that we have her...
«he is trying to kill us.
This whole thing
is Randall's fault.
Randall?
Yes. And we can take you to his
secret lab, which is right here
in this factory.
How could this happen?
Oh, how could this happen?
Does anyone else
know about this?
No, sir.
Good.
This company can't afford
any more bad publicity.
Now, before we do
anything else, let's...
take care of the child.
Oh, I never thought things
would come to this...
not in my factory.
I'm sorry you boys
got mixed up in this.
Especially you, James.
But now we can set
everything straight again
for the good of the company.
Uh...
sir, that's not her door.
I know, I know.
It's yours.
No!
Boo!
No! No!
No! No! No! No!
No!
It's too late!
We're banished, genius.
We're in the human world!
Oh, what a great idea, going
to your old pal Waternoose!
Too bad he was in
on the whole thing!
All you had to do was listen
to me-- just once!
But you didn't, did you?
You're still not listening!
Take that!
Welcome to the Himalayas!
“Abominable”!
Can you believe that?
Do I look abominable to you?
Why can't they call me
the Adorable Snowman or...
or the Agreeable Snowman,
for crying out loud?
I'm a nice guy.
Snow cone?
Yuck.
No, no, no.
Don't worry-- it's lemon.
Uh, how about you, big fella?
Snow cone?
Did you see the way she...
looked at me?
Ah, poor guy.
l understand.
It ain't easy being banished.
Take my buddy, Bigfoot.
When he was banished
he fashioned an enormous diaper
out of poison ivy.
Wore it on his head
like a tiara.
Called himself King Itchy.
Ah, it won't be so hard for
you guys, though, you know.
I mean, how lucky
can you get?
Banished with your
best friend.
He is not my friend.
Oh. I just assumed you
were buddies, you know
when I saw you out
there in the snow
hugging and all that.
Look at that big jerk.
Ruined my life, and for what?
A stupid kid!
Because of you, ! am now stuck
in this frozen wasteland!
Wasteland?
I think you mean wonderland!
I mean, how about
all this fabulous snow, huh?
Oh, and wait till you see
the local village.
Cutest thing in the world.
I haven't even mentioned
all the free yak's milk.
What... what did you say?
Yak's milk.
Milking a yak
ain't exactly a picnic.
You know, once you pick
the hairs out
it's very nutritious.
No, no. Something
about a village.
Where? Are there kids in it?
Kids? Sure.
Tough kids, sissy kids,
kids who climb on rocks...
Where is it?!
It's at the bottom
of the mountain.
Around a three-day hike.
Oh, three days?!
We need to get there now!
You want to go to the village?
Okay, rule number one
out here.
Always...
No.
Never go out in a blizzard.
We need to get to Boo.
Boo?!
What about us?
Ever since that kid came in
you've ignored
everything I've said
and now look where we are!
Oh, we were about
to break the record, Sulley.
We would have had it made!
None of that matters now.
None of it matter...
Wa-wait a second.
None of it matters?
Okay.
That's.... no. Good. Great.
So, now the truth comes out,
doesn't it?
Oh, would you look at that?
We're out of snow cones, uh...
Let me... just go outside
and make some more.
Sulley, what about everything
we ever worked for?
Does that matter? Huh?
And what about Celia?
lam never... never
going to see her again.
Doesn't that matter?
What about me?
I'm your pal.
I'm... I'm your best friend.
Don't I matter?
I'm sorry, Mike.
I'm sorry we're stuck out here.
I didn't mean
for this to happen.
But Boo's in trouble.
I think there might
be a way to save her
if we can just
get down to that...
"We"?
Whoa, whoa, whoa. "We"?
No.
There's no "we" this time, pal.
If-if-if you want
to go out there
and freeze to death
you be my guest...
because you're on your own.
Hey, I got more snow cones!
Ohh!
Ahh!
Oh, come on, now, George.
I know you can do this.
I picked out an easy door
for you-- in Nepal.
Nice, quiet Nepal.
You know, you're right.
Here, take this.
Go get 'em, Georgie!
Gangway! Look out!
Coming through!
Sorry, George.
Hey, you can't just...
23...
Out of the way!
-Hey!
-Whoa!
Don't!
Finally!
I never should have
trusted you with this.
Because of you, I had
to banish my top scarer!
With this machine,
we won't need scarers.
Besides, Sullivan got
what he deserved.
Sullivan was twice the scarer
you will ever be!
Kitty!
Sullivan?
Wh-whoa!
Kitty!
Sorry, Boo.
Stop him!
Let's get you home.
Ooh!
Finish him off!
Oh! Ooh! Oh!
You don't know how long
I've wanted to do
that, Sullivan.
Hah!
Ooh!
Mike?!
Look, it's not that I
don't care about the kid.
Mike, you don't understand.
Yes, I do. l was
just mad, that's all.
I needed some time to think.
But you shouldn't
have left me out there.
I'm being attacked!
No, I'm not attacking you.
I'm trying to be honest.
Just hear me out.
You and I are a team.
Nothing is more important
than our friendship.
I-I-l know, kid.
He's too sensitive.
Come on, pal.
If you start crying,
I'm going to cry
and I'll never get through this.
I'm sorry
I wasn't there for you
but lam now.
Ow!
Sulley, lam baring
my soul here.
The least you could do
is pay attention!
Hey, look at that--
it's Randall! It's...
Oh.
Come on!
Get up!
There can't be any witnesses.
There won't be.
I'm glad you came back, Mike.
Somebody's got to take care
of you, you big hairball.
Ow!
Schmoopsie-poo,
Il really can't talk.
Come on!
Michael, if you don't tell me
what's going on right
now, we are through!
You hear me? Through!
Here's the truth.
You know the kid that they're
looking for-- Sulley let her in.
We tried to send her back
but Waternoose
had this secret plot
and now Randall's right behind
us and he's trying to kill us!
You expect me to believe that
pack of lies, Mike Wazowski?!
Mike Wazowski!
l love you, Schmoopsie-poo!
Move it! Look out, you...
Oh!
- idiot!
Look out. Coming through,
here, coming through!
Make way. Move it!
Hurry up, hurry up.
There they are!
Attention, employees:
Randall Boggs
has just broken
the all-time scare record.
Huh?
No, I didn't.
Get out of my way!
Go get 'em, Googley Bear!
There it is!
Get off my tail!
Let me through!
Sulley,
what are you doing?
Grab on, Mike!
Are you out of your...?
Sulley, what are we doing?
We have to get Boo's door
and find a station.
What a plan--
simple, yet insane!
Whoa.
Oh, boy.
Hold on!
Wow!
Don't look down!
I'm gonna be sick.
I'm gonna be sick!
Whoa!
Oh, no!
No!
Aah...
-Boo's door?
-There it is!
How are we supposed
to get to it now?
Oh, it's a dead end, Sulley!
There he is.
Make her laugh.
What, Sulley?!
Just do it!
Oh... ow!
Get it open.
Here he comes.
Give me that kid!
Why couldn't we
get banished here?
Come on. We got to
find another door.
Look, Boo's door!
There he is!
Hurry up, hurry up!
Give me your hand.
Come on, it slides,
it slides!
Ooh, right, right, right.
Jump! I'm behind you!
Come on!
Hurry up! Keep moving!
Get inside!
Ooh! That was weird.
Mike?
Oh, sorry, buddy.
Oh!
l hope that hurt, lizard boy!
Great job, buddy. We lost him.
Boo!
Ha, ha!
No!
Nice working with you!
Get it open!
-I'm trying!
-Open the door!
Come on, get in here!
Boo!
There they are!
Sulley, what are you doing?
Sulley!
Looks like we caught
the express, pal.
Do you see them?
Straight ahead!
No...
Kitty!
Boo!
Look at everybody's
favorite scarer now!
You stupid, pathetic waste!
You've been number one
for too long, Sullivan.
Now your time is up!
And don't worry.
I'll take good care of the kid.
No!
She's not scared
of you anymore.
Looks like you're out of a job.
All right, come on,
over the plate.
Let's see
the ol’ stuff here, pal.
Come on, now, chuck him,
chuck him, baby. Hum, baby.
Hum, baby, here's the pitch.
Wait, please, don't,
don't, don't!
No!
And he is... out of here!
Mama, another gator
got in the house.
Another gator?!
Give me that shovel! Come here!
Get him, Mama! Get that gator!
Care to do the honors, Mikey?
With pleasure.
That's right, Boo.
You did it.
You beat him.
Come on.
Okay, Boo, it's time to go home.
Take care of yourself,
and be a good girl, okay?
Oh, no!
The power's out!
Make her laugh again.
All right, 1 got a move here.
It'll bring down the house.
Up...
Oh, sorry, she didn't see that.
What?! What'd you do,
forget to check
if her stupid hood was up
ya big dope?!
Uncle Mike, try not to yell
in front of her.
You know we still need her
to laugh.
Right.
Hey, Boo, just kidding. Look!
Funny, right? Huh?
See what the...
These are the jokes, kid.
Whoa!
What's happening?
Hold on!
When the door lands
in this station, cut the power.
You'll have the child
and the criminals responsible
for this whole mess.
Great.
A welcoming committee!
What are we going to do?!
This is the CDA.
Come out slowly
with the child in plain sight.
Okay, okay.
You got us.
Here we are.
Here's the kid.
I'm cooperating.
But before you take us away,
I have one thing to say:
Catch!
2319!
We have a toxic projectile!
Halt! After the suspect!
Cover the area!
Bring in reinforcements!
Stop him!
Come on.
Don't let them get away.
What...?!
No, wait, wait!
Come back! He has the child!
Sullivan? Sullivan!
Give me the child!
Me not go!
Give her to me!
Open this door!
Hey!
Sullivan!
Don't do it.
Come on.
Don't go in that room!
I think we stopped him, Boo.
You're safe now.
You be a good girl, okay?
This has gone far enough, James.
She's home now!
Just leave her alone!
I can't do that!
She's seen too much.
You both have.
It doesn't have to be this way.
I have no choice!
Times have changed.
Scaring isn't enough anymore.
But kidnapping children?!
I'll kidnap
a thousand children
before I let this company die
and I'll silence anyone
who gets in my way!
No!
Good night, Mom.
Good night, sweetheart.
What, wh-what is this?!
What? Who? Huh?
Simulation terminated.
Well, I don't know
about the rest of you guys
but I spotted
several big mistakes.
But-but-but how-how did...?
How did...?
You know what?
Let's watch my favorite part
again... shall we?
I'll kidnap a thousand children
before I let this company die.
What...? Wha...?
I'll kidnap
a thousand children before...
Shh, shh, shh, shh!
Shh!
lll get him.
All right, come with us, sir.
Wh-what are you doing?
Take your hands off me!
You can't arrest me!
Il hope you're happy, Sullivan!
You've destroyed this company.
Monsters, Incorporated is dead!
Where will everyone
get their scream now?!
The energy crisis
will only get worse
because of you!
Stay where you are.
Huh?
Number One
wants to talk to you.
Attention!
Hello, boys.
Roz?!
Two and a half years
of undercover work
were almost wasted
when you intercepted
that child, Mr. Sullivan.
Of course, without your help,
I never would have known
that this went all the way up
to Waternoose.
Now...
about the girl...
I just want to send her home.
Very good.
Bring me a door shredder.
What, you mean... you mean,
I can't see her again?
That's the way it has to be.
I'll give you five minutes.
Well, so long, kid.
Mike Wazowski!
Yeah.
Ah, Boo, it's been fun.
Go ahead.
Go grow up.
Uh-uh, B-Boo...?
Um... Boo?
Oh, look at that.
Yeah, you know...
Oh, that's cute, yeah.
Uh, Boo, um...
Well, that's very nice.
Come here, you!
Oh, he's a happy bear...
Nothing's coming
out of your closet
to scare you anymore, right?
Mm...
Yeah.
Good-bye, Boo.
Kitty.
Kitty has to go.
Boo!
Kitty?
None of this
ever happened, gentlemen.
And I don't want to see
any paperwork on this.
Take him away.
I bet we get
the rest of the day off.
You idiot!
They're going to shut down
the factory!
I'm telling you, pal,
when that wall went up
you should have seen the look
on Waternoose's face.
Whoo-hoo! I hope we get
a copy of that tape.
Hey, you all right?
Come on, pal,
cheer up, we did it!
We got Boo home.
Ah, sure, we put the factory
in the toilet, and...
gee, hundreds of people
will be out of work now.
Not to mention the angry mob
that'll come after us
when there's no more power,
but, hey...
at least we had
some laughs, right?
Laughs...
Hey, is this thing on? Hello?
Hello? Testing, testing.
Hey, good evening. How are you?
How are you? Nice to see you.
I tell you, it's good
to be here in... your room.
Where you from?
Never mind.
You're in kindergarten, right?
Oh, I love kindergarten.
Best three years of my life.
Of my life.
But I love sports.
Dodgeball was the best.
Oh, yeah.
I was the fastest one out there.
Course I was the ball.
But I...
was the ball, see?
All right.
Ah...
Ah?
Hey, thanks a lot.
I'll be here all week.
Remember to tip your waitresses.
Great job, Mikey.
You filled your quota on
the first kid of the day.
Not bad, huh?
You know, only somebody
with perfect comedic timing
could produce this much energy
in one shot.
Uh-huh, and the fact
that laughter is
ten times more
powerful than scream
had nothing to do with it.
Oh, Googley Bear.
Come here, you.
Schmoopsie-poo!
Googley.
Whoa!
Girls!
Girls, put...
Stop, stop, stop!
Michael, you're such a charmer.
Hey, did you bring the magazine?
They just delivered a whole box.
Let me see it!
Sulley and !
made the cover, right?
I don't believe it.
Googley Bear...
I'm on the cover of a magazine!
Ow!
Oh, this is great!
Oh.
Hey, Sulley!
Hey, uh, Mike.
I was, uh, just...
Well, listen,
if you got a minute
there's something
I want to show you.
But-but-but...
Okay, close your eyes.
Follow me. Come on.
I-I-I...
No peeking.
Keep coming, keep coming,
keep coming.
Come on, keep coming.
Keep coming, keep coming.
Mike...
Follow the sultry
sound of my voice.
Okay, stop.
Open them.
Ta-da!
Mike...
Is that...?
Sorry it took
so long, pal.
It was a lot of wood
to go through.
You know, it only works
if you have every piece.
Boo?
Kitty!
-Speed.
-Marker.
And... action.
With a million or two
I'd live in a penthouse
In a room with a view
And if l were handsome
No way.
It could happen.
Those dreams do come true
I wouldn't have nothing
if l didn't have you
Wouldn't have nothing if I
didn't have
Wouldn't have nothing
if I didn't have
Wouldn't have nothing...
Okay, cut.
Okay, you finished now, right?
Hello?
Hello.
Come on, get lost, you two.
You're making him lose
his focus.
Oh, sorry.
See you later, fellas.
Go get 'em, Mr. Solomon.
You idiot!
It's Sullivan, not Solomon!
What?
You're messing up the scene!
Sorry.
We're never going to work
in Hollywood again!
Let me do it over.
Shut up!
Keep rolling!
You're making it worse!
Duck and cover, people!
Hey, thanks, guys.
That was a close one.
Ta-da!
Oh, Boo, it's been fun.
Go ahead.
Go throw up.
What? What did I say?
What? What?
Cut.
Hey, Ted!
Good morning!
Cut.
Hey, how was that? Was I scary?
Do I get the part?
Thank you.
Can I do it again?
I can be taller!
Next!
And action!
Okay, let's move.
Let's move, let's move!
Ow!
Can we get a little more wax
on the floor, please?
Wait a minute. Randall?
That cheater!
He's trying
to boost his numbers!
There's something else.
What?!
Look-lay in the bag-bay.
I think you mean
“Ook-lay in the ag-bay.”
What? Didn't I...?
Well, you know, maybe
you should just take a minute
and ead-ray your ipt-scray.
You think he's going
to come through the closet
and scare you.
Oh, boy, how do I explain this?
Uh, it's empty.
See?
Guess who.
Hey, what's the...
Okay, very funny.
Hey, I look good in a suit.
Marker.
Let her rip.
Go.
Whoa!
Shut it off! Shut it off!
Pull the lever!
You're making it worse!
But I must admit it
Big guy,
you always come through
I wouldn't have nothing
if l didn't have you
You and me together
That's how it
always should be
One without the other
don't mean nothing to me
Nothing to me...
Oh, hey!
We're rehearsing a scene
for the upcoming company play
called Put That Thing Back
Where It Came From
Or So Help Me.
It's a musical!
Put that thing back where
it came from, or so help me
Bom-bom, bom-bom,
bom-bom...
Get that thing
away from me, you guys
Put that thing back
where it came from
Or I'll poke myself
in the eye!
It's a work in progress.
It's gonna get better.
Ladies and gentlemen
welcome to this year's
company play
starring, written
and directed by Mike...
and produced!
And produced by Mike Wazowski.
Oh.
Put that thing back where it
came from, or so help me
So help me
So help me get by
Put that thing back
where it came from
Or so help me
So help me
I just gotta cry...
Your seat is right
over there, sir.
Boo!
There's a child,
there's a child
There's a human child
Oh, no!
Running ‘round
the restaurant
This is really wild
What in heaven's name
will become of us
We who are living
in Monstropolis?
All right, Wazowski.
Tell us where the kid is.
I will never talk!
Never!
She's out of our hair
And just when I dare...
to care
She says, "au contraire”
You're my pair... of friends
I love you.
Keep it together, man!
And so we put that kid
back where she came from
And she helped us to find
A better tomorrow today!
Thank you!
What a night for my mother
to be in the audience!
Ladies and gentlemen
my mom!
Thank you, Monstropolis!
I don't have to say it
Ah, say it anyway.
‘Cause we...
Both know it's true
I wouldn't have nothing
if I didn't have
I wouldn't have nothing if I
didn't have
I wouldn't have nothing
if l didn't have you
Wouldn't have nothing
if l didn't have you.
One more time.
It worked!
I don't have to say it
I'm gonna anyway!
‘Cause we both know
it's true
Let's take it home, big guy.
I wouldn't have nothing
if I didn't have
I wouldn't have nothing if I
didn't have
I wouldn't have nothing
if l didn't have you
You, you
A, E, I, ©...
That means you, yeah.