Are you one of the patrol?
Yes
Good.
One of Ritai’ s men?
Yeah.
Fine, then cut him loose.
What are you looking at!
Don’ t stop.
Hold the leg up.
Turn the head a bit.
Give me the knife.
Kekexili,
the last virgin
wilderness of China.
This plain nearly
four miles high,
is the only remaining habitat
of the Tibetan antelope.
In 1985
Poachers began hunting
antelopes for their fine wool
which was prized in
foreign markets.
Within a few years,
the number of antelopes plunged
from one million to
under ten thousand.
To fight the poachers, a volunteer
civilian patrol was formed in 1993.
It was led by Ritai
a retired Tibetan army officer.
The patrol fought fierce
battles with the poachers
and aroused the attention
of the outside world.
In the winter of 1996,
Poachers murdered
one of the patrolmen.
My newspaper quickly
sent me to cover the story.
(Tibetan) Hey Mister.
Take our picture. Good morning.
(Tibetan) Where’ s Ritai?
(Tibetan) Ritai! Ritai!
(Tibetan) He’ s over there!
(Tibetan) Thanks!
Good Morning.
1? m Ritai.
1’ d like to interview you.
Who are you?
What?
Do you have some 1D?
1’ ma reporter from Beijing.
I don’ t have time.
Wait a second!
You want this place to be
declared as a nature preserve area
Maybe I can help.
(Tibetan) Dawa Dawa
Yes
Take him upstairs.
Your bag, follow me.
(Tibetan) Prepare dinner.
(Tibetan) Okay.
You are...
Yangjin
Are you Ritai’ s daughter?
(Tibetan) Yes
What are you reading?
Just some documents.
Oh
(Tibetan) Get some rest.
Where’ s Liu Dong?
Sit.
Here, have some meat.
(Tibetan) You’ re cutting
in the wrong direction.
You understand Tibetan?
(Tibetan)My father’ s a Tibetan.
Tibetan always point
knives toward themselves.
(Tibetan) Samba Cha Cha Cha---
Samba Samba Cha Cha Cha:
Dragon Dragon Cha Cha Cha:--
You cheat, you lost it!
Liu Dong, drink up!
Let me drink it for him.
Liu Dong, let’ s go.
Songji.
What’ s wrong? Where are you going?
(Tibetan)None of your business!
Honey, where are you going?
Liu Dong!
Liu Dong.
Yes.
Give me a hand.
Take your guns.
Ok
We’ re going into
the mountains. Hop in.
(Tibetan) Come back alive!
Take care yourself!
Midnight of November 1st, 1996
Here is a truck.
We have a check point here.
Gan you catch poachers here?
Maybe.
We’ re close to the
antelope breeding grounds.
They often pass by this road.
Where are you coming from?
Wudaoliang construction site.
Where are you going?
Ge’ ermu.
We’ re the mountain patrol .
We’ Il check your cargo,
get out.
Do you have pelts with you?
No.
What are those?
It’ s cotton!
One more time! What is it?
It’ s antelope wool! Move over!
Get off!
What will you do with him?
Let him go.
He’ s just a carrier.
We don’ t have the power
to arrest anybody,
just to confiscate the pelts.
Day 2: Budong springs
conservation station
AWang, he’ s a reporter
from Bei jing.
Hello!
He’ Il make you a big star!
Alright!
Have a seat.
Here are the supplies
for this month.
Great! Put them in the corner.
AWang, hurry up with dinner.
(Tibetan) 0K
My radio is broken.
What’ s the latest news?
(Tibetan) Q@iangba’ s
not with us anymore.
(Tibetan) Chasing
another girl?
He was killed.
You be careful!
(Tibetan song) I Give This
Song to the White Temple...
I Sing This Song for
the White Temple...
I Give This Song to
I Sing This Song for
the White Temple...
I Give This Song
to the White Temple...
I Sing This Song
for the White Temple...
Bless you! Be careful!
See you!
(Tibetan) Bless you!
He has stationed
there all by himself---
Yes, he has been
there for three years.
He keeps the poachers away.
Three years:
We are short of hands.
we have no enough people
Day 3: Zhuonai lake
403 404 405...
Are there all
Tibetan antelopes?
(Tibetan) Bastards
You! Come here!
Where are you from?
Suihua.
What are you
doing here?
Collecting worms.
Seen any poachers?
Yes
How many?
I don’ t know.
What about you?
l saw some.
How many?
Don’ t know.
Don’ t lie to us!
We closed our eyes
when they started shooting.
It was too dark,
we saw nothing.
Do you have a
fishing permit?
No
Fine them.
We bury more than 10, 000
antelopes each year.
Day 5: Yak Valley
No gas.
It’ s them!
They were here not along ago.
Let’ s go.
Day 7 Cumar River
That’ s them! Over there!
Stop! All of you!
Don’ t move! All of you!
Hold it there!
Get down on the ground!
Take off your pants.
Cross the river.
Don’ t move!
Down on the ground!
All of you!
Captain, they don’ t
have pelts or guns!
Down on the ground!
Where’ s his injury?
His leg.
There’ s no hope.
It’ s the artery.
I don’ t want to die!
What’ s your name?
Ma Rui.
Where are you from?
Hua long.
How old are you?
Have you ever
killed any antelopes?
Please help me!
(Tibetan prayer)
Take them across the river.
Hurry! Kneel down!
Ma Zhanlin, do you have
anything to say this time?
Let me have another coat...
1’ m freezing cold.
Where’ s your boss?
We just skin them.
Don’ t lie!
That’ s all I do...
Tell us the truth.
1 don’ t know anything...
re you the gunman?
No!
You’ re the gunman!
No, I’ m not.
Then what do you do?
1? m a driver.
Who’ s the gunman?
I don’ t know
Who knows?
My son is not the gunman!
Who is the gunman?
l really don’ t know.
Who knows?
He knew! He hired us.
Ma Zhanlin , cut the crap!
1’? m just a driver...
You’ re the gunman?
No! I’ m the driver!
Then tell us who
the gunman is?
I don’ t know.
They’ re lying .
l really don’ t know.
They say you’ re in charge.
They’ re lying to
save themselves.
Why are you still
here if you’ re the driver?
The truck broke down,
I couldn’ t fix it.
They can’ t see you now.
Talk!
l really don’ t
know anything.
This is your last chance...
l really can’ t help.
Talk!
I Know nothing...
I just drive the truck...
1 don’ t know. I really don’ t...
Talk to us!
1 don’ t know anything...
Talk!
I Know nothing...
Talk to us!
Let me go
Talk now or
1’ Il shoot you!
1 don’ t know anything...
I Know nothing...
Talk now or I’ II shoot you!
Alright I’ II tell you.
Don’ t kill me.
The pelts are here..
Dig!
They’ re all here.
There are more underneath...
How many do we have?
547, mostly female.
Now it’ s the breeding season.
What a shame.
The gunman got away.
What about the
men you captured?
They were from
small caliber rifles.
The real gunmen
use machine guns.
l ’ ve been chasing
them for years.
Can I have one?
Thanks.
What do you do?
I skin the animals.
How much do they pay you?
Five Yuan for each pelt.
1’? m the fastest
skinner in Ge’ ermu.
All my children
are here too.
He’ s my oldest,
the middle one and the youngest.
They’ re all skinners.
In the past,
I was a shepherd.
l herded sheep,
cattle and camels.
Now the grasslands
have turned into desert.
The sheep and cattle are
all gone dead or sold off.
It’ s tough to survive here.
I need to pee.
Me too.
Alright stop yelling.
Gayu hand me the bucket.
I want to pee.
Take your turn.
The gunman had to
cross this river...
if they’ re heading north.
It’ s crossable.
(Tibetan)1, 2 ,3
Get up and help!
Who wants a drink?
Day 9
Rope.
Everyone gets a half.
I want more!
l haven’ t had anything in days!
We are sharing our food
with you! That’ s all you got!
Thank you.
(Tibetan song) Like
flowing water...
Oh, dear mother...
no matter how far I travel...
I shall return...
Clouds of brilliant white
please deliver my message,
I long for home...
l pray for you
in my heart...
Get inside! Turn around!
Can’ t sleep?
Air is thin up here.
It’ s better outside the car.
Your nose is
bleeding again.
It’? s alright.
It’ s beautiful!
Isn’? t it.
I get homesick every time
I go out on patrol.
Even the lights in the
highway remind me of home.
But when I’ m home
I start thinking of Kekexili.
Do you know what does
Kekexili mean in Tibetan?
It means beautiful
mountains and girls.
Isn’? t it.
In Kekexili,
each step may be the
first human footprint ever,
ever in that spot
since the world began.
Those are not my words.
Two years ago a geologist
came from Bei jing.
I took him to Kekexili
and he said that to me.
Later the geologist
- -
was missing.
No one has seen him since then.
There’ s a lot of
quicksand around here.
(Tibetan) You idiot!
Where are the poachers?
Where are they?
Ma Zhanlin escaped with his sons.
When did you fall asleep?
Around 5 AM.
Captain...
Let go of me!
Hunt them down!
Stop!
Stop! Did you hear me.
Get down! Down!
Watch him!
Get up!
Where’ s the key?
I don’ t have it.
l really don’ t have it.
What’ s this?
What’ s wrong?
Pulmonary edema.
Water?
There isn’ t any.
I can help...
Let him try, he was
a vet in Ge’ ermu.
Hold his arm.
(Tibetan)Liu Dong, you take
Dawa back to see the doctor.
(Tibetan) Ping Cuo,
you should go back too.
(Tibetan) My shoulder
wound isn’ t that bad.
(Tibetan) 1 can help
watch the prisoners.
(Tibetan) Alright.
(Tibetan) We need money
for the doctor.
Give him some money.
It’? s not enough.
Do we have more?
One the fine for the county.
Give it to him.
Still not enough.
Sell the pelts.
1’ m going after the gunman,
you take the route
through Huatugou.
(Tibetan) 0K
(Tibetan) Good Luck.
Good Luck.
(Tibetan) Goodbye.
Goodbye.
(Tibetan) Be safe.
Captain,
we’ re almost out of food.
How many supplies
do we have left?
Two days.
not counting the prisoners.
Fuel’ s nearly gone too.
We should turn back...
No way!
How much fuel left ?
Four days if we
give up the truck.
That should be
enough to catch them.
Step back.
Remove the handcuffs
Ma Zhanlin, every time
I catch you, you pay a fine.
This time I am
letting you go without a fine.
Real ly?
Yes.
I can’ t make it back
from here, I’ m too old.
1 don’ t have food for you,
1? m short of fuel too.
1’ m going after your boss.
Il can’ t take care of you.
I can’ t make it.
Yes, you can.
There are 200 kilometers
to the Al Mountain.
And 100 more to
the Kunlun Pass.
You can make it.
If you can’ t make
it then it’ s your fate.
Good luck.
May God be with you!
Day 10 Bugedaban Peak.
What’ s wrong?
The engine’ s gone.
Out of oil.
Why didn’ t you
check the oil before?
We’ ve been going
non-stop for two days...
Gan you fix it?
Wait here for Liu Dong.
Let’ s go.
(Tibetan) Good luck.
(Tibetan) Good luck!
Gan Liu Dong find them?
If it doesn’ t snow...
Day 12
Day 15
(Tibetan) Doctor. Doctor.
(Tibetan) Get up, Get up.
(Tibetan) This bench is for
patients, Your friend is alright.
What do you want?
1’ m still working.
Where have you
been for so long?
You’ re a mess.
1’ m working. Let go of me.
Aren’ t you cold in
those fishing net.
It’? s my working outfit.
What do you want
from me anyway?
You look like a lunatic.
Are you playing deaf now?
I miss you!
You miss me but you
didn’ t come to see me.
I went patrolling.
I thought you were dead.
I need some money.
You pull this shit
every time I see you!
Lengxue.
Do you think I own a bank?
Did you spend my money
on other women?
1 don’ t know how you can
live that crazy life.
I just want to be with you
1’ m leaving...
You’ II forget me soon.
And find yourself
another girl...
Lengxue. .
Can Ma Zhanlin make
it out alive?
What about your men?
l hope it doesn’ t snow!
What’ s wrong?
They’ I1 never find us.
We’ re going to die here.
Shut up!
Your whole situation
looks pretty desperate.
We’ re short of money,
short of men, short of guns.
My guys haven’ t got
paid for almost a year.
Gan the county help?
We’ re not officially employed.
How do you pay for the patrol?
We have to come up
with the money ourselves.
What do you do with the pelts?
We hand most of them
to the authorities.
Do you sell some to
raise the money?
Selling the pelts is illegal.
How should I write
the article?
l always thought
1’? ma good journalist...
I know you’ re a reporter.
You think Kekexili is
protected by you reporters?
1’ Il go to prison if
I have to.
I know selling
pelts is illegal.
But I can’ t worry
about that now.
Ever seen prostrators
on a pilgrimage?
Their faces and
hands are filthy.
But their hearts are pure.
I sold pelts before,
1 had no choice.
It’ s highway on the other
side of the mountains.
We have to catch them
before they get there.
(Tibetan) Look around
for something to eat.
How much bullets do we have?
A few dozen.
Yixi ,what did you do
before this?
I was a student.
Where?
Qinghai Normal University.
You should be a teacher.
This job is more interesting
Gayu, are you married?
No.
Girlfriend?
We broke up right before
1 came here.
Just like my patrol,
each time they go out their
girlfriends leave them.
There are plenty nice girls
out there.
Isn’ t that right, Yixi?
Right.
What did Bading do before?
A professional rabbits hunter.
Nonsense.
He worked at a
highway checkpoint.
For logging trucks.
They worked all kind of
jobs before joined the team.
Liu Dong was a Taxi driver,
AWang was a soldier,
Songji was a herder.
For you.
Have some!
Up in those mountains,
there’ s nothing to eat .
Day 17
Gan Yixi and Bading
find their way out?
I think so.
Should we wait for them here?
Ma Zhanlin, you’ re still alive.
l am. But many died
on the way out.
My team got separated too.
This is captain Ritai,
This is our boss.
Captain, have a smoke.
1’ ve been chasing you
for years.
Why?
You killed my antelope.
So did a lot of people.
That’ s no excuse.
So what do you want?
You come with me.
Captain,
if you let me off the hook.
1’ Il buy you two cars,
And 1’ II build you
a new house too.
Our boss is kind,
And he’ s rich--s Shut up!
Surrender your guns
and come with me.
Sure! Let’ s give the
Captain our guns.
We’ II join his
mountains patrol ...
Who fired ?
Who fired the gun?
I did.
Fuck you.
You almost hit me.
He’ s still alive.
Are you a patrolmen?
No, he’ s not Ritai’ s guy.
You’ re a dead man if you are!
He’ s not.
Follow our footprints for five
kilometers to find the highway