? This is what you give me
To work with
2 Well, honey
I've seen worse
We're gonna turn
This sow's ear
¢ Into a silk purse
t We'll have you
washed and dried
¢ Primped and polished
till you glow with pride
? Trust my recipe
for instant bride
¢ You'll bring honor to us alf
Wait and see
When we're through
¢ Boys will gladly go to war for you
- J With good fortune
- J And a great hairdo
¢ You'll bring honor to us alf
¢ A girl can bring her family
¢ Great honor in one way
? By striking a good match
¢ And this could be the day
¢ Men want girls with good taste
¢ Who work fast-paced
- J With good breeding
- J And a tiny waist
¢ You'll bring honor to us alf
¢ We all must serve our emperor
¢ Who guards us from the Huns
¢ A man by bearing arms
? Agirl by bearing sons
- J When we're through you can't fail
- J When we're through
- f Like a lotus blossom, soft and pale
- f You can't fail
- J When we're through
- J How could any fellow say no sale
- J Soft and pale, how could any fellow
- f Like a lotus blossom
-f Tous alf
- f You'll bring honor to us all
? Beads of jade
¢ For beauty
¢ You must proudly
¢ Show it
¢ Now add a cricket
¢ Just for luck
¢ Ancestors, hear my plea
¢ Help me not to make a fool of me
¢ And to not uproot my family tree
¢ Keep my father standing talf
? Scarier than the undertaker
< We are meeting our Matchmaker
¢ Destiny
Guard our girls
¢ And our future as it fast unfurls
¢ Please look kindly
On these cultured pearls
¢ Each a perfect porcelain doll
? Please bring honor to us
¢ Please bring honor to us aif I
Look at me
¢ 1 will never pass
? For a perfect bride
? Ora perfect daughter
f Can it be
f i'm not meant
To play this part?
¢ Now I see
¢ That if! were truly
To be myself
tl would break
My family's heart
¢ Who is that girl! see
¢ Staring straight
¢ Back at me?
¢ Why is my reflection
¢ Someone I don't know?
¢ Somehow I cannot hide
¢ Wholam
¢ Though I've tried
¢ When will my reflection show
¢ Wholam
f Inside?
¢ When will my reflection show
¢ Wholam
f Inside? J
? Let's get down to business
! To defeat the Huns
- Did they send me daughters
¢ When I asked for sons
f You're the saddest bunch
lever met
¢ But you can bet
Before we're through
¢ Mister, [lf make a man
? Out of you
? Tranquil as a forest
¢ But on fire within
¢ Once you find your center
¢ You are sure to win
? You're a spineless
Pale, pathetic lot
¢ And you haven't got a clue
¢ Somehow I'll make a man
? Out of you
- J I'm never gonna catch my breath
- J Say good-bye to those who knew me
¢ Boy, was! a fool in school
For cutting gym
- This guy's got ‘em scared to death
- Hope he doesn't see right through me
¢ Now I really wish that
1 knew how to swim
¢ Beaman
You must be swift
. .
as 4 coursing river
¢ Beaman
? With the force of a great typhoon
? With all the strength
of a raging fire
¢ Mysterious as the dark side
f Of the moon
? Time is racing toward us
? Tilf the Huns arrive
Heed my every order
¢ And you might survive
? You're unsuited for the rage of war
¢ So pack up, go home
You're through
¢ How could! make aman
t Out of you?
¢ Beaman
¢ You must be swift as a coursing river
? With all the force of a great typhoon
¢ Beaman
With all the strength
Of a raging fire
¢ Mysterious as the dark side
f Of the moon
¢ Beaman
¢ We must be swift as a coursing river
? With all the force of a great typhoon
¢ Beaman
? With all the strength
Of a raging fire
¢ Mysterious as the dark side
f Of the moon f
? For a long time
We've been marching off to battle
¢ In our thundering herd
We feel a lot like cattle
? Like a pounding beat
Our aching feet
? Aren't easy to ignore
? Hey! Think of instead
A girl worth fighting for
Huh?
That's what I said.
¢ A girl worth fighting for
¢ 1 want her paler than the moon
? With eyes that shine like stars
¢ My girl will marvel at my strength
¢ Adore my battle scars
¢ 1 couldn't care less what she'll wear
Or what she looks like
2 It all depends on what she cooks like
¢ Beef, pork, chicken
? Bet the local girls
Thought you were quite the charmer
? And I'll bet the ladies love
A man in armor
¢ You can guess what
We have missed the most
? Since we went off to war
- ! What do we want?
- J A girl worth fighting for
of My girl will think
! have no faults
¢ That I'm a major find
¢ How ‘bout a girl who's got a brain?
¢ Who always speaks her mind?
¢ My manly ways and turn of phrase
? Are sure to thrill her
? He thinks he's such a lady-killer
S I've a girl back home
Who's unlike any other
¢ Yeah, the only girl
Who'd love him is his mother
¢ But when we come home in victory
? They'll line up at the door
- ! What do we want?
- J A girl worth fighting for
- J Wish that l had
¢ A girl worth fighting...
¢ Beaman
¢ We must be swift as a coursing river
? With all the force
of a great typhoon
¢ Beaman
? With all the strength
of a raging fire
¢ Mysterious as the dark side
f Of the moon f
¢ Whenever you feel your world
Is crashin' down on you
¢ Whenever you don't know
Where to turn or what to do
¢ Don't look too far
? You've got the guide
¢ To find your way
¢ Let your heart decide
? Be true to your heart
You must be true to your heart
- That's when the heavens will part
¢ And show the world
What you believe in
¢ Open your eyes
Your heart can tell you no lies
¢ And when you're true to your heart
¢ Then you've got all you need
To make it through
? Be true
¢ To your heart
¢ Someone you know is on your side
¢ Can set you free
¢ ican do that for you
If you believe in me
¢ Why second guess
J What feels so right
¢ Just trust your heart
¢ And you'll see the light
? Be true to your heart
You must be true to your heart
- That's when the heavens will part
¢ And show the world what you believe in
¢ Open your eyes
Your heart can tell you no lies
¢ And when you're true to your heart
¢ Then you've got all you need
To make it through
- f You know it's true
- J It'lf see you through
- J You've got to be true
- J Baby
¢ To your heart
? Be true to your heart
You must be true to your heart
- That's when the heavens will part
¢ And show the world what you believe in
¢ Open your eyes
Your heart will tell you no lies
¢ And when you're true to your heart
¢ Then you've got all you need
To make it through
¢ You've got to be true
¢ To your heart
¢ Sing the chorus, boys.
¢ When things are gettin’ crazy
¢ And you don't know where to start
¢ Keep on believin', baby
¢ Just be true to your heart
¢ When all the world around you
¢ it seems to fail apart
¢ Keep on believin', baby
¢ Just be true to your heart
¢ You've got to be true
¢ To your heart
? Got to be true
? Be true
True, true, true, true
¢ To your heart f
Look at me
¢ You may think you see who I really am
¢ But you'll never know me
¢ Every day
o It's as if! play a part
¢ Now I see
fifi wear a mask
! can fool the world
¢ But f cannot fool my heart
¢ Who is that girl! see
¢ Staring straight back at me
¢ When will my reflection show
¢ Who I am inside
fiam now
fina world where
! have to hide my heart
¢ And what I believe in
¢ But somehow
¢ 1 will show the world
What's inside my heart
¢ And be loved for who lam
¢ Who is that girl! see
¢ Staring straight back at me
¢ Why is my reflection
¢ Someone I don't know
¢ Must! pretend that I'm
¢ Someone else for aif time
¢ When will my reflection show
¢ Wholam
? Inside, there's a heart
¢ That must be free
i Tofly
¢ Andi burn
t With a need to know
¢ The reason why
¢ Why must we all conceal
¢ What we think
How we fee!
- Must there be a secret me
f I'm forced to hide
1 won't pretend that I'm
¢ Someone else for aif time
¢ When will my reflection show
¢ Who I am inside