We're under attack!
Light the signal!
Now all of China knows you're here.
Perfect.
Your Majesty, the Huns
have crossed our northern border.
Impossible. No one
can get through the Great Wall.
Shan-Yu is leading them.
We'll set up defenses
around the palace.
No. Send your troops
to protect my people.
- Chi Fu.
- Yes, Your Highness?
Deliver conscription notices
throughout the provinces.
Call up reserves and
as many new recruits as possible.
Forgive me, Your Majesty,
but I believe my troops can stop him.
l won't take
any chances, General.
Asingle grain of rice
can tip the scale.
One man may be the difference
between victory and defeat.
"Quiet and demure."
"Graceful. Polite. Delicate."
"Refined. Poised."
"Punctual."
Little Brother!
Little Brother.
There you are.
Who's the smartest doggy
in the world? Come on, smart boy.
Can you help me
with my chores today?
Honorable ancestors...
please help Mulan
impress the Matchmaker today.
Please.
Please help her.
- Father, I brought your...
- Mulan.
l brought a spare. The doctor said
three cups of tea in the morning...
- Mulan.
- And three at night.
Mulan, you should already be in town.
We are counting on you...
To uphold the family honor.
Don't worry, Father.
I won't let you down.
- Wish me luck.
- Hurry!
I'm going to pray some more.
Fa Li, is your daughter here yet?
The Matchmaker
is not a patient woman.
Of all days to be late! I should
have prayed to the ancestors for luck.
How lucky can they be?
They're dead.
Besides, I've got
all the luck we'll need.
This is your chance
to prove yourself.
Grandma, no!
Yep, this cricket's a lucky one!
I'm here.
What? But, Mama, I had to...
None of your excuses.
Now, let's get you cleaned up.
This is what you give me
To work with
Well, honey
I've seen worse
We're gonna turn
This sow's ear
- Into a silk purse
- It's freezing.
It would have been warm
if you were here on time.
We'll have you
washed and dried
Primped and polished
till you glow with pride
Trust my recipe
for instant bride
You'll bring honor
to us all
- Mulan, what's this?
- Notes.
In case I forget something.
Hold this. We'll need
more luck than I thought.
Wait and see
When we're through
Boys will gladly go to war for you
- With good fortune
- And a great hairdo
You'll bring honor to us all
A girl can bring her family
Great honor in one way
By striking a good match
And this could be the day
- Men want girls with good taste
- Calm.
- Obedient.
- Who work fast-paced
- With good breeding
- And a tiny waist
You'll bring honor to us all
We aif must serve our emperor
Who guards us from the Huns
A man by bearing arms
A girl by bearing sons
- When we're through you can't fail
- When we're through
- Like a lotus blossom, soft and pale
- You can't fail
- When we're through
- How could any fellow say no sale
- Soft and pale, how could any fellow
- Like a lotus blossom
- Tous all
- You'll bring honor to us all
There. You're ready.
Not yet. An apple for serenity.
A pendant for balance.
Beads of jade
For beauty
You must proudly
Show it
Now add a cricket
Just for luck
And even you can't blow it
Ancestors, hear my plea
Help me not to make a fool of me
And to not uproot my family tree
Keep my father standing talf
Scarier than the undertaker
We are meeting our Matchmaker
Destiny
Guard our girls
And our future as it fast unfurls
Please look kindly
On these cultured pearls
Each a perfect porcelain doll
Please bring honor to us
Please bring honor to us all
- "Fa Mulan."
- Present!
Speaking without permission.
Who spit in her bean curd?
Too skinny.
Not good for bearing sons.
Recite the final admonition.
Well?
Fulfil your duties
calmly and respectfully.
Reflect before you snack...
Act! This shall bring you
honor and glory.
This way.
Now, pour the tea.
To please your future in-laws,
you must demonstrate
a sense of dignity
and refinement.
You must also be poised.
- Pardon me.
- And silent!
Could I just take that back...
for a moment?
Why, you clumsy...
I think it's going well, don't you?
Put it out! Put it out!
You are a disgrace!
You may look like a bride...
but you will never
bring your family honor!
Look at me
! will never pass
For a perfect bride
Or a perfect daughter
Can it be
I'm not meant
To play this part?
Now I see
That if l were truly
To be myself
! would break
My family's heart
Who is that girl l see
Staring straight
Back at me?
Why is my reflection
Someone I don't know?
Somehow I cannot hide
Wholam
Though I've tried
When will my reflection show
Wholam
Inside
When will my reflection show
Wholam
Inside
My, my.
What beautiful blossoms
we have this year.
But, look, this one's late.
But I'll bet that when it blooms,
it will be
the most beautiful of all.
What is it?
Mulan, stay inside.
Citizens, I bring a proclamation
from the Imperial City.
The Huns have invaded China.
By order of the emperor,
one man from every family
must serve in the Imperial Army.
The Hsiao family.
The Yi family.
I will serve the emperor
in my father's place.
- The Fa family.
- No!
lam ready to serve the emperor.
- Father, you can't go.
- Mulan!
Please, sir, my father
has fought bravely...
Silence! You would do well
to teach your daughter
to hold her tongue
in a man's presence.
Mulan, you dishonor me.
Report tomorrow
to the Wu Zhong camp.
Yes, sir.
The Chu family!
The Wen family!
The Chang family!
You shouldn't have to go! There are
plenty of young men to fight for China.
It is an honor to protect
my country and my family.
So, you'll die for honor.
- [ will die doing what's right.
- But if you...
I know my place!
It is time you learned yours.
- Mulan is gone!
- What?
It can't be.
Mulan!
No.
You must go after her.
She could be killed.
If l reveal her...
she will be.
Ancestors, hear our prayer.
Watch over Mulan.
Mushu, awaken.
I live!
So tell me what mortal needs
my protection, Great Ancestor.
You just say the word and I'm there.
Anybody foolish enough
to threaten our family,
vengeance will be mine!
Mushu!
These are the family guardians.
- They...
- Protect the family.
And you, O Demoted One?
I... ring the gong.
That's right.
Now, wake up the ancestors.
One family reunion comin’ right up.
Okay, people, look alive.
Come on. Get up.
Let's move it. Rise and shine. Y'all way
past the beauty sleep thing, trust me.
I knew it. I knew it. That Mulan
was a troublemaker from the start!
Don't look at me. She gets it
from your side of the family.
- She's just trying to help her father.
- But if she's discovered,
dishonor will come to the family.
- Traditional values will disintegrate.
- They'll lose the farm.
My children never caused trouble.
They became acupuncturists.
- Well, we can't all be acupuncturists.
- No!
Your great-granddaughter
had to be a cross-dresser!
- Let a guardian bring her back.
- Yes, awaken the most cunning.
No. The swiftest.
- No. Send the wisest.
- Silence!
We must send
the most powerful of all.
OK, OK, I get the drift. I'll go.
Y'all don't think I can do it.
Watch this here.
Jump back.
I'm pretty hot, huh?
Don't make me have to singe
nobody to prove it.
You had your chance
to protect the Fa family.
Your misguidance led
Fa Deng to disaster.
- Yeah, thanks a lot.
- And your point is?
The point is, we will be sending
a real dragon to retrieve Mulan.
What? I'm a real dragon!
You are not worthy of this spot.
Now, awaken the Great Stone Dragon.
So you'll get back to me
on the job thing?
Just one chance,
is that too much to ask?
I mean, it's not like it'd kill ya.
Yo, Rocky, wake up!
Ya gotta go fetch Mulan!
Come on, boy!
Go get her! Go on!
Come on.
Hello?
Stony? Man, they're gonna kill me.
Great Stone Dragon,
have you awakened?
Yes, I just woke up.
I'm the Great Stone Dragon.
Good morning.
I will go forth
and fetch Mulan.
Did I mention that
Il was the Great Stone Dragon?
Go! The fate of the Fa family
rests in your claws.
Don't even worry about it.
I will not lose face.
My elbow.
I know I twisted something.
That's just great.
Now what? I'm doomed!
And all 'cause Miss Man decides to take
her little drag show on the road.
Go get her?
What's the matter with you?
After this Great Stone mess,
I'd have to bring her home
with a medal to get back in the temple.
Wait a minute. That's it!
l make Mulan a war hero
and they'll beg me
to come back.
That's the master plan.
You done it now, man.
Hey, what makes you
think you're comin'?
You're lucky?
Do I look like a sucker to you?
What you mean, a loser?
What about if 1 pop
one of your antennas off,
then who's the loser,
me or you?
Imperial scouts.
Shan-Yu.
Nice work, gentlemen.
You found the Hun Army.
The emperor will stop you.
Stop me? He invited me.
By building his wall,
he challenged my strength.
Well, I'm here to play his game.
Go! Tell your emperor
to send his strongest armies.
I'm ready.
How many men does it take
to deliver a message?
One.
OK, how about this?
Excuse me.
Where do I sign in?
Il see you have a sword.
l have one too.
They're very manly and tough.
I'm working on it!
Who am I fooling?
It's going to take a miracle
to get me into the army.
Did I hear someone ask
for a miracle?
Let me hear you say "ah"!
- That's close enough.
- A ghost.
Get ready, Mulan.
Your serpentine salvation is at hand!
For I have been sent
by your ancestors
to guide you through
your masquerade.
If you're gonna stay, you work.
So heed my word, 'cause if the army
finds out you're a girl,
the penalty is death!
- Who are you?
- Who am I?
lam the guardian of lost souls.
lam the powerful,
the pleasurable,
the indestructible Mushu.
Pretty hot, huh?
My ancestors sent
a little lizard to help me?
Hey, dragon. Dragon, not lizard.
I don't do that tongue thing.
- You're...
- Intimidating?
- Awe-inspiring?
- Tiny.
I'm travel-size for your convenience.
If l was my real size,
your cow here would die of fright.
Down, Bessie. My powers are beyond
your mortal imagination.
For instance, my eyes can see
straight through your armor.
That's it! Dishonor!
Dishonor on your whole family.
Make a note of this. Dishonor on you,
dishonor on your cow...
Stop. I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
I'm just nervous.
I've never done this before.
Then you're gonna have to trust me.
And don't slap me no more.
We clear on that?
All right.
Let's get this show on the road!
Cri-Kee, get the bags.
Let's move it, heifer.
OK, this is it.
Time to show 'em your man walk.
Shoulders back, chest high,
feet apart, head up and strut.
Two, three... Break it down.
Hup, two, three. And work it!
- Beautiful, isn't he?
- They're disgusting.
No, they're men. Now, you have to act
just like them, so pay attention.
Look. This tattoo
will protect me from harm.
l hope you can
get your money back.
I don't think I can do this.
It's all attitude.
Be tough, like this guy here.
- What are you lookin’ at?
- Punch him. It's how men say hello.
Yao, you've made a friend.
Good. Now slap him
on the behind. They like that.
I'm gonna hit you so hard,
itll make your ancestors dizzy.
Yao, relax and chant with me.
- Feel better?
- Yeah.
You ain't worth my time, chicken boy.
Chicken boy? Say that
to my face, ya limp noodle!
Sorry, Ling.
Hey!
Whoa! You're dead!
There he goes!
Hey, guys.
The Huns have struck here,
here and here.
I'll take the main troops
up to the Tung Shao Pass...
and stop Shan-Yu
before he destroys this village.
Excellent strategy, sir.
I do love surprises.
You will stay and train
the new recruits.
When Chi Fu believes
you're ready,
you will join us, Captain.
Captain?
This is an enormous
responsibility, General.
Perhaps a soldier
with more experience...
Number one in his class, extensive
knowledge of training techniques,
an impressive military lineage.
I believe Li Shang
will do an excellent job.
I will. won't let you down.
This is... l mean...
- Yes, sir.
- Very good, then.
We'll toast China's victory
at the Imperial City.
I'll expect a full report
in three weeks.
And I won't leave anything out.
Captain Li Shang.
Leader of China's finest troops.
No. The greatest troops
of all time.
Most impressive.
Good luck, Captain.
Good luck, Father.
Day one.
Soldiers!
He started it!
don't need anyone
causing trouble in my camp.
Sorry.
l mean, sorry you had to see that,
but you know how it is,
when you get those manly urges
and you just gotta kill somethin’,
fix things, cook outdoors...
- What's your name?
el.
Your commanding officer
just asked you a question.
I've got a name.
And it's a boy's name too.
- Ling. How ‘bout Ling?
- His name is Ling.
I didn't ask for his name.
l asked for yours!
- Try... ah, Chu.
- Ah Chu.
- Ah Chu?
- Gesundheit. I kill myself.
- Mushu.
- Mushu?
- No.
- Then what is it?
- Ping was my best friend growin' up.
- It's Ping.
- Ping?
- Of course, Ping did steal my...
Yes, my name is Ping.
Let me see your conscription notice.
- Fa Zhou? The Fa Zhou?
- [didn't know Fa Zhou had a son.
He doesn't talk about me much.
Il can see why.
The boy's an absolute lunatic.
OK, gentlemen,
thanks to your new friend, Ping,
you'll spend tonight picking up
every single grain of rice.
And tomorrow,
the real work begins.
You know, we have to work
on your people skills.
All right! Rise and shine,
Sleeping Beauty. Come on.
Get your clothes on. Get ready.
Got breakfast for ya.
Look, you get porridge,
and it's happy to see you.
Get outta there!
You gonna make people sick.
- Am [ late?
- No time to talk.
It's your first day,
so listen to your teacher,
play nice with the kids
unless they wanna fight,
then kick the other kid's butt.
But I don't wanna kick butt.
Don't talk with your mouth full.
Now let's see your war face.
I think my bunny slippers
just ran for cover.
Come on! Scare me, girl.
That's my tough warrior.
That's what I'm talkin’ about.
Now, get out there
and make me proud.
- What do you mean, the troops left?
- They what?
Wait!
You forgot your sword.
My little baby,
off to destroy people.
Order. People, order.
- I'd like a pan-fried noodle.
- Sweet and pungent shrimp.
- Moo goo gai pan.
- That's not funny.
Looks like our new friend
slept in this morning.
Hello, Ping. Are ya hungry?
Yeah, 'cause I owe you
a knuckle sandwich.
Soldiers!
You will assemble swiftly
and silently every morning.
Anyone who acts otherwise...
will answer to me.
Tough guy.
Yao.
Thank you for volunteering.
Retrieve the arrow.
I'll get that arrow, pretty boy,
and I'll do it with my shirt on.
One moment.
You seem to be missing something.
This represents discipline...
and this represents strength.
You need both to reach the arrow.
We've got a long way to go.
Let's get down to business
To defeat the Huns
Did they send me daughters
When I asked for sons
You're the saddest bunch
lever met
But you can bet
Before we're through
Mister, I'll make a man
Out of you
Tranquil as a forest
But on fire within
Once you find your centre
You are sure to win
You're a spineless
Pale, pathetic lot
And you haven't got a clue
Somehow I'll make a man
Out of you
- I'm never gonna catch my breath
- Say good-bye to those who knew me
Boy, was I a fool in school
For cutting gym
This guy's got ‘em scared to death
Hope he doesn't see right through me
Now I really wish that
1 knew how to swim
- Beaman
- You must be swift as a coursing river
- With all the force of a great typhoon
- Beaman
- With all the strength of a raging fire
Mysterious as the dark side
Of the moon
Time is racing toward us
Till the Huns arrive
Heed my every order
And you might survive
You're unsuited for the rage of war
So pack up, go home
You're through
How could 1 make a man
Out of you
Beaman
- You must be swift as a coursing river
- Beaman
- With all the force of a great typhoon
With alf the strength
Of a raging fire
Mysterious as the dark side
Of the moon
Beaman
- We must be swift as a coursing river
- Beaman
- With all the force of a great typhoon
With alf the strength
Of a raging fire
Mysterious as the dark side
Of the moon
What do you see?
Black pine,
from the high mountains.
White horse hair.
Imperial stallions.
Sulphur, from cannons.
This doll came from a village
in the Tung Shao Pass,
where the Imperial Army
is waiting for us.
We can avoid them easily.
No. The quickest way
to the emperor is through that pass.
Besides, the little girl
will be missing her doll.
We should return it to her.
Hey, no, this is not a good idea.
What if somebody sees you?
Just because I look like a man,
I don't have to smell like one.
So a couple of guys don't rinse out
their socks. Picky, picky, picky.
Well, myself, I kind
of like that corn chip smell.
All right. That's enough.
Now, get out before you get all pruny.
Mushu, if you're so worried,
go stand watch.
Yeah, yeah.
"Stand watch, Mushu...
while I blow our secret
with my stupid girlie habits."
Hygiene!
Me first! Me first!
We're doomed! There are a couple of
things I know they're bound to notice!
Hey, Ping!
Hi, guys.
I didn't know you were here.
l was just washing. Now I'm clean,
and I'm gonna go. Bye-bye.
Come back here.
I know we were jerks to you before,
so let's start over.
Hi. I'm Ling.
- And I'm Chien-Po.
- Hello, Chien-Po.
And lam Yao!
King of the rock!
And there's nothin’
you girls can do about it.
Oh, yeah? Well, I think
Ping and I can take you.
- [don't wanna take him anywhere.
- Ping, we have to fight!
No, we don't. We could just...
close our eyes and swim around.
Come on. Don't be such a gir...
Something bit me!
- What a nasty flavor.
- Snake!
- Poison!
Snake!
- Snake!
- Help!
Some king of the rock.
- Boy, that was close.
- No, that was vile.
You owe me big.
I never want to see
a naked man again.
Hey, don't look at me.
l ain't bitin’ no more butts.
You think your troops
are ready to fight?
They would not
last a minute against the Huns!
- They completed their training.
- Those boys...
are no more fit to be soldiers
than you are to be captain.
Once the general reads my report,
your troops will never see battle.
No, you don't! I've worked
too hard to get Mulan into this war.
He's messin’ with my plan.
- We're not finished!
- Be careful, Captain.
The general may be your father,
but lam the emperor's counsel.
And, by the way,
I got that job on my own.
You're dismissed.
Hey. I'll hold him and you punch.
Or not.
For what it's worth,
I think you're a great captain.
- [saw that.
- What?
- You like him, don't you?
- No! lL...
Yeah, all right. Yeah, sure.
Go to your tent!
I think it's time we took
this war into our own hands.
Let me see what you got.
"From General Li.
Dear Son, we're waiting at the pass,
it'd mean a lot
if you'd come and back us up."
Great, but you forgot,
"We're out of potpourri,
perhaps you wouldn't mind
bringing some."
Hello! It's the army!
Make it sound more urgent!
You know what
I'm talkin’ about?
That's better.
Much better. Let's go.
Khanny, baby.
Hey, we need a ride.
Insubordinate ruffians!
You men owe me
a new pair of slippers!
And I do not squeal like a girl.
Urgent news
from the general.
What's the matter? You never seen
a black-and-white before?
Who are you?
Excuse me? I think
the question is, who are you?
We're in a war!
There's no time for stupid questions!
l should have your hat for that.
Snatch it right off your head.
But I'm feeling gracious today,
so carry on before I report you.
Captain, urgent news from the general!
We're needed at the front.
Pack your bags, Cri-Kee.
We're movin’ out.
For a long time
We've been marching off to battle
In our thundering herd
We feel a lot like cattle
Like a pounding beat
Our aching feet
Aren't easy to ignore
Hey! Think of instead
A girl worth fighting for
That's what I said.
! want her paler than the moon
With eyes that shine like stars
My girl will marvel at my strength
Adore my battle scars
! couldn't care less what she'll wear
Or what she looks like
It all depends on what she cooks like
Beef, pork, chicken
Bet the local girls
Thought you were quite the charmer
And I'll bet the ladies love
A man in armor
You can guess what
We have missed the most
Since we went off to war
- What do we want?
- A girl worth fighting for
My girl will think
! have no faults
That I'm a major find
How ‘bout a girl who's got a brain?
Who always speaks her mind?
My manly ways and turn of phrase
Are sure to thrill her
He thinks he's such a lady-killer
I've a girl back home
Who's unlike any other
Yeah, the only girl
Who'd love him is his mother
But when we come home in victory
They'll line up at the door
- What do we want?
- A girl worth fighting for
- Wish that I had
A girl worth fighting...
Search for survivors.
I don't understand.
My father should've been here.
Captain!
The general.
I'm sorry.
The Huns are moving quickly.
We'll make better time to the Imperial
City through the Tung Shao Pass.
We're the only hope
for the emperor now.
Move out!
What happened?
You just gave away
our position! Now...
Get out of range!
- Save the cannons!
- Come on!
Empty it! Empty it!
Hey!
Sure. Save the horse.
Fire!
Hold the last cannon.
Prepare to fight.
If we die, we die with honor.
Yao, aim the cannon at Shan-Yu.
- Hey!
- Ping! Come back!
Ping!
Stop!
You might want to light that now.
Quickly. Quickly!
Come on! We gotta help!
You missed!
How could you miss?
He was three feet in front of you!
Mulan!
No.
Man, you are one lucky bug.
Shang!
- Do you see them?
- Yes.
Perfect. Now we'll
pull them to safety.
Hey, Mulan!
I found the lucky cricket!
We need help.
Nice. Very nice. You can sit by me.
We're gonna die!
We are definitely gonna die.
No way we survive this.
Death is coming!
I let them slip
through my fingers.
Pull!
I knew we could do it.
You the man!
Well, sort of.
Step back, guys.
Give him some air.
Ping?
You are the craziest man
I've ever met.
And for that, l owe you my life.
From now on,
you have my trust.
Let's hear it for Ping!
The bravest of us all!
- You're king of the mountain!
- Yes!
Ping! What's wrong?
He's wounded! Get help!
Ping, hold on.
Hold on.
I can explain.
So it's true!
Shang!
I knew there was
something wrong with you.
A woman!
Treacherous snake!
My name is Mulan.
I did it to save my father.
- High treason!
- [didn't mean for it to go this far.
Ultimate dishonor!
It was the only way.
Please believe me.
Captain?
Restrain him!
- No!
- You know the law.
A life for a life.
My debt is repaid.
- Move out!
- But you can't just...
Il said, "Move out."
l was this close.
This close
to impressin' the ancestors,
gettin’ the top shelf,
an entourage.
Man. All my fine work.
Hi.
I should never have left home.
Hey, come on. You went
to save your father's life.
Who knew you'd end up shamin' him,
disgracing your ancestors,
and losin’ all your friends?
You know, you just gotta...
You gotta learn to let these things go.
Maybe I didn't go for my father.
Maybe what I really wanted
was to prove I could do things right,
so when I looked in the mirror,
I'd see someone worthwhile.
But I was wrong.
l see nothing.
Now, that's just 'cause this needs
a little spit, that's all.
Let me shine this up for ya.
Il can see you. Look at you.
You look so pretty.
The truth is, we're both frauds.
Your ancestors never sent me.
They don't even like me.
You risked your life
to help people you love.
I risked your life to help myself.
At least you had good intentions.
What? What do you mean
you're not lucky?
You lied to me?
And what are you, a sheep?
I'll have to face my father,
sooner or later.
- Let's go home.
- Yeah.
This ain't gonna be pretty.
But don't you worry, OK?
Things will work out.
We started this thing together,
and that's how we'll finish it.
I promise.
Home is that way.
- [have to do something.
- Did you see those Huns?
They popped out of the snow
like daisies!
Are we in this together or not?
Well, let's go kick
some Hunny buns!
Make way for the heroes of China.
- Shang!
- Mulan?
The Huns are alive!
They're in the city!
You don't belong here, Mulan.
Go home.
Shang, I saw them in the mountains.
You have to believe me.
Why should I?
Why else would I come back?
You said you'd trust Ping.
Why is Mulan any different?
Keep your eyes open.
I know they're here.
- Now, where are you going?
- To find someone who will believe me.
My children!
Heaven smiles down
upon the Middle Kingdom.
China will sleep safely tonight,
thanks to our brave warriors.
Sir, the emperor's in danger.
But the Huns are here.
Please, you have to help.
- No one will listen.
- Huh? I'm sorry.
- Did you say something?
- Mushu.
Hey, you're a girl again,
remember?
Your Majesty.
I present to you
the sword of Shan-Yu.
I know what this means
to you, Captain Li.
Your father would have been
very proud.
- No!
- Come on!
They'll never reach
the emperor in time.
Hey, guys! I've got an idea.
Beaman
- We must be swift as a coursing river
- Beaman
- With all the force of a great typhoon
With alf the strength
of a raging fire
Mysterious as the dark side
Of the moon
Boo.
Guard the door.
Your walls and armies have fallen,
and now it's your turn.
Bow to me.
- OK. Any questions?
- Does this dress make me look fat?
Who's there?
- Concubines.
- Ugly concubines.
He's so cute!
Now, that's what I call
Mongolian barbecue.
Shang, go!
I tire of your arrogance, old man.
Bow to me!
No matter how the wind howls,
the mountain cannot bow to it.
Then you will kneel in pieces!
Chien-Po, get the emperor!
Sorry, Your Majesty.
No!
Come on!
No.
You!
- You took away my victory!
- No!
I did.
The soldier from the mountains.
So what's the plan?
- You don't have a plan?
- Hey, I'm making this up as I... go.
- Mushu!
- Way ahead of you, sister.
Come on, Cri-Kee.
- Citizens, I need firepower.
- Who are you?
Your worst nightmare.
- On the roof!
- Look!
It looks like you're out of ideas.
Not quite. Ready, Mushu?
lam ready, baby!
Light me.
Get off the roof,
get off the roof!
You are a lucky bug.
That was a deliberate
attempt on my life!
Where is she?
Now she's done it.
What a mess! Stand aside!
That creature's
not worth protecting.
- She's a hero.
- 'Tis a woman.
- She'll never be worth anything.
- Listen, you pompous...
That is enough.
Your Majesty, I can explain.
I've heard a great deal
about you, Fa Mulan.
You stole your father's armor,
ran away from home,
impersonated a soldier,
deceived your commanding officer,
dishonored the Chinese Army,
destroyed my palace,
and...
you have saved us all.
My little baby is all grown up and...
and savin' China.
You have a tissue?
- Chi Fu?
- Your Excellency?
See to it that this woman
is made a member of my council.
A member... What? But...
There are no council positions
open, Your Majesty.
Very well.
You can have his job.
What? I...
With all due respect,
Your Excellency,
I think I've been away
from home long enough.
Then take this,
so your family will know
what you have done for me.
And this,
so the world will know
what you have done for China.
Is she allowed to do that?
You...
You fight good.
Thank you.
Khan, let's go home.
The flower that blooms in adversity
is the most rare and beautiful of all.
Sir?
You don't meet a girl like that
every dynasty.
- Mulan!
- Father.
I brought you
the sword of Shan-Yu.
And the crest of the emperor.
They're gifts to honor the Fa family.
The greatest gift and honor
is having you for a daughter.
I've missed you so.
I've missed you too, Baba.
Great. She brings home a sword.
If you ask me,
she should've brought a man.
Excuse me.
Does Fa Mulan live here?
- Thank you.
- Sign me up for the next war.
Honorable Fa Zhou, I... Mulan!
You forgot your helmet.
Well, actually, it's your helmet,
isn't it? l mean...
- Would you like to stay for dinner?
- Would you like to stay forever?
Dinner would be great.
Come on. Who did a good job?
Come on. Tell me.
Who did a good job?
All right!
You can be a guardian again.
Take it, Cri-Kee!
You know, she gets it
from my side of the family.
Call out for egg rolls!
Guardians.
Thanks, Mushu.
Mushu!