“Eastbound train arriving
on Track 4.”
“Please wait
behind the white line.”
Tokuma Shoten Nippon Television Network
Studio Ghibli Present
Original Story by
Saeko HIMURO
THE OCEAN WAVES
“Thank you for your patience,
the plane is about to take off.”
Yutaka and! first met Rikako
two years ago.
it was the summer
of our junior year.
Yutaka called me at work.
Hurry up kid!
More dishes! Keep'em coming!
OK!
Taku, telephone!
Coming.
Hello.
- Taku?
- Hey, Yutaka.
Come to school
as soon as you finish today.
i be here waiting for you.
OK.
Sorry. have to leave
early today.
Now wait a minute!
See you tomorrow!
You can't rely on kids!
See you!
Yutaka!
You got here fast.
You told me to!
Take a look.
Who is it? l can’t see.
Just transferred to my class.
Her name's Rikako Muto.
- From next semester?
- Yeah.
A mid-year transfer?
That's unusual.
She moved here
from Tokyo, that's why.
[ just showed her
around the school.
That's right,
you're on the student council.
You really like her, huh?
Anyone would,
she's really good looking.
Really?
l can't tell, and we can't just
walk down and look.
If you want,
we can go down...
...and say we have a question.
Nah, let's not
go that far.
The teachers know
I'm working this summer...
...and not taking classes.
Still mad about
the jr. high school trip?
I don't like the way
they just cancelled it...
...and tried to buy us off
with Hawaii in high school.
Do they think we're stupid?
Everyone's excited.
l think it was a good move.
A relaxing trip will help us
cram for college entrance exams.
Hawaii's expensive.
I need to make some money.
Just remember to keep up
with your studies.
Don't fall behind.
Sure. By the way...
...was there something
you wanted to talk about?
Not really.
I just felt like seeing you.
I'll get my bike.
Wait by the gate.
All through jr. high school
and high school...
... Yutaka and!
were never in the same class.
Even so, ! always felt
he was a close friend.
it all started in our last year
of jr. high school...
...When the school trip to Kyoto was
suddenly cancelled.
“We regret to announce
that this year's jr. high school trip...”
“..bas been cancelled.”
‘In future. jr. high and high school
trips will be combined.”
“Last year, our college
placement results...”
“... were lower than the
prefectural high school.”
“Our school's proud traditions
and your obligations to your parents...”
“..make this completely unacceptable. ”
“To restore our school's honor...”
“... the high school seniors
must redouble their efforts.”
“You must set an example
for our jr. high school seniors. ”
Let's go see Miss Sayama.
Come on, Taku!
The whole thing was so stupid...
...we decided to complain
to our home room teacher.
We all think this is unfair.
Canceling the trip
won't help our grades.
The school owes us
a detailed explanation.
Ask for one
when your grades are better!
I'm already a top student!
Don't pressure Miss Sayama
just because she's a woman!
We thought that was the end
of the matter.
But a week later,
at the morning assembly —
Your parents have also approved
the trip cancellation.
lf you're still not satisfied,
we'll explain the decision.
Raise your hand
if you're still not satisfied.
He's got guts.
it was Yutaka Matsuno.
OK.
We'll explain the decision for students
who raised their hands.
Go to the art room
after classes. Dismissed!
MEETING POSTPONED
WRITE YOUR OPINIONS
ON THE PAPER PROVIDED
3RD YEAR, CLASS 3
TAKU MORISAKI
THE TRIP CANCELLATION
MAKES NO SENSE.
IT'S ONLY TO MAKE THE TEACHERS
AND PARENTS FEEL BETTER.
Iran into Yamao
and the others just now.
They're sorry for not coming.
Don't hold it against them.
Those jerks...
3RD YEAR, CLASS 4
YUTAKA MATSUNO
[ CAN'T AGREE WITH THIS
UNREASONABLE DECISION.
EVEN 20 YEARS AFTER I GRADUATE...
LL STILL THINK
THE SCHOOL WAS WRONG.
Wow!
You're already thinking
20 years into the future.
After that, l always thought
of Yutaka...
...@ bit differently
from my other friends.
This is my friend Taku Morisaki.
This is Rikako Muto.
She's transferring to my class.
See you, then!
See you next semester.
What, you made your move already?!
Huh? No, she asked me
where the bookstore was.
She needs to buy her textbooks.
OBIYAMACHI MALL
The cook where I work is
this former gang member.
Sometimes his old habits come out...
... like, the way he smokes.
What?
Do you think there's something
behind her transfer?
Ah, so that's it!
That's the real reason
Yutaka wanted to see me.
Maybe her dad got transferred
or something like that.
See you!
It really irritated me
when ! realized...
...that Yutaka was
interested in Rikako.
Better forget it!
Girls only care about looks.
i never thought
she'd see his real value.
When the new term started...
...Rikako was a bit of a sensation
with us simple country boys.
Hey Taku.
get a look at the girls!
Ariga, right?
l know, they're big.
No! The other court!
She's really cool.
She didn’t even break a sweat.
She's really something!
She plays like a pro!
Tokyo kids can really hit the ball!
- She stands out.
- Nice legs too!
Bet that type's hard to handle.
Rikako really stands out, huh?
I don't know why
you'd say that.
Hey, Yutaka!
Sorry.
Rikako's out of place in class.
I think it's because
she stands out too much.
Out of place, huh?
Yeah...in lots of ways.
RIKAKO MUTO
She really stands out, huh?
She's already 12th in the school!
Sports and study—
she's a super woman!
- Let's see Taku. you're...
- Number 92!
You were a better student
in jr. high.
What an attitude!
She's so stuck up!
That's enough!
Stop gossiping.
Time for class!
What's wrong?
Got a crush on Rikako?
No, but she doesn't seem
very happy.
Oh. come off it.
She's 12th in the school.
l hear you have a new student?
Yeah. Why?
l hear her grades are excellent.
Tokyo students really are top notch.
How did you hear?
They were talking about it in town.
Rikako's family
is related to the Mutos...
...0f Muto Fruit Packing.
Her mother moved back
for family reasons.
She brought
the two children with her.
Maybe her parents got divorced.
Is her father still in Tokyo?
l wonder.
I'm full.
Atsushi, mind your manners!
Poor Rikako.
With her grades...
... She'll just go back
to Tokyo for college.
Kids sure get jerked around.
Now don't talk like that!
A mother needs
her children with her!
You don't need
to get upset about it.
Relocating is a tough decision!
She can't leave them
behind just for school!
[t's natural for her
to want them with her!
Speaking from experience, huh?
Now you be nice to Rikako!
She must be having
a hard time adjusting.
Sure, sure.
Taku!
Taku! Telephone!
OK!
Hello? Hey, Yutaka.
What's going on?
Well...
What?
It's not really that important.
! visited Rikako today!
Where? At her house?
She was out sick.
! heard she lives alone.
! was worried.
She lives alone? Her mother's
house isn't that far from school.
And you went
to see her? Alone?
Yeah. And...she was
alone in bed!
She was in bed. So?
Nothing. That's it.
That's all.
So you like that kind of girl.
do you Yutaka?
The year ended,
and March came...
...and with it,
the long-awaited school trip.
Taku!
HAWAII
You're not going swimming?
Today's our last day!
I've had an upset stomach
all morning.
Too bad! See you, then!
So long.
And that's when
all the trouble started.
Taku!
Could you land me some money?
Money?
What happened?
Did you run out?
Well...not exactly.
I lost all the money
Il had with me!
That's awful!
Did you tell the teacher?
With traveler's checks.
you can get your money back.
I'll get in trouble.
Don't be silly!
You've got to report it!
I'm sorry. Your Kochi dialect
reminds me of samurai movies.
Want to sit down?
Let me tell you what happened.
I mostly brought cash. Travelers
checks are a pain, right? So...
Cash? You mean dollars?
Right, about $400 in cash.
I must have left it somewhere.
We were supposed to bring
less than ¥20,000 in cash!
The rest was supposed
to be traveler's checks.
Nobody really does that!
You sound like
one of the teachers!
Are you a goody-goody?
Too bad.
l heard you were different.
Your Tokyo dialect
sounds so harsh!
Why? I'm not angry!
And I'm not a samurai!
You're mean, Taku.
Nobody ever called me harsh.
Is that how I sound?
Yeah, Everyone thinks so.
But they're afraid you'll say
they sound like samurai.
OK, I'm sorry.
[ didn't mean
to make fun of you.
You hear dialects in dramas, right?
l thought dialects were all gone.
But Kochi people really talk that way.
l was shocked.
Still. [never told anyone
l felt that way, till today.
You'd better not!
At first 1 couldn't
understand a word.
l kept asking people
to say things twice.
Maybe that's why nobody likes me.
Who doesn't like you?
Everybody. boys especially.
Nobody talks to me.
Well, except Yutaka, the class
representative. He's nice.
Yeah, Yutaka's a good guy.
Did he tell you about ma?
Yes. l saw you working
at the restaurant...
...during the winter vacation.
Yutaka was with me.
He said you work really hard.
Then he told me
a lot about you.
Like your protest
over the cancelled school trip.
He told you about that?
You must have a lot of
money from your job, right?
OK, how much?
What can you spare?
I brought about ¥60,000 and $400.
I haven't spent much.
How about $300?
Really? Then could you
lend me the ¥60, 000?
Wait here.
Sixty thousand yen!
Much obliged, Mr Morisaki!
Should I give it
to you right here?
You're pretty cautious.
OK. sit down right there.
Put it in this handkerchief
and hand it to me.
Feels like we're doing
something illegal!
] probably can't pay
you back right away.
I'm expecting some money, though.
Pay me back anytime.
Please don't tell anyone about this.
Sure, but why?
Mama would yell at me.
“Mama...”
What's her story?
Hey!
I'm surprised she knew
so much about me!
So you guys are friends.
Dating, huh?
That wasn't a date.
l ran into her over vacation.
l asked her to a movie—
and she said yes!
I couldn't think
of a thing to say.
We passed your restaurant,
so l started talking about you.
It really helped.
Maybe, but I just got hit
for a loan.
Rikako asked you for a loan?
Yeah. I walked by.
and she said she lost her money.
Maybe she remembered
l made money over the break.
So she lost all her money?
Poor thing!
- Want to walk around town?
- Sure.
Wait a sec.
I'll drop my stuff.
[ said not to tell!
You already told Yutaka!
Huh? What did he say?
He offered to land me money!
See?
Isn't he a good guy?
I borrowed ¥20.000...
but please keep this a secret!!
] hope you can remember this time!
How did her parents raise her?!
The next day we returned to Kochi...
...and I bought some candid shots
of Rikako from a friend.
! fait like getting even.
And thought that was it
for my bad feelings.
But next term,
we ended up in the same class.
Yumi, lunch!
Rikako finally made a friend—
—a quiet girl in the same class.
Her name was Yumi Kohama.
That was nice for her...
...but spring break came, and
I still didn't have my money.
! thought she'd forgotten it.
Taku, telephone!
It's Yumi Kohama!
Is that you Yumi?
Where are you calling from?
You're the only person
! could think of to call!
What's wrong?
We were going to Osaka
for two nights...
...for a concert.
Now we're at the airport.
and Rikako says she’s going to Tokyo!
That was her plan all along!
She doesn't know I'm calling you.
Unbelievable!
She says there's no difference
where we go.
Rikako even bought
two tickets to Tokyo.
! don't want to lie
to my mother!
Look, calm down!
You don't have to go!
Just leave and let Rikako
go by herself.
} can't! Her mother let her go
because I'm with her!
She really wants me to go.
What should } do?
What should you do...?
Wait a minute!
Why are you asking ME?
She told me you lent her
the money for the tickets.
You're her friend.
Can't you convince her?
Please come to the airport.
Our flight is at 11:30.
We've got 90 minutes.
! really need you to coma!
That money again!
So she didn't really
lose her money. It was a lie!
It was just part of her plan
for this trip!
What a jerk!
KOCHI AIR TERMINAL
You came!
Where is she?
In the rest room.
Says she's not feeling well.
I wish she'd get worse.
Then we wouldn't have to go!
Anyway, she's way out of line!
You're her friend.
You should tell her of f!
She really wants to see her father.
1 feel sorry for her.
What about her father?
What are you doing here?
Did Yumi call you?
Rikako. let's not lie
about this trip!
Let's tell your mother.
She'd never let me go!
I've been planning
this for so long.
Wait a minute.
OK, how about this.
Yumi, call home.
Say you feel sick and can't go.
But...
And Rikako's going by herself...
... because it would be a shame
to waste both tickets.
Your parents
will only worry about you.
They won't think about Rikako.
You're right!
My mom doesn't know Rikako's mom.
She won't say anything.
OK. fine.
I'll call her!
Yumi's from a strict family.
She's not going to run
off to Tokyo just like that.
So, you're not feeling well?
My period just started.
Sometimes it's really bad.
It must be tough.
Boys don't know what it's like.
Do you really have to go?
I'll get your money from Papa.
Don't worry, I'll pay you.
If you're worried about going alone,
shall 1 go with you?
Really?
Would you really do that?
Hey, listen.
Your father knows
you're coming, right?
Is he meeting you?
No, ! doubt it.
Could he find a place
for me to stay?
Sure. I'll ask him,
When I see Papa.
I'm going to tell him.
l want to move back to Tokyo
and live with him,
“We are now in our final approach
to Haneda Airport.”
As I followed Rikako
around Tokyo, ! thought—
“she's done it to me again.”
But ! couldn't just let her go
to Tokyo by herself.
The cherry trees around here
are really nice.
My house is this way.
My grandparents used to live here.
This was all farm land.
They built apartments,
and we got the nicest one.
It was big. even for four of us.
I bet Papa's lonely.
He'll be glad to see you.
It's good to be back.
Who is it?
Isn't this the Mutos?
Yes, that's right.
Umm...is Papa home?
ls that Rikako? I'll come down,
wait in the lobby!
What a surprise!
I didn't know you were coming.
Are you alone?
My boyfriend, from Kochi.
It's spring break.
We came to visit.
Oh really?
Thanks for looking after Rikako.
Shall we go for coffee?
I want to see my old room!
How's it look?
OK, let's go up.
I'm sorry...could you wait
here for a little while?
Sure,
Morisaki, thanks
for putting up with Rikako.
I hear you don't have a place to stay?
l made a reservation.
And Rikako owes you money.
Thank you very much.
! really felt sorry for her—
from the bottom of my heart.
GUIDE TO WEST SHINJUKU
Hi, Mom?
Taku? It's almost dinner time.
Come home.
Look, I can't make it tonight.
OK, we'll go ahead.
Don't be too late.
I'm in Tokyo.
Tokyo?! How did you get there?
I took a plane
straight to Tokyo.
What?!
I'm escorting someone.
Escorting?! Who?
I'll be home in two days.
What's going on?!
Hello? Hello?
I'll explain later! Goodbye!
Taku! Wait!
Rikako!
What happened?
I'm staying here tonight.
Papa's paying, so l can if ] want.
Hey...
The whole thing was starting
to feel like a bad soap opera.
Want some beer, Rikako?
No? We drink it sometimes
when no one’s around.
Make me a rum and coke.
Il tried them at a friend's house.
Papa's going on a trip with his
lady friend for the holidays.
Well, it IS spring vacation.
My room was completely changed!
The wallpaper's dark green!
l hate green!
You're right.
Green's no good!
All the pots are fancy enamelware.
It's so stupid.
Nobody uses enamelware anymore!
Listen. Taku.
When my parents were fighting,
] thought Mama was wrong.
She wouldn't give in,
so Papa didn't either.
It ended in a bad divorce.
My brother and I had to move
and leave all our friends.
l was on Papa's side.
But he wasn't on my side.
On your side? Wait...
My life is so sad.
Things must be tough,
but you should help your mother.
You shouldn't be living by yourself.
I didn't want to impose
on Mama's family.
] wasn’t mad at her.
Well, that's different.
It's none of your business.
“Good evening.”
“How are you spending
the spring holidays?”
Ouch!
She's having a tough time?
What about me?
Taku!
Get up!
It's about time.
l was waiting to use the bathroom.
l had to go downstairs!
Sorry...
Could you leave for a while?
I'm meeting someone.
I need to dress.
Your father?
A high school friend.
I called this morning.
We're meeting downstairs.
That's great.
I need to shower and change.
Hurry up and leave.
! think this was when I decided
to attend college in Tokyo.
Seeing Rikako bounce back somehow
made me feel at ease here.
Good timing. My friend just called,
we're meeting in the lobby.
- Oh. really?
- See you, then!
What about the key?
Are you going out?
No, I'll take a nap.
Really? Sorry!
Don't worry.
Enjoy yourself.
Hello?
Taku, could you come
down to the coffee shop?
What happened?
Forget your wallet?
Just come down!
You're rescuing me.
So, what is it this time?
Taku, over here!
This is Taku Morisaki.
He was worried about me.
so he came along.
Taku, this is Okada,
my former classmate.
Hi.
Rikako. a boyfriend already?
What a shock!
Look who's talking.
As soon as I left...
... you got together with Ryoko.
! feel kind of betrayed!
But you're prettier.
Ryoko says so too.
She says she can’t compete.
Listen. Taku.
Wouldn't YOU be shocked?
date Okada for a year...
...and two months after I leave,
he's dating a friend of mine!
Happens all the time.
Nothing surprises him either!
I called Ryoko. Are you free?
Why don't we all see a movie?
Like a double date.
I'd like to, but...
...Papa's treating me to
lunch this afternoon.
Too bad. If we'd known you were
coming, we could've made plans.
But your mother’s not very fair.
She could've left you in Tokyo.
You're going to college here anyway.
She had to drag her children
off to the country.
What are you talking about?
She's not a child!
What's wrong, Taku?
You're a bore, that's what!
You and this guy both!
He must be jealous of me.
Sorry about that.
! was disappointed.
In Kochi Rikako seemed so strong, but
she gets to Tokyo and all she does...
...is put on a big show and
fawn over a stupid guy.
Rikako?
Okada says to tell you
he's not mad.
That guy's really dumb.
When we were dating ] thought
he was kind and thoughtful.
I called you because
l wanted to show off.
Afterwards I just felt stupid.
We're really bores—
him and me both.
Well. 1 can see you'd be shocked
about his new girlfriend.
You don’t get it, Taku.
l was shocked because
he wasn't like ] remembered.
All he talked about was himself.
He didn't even ask about Kochi.
But that's his real personality.
I just never noticed.
lll stay at my aunt's tonight.
We shouldn't stay
in the same room anyway.
Let's meet at the airport tomorrow.
Our Tokyo trip
wasn’t much fun, was it?
In half an hour,
Rikako seemed to have grown up.
Yumi, what's this?
Do you want one?
After the holidays,
Rikako ignored me...
...Just as if nothing had happened.
As usual, her only friend
was Yumi Kohama.
Don't get me wrong.
I'm not worried about you...
...but you're going to end up
without any friends.
Try to be a little more...
Leave me alone!
How were your finals?
Awful. I'm going to cram school
in Osaka this summer.
Training camp, huh?
It'll be a nice change.
Listen...
Don't be upset, but...
...did you and Rikako
take a trip during vacation?
Yeah, we did.
How did you know?
How do you think?
The rumor’s all over school.
Haven't you heard?
No, I haven't.
That's just like you.
Nobody wants to joke about it
to your face.
People are whispering.
Listen, I don't know
what people are saying.
Rikako just went
to see her father.
Yeah, I heard.
From who?
Did Yumi tell you?
Yumi? Why her?
l heard it straight from Rikako.
I ran into her on the way
home and asked her.
What, that story again?
Yes, I stayed with Taku
in a Tokyo hotel!
What's that got
to do with you?
‘m..
I'm in love with you.
Look—
Il hate Kochi, and boys
who speak Kochi dialect!
Don't say that to me!
It makes me sick!
“Sick,” huh?
Yeah. It was kind of tough.
Is that what
did your grades in?
I'll get back on track
over summer.
Now she's gone too far!
Taku!
Red or white?
Red!
I've gotta talk to you.
Let's go!
What?!
What's the problem?
Don't talk to me in school!
People will notice.
You told Yutaka
we stayed in a hotel in Tokyo?
So what?
It was all your idea!
But people are pointing at ME!
Why. you... !
I'm suffering thanks to you.
You're the worst, you really are.
You're such a loyal friend!
Satisfied?
That trip to Tokyo...
... really was a total disaster
for both of us.
And so autumn came.
Rikako was as isolated as aver.
But her grades
just got better and better.
Then, during the last event of
senior year — the school fair...
Sanuki udon noodles!
She didn't come today either!
Probably won't come
to the dance performance.
She missed all the rehearsals.
Probably thinks it's stupid!
She cuts group events to raise
her grades! Can you believe it?
Let's tell her off!
How about tomorrow?
Excuse me...
Welcome!
“Announcement from
the Organizing Committee.”
“Today's final program
is Dance Paradise.”
“Classes finished with cleanup
should assemble in the courtyard.”
‘lL repeat. Classes finished
with cleanup should assemble...”
Is that all?
I'm in a hurry!
What? What did you say?
In a hurry? Don't you care
about class harmony?
Class harmony? You sound like some
stupid politician!
You're wrapped up in yourself.
What about the rest of the world?
What kind of world is it where people
can't think of themselves?
Does the world care about me?
I'll take care of myself!
You pretend you're not interested in boys.
but I see you flirting!
Making eyes at Yanagida!
Yanagida?!
I don't even know who he is!
Bring him here!
I'll tell him ] hate him!
Stop it!
You'll just hurt your school record.
No point crying
because of someone like this.
We won't forget this!
[ think 1 expected
too much from you.
Taku! How long
have you been there?
I'm just throwing this out.
l heard voices.
Good for you.
You stood up to all those girls.
Even made one of them cry.
It was really impressive.
You idiot! You're the worst!
Hey!
Rikako just ran by.
I think she was crying.
Oh. she just got bullied
by the girls in our class.
She cut all the activities.
But she really stood up to them.
They couldn't touch her.
That Rikako, she's tough.
It was really something.
You didn't stop them?
They'd have just told me
to butt out. They're fed up.
She can be a real pain.
You idiot!
! figured Yutaka and I would
be back to normal by next day.
At least, that's what! thought.
But we graduated
without speaking again.
Rikako enrolled at Kochi University.
Yutaka went to Kyoto...
...and f went
to college in Tokyo.
“We have just landed at Kochi Airport.”
KOCHI AIR TERMINAL
Hey, Taku!
Yutaka!
Thanks for picking me up.
Sure. I got my license
last month.
I'm impressed you found the time
to take lassons.
Took me two months
just to get used to Tokyo.
Another month for my job.
Before I knew it, summer came.
Tokyo and Kyoto are really different.
Kyoto's almost like Kochi.
Il settled in right away.
But Kochi's nice.
It's not crowded.
And everything you need
is right at hand.
Tokyo's got everything, but
it takes an hour to get anywhere.
Even Katsura Beach's
only an hour from here.
Jingu Stadium's an hour,
with train transfers.
An hour from Kyoto...
... you can get to Osaka or Nara.
Gosh, sounds like Kyoto's better.
Want to come in?
I'll pass for today.
Your family must be waiting.
See you at the reunion?
l always wanted to apologize.
Sorry ] punched you.
Ah, so that explains
the free ride from the airport!
I'll call you.
Want to take a walk?
It's been a while.
l was angry that time...
...because I knew you were
holding back on my account.
l hadn't noticed till then...
...that you really liked Rikako.
Yutaka and! spent an hour
there — then we went home.
PRIVATE PARTY
You're living in Osaka?
I'm close — Kobe!
Have a drink!
Thank you...
It's ridiculous!
I can't even resign from a club...
...unless the alumni approve.
So, I went
to Disneyland with him.
We missed the last train.
What happened??
I thought I was joining a ski club,
not a religious group!
They keep telephoning me.
It's driving me nuts!
Better watch the drinking, Yamao.
She's late...
Late? Who?
Scoot over more!
What's happening?
Yamamoto just confessed.
He always liked Nishimura!
Good for him.
We've got a new couple!
Time for me to confess too!
I've always had a thing
for Yumi Kohama!
Well done, Yamao.
That's the spirit.
What did Yumi say?
She's not here yet!
From the start, she was always
in that flashy Rikako’s shadow.
While you were mooning over Rikako,
l had my eye on Yuni.
What's that supposed to mean?
Come on, now.
Shall we go to men's room?
Hey, Yamao! Are you OK?
Maybe Rikako’s not coming after all.
Rikako said she regrets
the things she said to you.
Well, he's passed out.
You're really looking good, Shimizu.
Thanks.
Of course, Rikako was always pretty,
but she's even prettier now.
Shimizu told me she saw Rikako.
Rikako's not here!
I ran into her yesterday,
in the department store.
l told her about the reunion...
...but she's probably flown home.
Flown?
Rikako went back to Tokyo?
Yeah. I'd always thought
she was in Kochi U.
She got into Kochi U
to please her mother.
But she secretly
tested for a Tokyo school too.
When you met her,
were you, like...
“Wow, it's great to see you.”
and stuff like that?
How'd you know?
Well. ] knew
you never liked her!
You're right, I never did.
l really hated her.
But seeing her again
made me feel nostalgic.
It's kind of like changing seats.
When you're little and have to sit
next to someone you hate...
... You don't even
want to go to school.
The problem is.
your world is too small.
If you have something other than
school, like piano lessons...
...people you dislike
aren't a problem.
Let's sea. That means...
... you realize your world
was too small then?
And that's why
you went after Rikako?
We both had the same problem.
Rikako said her world
was really small, too.
Yumi!
Hey, Yumi!
Yumi?
Huh?
Yu... Yumi...?
Yumi!
Come on, Yamao!
Take it easy!
Yumi!
Hey! Come on!
Yoo-hoo!
What? You saw Rikako too?
Yes. ! wish Rikako had come.
It felt like she was there.
Me too.
That reminds me...
...She said there's someone
in Tokyo she wants to see.
But she didn't say who.
It's someone who likes
to sleep in bathtubs!
I'd forgotten
just how pretty it was.
The castle!
! always thought
lighting up Kochi Castle...
... Was a waste of electricity.
But with Rikako next to me,
it would have been beautiful.
There were so many things
! wanted to talk to her about.
! wanted us to see the castle
together, like this.
Taku! Could you
lend me some money?
You sound like
one of the teachers!
Are you 2 goody-goody?
! heard you were different.
! said not to tell!
You already told Yutaka!
My period just started.
Sometimes it's really bad.
When ! see Papa,
I'm going to tell him.
I want to move to Tokyo
and live with him.
I'm staying here tonight.
Papa's paying, so! can if I want.
My room was completely changed!
The wallpaper's dark green!
1 was on Papa's side.
But he wasn't on my side.
We're bores — him and me both.
Our trip wasn't
much fun, was it?
You're such a loyal friend!
Satisfied?
You idiot! You're the worst!
There's someone in Tokyo
l want to see.
It's a guy who
likes to sleep in bathtubs!
And that's when I knew—
I'd always been crazy about her.
Voices
Nobuo TOBITA
Yoko SAKAMOTO
Toshihiko SEKI
Screenplay written by
Kaori NAKAMURA
Music by
Shigeru NAGATA
Theme song performed by
Yoko SAKAMOTO
English translation by
Jim HUBBERT
English subtitles by
AURA
Produced by the Future Producers
of Studio Ghibli Group
Producer
Nozomu TAKAHASHI
Directed by
Tomomi MOCHIZUKI