[chorus] f In Sixteen Hundred Seven
- We sailed the open sea
¢ For glory, God, and gold
¢ And the Virginia Company
? For the New World is like heaven
¢ And we'll all be rich and free
t Or so we have been told
? By the Virginia Company
¢ So we have been told
¢ By the Virginia Company f
¢ For glory, God, and gold
And the Virginia Company f
? On the beaches of Virginny
¢ There's diamonds like debris
? There's silver rivers flowin'
¢ Gold you pick right off a tree
? With a nugget for my Winnie
And another one for me
¢ And aif the rest'll go
¢ To the Virginia Company
w It's glory, God, and gold
¢ And the Virginia Company f
¢ We'll kill ourselves an injun
¢ Or maybe two or three
? We're stalwart men and bold
of the Virginia Company f
[chorus] S It's glory, God, and gold
¢ And the Virginia Company f
Hega hega
? Ya-hi-ye hega
? Ya-hi-ye-ne-he
Hega
- Hega, hega
? Ya-hi-ye hega
? Ya-hi-ye-ne-he
Hega
¢ Steady as the beating drum
Singing to the cedar flute
¢ Seasons go and seasons come
¢ Bring the corn and bear the fruit
- By the waters sweet and clean
Where the mighty sturgeon is
¢ Plant the squash and reap the bean
? Alf the earth our Mother gives
tO, Great Spirit, hear our song
? Help us keep the ancient ways
¢ Keep the sacred fires strong
J Walk in balance all our days
¢ Seasons go and seasons come
¢ Steady as the beating drum
¢ Plum to seed to bud to plum
¢ Steady as the beating drum J
? Ya-hi-ye hega
? Ya-hi-ye-ne-he hega J
? As the river cuts his path
¢ Though the river's proud and strong
¢ He will choose the smoothest course
¢ They're steady
? As the steady beating drum
¢ What I love most about rivers is
You can't step in the same river twice
¢ The water's always changing
Always flowing
¢ But people, ! guess, can't live like that
We aif must pay a price
! To be safe
We lose our chance of ever knowing
¢ What's around the river bend?
? Waiting just around the river bend?
fl look once more
¢ Just around the river bend
Beyond the shore
Where the gulls fly free
Don't know what for
¢ What I dream the day might send
Just around the river bend
Forme
¢ Coming for me
! feel it there beyond those trees
And right behind these waterfalls
¢ Can ignore that sound
Of distant drumming?
¢ For a handsome, sturdy husband
Who builds handsome, sturdy walls
¢ And never dreams that
Something might be coming
¢ Just around the river bend
fl look once more
Beyond the shore
¢ Somewhere past the sea
Don't know what for
¢ Why do all my dreams extend
Just around the river bend?
¢ Just around the river bend
¢ Should I choose the smoothest course
? Steady as the beating drum?
¢ Should i marry Kocoum?
¢ Is all my dreaming at an end?
¢ Ordo you still
¢ Wait for me, dream giver?
¢ Just around the river
ft Bend?
Que que na-to-ra
¢ You will understand
? Listen with your heart
? Let it break upon you
? Like a wave upon the sand
? Listen with your heart
¢ You will understand
¢ The gold of Cortez
¢ The jewels of Pizarro
t Will seem like mere trinkets
? By this time tomorrow
¢ The gold we find here
Will dwarf them by far
? Oh, with all ya got in ya, boys
? Dig up Virginia, boys
¢ Mine, boys
¢ Mine every mountain
¢ And dig, boys
? Dig till ya drop
¢ Grab a pick, boys
? Quick, boys
¢ Shove in a shovel
Uncover those lovely pebbles
¢ That sparkle and shine
o It's gold
¢ And it's mine, mine
Mine
? Dig and diggety dig
¢ And dig and dig and diggety dig
¢ Hey, nonny, nonny, hi, nonny, nonny
Ooh, how I love it
Riches for cheap
¢ Hey, nonny, nonny, hi, nonny, nonny
There'll be heaps of it
¢ And I'll be on top of the heap
t My rivals back home
It's not that I'm bitter
? But think how they'll squirm
When they see how ! glitter
? The ladies at court will be aif a-twitter
¢ The king will reward me
? He'll knight me
No! Lord me
f it's mine!
¢ Mine, mine for the taking
Z It's mine, boys,
Mine me that gold
? With those nuggets dug
It's glory they'll give me
¢ My dear friend King Jimmy
Will probably build me a shrine
¢ When all of the gold
fis mine
¢ And dig and dig and diggety dig
S All of my life l have searched
For a land like this one
¢ A wild or more challenging country
¢ I couldn't design
¢ Hundreds of dangers await
¢ And I don't plan to miss one
finalandicanclaim
A land I can tame
¢ The greatest adventure is mine
¢ Keep on working, lads
Don't be shirking, lads
- Mine, boys, mine
¢ Mine me that gold
- J Beautiful gold
- J Dig for that gold
? This is my land, my land
¢ Make the mounds big, boys
I'd help you to dig, boys
? But I've got this crick in me spine
- f This land we behold
- J This beauty untold
- f Amancan be bold
- fit alfcan be sold
¢ And the gold is
¢ Mine, mine, mine
f it's mine f
? Listen with your heart
¢ You will understand
? Let it break upon you
? Like a wave upon the sand
? Listen with your heart
¢ You will understand f
¢ You think I'm an ignorant savage
¢ And you've been so many places
i guess it must be so
¢ But still, } cannot see
o If the savage one is me
¢ How can there be so much
¢ That you don't know
f You don't know
¢ You think you own
Whatever land you land on
¢ The earth is just
A dead thing you can claim
¢ But Il know every rock
And tree and creature
? Has a life, has a spirit
? Has a name
¢ You think the only people
Who are people
? Are the people
Who look and think like you
? But if you walk
The footsteps of a stranger
¢ You'll learn things
You never knew you never knew
¢ Have you ever heard the wolf cry
? To the blue corn moon?
¢ Or ask the grinning bobcat
Why he grinned?
¢ Can you sing with all the voices
Of the mountain?
¢ Can you paint with all the colors
t Of the wind?
¢ Come run the hidden pine trails
Of the forest
< Come taste the sun-sweet berries
t Of the earth
¢ Come roll in aif the riches all around you
¢ And for once, never wonder
What they're worth
¢ The rainstorm and the river
¢ Are my brothers
¢ The heron and the otter
¢ Are my friends
¢ And we are all connected to each other
finacircle
In a hoop that never ends
¢ How high
¢ Does the sycamore grow?
oS If you cut it down
¢ Then you'll never know
¢ And you'll
¢ Never hear the wolf cry
? To the blue corn moon
¢ For whether we are white
Or copper-skinned
¢ We need to sing with alf the voices
f Of the mountain
We need to paint with alf the colors
t Of the wind
¢ You can own the earth, and stilf
¢ Alf you'll own is earth until
¢ You can paint
? With all the colors
f Of the wind
We shot ourselves an injun
¢ Or maybe two or three I
? Let it break upon you
¢ Like a wave upon the sand
¢ What can you expect
From filthy little heathens?
- Here's what you get
When races are diverse
? Their skin's a hellish red
They're only good when dead
¢ They're vermin as I said
And worse
¢ They're savages, savages
? Barely even human
? Savages, savages
¢ Drive them from our shore!
¢ They're not like you and me
Which means they must be evil
¢ We must sound the drums of war
¢ They're savages, savages
? Dirty shrieking devils
¢ Now we sound the drums of war
- This is what we feared
The paleface is a demon
¢ The only thing
They feel at all is greed
¢ Beneath that milky hide
There's emptiness inside
¢ l wonder if they even bleed
¢ They're savages, savages
? Barely even human
? Savages, savages
? Killers at the core
They're different from us
¢ Which means they can't be trusted
¢ We must sound the drums of war
¢ They're savages, savages
? First we deal with this one
Then we sound the drums of war
? Savages, savages
- J Savages
? Barely even human
¢ Now we sound the drums
f Of wart
? This will be the day
¢ This will be the morning
We will see them dying in the dust
¢ 1 don't know what I can do
Still 1 know I've got to try
¢ Now we make them pay
? Eagle, help my feet to fly
- f Now, without a warning
- J Mountain, help my heart be great
¢ Now we leave them
Blood and bone and rust
- J Spirits of the earth and sky
- f it's them or us
- Please don't let it be too late
¢ They're just a bunch of
Filthy, stinking savages
- J Savages
- ! Demons
t Devils
- J Savages
? Destroy their evil race
¢ Until there's not a trace left
¢ How loud are the drums of war?
< Now we see what comes
Of trying to be chums
f ls the death of alf I love
Carried in the drumming of
< Wart