Once upon a time,
there was a lovely princess.
But she had an enchantment
upon her of a fearful sort...
.. which could only be broken
by love's first kiss.
She was locked away in a castle...
.. guarded by a terrible,
fire-breathing dragon.
Many brave knights had attempted to
free her from this dreadful prison...
.. but none prevailed.
She waited in the dragon's keep,
in the highest room of the tallest tower...
..for her true love
and true love's first kiss.
Like that'll ever happen.
What a load of
It's in there.
Let's get it!
Hold it.
You know what it could do to you?
Yeah.
It'll grind your bones for its bread.
Actually, that would be a giant.
Now, ogres...
..are much worse.
They'll make a suit
from your freshly peeled skin.
They'll shave your liver...
.. squeeze the jelly from your eyes.
It's quite good on toast.
Back! Back, beast! Back! I warn you.
Right.
This is the part where you run away.
And stay out!
Wanted. Fairy Tale Creatures.
This one's full. Take it away.
He ho hi he
Dwarf prisoners are we.
Give me that!
Your flying days are over.
Twenty pieces of silver for the witch. Next.
Lousy twenty pieces.
Sit down.
Keep quiet.
This cage is too small.
Please don't turn me in.
I'll never be stubborn again.
l can change, give me another chance.
Shut up.
Next.
-What have you got?
-This wooden puppet.
I'm not a puppet. I'm a real boy.
Five shillings for the possessed toy.
Take it away.
Father, don't do this!
Next. What have you got?
have a talking donkey.
Well, that's good for 10 shillings,
if you can prove it.
Go ahead, little fellow.
Well?
He's just nervous.
He's really quite a chatterbox.
Talk, you dolt!
I've heard enough. Guards!
No! He talks. He does.
I can talk. I love to talk.
I'm the talkinest damn thing you ever saw.
Get her out of my sight.
l swear! Let me go!
He can talk!
Hey, I can fly.
-He can fly.
He can talk.
That's right, fool.
I'm a flying, talking donkey.
You might have seen a house fly.
Maybe even a super fly.
But I bet you ain't
never seen a donkey fly.
Seize him!
Get him!
This way! Hurry!
You, there. Ogre.
Aye?
By order of Lord Farquaad, 1 am
authorized to place you both under arrest...
..and transport you to
a designated resettlement facility.
Oh, really? You and what army?
Can I say something to you?
You was really something back there.
Incredible!
Are you talking to...
..me?
Yes, l was. You were great.
Those guards thought...
.. they was all that.
You come, they trip over themselves
like babes in the woods.
It was good to see that.
That's great.
It's good to be free.
Why don't you go celebrate
your freedom with your own friends?
But, uh...
..[ don't have any friends.
And I'm not going out there alone.
I know! I'll stick with you!
You a mean, green fighting machine.
We'll scare anyone who crosses us!
Wow! That was really scary!
And if that don't work,
your breath will get the job done.
You definitely need Tic Tacs...
your breath stinks!
You almost burned the hairs on my nose.
Just like the time...
.. ate some rotten berries.
Strong gasses
eeked out my butt that day.
Why are you following me?!
I'll tell you why.
‘Cause I'm all alone
There's no one here beside me
My problems have all gone
There's no one to deride me
But you gotta have friends
Stop singing!
No wonder you don't have any friends.
Wow! Only a true friend
would be that cruelly honest.
Listen, little donkey,
look at me. What am I?
Really tall?
No! I'm an ogre!
You know,
"Grab your torch and pitchforks!"
Doesn't that bother you?
Nope.
Really?
Really, really.
I like you. What's your name?
Shrek.
Shrek? Well, you know
what I like about you, Shrek?
You got that "I don't care what
nobody thinks of me" thing.
l like that. l respect that, Shrek.
Look at that. Who'd want to live
in a place like that?
That would be my home.
And it is lovely! Just beautiful.
You are quite a decorator.
You've done so much
on such a modest budget.
I like that boulder.
That is a nice boulder.
You don't entertain much, do you?
I like my privacy.
Me, too. I hate when
someone's in your face...
..and you give them a hint
and they won't leave...
..and there's this awkward silence....
Can I stay with you?
What?
Can I stay with you, please?
Of course.
-Really?
-No.
I can't go back!
You don't know what it's like
to be considered a freak!
Well, maybe you do.
But that's why
we got to stick together!
Let me stay! Please!
Okay! Okay! But one night only.
Thank you!
This'll be fun.
Weill stay up late,
swap manly stories...
..and in the morning, I'll make waffles!
Where do I sleep?
Outside!
That's cool.
I mean, I don't know you,
you don't know me...
..So0 I guess outside is best.
Here I go.
Good night.
I do like the outdoors.
I'm a donkey. I was born outside.
I'll just be sitting by myself
outside. By myself, outside.
I'm all alone
There's no one here beside me....
I told you to stay outside.
lam outside.
It's a far cry from the farm,
but what choice do we have?
It's not home, but it'll do just fine.
What a lovely bed.
Gotcha!
l found some cheese.
Awful stuff.
-ls that you, Gorder?
-How did you know?
Enough!
What are you doing in my house?
Oh, no.
Dead broad off the table!
Where do we put her?
The bed's taken.
What?
I live in a swamp! I put up signs!
I'm a terrifying ogre!
What do I have to do
to get a little privacy?
Oh, no.
-Quit it.
-Don't push.
What are you doing in my swamp?!
Get out of here! All of you...
.. move it! Let's go! Hapaya! Hapaya!
No, no, not there. Not there!
Don't look at me. I didn't invite them.
Gosh, no one invited us.
-What?
-We were forced to come here.
-By who?
-Lord Farquaad.
He huffed und he puffed und he...
signed an eviction notice.
All right.
Who knows where this Farquaad guy is?
Me! I know where he is!
Does anyone else know
where to find him?
-Anyone at all?
-Me! Me!
-Anyone?
-Oh, pick me!
I know! I know! Me, me!
Okay, fine.
Attention, all...
. fairy tale things!
Do not get comfortable!
Your welcome is officially worn out!
I'm gonna go see
this guy Farquaad right now...
..and get you off my land
and back where you came from!
You.
You're coming with me.
That's what I like to hear.
Shrek and Donkey, two stalwart friends,
off on a whirlwind, big-city adventure!
On the road again
Sing with me, Shrek!
I can't wait to get On the road again
What'd I say about singing?
-Can I whistle?
-No.
-Well, can I hum?
-All right. Hum.
That's enough! He's ready to talk.
Run, run, as fast as you can.
You can't catch me,
I'm the Gingerbread Man!
Monster!
I'm not the monster, you are!
You and the rest of that fairy tale trash,
poisoning my perfect world.
Now where are the others?
Eat me!
I've tried to be fair to you creatures.
Now my patience has reached its end!
Tell me, or...
Not the buttons! Not my gumdrop buttons!
All right. Who's hiding them?
Okay, I'll tell you.
Do you know the Muffin Man?
-The Muffin Man?
-The Muffin Man.
Yes, I know the Muffin Man.
Who lives on Drury Lane?
Well, she's married to the Muffin Man.
-The Muffin Man?
-The Muffin Man!
She's married to the Muffin Man.
My Lord, we found it.
What are you waiting for? Bring it in.
Magic Mirror....
Don't tell him anything!
Evening.
Mirror, mirror, on the wall...
. is this not the most
perfect kingdom of them all?
Well, technically, you're not a king.
Uh, Thelonius.
You were saying?
What I meant is, you're not a king yet.
But you can become one.
Just marry a princess.
Go on.
So, just sit back and relax, my Lord...
.. because it's time for you to
meet today's eligible bachelorettes.
And here they are!
Bachelorette #1 is a mentally
abused shut-in from a kingdom far, far away.
She likes sushi and hot-tubbing.
Her hobbies include cooking
and cleaning for her two evil sisters.
Please welcome...Cinderella!
Bachelorette #2 is a girl
from the land of fancy.
Though she lives with 7 other men,
she's not easy.
Kiss her dead, frozen lips
and see what a live wire she is.
Give it up for...Snow White!
And last, but certainly not least...
... Bachelorette #3, a redhead from a dragon-
guarded castle surrounded by hot lava!
But don't let that cool you off.
She likes Pina Coladas...
..and getting caught in the rain.
Yours for the rescuing...Princess Fiona!
So will it be Bachelorette #17
Bachelorette #27
Or Bachelorette #37
Two, three, one. Three.
Pick number three, m'Lord.
Okay! Okay! Uh...number three!
Lord Farquaad,
you've chosen Princess Fiona.
Princess Fiona.
She's perfect.
I'll just find someone to go...
-There's this thing that happens at night...
-I'll do it.
-Yes, but after sunset...
-Silence!
I will make Princess Fiona my queen...
..and DuLoc will
finally have the perfect king!
Captain, assemble your finest men.
We're going to have a tournament.
That's it. That's DuLoc.
I told you I'd find it.
So...
.. that must be Lord Farquaad's castle.
That's the place.
You think maybe
he's compensating for something?
Hey, wait! Wait up, Shrek!
Hurry, darling! We're late!
Hey! You!
Wait a second.
Look, I'm not going to eat you.
I just...Look, I just...
It's quiet.
Too quiet.
Where is everybody?
Look at this!
Welcome to DuLoc Such a perfect town
Here we have some rules
Let us lay them down
Don't make waves, stay in line
And we'll get along fine
DuLoc is a perfect place
Please keep off of the grass
Shine your shoes, wipe your...face
DuLoc is
DuLoc is a perfect place!
Wow.
Let's do that again.
No.
Brave knights!
You are the best
and brightest in all the land!
Today, one of you shall prove...
You're heading for a smacked bottom.
Sorry about that.
The champion shall have the honor...
no, no, the privilege...
.. to go and rescue...
..the lovely Princess Fiona...
.. from the fiery keep of the dragon.
If, for any reason,
the winner is unsuccessful...
. the first runner-up
will take his place.
And so on and so forth.
Some of you may die...
.. but it's a sacrifice
lam willing to make.
Let the tournament begin!
What is that?
It's hideous!
That's not very nice.
It's just a donkey.
Indeed. Knights! New plan.
The one who kills the ogre
will be champion! Have at him!
Oh, hey, now, come on.
Hang on now.
Can't we just settle this over a pint?
No?
All right, then.
Come on!
Hey, Shrek! Tag me! Tag me!
The chair! Give him the chair!
Thank you!
Thank you very much.
I'm here till Thursday. Try the veal.
Shall I give the order, sir?
No, I have a better idea.
People of DuLoc...
...[ give you our champion!
What?
Congratulations, ogre.
You've won the honor of embarking
on a great and noble quest.
I'm already on a quest.
A quest to get my swamp back.
Your swamp?
Yeah! My swamp...where you dumped
those fairy tale creatures.
Indeed.
I'll make you a deal, ogre.
Go on this quest for me,
and I'll give you your swamp back.
Exactly the way it was?
Down to the last slime-covered toadstool.
And the squatters?
As good as gone.
What kind of quest?
So you're going to fight a dragon...
..for a princess,
so Farquaad will return a swamp...
.. you only don't have
‘cause he filled it
with freaks to start with.
You know, maybe there's a
good reason donkeys shouldn't talk.
I don't get it.
Why not pull some ogre stuff on him?
Throttle him, attack his fortress,
grind his bones for bread?
The whole ogre trip.
I know. Maybe I could
decapitate an entire village...
..put their heads on a pike,
get a knife, cut open their spleen...
..and drink their fluids.
Does that sound good to you?
Not really, no.
For your information,
there's more to ogres than people think.
Example?
Okay, um...
..ogres are like onions.
-They stink?
-Yes...No!
-They make you cry.
-No.
You leave them out
in the sun and they get brown.
No! Layers!
Onions have layers.
Ogres have layers. Onions have layers.
Get it? We both have layers.
Ohhh. You both have layers.
You know, not everyone like onions.
Cake! Everyone loves cake!
Cakes have layers.
I don't care what everyone likes.
Ogres are not like cakes.
You know what else
everyone like? Parfaits.
Who ever says,
"No, I don't like parfaits"?
They're delicious.
No! You dense, irritating,
miniature beast of burden!
Ogres are like onions!
End of story. Bye-bye.
See you later.
Parfaits may be the most
delicious thing on the planet.
I think I preferred your humming.
Do you have a tissue or something?
Just the word "parfait"
make me start slobbering.
Shrek, did you do that?
You got to warn somebody
before you crack one off.
Believe me, Donkey,
if it was me, you'd be dead.
It's brimstone.
We must be getting close.
Yeah, right. Brimstone.
I know what I smelled
and it wasn't no brimstone.
Didn't come off no stone, neither.
Sure, it's big enough.
But look at the location.
Shrek, uh, remember when you said...
. that, that ogres have layers?
Well, 1 have a confession.
We wear our fear on our sleeves.
Donkeys don't have sleeves.
You know what I mean.
Don't tell me you're afraid of heights.
No, I'm just uncomfortable being on
a rickety bridge over boiling lava!
Come on, Donkey.
I'll be right here beside you...
..for emotional support.
We'll tackle this together,
one baby step at a time.
-Really?
-Really, really.
That makes me feel much better.
Just keep moving. And don't look down.
Don't look down.
Keep moving. Don't look down.
Shrek! I'm looking down!
I can't do this! Let me off.
You're already halfway.
But I know that half is safe!
I don't have time for this. You go back.
Shrek! Wait!
Let's have a dance. Come on.
Don't do that!
I'm sorry. Do what?
This?
Yes, that!
Yes? Yes. Do it. Okay.
No, Shrek!
-Stop it!
-You just said do it! I'm doing it!
I'm going to die!
I'm going to die! Shrek!
That'll do, Donkey. That'll do.
Cool.
So where is the
fire-breathing pain in the neck?
Inside, waiting for us to rescue her.
l was talking about the dragon, Shrek.
You afraid?
No.
But, shhh.
Good. Me, neither.
There's nothing wrong
with being afraid.
Fear's a sensible response
to an unfamiliar situation.
If a dragon breathes fire and
eats knights and breathes fire...
. it doesn't mean you're a
coward if you're a bit scared.
I know I'm no coward.
Donkey, two things...okay?
Shut. Up.
Go see if you can find any stairs.
Aren't we looking for the Princess?
She'll be up the stairs in the
highest room in the tallest tower.
How do you know?
I read it in a book once.
Cool. You handle the dragon,
I'll handle the stairs.
l'll find those stairs.
I'll whip their butt, too. That's right.
Gonna take drastic steps.
Don't mess with me. I'm the stair master.
I've mastered the stairs.
Wish I had a step now,
I'd step all over it.
There's the Princess.
But where's the...
Dragon!!!
Donkey, look out!
I'm coming!
Gotcha!
No, don't.
No. Oh, no!
What large teeth you have.
White, sparkling teeth.
You probably hear this
all the time from your food.
You must bleach,
‘cause you have one dazzling smile.
Do I detect a hint
of minty freshness?
You know what else?
You're...you're a girl dragon!
I mean, of course you're
a girl dragon, ‘cause...
you're just
teeking of feminine beauty.
What's wrong?
Is something in your eye?
I'd love to stay,
but I'm an asthmatic...
..and it won't work out
if you keep blowing smoke rings.
Shrek!
No, Shrek!
-Wake up.
-What?!
Are you Princess Fiona?
lam.
Awaiting a knight
so bold as to rescue me.
That's nice. Let's go!
But wait, Sir Knight!
This be-ith our first meeting.
Should it not be a
wonderful, romantic moment?
Sorry, lady. There's no time.
What are you doing?
You should sweep me away...
..out yonder window and
onto your valiant steed!
You've had a lot of time
to plan this, huh?
We have to savor this moment.
You could recite an epic poem for me.
A ballad? A sonnet?
A limerick? Something!
I don't think so.
Can I at least
know the name of my champion?
Um...Shrek.
Sir Shrek...
..[ pray that you take this favor
as a token of my gratitude.
Thanks.
You didn't slay the dragon?!
It's on my to-do list. Come on!
But this isn't right. You should go...
.. sword drawn, banner flying.
That's what the other knights did.
Right before they burst into flame.
That's not the point.
Where are you going?
The exit's over there.
Il have to save my ass.
What kind of knight are you?
One of a kind.
Slow down, baby.
I believe it's healthy to get to
know someone over a long period of time.
Just call me old-fashioned.
I don't want to rush into...
..a physical relationship.
I'm not ready for a commitment of this...
.. magnitude, really,
is the word I'm looking for.
That is unwanted physical contact!
What are you doing?
Let's back up and
take this one step at a time.
We should get to know each other
as friends. Or pen pals.
I'm on the road a lot,
but I just love receiving cards.
I'd really love to stay, but...Hey!
Don't do that!
That's my personal tail!
You'll tear it off.
What are you going to do with that?
-Hi, Princess.
-It talks.
Yeah. It's getting him
to shut up that's the trick.
You two, head for the exit!
I'll take care of the dragon.
Run!
You did it!
You rescued me! You're amazing!
You're wonderful! You're...
.a little unorthodox, I'll admit, but...
.. thy deed is great and thine heart is pure.
lam eternally in your debt.
And where would a brave knight
be without his noble steed?
I hope you heard that. She called me
a noble steed. She think I'm a steed.
The battle is won.
You may remove your helmet,
good Sir Knight.
Uhh, no.
Why not?
l have helmet hair.
Please...1 would't look upon
the face of my rescuer.
No, you wouldn't...tst.
But how will you kiss me?
What!?
That wasn't in the job description.
Maybe it's a perk.
No, it's destiny.
You must know how it goes.
A princess locked in a tower
and beset by a dragon...
.. is rescued by a brave knight...
..and then they share
true love's first kiss.
With Shrek? You think...?
Wait a sec. You think
Shrek is your true love?
Well...yes!
You think Shrek is your true love!
What is so funny?
Let's just say I'm not your type, okay?
Of course you are. You're my rescuer.
Now, remove your helmet.
This is really not a good idea.
-Take off the helmet.
-l won't.
-Do it.
-No!
Now!
Okay! Easy.
As you command, Your Highness.
You're an...an ogre.
Oh, you were expecting Prince Charming.
Well, yes, actually.
Oh, no. This is all wrong.
You're not supposed to be an ogre.
Princess, l was sent to rescue you
by Lord Farquaad, okay?
It's he who wants to marry you.
Then why didn't he rescue me?
Good question.
Ask him that when we get there.
But I have to be rescued
by my true love...
.. not by some ogre and his pet.
So much for "noble steed".
You're not making my job any easier.
I'm sorry,
but your job is not my problem.
You can tell Lord Farquaad that
if he wants to rescue me properly...
. I'll be waiting for him right here.
Hey! I'm no one's messenger boy, all right?
I'm a delivery boy.
You wouldn't dare.
-Coming, Donkey?
-Right behind you.
Put me down,
or you will suffer the consequences!
This is not dignified! Put me down!
Here's another question.
This woman digs you,
but you don't like her that way.
How do you let her down real easy without
getting burned to a crisp and eaten?
Just tell her she's not your true love.
Everyone knowest what happens
when you find your...
I can't wait to get to DuLoc.
You'll love it, Princess.
It's beautiful.
And what of my groom-to-be,
Lord Farquaad? What's he like?
Let me put it this way.
Men of Farquaad's stature...
..are in short supply.
I don't know, Shrek...
there are those who think little of him.
Stop it. Stop it, both of you.
You're just jealous you could never measure
up to a great ruler like Lord Farquaad.
Maybe you're right, Princess.
I'll let you do the measuring
when you see him tomorrow.
Tomorrow?
It'll take that long.
Shouldn't we make camp?
No. That'll take longer.
-We can keep going.
-But there are robbers in the woods.
Time out, Shrek.
Camping's starting to sound good.
Come on. I'm scarier than anything
we'll see in this forest.
I need somewhere to camp, now!
Hey, over here.
We can do better than that.
This isn't fit for a princess.
It's perfect.
It just needs some homey touches.
Homey touches? Like what?
A door?
Gentlemen, I bid thee good night.
Want me to read you a bedtime story?
l said good night!
What are you doing?
I just... You know.
Come on, I was just kidding.
And that one.
That's Throwback, the only ogre ever to
spit over three wheat fields.
Right. Yeah.
Can you tell my future from the stars?
The stars don't tell the future.
They tell stories.
Look. There's Bloodnut the Flatulent.
Guess what he was famous for?
Now I know you're making this up.
No. Look. There he is.
And there are the
hunters fleeing his stench.
They're just a bunch of little dots.
Donkey, sometimes things
are more than they appear.
Forget it.
Shrek, what will we do
when we get our swamp?
Our swamp?
When we're through
rescuing the Princess.
We? Donkey, there's no "we".
There's no "our". There's just...
..me and my swamp.
And the first thing I'll do is
build a wall around my land.
You cut me deep, Shrek.
You cut me real deep just now.
You know what? I think this whole wall thing
is just a way to keep someone out.
No. You think?
You hiding something?
Never mind, Donkey.
This is another one
of those onion things.
No, this is one of
those "drop it" things.
-Why don't you want to discuss it?
-Why do you want to?
-Why are you blocking?
-I'm not.
-Yes, you are.
-I'm warning you.
Who you trying to keep out?
Everyone! Okay?
Now we're getting somewhere.
Oh, for the love of Pete!
What's your problem?
What you got against the world?
I'm not the one with the problem.
It's the world that has a problem with me.
People take one look at me and go,
"Aaagh! Help! Run!"
"A big, stupid, ugly ogre!"
They judge me before they even know me.
That's why I'm better off alone.
You know, when we met,
I didn't think you were
just a big, stupid, ugly ogre.
Yeah, I know.
So, are there any donkeys up there?
Well, there's Gabby...
.. the Small and Annoying.
Okay, okay, I see it now.
The big, shiny one right there. Right?
-That's the moon.
-Oh. Okay.
Again. Show me again.
Mirror, mirror...show her to me.
Show me the Princess.
Perfect.
Yeah, you know I like it like that.
Baby, I'll give you a ride.
Donkey, wake up.
Wake up.
Morning.
How do you like your eggs?
Good morning, Princess!
What's this all about?
We got off to a bad start yesterday.
l wanted to make it up to you.
I mean, after all...you did rescue me.
Thanks.
Eat up. We have a big day ahead of us.
-Shrek!
-What? It's a compliment.
Better out than in, I always say.
It's no way to behave in front of a princess.
Thanks.
She's as nasty as you are.
You know,
you're not exactly what I expected.
Maybe you shouldn't judge people
before you know them.
La liberté!
Princess!
-What are you doing?
-Be still, cherie. 1 am your savior!
And lam rescuing you from this green...
. beast.
That's my princess! Go find your own!
Please, monster!
Can't you see I'm busy here?
Look, pal,
I don't know who you think you are..
Of course! How rude.
Please let me introduce myself.
Oh, Merry Men!
I steal from the rich,
give to the needy
-He takes a wee percentage
-But I'm not greedy
l rescue pretty damsels
Man, I'm good
What a guy!
Monsieur Hood!
Break it down.
I like an honest fight
And a saucy maid
-What he means is he likes to get...
-Paid!
When an ogre in the bush
Grabs a lady by the tush, that's bad!
That's bad!
When a beauty's with a beast
It makes me mad!
He's really, really mad!
l take my blade
To ram through your heart
Keep your eyes on me, boys
‘Cause I'm about to start
Man, that was annoying.
Oh, you little...!
Shall we?
Hold the phone.
Whoa, whoa...hold on.
Where did that come from?
That. Back there. That was amazing.
Where did you learn that?
When one lives alone,
one has to learn
these things in case there's...
There's an arrow in your butt!
Look at that.
This is all my fault. I'm so sorry.
-What's wrong?
-Shrek's hurt.
Shrek's hurt?! No, Shrek's gonna die!
Donkey, I'm okay.
No. I'm too young for you to die.
Elevate your legs.
Turn your head and cough!
Do the Heimlich!
Donkey! Calm down.
If you want to help Shrek,
go find me a blue flower with red thorns.
Blue flower, red thorns...I'm on it.
Don't die, Shrek.
If you see a long tunnel,
don't go to the light!
Donkey!
Right. Blue flower, red thorns.
-What are the flowers for?
-For getting rid of Donkey.
Now hold still and I'll yank this out.
Easy with the yanking!
Sorry, but it has to come out. Now..
No, it's tender. Would you..
What you're doing is the opposite of help.
Time out.
Okay. What do you propose we do?
Blue flower, red thorns.
This would be so much easier
if l wasn't color blind!
Hold on, Shrek! I'm coming!
Not good.
Okay, I can nearly see the head.
It's just about..
Nothing happened. We were just, uh....
If you wanted to be alone,
all you had to do was ask.
Come on.
That's the last thing on my mind.
The Princess was just..
Ow.
Hey, what's that? Eh...is that blood?
There it is, Princess.
Your future awaits you.
That's DuLoc?
Shrek thinks Lord Farquaad's
compensating for something.
Which I think means he has a really..
Well, 1 guess we'd better move on.
Sure. But...Shrek?
I'm...I'm worried about Donkey.
I mean, look at him.
He doesn't look so good.
What do you mean? I'm fine.
That's what they all say...
tight before they're on their back.
Dead.
She's right. You look awful.
Do you want to sit down?
I'll make some tea.
Well, 1 do have this twinge in my neck.
When I turn my head like this...Ow! See?
-I'll find us dinner.
-I'll get the firewood.
Hey, where you going?
Oh, man...I can't feel my toes!
I don't have any toes!
I think I need a hug.
This is good. This is really good.
-What is this?
-Weedrat.
Rotisserie-style.
No kidding?
Well, this is delicious.
They're also great in stew.
I don't mean to brag,
but I make a mean weedrat stew.
I guess I'll be dining
a little differently tomorrow night.
Maybe you can come visit me
in the swamp sometime.
I'll cook lots of stuff for you.
Swamp toad soup,
fish eye tartare...you name it!
I'd like that.
Princess?
Yes...Shrek?
I, um...l was wondering.
Are you, uh....
Are you going to eat that?
Man, isn't this romantic?
Just look at that sunset.
Sunset?! Oh, no!
I mean, it's late. It's very late.
Wait a minute.
l see what's going on here.
You're afraid of the dark, huh?
Yes! That's it. I'm terrified.
I'd better go inside.
Don't feel bad.
l was afraid of the dark, too, until.
Hey, wait. I'm still afraid of the dark.
Good night.
l see what's going on here.
What do you mean?
I'm an animal and I got instincts.
I know you two
were diggin’ on each other.
You're crazy.
I'm just bringing her back to Farquaad.
Come on, Shrek.
Wake up and smell the pheromones.
Go tell her how you feel.
There's nothing to tell.
Besides, even if I did tell her...
..well, you know.
I'm not saying I do. 'Cause I don't.
She's a princess, and I'm....
An ogre?
Yeah. An ogre.
-Where are you going?
-To get...more firewood.
Princess?
Princess Fiona?
Princess? Where are you?
Princess?
It's spooky in here.
l ain't playing no games.
No! Help! Shrek!
No! It's okay.
Where's the Princess?!
Donkey! I'm the Princess.
It's me, in this body.
Oh, my God! You ate the Princess!
Can you hear me?
Keep breathing!
I'll get you out of there!
Shrek! Shrek!
This is me.
Princess?
What happened to you? You're...
..uh...duh...different.
I'm ugly, okay?
Was it something you ate?
I told Shrek not to serve rats.
You are what you eat.
No! I've been this way
as long as I can remember.
I never seen you like this before.
It only happens when the sun goes down.
"By night one way, by day, another...
"...this shall be the norm.
"Until you find true love's first kiss...
"and then take love's true form."
That's beautiful.
I didn't know you wrote poetry.
It's a spell!
When I was a little girl,
a witch cast a spell on me.
Every night, 1 become this.
This horrible, ugly beast!
l was placed in a tower to await the day
my true love would rescue me.
That's why I must marry Lord Farquaad
tomorrow before sunset, when he sees me...
. like this.
Okay, calm down.
It's not that bad.
You're not that ugly.
And...Well...
I ain't gonna lie...you are ugly.
But you're only this way at night.
Shrek's ugly 24(7.
But, Donkey, I'm a princess...
..and this is not
how a princess is meant to look!
What if you don't marry Farquaad?
l have to. Only my true love's kiss
can break the spell.
But, you know, you're kind of an ogre.
And Shrek....Well,
you've got a lot in common.
Shrek?
Princess, I....How’s it going,
first of all? Good?
Good for me, too. I'm okay.
I saw this flower and thought of you,
because it's pretty and...
..well, [ don't really like it,
but I thought
you might because you're pretty.
But I like you anyway. I'd..
I'm in trouble.
Okay, here we go.
I mean, really.
Who could ever love
a beast so hideous and ugly?
Princess and ugly don't go together.
That's why I can't stay with Shrek.
My only chance to live happily
ever after is to marry my true love.
Don't you see, Donkey?
That's just how it has to be.
The spell has to be broken.
At least tell Shrek the truth.
No! You can't tell.
No one must ever know.
What's the point of being able to talk
if you have to keep secrets?
Promise you won't tell. Promise.
All right, 1 won't tell him.
But you should.
Before this is over, I'm gonna need
a lot of serious therapy.
My eye is twitching.
I tell him. I tell him not.
I tell him.
Shrek!
Shrek? There's something I want..
-Are you all right?
-Perfect. Never been better.
I have to tell you something.
You don't have to tell me anything.
l heard enough last night.
-You heard what I said?
-Every word.
Well, I thought you'd understand.
I understand.
Like you said,
who could love a hideous, ugly beast?
I thought that wouldn't matter.
Well, it does.
Right on time.
Princess,
I've brought you a little something.
What did I miss?
Who said that? Not a donkey.
Princess Fiona.
As promised. Now hand it over.
Very well, ogre.
The deed to your swamp,
cleared out, as agreed.
Take it and go...
.. before 1 change my mind.
Forgive me, Princess, for startling you,
but you startled me.
Il have never seen
such a radiant beauty before.
lam Lord Farquaad.
Lord Farquaad?
Oh, no.
Forgive me, my Lord,
for l was just saying a short..
.. farewell.
How sweet. You don't have
to waste good manners on the ogre.
It's not like it has feelings.
No, you're right. "It" doesn't.
Princess Fiona...
beautiful, fair, flawless Fiona...
..l ask your hand in marriage.
Will you be the perfect bride
for the perfect groom?
Lord Farquaad, I accept.
Nothing would make..
Excellent! I'll start the plans.
Tomorrow, we wed!
No!
I mean...why wait?
Let's get married today.
Before sunset.
Oh, anxious, are we?
Well, the sooner, the better.
There's much to do!
There's the caterer,
the cake, the band, the guests.
Captain, round up some guests!
Fare thee well, ogre.
Shrek, you're letting her get away!
So what?
You don't know about her.
We talked last night..
Yeah, I know you talked last night.
You're great pals, aren't you?
And since you are,
why don't you follow her home?
But I want to go with you.
I told you,
you're not coming home with me!
I live alone!
My swamp! Me! Nobody else!
Understand? Nobody!
Especially useless, pathetic,
annoying, talking donkeys!
But I thought..
Well, you know what?
You thought wrong!
Shrek.
Donkey?
What are you doing?
You of all people
should recognize a wall.
Well, yeah.
But the wall should go around my swamp,
not through it.
It is. Around your half. This is my half.
Oh, your half.
I helped rescue the Princess.
I did half the work.
I get half the booty.
Hand me that big rock...
the one that looks like your head.
-Back off.
-No, you back off!
-This is my swamp!
-Our swamp!
-Let go!
-You let go!
-Stubborn jackass!
-Smelly ogre!
Fine!
I'm not through with you yet!
I'm through with you!
With you, it's always "me, me, me!"
Well, guess what? Now it's my turn,
so you shut up and pay attention!
You are mean to me, you insult me,
you don't appreciate anything I do.
You either push me around
or push me away!
Well, if I treated you so bad,
why did you come back?
Because that's what friends do!
Forgive each other!
Yeah, you're right, Donkey.
I forgive you...
.. for stabbing me in the back!
You're so wrapped up in layers,
onion boy,
you're afraid of your own feelings!
Go away.
You're doing it like you did to Fiona.
All she did was like you.
Maybe love you.
Love me? She said I was ugly!
A hideous creature.
l heard you two talking.
She wasn't talking about you,
she was talking about...somebody else.
She wasn't talking about me?
Then who was she talking about?
I'm saying nothing.
You don't want to listen to me, right?
-Donkey.
-No.
Okay, look...I'm sorry. All right?
I'm sorry.
I guess I am just a big, stupid, ugly ogre.
Can you forgive me?
That's what friends are for. Right?
Right.
-Friends?
-Friends.
So, um...
..what did Fiona say about me?
Why are you asking me?
Just go ask her.
The wedding!
We'll never make it on time!
Never fear. Where there's a will,
there's a way. And I have a way.
Donkey?
It's just my animal magnetism.
-Come here, you.
-Don't slobber. No one likes a kiss ass.
Hop on and...
. hold on tight.
I haven't installed seat belts yet.
People of DuLoc...
..we gather here today...
..to bear witness to the union...
Excuse me.
Could we just skip to the "I do's"?
Go on.
Go have some fun.
If we need you, I'll whistle.
Wait! Don't you want to do this right?
What do you mean?
There's a line the priest will say.
"Speak now or forever hold your peace.”
Then you say, "I object!"
I haven't time for this.
Listen to me.
You love this woman, right?
You want to hold her? Please her?
Then you gotta,
gotta try a little tenderness!
Chicks love romantic crap.
Okay!
When does this guy say the line?
Let's check.
And so, by the power invested in me...
-Well?
-The whole town's in there.
...l now pronounce you....
They're at the altar.
Mother Fletcher, he said it.
Oh, for the love of Pete!
I object!
Shrek?
Oh, now what does he want?
Hi, everyone. Having a good time?
l love DuLoc. Very clean.
Why are you here?
Yes, it's rude enough being alive
when no one wants you.
But coming uninvited to a wedding!
Fiona, I need to talk to you.
Oh, now you want to talk?
Well, it's too late for that.
-You can't marry him!
-Why not?
He's just marrying you
so he can be king.
Outrageous! Don't listen to him.
He's not your true love.
What would you know about that?
I, uh...
Oh, this is precious.
The ogre has fallen in love
with the Princess!
Oh, good Lord!
An ogre and a princess!
Shrek, is this true?
Who cares?! It's preposterous!
Fiona, my love,
we're but a kiss away from-
-our happily ever after. Now kiss me!
"By night, one way, by day, another."
I wanted to show you before.
That explains a lot.
It's disgusting!
Guards! Guards!
Get that out of my sight!
Now! Get them!
Get them both!
All this hocus-pocus alters nothing!
This marriage is binding,
which makes me king! See?!
Let go of me!
Don't just stand there!
Get out of my way! Fiona!
Insolent beast!
I'll make you regret
the day we met!
I'll see you drawn and quartered!
You'll beg for death to save you!
And as for you, my wife...
.. you'll be locked back up
for the rest of your days!
lam king!
I will have order!
I will have perfection! I will have..
Nobody move! I got a dragon
and I'm not afraid to use it!
I'm a donkey on the edge!
Celebrity marriages...
they never last, do they?
Go on, Shrek.
Fiona?
Yes, Shrek?
...[L love you.
Really?
Really, really.
I love you, too.
AHHH!
Until you find true love's first kiss...
..and then take love's true form.
Fiona?
Fiona. Are you all right?
Well, yes.
But I don't understand.
I'm supposed to be beautiful.
You are beautiful.
l was hoping this had a happy ending.
God bless us, every one!
Come on, y'all!
Oh, that's funny!
I can't breathe. I can't breathe.