CLONE 1: ...breaking a whole unit.
CLONE 2. Fire at will.
REX: Squad 2, pick your target.
CLONE 3: There's too many, Captain!
REX: Watch your stabilizer, Gold 6.
CLONE 3: Anybody, cover me.
I've got two vultures on my tail.
-We gotta hold them here.
-REX: Watch your left!
-l can't shake them! I'm hit! I'm hit!
-Where's our reinforcements?
{STAR WARS THEME SONG PLAYING)
NARRATOR: A galaxy divided!
Striking swiftly
after the Battle of Geonosis,
Count Dooku's droid army has seized
control of the major hyperspace lanes,
separating the Republic
from the majority of its clone army.
With few clones available,
the Jedi generals cannot gain
a foothold in the Outer Rim
as more and more planets choose
to join Deoku's Separatists.
While the Jedi are occupied fighting a war,
no one is left to keep the peace.
Chaos and crime spread,
and the innocent become victims
ina lawless galaxy.
Crime lord Jabba the Hutt's son has
been kidnapped by a rival band of pirates.
Desperate to save his son,
Jabba puts out a call for help.
A call the Jedi are cautious te answer.
Jabba requests that anyone whe can
help us find his kidnapped son
send any information
they have immediately.
We must help Jabba. This is
the opportunity we've been looking for.
The Jedi must rescue Jabba's son.
I don't like it,
dealing with that criminal scum.
This is a dark day for the Republic.
l agree, my friend,
but what choice do we have?
The Hutts control the Outer Rim,
and we'll need their space lanes
in order to move our troops.
There is more to this kidnapping
than it seems.
Then you must send
as many Jedi as you can.
Impossible, Chancellor.
The droid General Grievous
has our forces spread thin.
The only Jedi we can spare
are Skywalker and Kenobi.
They just captured
the planet Christophsis.
Then contact them immediately.
We need to make contact
with General Kenobi.
We've been unable to reach him.
It could be a solar storm,
or they're rebooting
their communication system.
I'm sure the blackout is temporary.
A messenger, we are sending,
with important orders for General Kenobi.
See to it that she gets there
as fast as possible.
Yes, sir.
As soon as we load relief supplies.
No time, there is.
Immediately, the messenger must ga.
l understand, sir. I will personally take
an unloaded ship to drop her off,
then return to pick up my reinforcements.
(GUNS FIRING)
Go, go, go, go, go!
They're back!
I told you this victory was too easy.
We never should have
sent the ship back for supplies.
It wasn't my idea to send the ship back.
All right, men. Second wave incoming.
Rex, you and your men follow me.
Cody, battle positions!
CODY: Up to the front!
(R2-D2 BEEPING)
Incoming!
(SHOUTS)
Skywalker should have attacked by now.
Don't worry! He knows the plan!
What's our plan of attack, sir?
Follow me.
Come on, then!
(GROANS)
-Right on!
-Give it to them!
That's the stuff!
(GROANING)
Come on you traitors!
-Target.
-Careful, lads. There, on the right!
We're gonna need reinforcements.
We haven't been able to
get through to the Admiral.
-Why are we stopping?
-We cannot get past their cannons, sir.
Cannons? This will never do.
We must pull back
and set up our deflector shields.
Turn the troops around!
Retreat! Retreat!
DROID 1: Roger, roger.
DROID 2: Roger, roger.
They're pulling back.
Looks like help has arrived.
(R2-D2 BEEPING)
Our cruiser must be back.
Which means we'll be able
to get our reinforcements.
Then it looks like our problems are solved.
Fresh troops, new supplies,
and perhaps they brought
my new Padawan with them.
You really think it's a good idea
to bring a Padawan learner into all this?
I spoke to Master Yoda about it.
You should put in a request for one.
You'd make a good teacher.
(CHUCKLING) No, thanks.
Anakin, teaching is a privilege.
And it's part of a Jedi's responsibility
to help train the next generation.
A Padawan would just slow me down.
A youngling?
And who are you supposed to be?
(R2-D2 BEEPING EXCITEDLY)
I'm Ahsoka. Master Yoda sent me.
I was told to tell both of you
that you must get back to
the Jedi Temple immediately.
-There's an emergency.
-Well, I don't know if you've noticed,
but we're in a bit of
an emergency right here.
Yes, our communications
have been a bit unreliable,
but we've been calling for help.
Master Yoda hadn't heard from you
so he sent me to deliver the message.
(SIGHS)
Oh, great.
They don't even know we're in trouble.
Maybe you can relay a signal through
the cruiser that just dropped me off.
(CHATTERING)
We need to go back
and pick up our reinforcements.
We've got to get out of here!
We're under attack
by Separatist warships,
but I'll try to make contact with
the Jedi Temple for you. Stand by.
Master Kenobi,
glad Ahsoka found you, am.
Master Yoda, we are trapped here,
and vastly outnumbered.
We are in no position
to go anywhere or do anything.
Our support ships
have all been destroyed.
Send reinforcements to you, we will.
(TRANSMISSION CRACKLING)
Master Yoda? Master Yoda?
We've lost the transmission, sir.
We have to leave orbit immediately.
More enemy ships have just arrived.
We'll get back to you as soon as we can.
Well, l guess we'll have to hold out
a little longer.
My apologies, young one.
It's time for a proper introduction.
I'm the new Padawan learner.
I'm Ahsoka Tano.
I'm Obi-Wan Kenobi, your new master.
I'm at your service, Master Kenobi,
but I'm afraid I've actually been assigned
to Master Skywalker.
What? No, no, no.
There must be some mistake.
He's the one who wanted the Padawan.
No, Master Yoda was very specific.
I'm assigned to Anakin Skywalker,
and he is to supervise my Jedi training.
-But that doesn't make any sense.
-We'll have to sort this out later.
It won't be long before those droids
figure out a way around our cannons.
I'll check on Rex in the lookout post.
You'd better take her with you.
I have brought Jabba's son
to the abandoned monastery.
He will be safe here.
Goed, goad.
Everything is going as planned.
Yes, my lord.
Soon the Jedi will not only be
at war with you, Count,
but the Hutt clan as well.
What's the status, Rex?
Quiet for now, sir.
They're gearing up for another assault.
Who's the youngling?
I'm Master Skywalker's Padawan.
The name's Ahsoka Tano.
Sir, ] thought you said
you'd never have a Padawan.
There's been a mix-up.
The youngling isn't with me.
Stop calling me that!
You're stuck with me, Skyguy.
(LAUGHING)
What did you just call me?
Don't get snippy with me, little one.
You know, I don't even think
you're old enough to be a Padawan.
Well, maybe I'm not,
but Master Yoda thinks I am.
Well, you're not with Master Yoda now.
So, if you're ready,
you better start proving it.
Captain Rex will show you how
a little respect can go a long way.
(STUTTERS) Right.
-Come on, youngling.
-Padawan.
Have you thought about
moving that line back, Captain?
They'd have better cover that way.
Thanks for the suggestion,
but General Skywalker thinks
they're fine where they are.
So, if you're a captain and I'm a Jedi,
then, technically, l outrank you, right?
In my book, experience
outranks everything.
Well, if experience outranks everything,
I guess I better start getting some.
What's that?
Not good. They've got an energy shield.
That's gonna make things
damn near impossible.
If you wanted experience, little one,
it looks like you're about to get plenty.
(GRUNTS)
What is it?
The clones are pulling back,
and the lead tanks are now
approaching the city center.
Get to those heavy cannons
as quickly as you can!
The shield generator is
somewhere in this area.
They're slowly increasing the diameter,
and keeping it just ahead of their troops.
Heavy cannons
are gonna be useless against that.
As they get closer, suppose we could
try to draw them into the buildings.
That might level the playing field a bit.
If that shield's gonna be such a problem,
why don't we just take it out?
-Easier said than done.
-Well, I, for one, agree with her.
Someone has to get to that
shield generator and destroy it.
That's the key.
Right, then. Maybe you two
can tiptoe through the enemy lines
and solve
this particular problem together.
-Can do, Master Kenobi.
-I'll decide what we do.
If Rex and I can engage them here,
you two might have a chance to get
through their lines undetected, here.
They won't have much time.
The droids far outnumber us,
so our ability to street fight is limited
without the use of heavy cannons.
They will march forward under
the protection of their shield
until they are right on top of our cannons,
then they'll blow them away.
We'll figure out a way.
Come on, Master, let's go.
If we survive this, Snips,
you and I are gonna have a talk.
They make quite a pair, don't they, sir?
You think they have a chance?
They better.
If they can't turn off that shield generator
before it reaches the heavy cannons,
there'll be no escape for any of us.
What's the status?
It looks like those bounty hunters
went up there.
Contact General Windu.
Tell him we found the Hutt.
Yes, Commander?
REX: We've discovered that Jabba the Hutt
has alse hired bounty hunters
to track down his son,
and we followed them to
a monastery on planet Teth.
We feel it's where
Jabba's son is being held,
but it's too heavily fortified for us
to do anything alone, sir.
Commander, stay out of sight
and await further orders.
Will do, General.
Unusual, it is, a problem Obi-Wan
has, subduing the droid army.
I'll take care of it.
Get me Admiral Wurtz.
I need three of his star cruisers.
Yes, General.
Greater than we think,
this mystery may be.
Go with the fleet
to aid Master Kenobi, I will.
So, what's the plan?
(SCOFFS) I thought
you were the one with the plan.
No, I'm the one with enthusiasm.
You're the one with the experience, which
I'm looking forward to learning from.
Well, first, we need to get behind
that shield, then get past their tank lines.
Why don't we just go around?
Outflank them?
-That'd take too long.
-Sneak through the middle, then?
Impossible.
Unless you can turn yourself into a droid.
All right. You win.
My first lesson will be to wait
while you come up with the answer.
Well, the wait's over. I've got a plan.
That shield is certainly putting
a crimp in my day.
It's no use, sir! Even at full power
the cannon doesn't affect it.
All right, Rex. It was worth a try.
Tell the men to fall back!
This is a stupid plan!
We should fight these guys,
instead of just sneaking around.
Except for the fact that their deflective
energy shield just passed over us.
If you can't cross their lines,
let their lines cross you.
If you say so.
We're inside the shield.
Just stay away from those tanks.
A Jedi?
-Where's the General?
-CLONE: I don't know, sir!
Fall back!
I think we made it past all of them,
Master. We may pull this off yet.
We still have a ways to go before
we get to the generator station.
Do we still need this thing?
I can't take it anymore.
I have to stand up.
You have got to be careful!
You never know
what you're gonna run into.
See what I mean?
-We can't beat its shield.
-Run!
-What? Jedi don't run!
-Il said, run!
-Ahsoka, stop!
-Make up your mind!
I said, stop!
Good. You take direction well.
They're right behind us, sir!
They wiped out most of my unit.
We had to pull out of there.
(EXPLOSION)
The shield has almost reached
the heavy cannons.
We're not gonna be able to stop them, sir.
Move your troops back
to the heavy cannons.
Do everything you can to protect them.
I'll delay the droids.
-But...
-That is an order, Captain!
(GENERATOR BUZZING)
There it is. Come on.
You must be
the infamous General Kenobi.
I surrender.
Now, Master Kenobi,
order your troops to stand down.
General, have a seat.
Have you gone mad?
I've conceded the battle.
Now we simply have to
negotiate the terms of surrender.
Don't try any of your tricks, Jedi.
Surely there's no reason
we can't be civilized about this.
‘Tis a rare honor to be able to meet
one's opponent face-to-face.
You're a legend
throughout the Inner Core.
Thank you. The honor is all mine.
I'm so glad you decided to surrender.
Well, at some point, one must accept
the reality of the situation.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Might we have some refreshments?
You! Bring us something liquid.
Thank you. This shouldn't take long.
We are approaching Christophsis, sir.
The Separatist blockade
is holding position.
Deploy the fleet.
Have the cruisers protect the transports.
Yes, sir.
Admiral, hurry, we must,
if we are to aid General Kenobi.
It will not be easy to breach the blockade,
Master Yoda.
It's what stopped our relief ships before.
Last time, not as many ships did you have.
Get past it, we must.
Get past it, we will.
Stay close. We've gotta be careful.
-Come on!
-Wait!
Why? We're almost there. It's right...
(BEEPING)
I said, wait!
Forget about the droids!
Set those charges!
(RHYTHMIC BEEPING)
Sorry!
Whose side are you on, anyway?
Setting the charges.
Sir! General Kenobi's been captured!
There's no one else left.
We've got to hold out! We can't
let that shield reach the cannons.
Keep fighting!
I could use a little help!
Skyguy, don't move!
What? No, no, no!
(GRUNTS)
-You could have gotten me killed!
-l know what I'm doing.
-l had everything under control.
-I just saved your life.
CLONE 1: There's too many of them!
CLONE 2: Fall back, fall back!
Man down!
Medic! We need a medic here!
And, of course, once you've
taken custody of my troops,
arrangements will need to be made
for their food and shelter.
-Tell me, do you have enough supplies...
-Enough of this! You are stalling!
Nonsense. General, there are
numerous details to be discussed.
(GRUNTING)
Seize him!
Unless you call off your troops right now,
I will have no choice but to destroy you.
Truthfully, ! was hoping your shield
would be knocked out by now.
-Did you get the charges set?
-Yes.
Then what are you waiting for?
Uh-oh.
Oh, well.
Don't fire!
Something appears
to have happened to your shield, General.
All cannons, fire on those tanks!
What happened to the shield?
General Kenobi, if you can hear me,
we're through the blockade.
The Separatist armada is in retreat.
Your reinforcements
should be landing in a moment.
Your timing is perfect, Master Yoda.
You're reckless, little one.
You never would have made it
as Obi-Wan's Padawan.
But you might make it as mine.
Come on.
Great job, General Skywalker.
You, too, kid.
-Thanks for the ride, Rex.
-Anytime, sir.
Master Obi-Wan.
Master Yoda.
Trouble, you have,
with your new Padawan, I hear.
I was explaining
the situation to Master Yoda.
Really?
If not ready for a Padawan, you are,
then perhaps, Obi-Wan, we can...
No, wait a minute. l admit Ahsoka
is a little rough around the edges.
But with a great deal of training,
and patience,
she might amount to something.
Then go with you, she will,
to the Teth system.
Teth? That's Wild Space.
The droid army isn't even in that sector.
Kidnapped, Jabba the Hutt's son has been.
You want me to rescue Jabba's son?
Anakin, we'll need the Hutts’ allegiance
to give us an advantage over Dooku.
Negotiate the treaty with Jabba,
Obi-Wan will.
Find the renegades that hold Jabba's son,
your mission will be, Skywalker.
Come on, Master,
it doesn't sound that hard.
I'll find Rex and get the troops organized.
Don't worry, Anakin.
Just teach her everything I taught you
and she'll turn out fine.
You know, something makes me think
this was your idea from the start.
Let's just hope Anakin
is ready for this responsibility.
Ready, he is, to teach an apprentice.
To let go of his pupil,
a greater challenge it will be.
Master this, Skywalker must.
If I've got to make a deal
with Jabba the Hutt,
I'd best be on my way.
(BEEPS)
Jabba, the bounty hunters you sent out
to find your son have returned.
(SPEAKING HUTTESE)
(EXCLAIMS)
Contact the Supreme Chancellor
immediately.
The all-powerful Jabba demands to know
why the Jedi are not looking for his son.
Mighty Jabba, rest assured,
the Jedi are on their way.
{SPEAKING HUTTESE)
They better be if you want the Republic
to have safe passage
through Jabba's territory.
Lieutenant, did the kidnappers see you?
No, sir.
We're the best scouts in the regiment.
What about the bounty hunters?
Are they still down there?
I don't think so.
We haven't seen them in a while.
Well, what are we up against?
Looks like at least two droid battalions
protecting a monastery.
It's heavily fortified, sir,
you won't be able to land there.
Good work. Get some rest.
That sounds like a lot, even for a Jedi.
I heard you were surrounded by droids.
How did you ever get the shield down?
Okay, so there's a wall behind him
with a hole in the middle,
so I pull the wall down on top of
the droids, destroying them
and saving the General.
(ALL LAUGHING)
-Is that true, sir?
-Well, most of it.
(ELECTRONIC CHUCKLING)
All right, men, we still got a job to do.
-Yes, sir. You heard the General, move it!
-CLONE: All right, back to business.
Would this be a good time to teach you
that a Jedi is humble, my young Padawan?
Sorry, just trying to keep
the boys inspired, is all.
Don't worry,
I'm sure Jabba's in a good mood.
(BEEPING)
We should not keep the wise
and powerful Jabba waiting.
I wouldn't dream of it.
(BEEPING)
(CHATTERING)
(SHOUTS)
Mighty Jabba, one of our most powerful
Jedi is on his way to rescue your son.
We will not let you down.
(SPEAKING HUTTESE)
The most gracious Jabba
has one more small condition.
He demands you bring back the slime
who kidnapped his little punky muffin.
“Punky”?
Dead or alive.
If you do not succeed,
Count Dooku and his droid army will.
All right, Anakin, here's the story.
Jabba has given us
only one planetary retation
to get his son back home
to Tatooine safe and sound.
Won't take us that long, Master.
Well, take extreme care. We have no idea
who's holding Jabba's sen.
When I've finished negotiations with him,
l will join you.
DROID: There's something coming.
I can't make out what it is.
I don't like it. Prepare to attack.
What if it's one of ours?
-Shut up, Sergeant. I'm in command here!
-Roger, roger.
-Stay close to me, if you can.
-It won't be a problem, Master.
-This isn't practice, Ahsoka.
-I know, and I'll try not to get you killed.
(RUMBLING)
Good shot, boy!
Sir! We're taking heavy fire!
Close the blast shields, Lieutenant!
Get us under those guns!
Yes, sir.
AHSOKA: Here we go.
-Ridge, your com's gone static.
-Got it.
Red light. Stand by.
Welcome to paradise, rockjumpers.
Green light!
Go, go, go!
Move it! Move it!
Watch it! Watch it!
Hurry!
Go, go, go!
Concentrate fire on Sector 11374265!
1137... What was that again?
Just fire right there!
(CLONE TROOPERS SHOUTING)
Follow me!
I can't see them.
Where'd they go?
(EXCLAIMING)
Oh, my God!
Get back here, Sergeant.
-So, this is where the fun begins.
-Race you to the top.
-I'll give you a head start.
-Your mistake.
Ascension cables!
I'm right behind you, Master!
(WEAPONS FIRING)
(EXCLAIMS) Target those walkers!
(GROANING)
(GROANS)
Gotta keep up!
Hey! No fair!
Rex, follow me!
Yes, sir! Working on it.
Get this thing moving!
Surrender, Jedi!
(SHOUTING)
Blast it, Ahsoka,
I told you to stay close to me.
I can't get much closer, Skyguy.
I knew you'd get here, Snips, eventually.
Always in time to save your life.
-All clear, General.
-Nice work, Rex.
Have some men look after the wounded.
REX: Roger that, sir.
Gunships are holding at a safe distance.
The droids have done their part.
Now it's your turn.
ANAKIN: Too many droids here
for them to be renegades.
I sense Count Dooku's hand in this.
Let's find Jabba's son and get outta here.
-No problem. The hard part's over.
-l wish you wouldn't say that.
REX: I don't like this place.
It gives me the creeps.
This looks like one of those
B'omarr monk monasteries
that l read about
in my studies at the Temple.
Smugglers take these monasteries over,
turn them into
their own personal retreats.
And the monks just let them?
Smugglers usually get what they want
one way or another.
(METALLIC RATTLING)
-Good guy or bad guy, Master?
-Who are you?
Merely the humble caretaker,
O mighty sir.
You have liberated me
from those dreadful battle bots.
lam most thankful.
Where is the Hutt?
The battle bots kept their prisoners
on the detention level.
I must warn you it is very dangerous
down there, my friend.
Not a place for a servant girl.
Do servant girls carry these?
lam a Jedi Knight
or soon will be.
A thousand apologies, young one.
Captain, we'll get the Hutt.
Stay here and keep your eyes open.
Copy that, sir.
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
They have taken the monastery, Master.
Skywalker is here.
He's on his way to rescue the Hutt.
Well, done, Ventress.
All is going according to plan.
I could easily take them now.
Patience. Collect the data I need.
You will get your chance
at revenge soon enough.
Mistress, the Jedi
have entered the dungeons.
Master, you know
you're walking us into a trap?
ANAKIN: I know.
-We just passed two more droids.
-l know.
Well, I don't like this.
Can I just take care of them?
Oh, well, if you feel so strongly
about it, go ahead.
(GRUNTING)
Not bad. You remembered to
destroy their weapons first.
I'm improving your technique.
-Of course, you did miss one.
-I did that on purpose.
-l sense our kidnapped Hutt is in here.
-(EXCLAIMS IN DISGUST) I smell him, too.
(WHINING)
He's a lot younger than I thought he'd be.
Oh, he's just a baby.
This will make our job a lot easier.
Oh, he's so cute.
Just wait until you see
what he'll grow into.
(CHATTERING)
I know, R4. l want to get out of here, too.
(BEEPING)
O great Jabba the Hutt,
I have news of your son.
I have discovered it is the Jedi
who have kidnapped him.
(SPEAKING HUTTESE)
How have you come by this information?
I have my ways. More importantly,
mighty Jabba, I bring a warning.
The Jedi are planning to destroy you.
The most wise Jabba demands proof.
And he shall have it.
-No sign of any more droids, Captain.
-All right, Sergeant.
General Skywalker, the castle is secure,
and it's nearly midday.
Thanks, Rex. We've got Jabba's son.
Any sign of General Kenobi yet?
Wo, sir.
Master, my Jedi training didn't prepare me
for this. What are we gonna do?
Well, since you think that smelly larva
is cute, you're gonna carry it.
(WHINING)
Commander, tell Admiral Yularen
to get underway.
-We need to reinforce Anakin.
-Right away, sir.
How do you like your little buddy now?
Still cute?
You know, he's reminding me
of you more and more.
See? You're two of a kind.
Maybe you should carry both of us then.
(WHINING)
(COUGHS)
Master, I think this little guy is sick.
He's burning up with a fever.
You're right. We've got to get him back
to the ship immediately.
Trooper! Get me a backpack!
AHS OKA: Will you just let me do it?
ANAKIN: I hate Hutts.
VENTRESS: My lord,
I have the recording you requested.
Transmit it at once. Your new objective
is to recover the Hutt.
And deliver him to Jabba unharmed?
Precisely. Do not fail me.
AHS OKA: Will you just let me do it?
ANAKIN: I hate Hutts.
(GRUNTING)
(SQUEALING)
As you can see, it is the Jedi who have
your son and are plotting against you.
(SPEAKING HUTTESE)
My droid army
has already initiated a rescue.
Rest assured, mighty Jabba,
your son will be saved.
Mighty Jabba wishes to know
what you ask in return.
Perhaps you would consider joining
our struggle against the Republic.
OBI-WAN. Anakin,
did you locate Jabba's son?
We have him, but it looks like
the Separatists are behind his abduction.
This smells like Count Dooku to me.
I think it's little Stinky you smell.
I'll bet Dooku is using us
to get Jabba to join the Separatists.
Master Kenobi, we have another problem.
This Huttlet is very sick.
I'm not sure we can get him back
to Tatooine alive, Master.
This whole rescue may backfire on us.
I still don't think dealing
with the Hutts is a good idea.
Anakin, you know they control
shipping routes in the Outer Rim.
Jabba's cooperation is crucial
to the war effort.
if you let anything happen te his son,
our chances ofa treaty
with him will disappear.
Master? We've got trouble!
Defensive positions!
-Anakin?
-I'll have to call you back, Master.
We're under attack. We could use
a little help here if you have the time.
I'll get there as soon as can.
Protect the Hutt, Anakin.
CLONE: We've got spiders inbound!
Get inside!
(GROANS)
Fall back!
Fall back! Fall back!
Mistress, the Jedi have barricaded
themselves inside the main vault.
They have nowhere to run.
Captain, we'll stay here until General
Kenobi arrives with reinforcements.
-What?
-Master,
do you honestly think
we can hold them off?
We've got to find a way out of here.
Our mandate is to protect this Hutt,
and that's what
we're going to do, Ahsoka.
Our mandate was to get this Hutt
back to Tatooine,
-and time is running out.
-l suppose you have a plan.
(R2-D2 BEEPING)
Yes, or I think so, R2 willing.
All right, Snips. I'll trust you on this one.
Captain, hold them here
as long as you can.
REX: Will do, sir. You heard the General!
Get ready to turn those clankers
into scrap metal!
AHSOKA: If there's a way out of here,
Artooie will find it.
Make it quick.
Finally asleep, huh? Put him down.
Get some rest yourself.
It's been a long day for you, little one.
I can hold him, Master. I'm not tired.
Okay, suit yourself. 1 don't see why
you won't just listen to me.
I do listen to you, Master.
I just don't like
being treated like a youngling.
You must have patience.
What are you trying to prove anyway?
That I'm not too young
to be your Padawan.
Ahsoka, a very wise Jedi once said,
“Nothing happens by accident.”
It is the will of the Force
that you are at my side.
I just want to keep you there in one piece.
-The red one?
-No.
-The blue one?
-No, not that one.
That'll work.
They've cut the lock!
Here they come!
Hold the line!
Second wave! Second wave!
Watch your left!
That sounded bad.
(R2-D2 BEEPING)
A backdoor landing platform!
We'll call for a gunship when we get there.
Lead the way, R2.
Ahsoka, wait. Where's Stinky?
-You told me to put him down!
-Find him!
(GRUNTING)
Come outta there, you grubby little slug.
(YELPING)
Take care of what's left of the clones.
I'll go after Skywalker.
Roger, roger.
Seal the main gate and all portals.
Let nothing escape this castle.
Yes, Mistress.
(LIGHTSABER WHOOSHING)
(GRUNTING)
Where is Skywalker?
I don't talk to Separatist scum.
You will contact Skywalker now.
REX: I will contact Skywalker now.
Let's see you get away this time.
-REX: Anakin, come in.
-"Anakin"?
-We've held the draids, sir.
-That's not like Rex.
-What is your location?
-Ventress.
Dooku's assassin?
She's here to kill the Hutt. Come on.
Mistress, l must inform you that
Republic reinforcements have arrived.
-We must hurry.
-Roger, roger.
Skywalker is in trouble.
You know the drill.
Copy that, sir.
VENTRESS:
The Jedi warships have arrived.
You must hold them off until I finish
my mission. Do you understand?
Yes, sir. 1 mean, ma‘am, sir.
Launch all fighters!
(BEEPING)
Skywalker to Obi-Wan.
Mark my position.
I need a medical ship immediately.
-Do you copy?
-Anakin, do you read me?
Anakin.
Come in!
They're jamming our transmissions.
I hope Anakin is having an easier time
than we are.
I can't get ahold of Obi-Wan.
I'll see if l can find Captain Rex.
ANAKIN: Come in, Rex. De you copy?
Rex?
-Did you hear that?
-It came from the prisoners.
REX: Let me show you
how it works, clanker.
ANAKIN: De you copy?
Captain Rex, respond.
l read you, General.
We're pinned down in the courtyard.
Do you need help?
I'll take that as a yes, Captain. Stand by,
we're on our way. Skywalker, out.
Master, Stinky is really sick.
He's turning every shade of green
except the one he's supposed to be!
Our mission was to
get him back to Tatooine alive.
Obi-Wan will get here eventually.
Right now, we need Rex
to help us find a ship.
Great. Rolling death balls.
R2, the door!
(BEEPING)
(GRUNTS)
-I think now's a good time for a retreat.
-"Retreat"? That's a new word for you.
Maybe into the jungle.
Wait, l remember the jungle
was a bad place.
So much for going that way.
We can't hold out much longer, sir!
Where's General Skywalker?
He'll be here.
Looks like we're out of options.
(WHIMPERING)
No, not now, Stinky.
Master! Another landing platform!
-With a ship on it.
-Nice work, Stinky.
-So, how are we gonna get over there?
-Leave that to me.
(EXCLAIMING)
I hope I don't have to learn that.
(GROANS)
Where is Skywalker?
Right here, Ventress!
(EXCLAIMS)
Time to go.
(WHISTLES)
-Hop on, Snips.
-Like I have a choice!
(R2-D2 BEEPING NERVOUSLY)
(EXCLAIMS)
(SHOUTS)
Count Dooku demands a report
soe
on your mission.
Should I tell him they got away or what?
(WAILING) Why?
I'm hit! I can't shake them!
Just relax, Odd Ball. I'm right behind you.
Thank you, sir. I'm sorry I panicked.
OBI-WAN: That's all right, Odd Ball.
lt happens to everybody.
It looks like there's some kind of battle
on the east side of the palace.
I see it, sir.
And if there's a battle,
Anakin's probably in the middle of it.
We'll start looking for him there.
All ships, follow me.
AHSOKA: We're taking this junker?
We'd be better off on that big bug.
Get aboard and prime the engines.
Assuming it has engines.
Hey! You're that caretaker droid.
I wondered what happened to you.
Oh, young one.
I mean, soon to be Jedi Knight.
I had to get away from that terrible...
Okay, everything's loaded.
Let's get out of here.
Why, you tin-plated traitor!
Blast her!
She's at it again. Let's go.
Don't you dare!
Don't...you...dare.
Commander Cody, prepare the gunships
for ground assault.
Yes, sir.
Go, go, go!
This is it! Scrap them!
Take over, R4.
(BEEPING)
-Surrender, Republic dogs!
-We've got you outnumbered!
Outnumbered? Wait. One, two, three...
-Where's Skywalker?
-Best guess is he's still in the castle, sir.
Keep the droids occupied. I'll go find him!
Have you recovered Jabba's son?
Skywalker is still in possession of the Hutt
and has temporarily eluded me,
but he will not escape the system alive.
Need I remind you
whoever gains Jabba's favor
will control the war in the Outer Rim?
Only we must be allowed
to return Jabba's son to him alive.
fl understand, Master.
l will double my efforts.
l hope so, for your sake.
Wait!
Master Kenobi.
Always chasing after Skywalker.
How predictable.
Anakin leaves quite a mess.
Which always leads me to you, Ventress.
Take him.
Now let's get Stinky out of here.
If we can.
(ENGINE STALLING)
(GROANS)
Relax, Snips. R2, see if you can
spark the ignition couplers.
(R2-D2 BEEPING)
No, that's not it.
Try opening the fuel lifters all the way.
(POWERING UP)
Good work, buddy.
Master Kenobi is here.
Now we'll see some real fireworks.
Excuse me? What do you call
what I've been doing all day?
I don't know.
The word “reckless” comes to mind.
Very funny, Snips. Back to work.
The troops still need our help.
Charge the main guns.
How are we gonna help?
Stinky's getting sicker and sicker.
But we promised Rex we'd help them.
Master, we've got to get him to
the medics on the Jedi cruiser.
It's our only chance to get Stinky
back to his father still breathing.
(WHIMPERING)
Captain Rex, this is General Skywalker.
Yes, General.
We're not going to be able help you.
Don't worry about us, General.
We'll be all right.
The mission always comes first, sir.
Cover me!
(POWERING UP)
Ventress, I know you're here.
You can't hide. I feel your frustration.
Let me guess,
you're after Jabba's young son, too.
(GRUNTS)
(GRUNTING)
You'll have to do
better than that, my darling.
Well, now I'm impressed.
Now you die.
(GRUNTING)
-Shall we continue?
-My pleasure.
Master, today I did my best
to stay calm, focused,
and when I did,
everything seemed so easy.
Well, get focused,
‘cause things just got a lot harder.
All we've got to do
is land on that Jedi cruiser.
But, Master,
their deflector shields are up!
(GASPS)
They must think this grease bucket
is an enemy ship.
-Jedi cruiser, hold your fire!
-CLONE: Whe is that?
Incoming ship, identify yourself.
Captain, what's going on down there?
CLONE: Repeat, identify yourself.
This is General Skywalker.
We have Jabba the Hutt's son.
He needs medical attention.
We must board immediately.
-Stand by.
-Stand by? That's helpful.
(RUMBLING)
Hang on!
(BEEPING)
(SHOUTING)
Open the main hangar door
and lower the deflector shields.
You got it, sir.
General Skywalker, we think we can
lift the shields on the lower rear hangar.
We're on our way!
We've made it! We've made it!
General Skywalker, abort! Abort!
That changes our plans.
Looks like we're gonna have to take this
bucket of bolts all the way to Tatooine.
(GRUNTING)
We know of Dooku's plot to turn
the Hutts against us. It will not succeed.
It will when the truth dies with you.
You can't run.
We're clear
to make the jump to hyperspace.
R2, program the navicomputer.
(BEEPING)
I don't think he's gonna make it, Master.
There's gotta be
something we can do for him.
Take a look in the back.
See if you can find some medical supplies.
I'm on it.
(WAILING SOFTLY)
Don't die on me now, little guy.
Just hang in there.
If you've locked the coordinates,
R2, let's go.
(BEEPS)
I sense it, too. Anakin is gone.
You've failed, Ventress.
(VENTRESS GRUNTS)
Your master will not be pleased.
Jedi scum!
The Hutt is safe.
There's no point to fighting any longer.
We've won. Lay down your weapon.
(BEEPS)
(GRUNTS)
Looks like this hasn't been used in a while.
Hey, Dr. Droid, can you hear me?
Yes. What seems to be the problem?
Great. I've got a sick Huttlet.
You got a remedy?
Oh, yes. I see.
You must dispense one of these
medical boosters into the infant's mouth.
if you have any problems,
please call an actual doctor to assist you.
I hope this works.
Okay, sweetums.
I've got some yum-yum for you.
You'll take this and like it!
(BELCHES)
There you go. Good boy.
Captain, I understand
General Skywalker escaped.
REX: Yes, sir.
On some beat-up old space freighter.
I'll be surprised if he even makes it
to Tatooine in that junker.
If anybody can fly a bucket of bolts
through hyperspace, he can.
AHSOKA: The medicine, it's working!
His fever broke. I think
he's gonna live to stink another day.
Great. Keeping him alive wasn't as easy
as you'd hoped, was it?
Master, if you have taught me one thing,
it's that nothing is easy
when you are around.
You think Rex and Master Obi-Wan
made it out okay?
If 1 know my old master, he has things
well in hand. Now help me with this.
I want the primary systems fully repaired
by the time we reach Tatooine.
You grew up on Tatooine, right?
So, for you, this trip is like going home.
Yeah.
Home.
VENTRESS: The Republic had too many
clone troopers, my lord.
By the time we were able to find
Jabba's son, Skywalker had already
killed him.
(ALL MURMURING)
(GRUNTING)
Most unfortunate.
This is a very unexpected turn of events.
I take it you at least defeated the Jedi?
No, Master. The Jedi escaped
and are headed to Tatooine.
I'm sure you did the best you could.
We will discuss your failure later.
Yes, my master.
(SPEAKING HUTTESE)
Glorious Jabba demands to know why
the Jedi would dare come to Tatooine.
To kill you, Jabba.
The Jedi plot is quite clear now.
They only promised to rescue your son
to win your trust.
Now Skywalker is coming here
to finish his true mission...
to wipe out the entire Hutt clan.
If it pleases you, mighty Jabba,
this time I will deal
with Skywalker personally.
I was hoping I'd never have to lay eyes
on this dust ball again.
Okay. What happened?
I don't want to talk about it.
How's Stinky holding up?
He seems to be feeling much better.
His fever is gone. Even you have to admit
he's cute when he's asleep.
l admit I like him better when he's quiet,
but only a little.
(BEEPING)
No, R2.
I want the cannon operational first.
Leave the rear deflector shields for later.
No rear shields, Master?
That's awful risky.
A strong attack
eliminates the need for defense, Snips.
(ALARM SOUNDING)
Attack ships closing!
Somebody doesn't want Stinky
to get home in one piece.
Wow! Quite a welcome home party!
(R2-D2 BEEPING)
Set the approach vector
and make ready to land.
(BEEPS)
Ahsoka, activate the guns!
All the guns
are locked in the forward position.
It's too bad you decided not to repair
the rear deflector shields.
Not now, Ahsoka!
R2, see if you can unlock those guns!
Sometimes a good defense
is the best offense.
Why don't you go
secure your little Huttlet friend?
None of us are secure with you flying!
Hang on, back there!
(EXCLAIMING)
(WAILING)
Great! You woke the baby!
I'm a little busy here!
-Got one of them!
-What about the other one?
One thing at a time!
I think we needed
those rear shields after all.
I told you so!
R2, turn those guns around!
R2!
Why can't you be a tiny little mouse droid?
(BEEPING)
Get him, R2!
(R2-D2 BEEPING)
Good shot, buddy!
You've been holding out on me.
Ahsoka, strap in.
-You've got that “we're in trouble” look.
-There's a look?
-You can't miss it.
-Very funny, Snips.
Obi-Wan, come in! Do you copy?
Kenobi, here. Anakin,
have you reached Tatoaine yet?
-Almost, but we ran into some old...
-Anakin, did you get shot down again?
Yes!
This ship is too slow.
I haven't had time to modify it yet.
I'm still cleaning up your other mess,
but I'll get there.
So much for reinforcements.
Hang on, this landing
could get a little rough.
Crashes are rough. Landings are not.
Then it's a crash landing.
(SHOUTING)
Mighty Jabba, my battle droids
have shot down Skywalker's ship.
(SPEAKING HUTTESE)
Jabba will send out his bounty hunters
to see that he is dead.
Allow me. I have much more experience
dealing with Jedi.
OBI-WAN: Anakin has reached Tatooine
with the Huttlet, Master,
but he’s still in grave danger.
Separatist troops
are desperate to intercept him.
think this whole plot
was engineered by Dooku
to convince Jabba we kidnapped his son.
If believe this, the Hutts do, ended will
our chance of a treaty with them be.
Join Dooku and the Separatists,
Jabba will, yes.
That would be a disaster.
We must have this alliance with the Hutts
if we are to win the war in the Outer Rim.
In Skywalker is the Republic's only hope.
Return Jabba's son, he must.
Anakin's experience with the Hutts
should help. He'll come through.
Please, excuse me, Master Yoda.
I must return to
the grand adventure of politics.
-Greetings, Senator Amidala.
-Master Yoda. So good to see you.
Good, it is, to see you, Senator.
Padmé. We were to discuss...
The new security measures
you put into effect on Naboo.
My security chief tells me there are
several new battles in the Outer Rim.
Including a small skirmish
with Obi-Wan Kenobi and Anakin.
Anakin? Is he in danger?
I'm afraid the Jedi's efforts
to strike a secret treaty with the Hutts
have gone terribly wrong.
Jabba believes Anakin
has abducted his infant son.
A Jedi would never do such a thing!
Perhaps I can get that treaty signed.
I will go to the Hutts and convince them
of Anakin's innocence,
as a representative
of the Senate, of course.
That is very courageous of you, Senator,
but far too dangerous.
Besides, we've attempted
to contact Jabba,
he won't accept communication from us.
Jabba the Hutt has an uncle in the
old downtown area here on Coruscant.
Perhaps I can reason with him
and reopen negotiations.
Please, my dear, I beg you, reconsider this.
Don't worry, Chancellor, I've dealt
with far worse than the Hutts.
Do take care, Senator.
The Hutts are vile gangsters.
Welcome home, Stinky.
Jabba's palace is on
the far side of the Dune Sea.
We'd better hurry
if we're gonna make it by morning.
(WHIMPERING)
(CRIES)
I'm coming.
(R2-D2 BEEPING NERVOUSLY)
Oh, Artooie, it's just endless tracts
of gritty, abrasive sand.
I'll clean your servos later. Come on.
(CHATTERING)
(JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING)
O exalted majesty.
What is it, Kronos-327?
My mission to the twelfth moon
of Yout has failed.
(LAUGHING)
After all these years
my most trusted of assassins
has finally failed.
O Ziro the Hutt,
master of the Hutt clan on seven systems,
lam sorry, your highness.
It will not happen again.
I know. Take him away
-and use him for spare parts!
-No, no! No!
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
(ZIRO CHUCKLING)
Your majesty,
you have an important visitor.
Greetings, Ziro. 1am Senator Amidala
of the Galactic Congress.
A senator? In this neighborhood?
Hmm.
I know that you are the uncle
of Jabba the Hutt of Tatooine.
I come to ask a favor of you.
A favor? Hmm?
There has been a grave misunderstanding
between Jabba and the Order of the Jedi.
How may I serve you, Senator?
I was hoping you and I could resolve
this dispute and broker a treaty
between the Republic
and the great clan of the Hutts.
A treaty? A treaty?
A treaty is impossible.
My nephew Jabba's son has been
kidnapped by your Republic Jedi scum.
But, sir, there's been a misunderstanding.
There is no misunderstanding.
It is the Jedi who have rescued his son.
If you can put me in touch with Jabba,
lam confident
I can convince him of the truth.
No! No more discussions.
Escort her out!
Please, Ziro! Your nephew Jabba
is in danger. You're being deceived.
I said throw her out.
Don't touch me.
(SQUEAKING)
Master Yoda has a saying.
“Old sins cast long shadows.”
Do you know what he means by that?
He means your past can ruin your future
if you allow it.
But you forget
it was Master Skywalker who said,
“[ don't want to talk about my past.”
Okay, fine.
There is so much more we can talk about
out here. Like the sand.
The desert is merciless.
It takes everything from you.
That's a happy thought. It won't
take us, Master. Right, Artooie?
(BEEPING)
(GRUNTING)
Your plot is coming apart, Count Dooku!
A senator from the Republic was here.
What if she found out
I helped you kidnap Jabba's son?
Don't worry, l have convinced Jabba
that the Jedi have murdered his son
and are on their way to kill him.
Jabba will slay the Jedi on sight!
Then the mighty Jedi Order will be forced
to bring Jabba to justice,
and you, my friend, will be left
to take control of all the Hutt clans.
Then the plot against my nephew Jabba
has succeeded.
But what about this meddling senator?
if she continues her investigation,
have her meet with an accident
with extreme prejudice.
! will have someone in the Senate
cover jt up.
Count Dooku.
So, the poisonous traitor
rears his ugly head once again.
I'm equally delighted to remake
your acquaintance, Senator
Amidala, isn't it?
I was just leaving.
I'm sorry, that cannot be permitted now.
Ziro, this particular senator is
extremely valuable to my Separatist allies.
They will pay a handsome price for her.
Hmm.
I like the sound of that.
Take her to the dungeon!
You will regret this, Ziro!
No, I think I will become rich with this!
(LAUGHING)
Thank you, Count Dooku.
This has been a mest profitable alliance.
I will contact you when the Huttlet
has been disposed of,
your high exalted master of the Hutts.
Count Dooku, we have picked up
three life forms crossing the desert.
One is a very young Huttlet.
Skywalker.
(DISTANT CHATTERING)
We're not alone.
I sense it, too.
It's the dark side of the Force.
(WHIMPERING)
Whatever it is, it's coming for the Hutt.
Time to split up.
We'll face it together, Master.
Not this time, Snips. l have a far more
important mission for you.
More important than keeping you alive?
Ahsoka, I need you to
trust me on this one.
(BEEPING)
What's that?
Don't touch that! Whatever you do,
keep away from it.
Please. I beg you.
Don't turn that on.
Could be dangerous. I better check it out.
At last, you answered!
Oh, I've been so worried.
Wait! Whe are you?
You're not Mistress Padmé!
3PO, get help!
I'm being held by Ziro the Hutt!
You're in trouble! I knew it!
Wait, wait!
Surrender the Huttlet or die, Skywalker.
Your training has come a long way, boy.
Now I remember.
This was your home planet, wasn't it?
I sense your strong feelings.
Feelings of pain, loss.
(WIND HOWLING)
You've failed, Jedi.
Il have just killed Jabba's son.
You've fallen for my little trick, Count.
It's nothing but rocks.
The Huttlet is with my Padawan,
safely at Jabba's palace.
l expected such treachery from a Jedi.
l assure you my web is strong enough
to catch your insignificant little Padawan.
She's more skillful than you think.
You deceive yourself!
Look, I have a message
from your Padawan.
(GRUNTING)
(SCREAMING)
After my droids kill Jabba's son,
they will deliver your Padawan to him
for punishment for the Huttlet's murder.
I can't imagine he will be merciful.
(LAUGHING MALICIOUSLY)
(BEEPS)
R2!
Three against two?
Stinky, you watch my back!
(WAILING)
I thought you liked to play in the sand.
This part of town is definitely
not my kind of town.
(ZIRO EXCLAIMS)
You tried to call for help, Senator.
I believe you are too dangerous
to be kept alive.
Killing a Galactic Senator,
here on Coruscant?
Are you out of your mind?
I have powerful friends in the Senate.
(RAPID BEEPING)
I'm not afraid of... Huh?
(EXPLOSION)
C-3P0: Is anybody home?
3P0?
What is that?
-Go, go, go!
-Give it all you got.
Run for it!
Stop, Ziro! Stop right where you are!
Mistress Padmé, are you all right?
Was I too late?
3PO. Your timing was perfect.
Oh, thank the maker! I'm so relieved.
-Should we arrest the Hutt, Senator?
-l had no choice.
Dooku said he'd kill me if I didn't help him
kidnap Jabba's son.
You have to believe me!
Il love that Huttlet!
Oh, I believe you.
Master! Over here! Master!
(GROANS)
He never listens.
-Where is my Padawan?
-This way.
Your weapon, please.
Okay, stick-tinnies, you're going back
to Dooku in pieces.
This is Jedi Knight Anakin Skywalker.
As Count Dooku said,
your son is not with him.
What? Your son's not here?
(SPEAKING HUTTESE)
Where's Ahsoka?
What have you done with my Padawan?
You came here to kill Jabba.
Mighty Jabba, I came here to negotiate.
Being a Padawan is harder than I thought.
Let's get you home.
You came here to die.
AHSOKA: Stop!
(R2-D2 BEEPS)
(SPEAKING HUTTESE)
(HUTTLET WAILING)
You are to be executed immediately.
-What?
-Does this always happen to you?
-Everywhere I go.
Your Uncle Ziro is contacting us.
Greetings, honorable Jabba.
fam Senator Amidala
of the Galactic Congress.
l have discovered a plot against you
by one of your own.
Your uncle will admit he conspired
with Count Dooku toe kidnap your son
and frame the Jedi for the crime.
(SPEAKING HUTTESE)
{SPEAKING HUTTESE)
lt was Count Dooku!
Ziro will be dealt with
by the Hutt family most severely.
Perhaps now you will allow the Republic
to use your trade routes
and hostilities can come te an end.
(CHUCKLING)
Jabba agrees. A treaty is in order.
You will net regret this, Jabba.
The clone armies
may move through Jabba’'s territories.
Senator, you have my undying gratitude.
No, Master Skywalker, it is 1
and the Republic, whe owes you thanks.
Jabba would be most appreciative
if you bring Dooku to justice
for his crimes against the Hutts.
You can count on it, Jabba.
It is unfortunate, Master.
The Jedi armies will now have
their supply routes to the Outer Rim.
Our fight has become far more difficult.
Allow the Jedi
their small victory, my friend,
for the engines of this war
turn in our favor.
{STAR WARS THEME SONG PLAYING)
English - SDH