Hi. Welcome to Surf's Up.
Audio commentary.
I will be your guide...
.. through this wonderful presentation
of Surf's Up.
I'm Chris Buck, one of the directors.
Ash Brannon, another director.
And I'm Chris Jenkins
and I make the coffee.
And it's good coffee too.
Not that crystal stuff.
And he's the producer, okay,
here we go.
Hey, look at that logo, guys.
We came up with the logo
just for Surf's Up.
Here we are.
Okay.
Interesting thing about this one
was that...
.. this was the last scene created
and the first scene in the movie.
But the movie originally started
with the sequences coming up...
.. which was what we call
the legend sequence, right?
And, Ash, you boarded the whole bit--
The sort of history of surfing.
-Yeah.
-We thought that we needed Cody.
Cody to introduce it and get to know
Cody a little bit more before--
Yeah, it was originally
a disembodied voice.
You didn't know who it was.
Okay, everybody wants to know...
.. why a documentary, right, guys?
Why do an animated documentary?
Lots of reasons.
First of all, surf videos are actually
made that way.
And we thought it would be cool...
..to do the subject of Surf's Up
as a surf documentary.
Well, there was originally
a storyline, right?
When Chris Jenkins was on this
about four and a half years ago.
It was 48 years ago, actually.
It was a comedy based
on Romeo and Juliet.
Yes, it was, Ash Brannon.
Thank you.
And they were racing cars...
..and they were wearing clothes
and all that, right?
Yeah, and they were dressed
as policemen...
..and they were falling off cliffs
and dying and--
-Isn't really a comedy.
-Okay.
-And how did it become this, Chris?
-It became this--
It became this when, you know...
. I'm kind of looking at the idea
of doing a surf movie.
And looking at the prevalence
for surf docs...
.. movies to be done
as documentaries.
Or for the whole reality TV thing
to be realized in animation.
-Did that make sense?
-Yeah, kind of. In a Welsh kind of way.
And the storyline was designed
to work as a documentary.
We had to imagine that there was a kid
we heard about who's up and coming.
We decided to send a crew
down there and follow him...
..as he went to his first contest.
And then follow him.
Yeah, and be able to just put
a camera--
Not a camera. What do they call
the things where you--?
-Like a microphone.
-Microphone, yeah.
Like that thing in front of you
right now.
But it's interesting, we had rules.
Like, we never saw
the documentarians. We never--
No, people really wanted to know
who the documentarians are.
-What species.
-Yeah.
And we felt that if we did that...
.. then we would really be winking
at the audience...
..in a particular way, you know?
It would be more--
I suppose, more mockumentary
in that way...
.. than we wanted it to be.
And the thing, I think,
that fascinated me was that...
..we could get inside
an animated character's head.
Via the interviews, you can find out
what these guys were thinking...
..and what they just thought
about the scene that we just shot.
I don't know. It's something
that we'd never done before...
..in other animated movies.
There was a lot of things going on,
the idea that in this day and age...
.. everybody seems to have an opinion
or reaction to a camera...
.. being put in their face and they have
an opinion about something.
Maybe they're hiding things.
Maybe they wanna use it
as a confessional.
And it just felt it was the right time
to take an animated feature...
..and really follow the inner life
of these characters on the screen.
Well, people are fascinated
by the documentary and reality TV.
I mean, I know that's what we watch
at home.
There's so many of those shows
who love it.
I mean, a lot of times, it's what,
you know...
.Jit's what the camera catches
that they weren't supposed to catch...
.. that everybody loves.
Or the thing that somebody
said that, you know...
.. they didn't really mean to say this
or whatever...
...but it's very telling.
The-camera-doesn't-lie
kind of thing, so....
-We planned in a kind of spontaneity.
-It's fun.
Planned spontaneity.
Planned these things, like the camera
would stay on a character...
.. after they'd finished saying
what they were gonna say.
And their reaction, then,
after their last sentence...
..Was more telling
than what they were trained to tell you.
And it wasn't easy
the whole way through.
There are a lot of rules we set up
for ourselves.
And it was tough
between the camera work...
.. where the camera could be.
The type of questions
that we would ask these guys.
When the character's
aware of the camera or not.
These are rules,
set of rules that we had.
Once in a while, we'd break them.
And we can talk about those
as we go through this but....
It's kind of
the whole documentary thing.
Remember, we had lots of talk about,
you know...
.. where the camera crew
is coming from...
..and how did they get there.
All the kinds of things
that quite honestly in the end--
-Nobody thinks about.
-Yeah.
He can't help it.
That's just the way he is.
It was important
when we started the movie...
...we knew it was a surf movie,
but the surfing is really a metaphor.
And we didn't want the film just to be
about surfing per se.
And we came across an article...
.. by some guys named
the Malloy brothers.
They said something interesting.
They said, "A lot of surf movies
don't get it right.
They think it's all about just riding
the waves.
And it's really about life
and the way you live it."
And we just really fell in love
with that concept.
Being one with the wave
and with life--
And that's how we, you know,
faced the production every day.
We came in
to have a good time every day.
-Not gonna touch you.
-Do you see this?
-Don't. Please?
-I'm not.
Well, now, Shiverpool's...
.. kind of inspired
by an Errol Morris film...
..he did one about a
town in Florida...
.. where nothing happens.
This is where, again,
we play with-- This whole sequence...
..we play with the whole
documentary feel.
Like you're saying,
that's an Errol Morris film.
The cutting that we did,
we kept moving things around.
And then the interviews.
Yeah, our editor Ivan Bilancio
kind of took all these moments...
..as if he had coverage.
And just found an entertaining way
to intercut them.
Kind of a proof of concept,
this whole sequence, in a way.
Right, ! remember this is one
of the first ones.
And it was really interesting how...
..when Errol came in
to take a look at the stuff...
..and we were calling it
a mockumentary...
..he said, "It's not a mockumentary.
It's a documentary."
-Right.
-Because we don't nod to the camera.
Right.
Yeah, that was important to us,
to keep the tongue out of the cheek.
And have these characters believe
who they were.
And you get the humor
out of the seriousness of that.
Right.
But this kind of performance too,
all this improv...
..all these multiple cast recording,
this was pretty new.
I mean, it sounds strange to say it...
.. but this was a new technique
for animation.
Because in animated movies...
.. usually we have the actors
by themselves.
And we get a very clean recording...
..and then you can cut
everybody together.
The problem with that is that,
you get a very--
You can get
a very sterile performance.
And they don't always feel like
they're in the same room together.
Or that they're actually relating
to the other character.
Biggest challenge for an editor...
.. 1s to cut a natural performance
from a bunch of different sessions.
And they said, "Well, let's skip
all that. Let's encourage--
Get them in together,
have them overlap...
.. have them, you know, of course,
work off the script...
..but turn the pages over and see...
.. and just let it, kind of,
go on its own and wing it."
We told all the actors
we're gonna do this at the outset.
-And they were all excited.
-Right.
And they were all really good at it.
Not all actors can pull that off.
James Woods, of course.
We have so much recording
of James...
... that in the end, we were
unable to use for all sorts of reasons.
It was a heart thing, you know?
Can we just take five minutes?
We couldn't have written
some of the stuff the way-- You know?
So we try to replicate
as much as possible...
.. the conditions
on the recording stage.
So the actors could even get out
from behind the podium...
..and move around
and act things out.
And we had a guy with a boom,
following them on occasion.
And I just freed them up
to get more physical with everything...
..and make it real.
l remember many times, you guys
would pick up a video camera.
And really be in-- Quite intrusive
with the camera like you were there.
That's right. We did that to Jeff.
That's right.
And you really did throw
something at us.
How's your head, by the way, there?
Sal Masekela,
the real voice of the X Games.
This all worked--
I forgot how this happened.
But we came up with the idea that...
. if we had
this fake sports network...
..we could just get a lot of information
out in short order.
And then coincidentally,
Sal dropped by the studio...
..through Quicksilver
and was a perfect match.
Over lunch, I think,
we had an accidental lunch--
Yeah, we just talked about it,
how we could use him in the movie.
And same with Kelly.
Yeah, they did their scenes together.
We had Kelly, Rob and--
-Yeah, all three.
-And Sal.
They weren't originally a part of--
Kelly and Rob...
.. weren't originally in the movie.
They were on as consultants.
To help us get the waves right
and the surf culture right.
-Right.
-But it turned out to be really good.
The twisted Tank.
Diedrich.
You never want to get in there
and help them out...
He is the biggest character
in the movie.
A big personality
and the nicest guy.
He's a really great guy to work with.
But Tank, you know, we tried
to just find something...
...a little bit different for him,
so he wasn't the same old villain.
And I think we came up
with something very unique for him.
Yeah.
We always said he was like
a cross between...
..John McEnroe and a forklift truck.
Mikey Abromowitz played
by Mario Cantone...
.. is anything but the typical surfer.
He's sort of a-- He's sort of a--
We refer to him
as an office gopher...
.. which got very confusing because
he's really a sandpiper.
And he's the kind of guy,
originally, anyway--
We were thinking of
the kind of guy...
..that really didn't wanna get
his feet wet with his boss.
So the sandpiper's interesting...
.. because they never really seem
to get their feet wet...
.. when they're fishing for....
Yup, and he's a talent scout
that doesn't surf.
A surfing talent scout.
But Mario gave him a great edge.
This guy has done this way too much.
Nothing fazes him.
Ash, you brought up Mario
from a one-man show.
Oh, yeah, my wife and I saw him
in his last show in Broadway.
His one-man comedy show.
And a few months later,
we're trying to figure out...
..who would do the voice
and popped in the head.
-Great.
-He's a huge animation fan.
He knew more about animation
than we did.
Jon Heder knows about animation.
Jon Heder, Chicken Joe.
Now, this was added late.
But it was about...
.. showing what Cody really wanted,
you know?
It's not about winning
the competition.
He just wants somebody
to be there for him.
And he clearly doesn't have it
in his hometown.
You know, I think it was also added...
..S0 that he would have a chance
with mom.
Because originally,
it wasn't in there...
..$0 he would just go from the fish pile
to the water, to the whale.
-He's gone. He never says goodbye.
-He didn't get to say goodbye.
To his family.
And this was his chance
to say goodbye...
..but mom, still,
is not really interested, so....
It seemed to help his character
a little bit better.
Well, I think it re-injects that pathos
that you have for this young kid...
.. that just has a passion
right from the beginning.
Lets you know what he really wants,
what's important.
-And how no one understands him.
-Yeah.
I gotta thank my wife, Nicole,
for that toucan line.
She had a handle on who Mike was.
Can't this blubber ball go any faster?
Step on it, fish sticks!
Bunch of other surfers up there
on the whale.
They were gonna be bigger characters
initially. We have an Aussie up there.
Japanese surfer.
-Brazilian.
-Brazilian, yeah.
There's so much material
that you discover...
.. when you create a movie like this.
Particularly, I think, as a documentary
or reality show.
You can really get
into these characters.
And then, at the end of the day...
.. you realize, well, you got 80 minutes
and a story to tell.
So there were a lot of casualties
simply from the point of view...
..of not having enough time
to get into all those back-stories.
-Casualties.
It sounds painful.
The whole idea of Cody
chasing this whale...
..Was inspired by surfers...
...who ride the wakes of oil tankers,
I think, in the Gulf of Mexico.
-Yeah.
Yup.
They had a hard time getting
these two together too.
We had to get Joe and Cody
get an introduction...
.. before we get to the next sequence
of Pen Gu where the just takes off, so...
Yeah, they needed a quick moment
to bond.
Deeply enough that you could buy...
.. that Joe would spend
the next several days...
..going to find Cody
as he's lost in the jungle.
Joe, kind of--
We always had that character.
He was gonna be that guy that,
you know, nothing fazed him.
But we did have. We went down
the road where he got a little.
You know, he'd get angry sometimes
or this or that...
..and you realize, this guy just--
Nothing fazes Joe.
Everything is good.
Every moment is good.
And he turned out to be one
of the favorite characters in the movie.
He seems to epitomize
a quintessential surfer attitude.
Inspired Ash Brannon moment
there.
Butt freeze?
No, the whole whale spout.
Joe being blasted off in the air.
Finding a way to end that scene
properly.
Our visual development team,
Paul Lasaine...
..Marcelo Vignali.
Hope I pronounced it right.
Armand Serrano, Ron Lukas...
..designed a beautiful world.
-The characters.
-They're natural primitive.
-Oh, yes, Sylvain Deboissy.
-Sylvain Deboissy.
He had a real challenge...
.. because most of our characters
.
are penguins.
It's real easy for them to start
looking alike...
..but he gave them all distinction.
They ended up having different tattoos
to help you....
I think it started with
the Hawaiian shirt thing.
-That was a Marcelo invention, right?
-Yeah, Marcelo.
It was a brilliant, brilliant invention...
.. because it just carried forward
to everybody else then.
I think we wanted to find
a much more organic way...
..to actually feel the excitement
of this island and the MTV style.
You know, music video
was the best way to go.
Introduced a lot of things in here.
Introduced the fact that Joe and Cody
are really good friends.
Or have become really good friends.
Yeah, saving--
Joe saving Cody made all that work.
Just instant bond, you get that.
Like when we pulled you out
from in front of that moving train.
Yeah, the one that you were driving.
Coming through! Oh, crap.
-Introduction of Lani.
-Lani.
Now, the squid life preserver.
That was an invention of our character
designer, Sylvan Deboissy.
Brilliant invention.
This is why animation is great
because of that squid.
This is also a scene that Zooey
ad-libbed.
She came up
with the character Arnold.
She was holding a sandbag,
remember?
-And invented that character.
-That's right.
Then we said, "Well, she's talking
to a kid, we need a kid."
And Chris Buck...
.. took a portable DAT recorder
home.
-Yup.
-And just recorded his--
What was he, eight at that time
or seven?
-He was probably eight.
-His son, Reed, just at home.
To do scratch
and it turned out so good...
..we had to use it in the production.
Yeah, because a lot of times
there's nothing worse than an adult...
..trying to do a kid voice.
So we have real kids.
l love my job.
I have an amazing job.
This is so Zooey.
This whole thing here.
Again, the camera work here,
working so beautifully.
They're gonna go...
..for the interesting thing
that's happening at the moment.
That would be this little kid
who's about to drown.
And James Williams,
our head of layout.
Wonderful cinematography
in this movie.
A lot of times, the camera--
We had to sort of give the illusion
that the camera was finding the action.
It couldn't be ahead of it.
As you would normally create
these shots at this stage.
-Remember?
-No, no. Not really.
More of the archival footage that we--
Little scratches on the side.
Actually, that stuff is pretty easy to do
from what I've been told.
It looks hard.
I think a lot of times it was just--
Well, you know,
the guys would do the work...
..and it'd be beautiful and pristine
and the color would be perfect.
And then, we would say,
"Okay, now, make it look--"
Yeah, muck it up,
make it look pretty bad.
And then, you know--
-They would do it.
-And then, on the long run, they go:
"Okay, I get it.
I know what you guys are doing."
It was all part of getting
a real organic look...
..and feel for the movie.
That was really important to us.
That it didn't feel CG.
And in fact...
.. archival footage aside...
..every shot including shots like this
have film grain.
Because when we saw
the original images...
.. they were too perfect.
And, too, almost a little sterile.
But adding that little bit of film grain
took the edge off everything.
The character of Tank
was really articulated...
.. by Jeff Ranjo, our head of story.
He took what could have been
a real cutout, cardboard-like villain...
..and went somewhere different
with him as you'll see later.
We used to have a sequence...
.. that took us off into a big luau party
right here.
And actually, Cody was gonna ride
the wave the next day, isn't that right?
It slowed everything down.
We had, like, a three-hour first act,
didn't we?
Yeah, 80 minutes. Get to the point.
This used to be
a much more complicated scene.
It was a big dialogue-driven--
Or even before that, remember?
When Cody was saving Chicken Joe
from being beaten up.
-That's right.
-And then the Ransoms came in.
They were Tank's cronies.
And they held Cody down.
Lani rushed in and flipped Tank
on his back.
That was the three-hour version,
I think.
It was our head of story, Jeff Ranjo.
He came up with the great,
efficient way of just moving forward.
You have the memorial surfboard
out on the rock.
And somebody's throwing rocks at it.
Now, those urchins, they come back
a little bit later.
At least one of them does.
This one used to be, like,
so much longer too.
Cody would--
He wouldn't take a wave.
And he was really-- Really was
wearing his fear on his sleeve.
You just wanted him to wipeout.
l remember nearly doing this.
Of course the wave that I was on
doing that...
..Was about a foot and a half high,
but it was still pretty frightening.
Well, we've had some
of the best teachers in the world.
We had Kelly and Rob
teaching us too, so....
And we still surf the way we do.
-Yup, no reflection on their skill.
-Yup.
-We're still useless.
-l wouldn't call it surfing.
Now, we can't tell you anything
about the waves technically...
.. because we don't know anything
about the waves.
And we all, between us, we have
a brain the size of a hamster.
But a lot of the scenes with the water,
and the jungles and everything...
..1 know we would look at them
and say, "Fantastic."
And the guys would say,
"Yeah, but we're not done yet."
You know, and a few days later,
it would look even better.
And these guys
kept topping themselves.
And this one, this is an odd one
where we kept trying, you know...
...well, would it be
just two wipeouts, three?
Rule of comedy is three.
But somehow when we added
the fourth one in...
.. people really laughed.
The three was funny.
The fourth one they weren't expecting,
especially the different angle.
Plus Cody had said, "You know,
you're gonna wanna watch it...
..one, two, three.
Over and over and over and over."
Now, why the camera people
didn't go and rescue Cody--
-I'm not sure why they--
-There's a rule of noninvolvement.
-Oh, right. That's right.
-Yeah, don't make the news.
-Just report the news.
-Yeah.
We used to have Lani out there,
doing the rescue.
Cody was passed out...
..and she was the one
kind of suffering for Cody.
I don't know why we did that.
-Now, this scene...
-Try, you try.
..described to us by a guy
from Quicksilver and he walked in.
Yeah.
He described what it's like
to almost drown.
It stayed with this, because I think...
. it was early on that he showed us
that-- You know...
..what it looked like to drown
as he's, sort of, like, lying on the floor...
..of the conference room
with his arms and legs in the air.
-l forgot about that.
-Yeah.
A lot of the surfers talk about
how once you're--
If you've wiped out
and you're under water...
.. often, you can't tell which way is up,
which way is down.
And you'll be swimming thinking
you're surfacing...
..and you'll hit the bottom
of the reef...
.. realize you're going
the wrong way.
When you come up for air,
sometimes that next wave...
.18 right down on top of you.
You don't even get another breath.
-Tank, you okay?
-Tank needs fuel.
Now, he says it tastes like--
-Shellfish.
Shellfish, I just wanna be clear
about that.
And he doesn't like shellfish.
I think it was Ed who animated that.
I'm sorry, boarded that scene,
initially.
And there were fish coming out
of Cody's mouth...
.. when Lani was pushing down
on his chest.
That's right.
Ed Gombert.
-You know, I'm--
-Ha.
We had these three actors
on the coach together and they were--
This was the moment
where Glen acts out Cody wiping out...
... that was a touch that the animator,
Pete Nash, added.
-That was beautiful.
-We didn't expect that.
Again, beautiful camerawork here...
.. with a little spotlight that they used.
The rain.
We did have one point,
we were gonna do it...
all that sort of night camera.
Green with those sort of, you know,
those glowing eyes.
-Green retinas and all that.
-Just a little too creepy.
-But I think we always wanted this.
-Yeah.
And it came out beautifully.
I think from the beginning...
..we always imagined setting up
the Geek as--
Or introducing him as being a guy
asleep outside in the rain.
Just kind of tells you all about
how out of touch he is...
...how washed up he is.
Jeff's great here.
Remember when he first came in...
..he was actually doing more
of a cartoon voice.
Yes, little bit higher voice
and all that.
We said, "Just do your own voice."
-l remember.
-Jeff is this character.
-He just--
-Yeah.
He brought so much
of himself to it.
These actors did this, mean,
the same thing all together...
..the three of them.
It gives all that overlapping feeling.
The three of them acting,
workshopping this sequence...
.. was fantastic.
Okay, Fire Urchin.
Oh, Ivan, you know, this is a tribute
to our editor.
Who came--? Who did this first?
Was this Ed Gombert, who did the--?
Yeah, but I think it was your idea,
Chris, to--
To interview the Fire Urchin.
Yeah, and then Ed Gombert
boarded it...
..and came up
with a lot of great dialogue.
I'll take credit for it...
. if you like it at home.
And if you don't,
it was Chris Jenkins.
And Matt Taylor did the voice
for the urchin...
.. which is-- Matt was one of our
storyboard artist.
And great improviser. He helped--
We would workshop scenes
with Matt...
..and one of our development guys,
Pete Burns...
..and they would give us
great material.
Particularly with our final sessions
with him.
It was written in a different way
in that regard.
I mean, we just allowed the improv
to, you know, create the scenes.
Knowing that we were hitting marks
all the way along that....
We went back and forth in this scene
a couple of times.
Yeah, well, our first instinct
was to go with this.
That's what you do when you get
some kind of--
Yeah, it's really a surefire cure.
It really is.
Then, we second guessed ourselves.
Well, Jeff, every time he came in,
he'd go, "Is the pee scene still in?"
We got nervous at one point.
-We said, "Yeah, kind of."
-Because I'm not, you know--
-Oh, good. Okay, good.
-And it really works, right guys?
-l hope.
-I don't know.
We hear.
Why did you--?
That time I cut my foot?
Then the kids came in later
and I think...
.. they kind of take the ick factor off it,
if you have any of it.
Now, this is Reese,
our youngest daughter.
And then Reed, my son,
and Jeff Ranjo's son.
-Jack.
-Smudge, Jack.
-Playing Smudge.
-ls his son named Smudge?
-Son Jack playing Smudge.
-Okay.
-Oh, come on.
-Bye.
-This was a much longer scene too.
-Oh, yeah.
And then we decided to end
with a little classy joke.
-Look at that for--
-Masterpiece Theatre right there.
Now, that burp was provided
by Jon Heder.
-Jon Heder.
That's right.
With the Reggie character...
.. he was originally much more
of a villain, and then he just--
Cody was his own villain, really.
You know,
it's his struggle whether to--
Yeah, the internal struggle
and his struggle with Z.
-Yeah.
-We didn't need a-- kind of villain.
-Right. So Reggie's part got a little--
-We couldn't even spell that.
-Or villain?
-Yeah.
-l can't spell either of them.
Okay, so then...
..we got the idea of Joe--
We gotta keep Joe in the movie.
Everybody loved Joe,
but Joe was separate from Cody.
So, what is-- l guess the idea came up
that he would be searching for him.
-Yeah.
-So that keeps Joe alive.
Well, not in that scene.
Chicken Joe, of course,
was just a breakout...
..cool and wonderful character
in the movie.
Yeah, Jon just found him.
But Jon found him
in the first session.
-Yeah, he did.
-But we had him come in and audition.
Just in that room, set up a little tape
recorder and did some great stuff.
Jon was always the choice
for Chicken Joe...
.. after seeing Napoleon.
Napoleon Dynamite that is.
At this point in the movie,
you can't smell this...
..but, you know, Z hasn't washed
for about 10 years.
The jungle that these guys created,
the lighting...
..and the leaves
and the wind blowing...
. it's amazing.
I think it was one of our writers,
Don Rymer...
..who came up with this idea
that Cody lost his necklace.
And once he had made
that suggestion...
.. everything fell into place here.
Because we struggled
for a long time...
.. about how to get Z motivated
to help this kid out.
-And get involved in his life.
-That's right.
Yeah, we had that whole thing about Z
having a particular scar.
Yeah, and Cody would recognize.
So losing the necklace brings up
the conversation...
.. about the meeting
10 years earlier.
And then gives Z a chance
to make a decision...
.. after he's gone back to his tree.
Yeah, so Z feels somewhat
responsible...
.. for where this kid is right now.
And has set him on his path.
Beautiful song
by Ken Andrews here.
It's just fantastic.
We had a great music supervisor...
...Liza Richardson,
also working with Lia Vollack.
Some incredible music.
They would just turn up--
These original songs would come
into the studio.
They can bring a CD in and say,
"Hey, we're gonna play this moment."
They were perfect.
It was a treat the day this came in.
This anchors the scene emotionally.
The values in this scene,
it's not sad.
It's just, there's a certain kind of...
.. something that I can't think about
right now.
-If you say so.
-Not quite.
This is the international version,
listeners.
One of the inspirations for Z...
..Was a legendary surfer named
Greg Knoll...
.. who rode big waves
before anybody else was.
Back in the '50s.
And he rode one of the biggest waves
ever recorded.
It wasn't filmed or anything...
..and he walked away from surfing
after that.
And that was part of our-- Something--
That idea led to, you know...
.. what if we had
this Elvis-type surfer...
..who got really big...
..and then all of a sudden
disappeared one day?
We learned all about the koa wood.
And how boards...
.. how they're made, best boards.
You want to make one?
Remember we talked about
this bit, too...
.. where, you know,
l was talking about a scene...
.. you know, at home...
.. where you go to your teenager
and wanna do something with them.
And you wanna be the best dad
in the world.
And you're gonna go to them
and say:
"Hey, you wanna go do this with me?
I think it'll be great."
You're expecting the kid to say,
"Yeah, Dad. You're the best."
And give you a big hug and all that,
whatever.
But normally, they would just say:
"Never mind, I don't really want to."
And so we tried to go
for that kind of feeling...
...more than-- You know,
the believable kind of relationship...
..with Cody and Z...
..as opposed to just the, you know,
the fantasy of it all.
I think that happened to you,
didn't it?
Isn't that--? There was an example
that weekend...
.. you brought it in, we thought,
"Great, let's get that."
Oh, yeah, we bring our lives into this,
you know...
. this movie.
And I think our families...
..Will be scarred forever
by watching some of this.
Now, this whole log-rolling concept
came up...
..we just needed a device
to get Z and Cody to the beach.
We knew Z wouldn't consciously
go back to his old place.
See, he's heading back
to his house.
His house is off on the right there.
And now, they're heading away.
Mychael Danna created
some really great music for this.
It was fun watching this stuff
being recorded too.
Oh, once again we threw something
completely different to him, you know.
Instead of this big, lush,
symphonic score, we were like:
"This little bit, try something
kind of Islandy sort of thing.
-You know, log chasing."
-"Okay."
-And he'd go for it.
-Yeah.
His brother happened to be in town
that weekend.
And his brother plays the uke
and they put this little piece together.
-It's a great piece.
-Yeah.
Well, the scene used to feel
really dangerous.
We had Steve Ticknor,
who's our sound designer...
..and he did brilliant work.
But it was scary
because a giant log rolling down...
..and Z caught going off a cliff.
But we added the music
and it made it...
.. Just gave it a tone--
A little more humor, right?
Here's the most perfect beach
you will ever find.
And it doesn't exist.
-Darn.
-Yeah.
Squids don't necessarily need
to live in water in our movie.
There's a tank of water
just off frame.
Our visual development team...
.. just did a beautiful job
.
coming up...
.. with this world.
We said we wanted something natural
and primitive.
-And I think it was Armand Serrano.
-Armand Serrano.
-Beautiful.
-Who drew this originally.
This leaned-over palm tree converted
into a board shack, like an old garage.
l love watching this with people.
Actually people that-- Or kids.
They may have figured it out
in the scene before, you know.
-It was Z.
-"It's Z. It's Z."
But they're not sure yet.
So they're with you on the journey.
Of course they look
at the Hawaiian flowers.
They sort of figure it out.
Yeah, on his chest.
Everything's working in the scene.
The way that the flowers
in the background...
..at the bottom left there.
Sand's moving.
It was tough finding out
where to reveal Z.
And then, it just kind of landed
in our laps.
When he gets to his old house,
it's the perfect way to reveal it.
Well, he reveals himself
and he doesn't tell Cody who he is...
. it just happens, right?
Because of his being confronted
with his past, he just--
That's how he reacts to everything.
Cody puts it together.
It's a very organic reveal that--
l remember we had so many ideas
about Z having a scar...
..a Cupboard of trophies....
Well, the question was always, like,
"How would Cody know who this--?"
It's like,
"Wait a minute, Cody's not--"
He's pretty bright.
He's gonna put it together, you know.
You see this character reacting
the way they do.
Often in story development,
you work on these things.
And you second guess yourself.
Or you're being guessed
by a lot of people around you.
All for good reasons, really,
but you kind of forget...
.. that people are discovering
their journey with you.
And sometimes you try too hard
to disguise things without realizing...
.. that your perspective as a storyteller
is everything.
You know the story inside out.
But the audience
is just walking this path...
..and discovering things
as they come up.
-What happened?
-l don't want to talk about it.
I love the way he looks
in the camera there.
We were always trying to keep
that idea alive...
.. that these characters
were going about their business.
But at times,
when they were revealing things...
.. they didn't wanna be revealed,
in particularly with Z...
.. they'd looked right at the camera.
Yeah, we wanted awareness
of the camera throughout.
Not too often,
but enough to remind you...
.. that there's cameras
on the beach.
And there's only 800
and something shots in the movie.
It's a really low shot count
for a movie like this.
Especially when we get to
making the board...
..which is very long.
Couple of long scenes.
We wanted the limitation
of the camera...
.. having to stay away
from the characters.
It couldn't get exactly where it wanted
to get for the perfect shot every time.
We had this kid thing all as one
and then, I think, lvan our editor...
. Split it up into three.
Just kind of wrap the whole thing
around, yeah.
lvan's not only a fantastic editor...
. he's a really great,
accomplished surfer himself.
It turned out to be indispensable
that he was--
Could help us connect
to the surf world...
..and keep it real every day.
Jack Ranjo's big line coming up.
He's a dirty trashcan full of poop.
Hey, now, nobody made him
say that line, Chris.
That was his own line.
Yeah, well, maybe Jeff wrote it.
We don't know.
-Hey, what's that?
-And Tank's mom--
-What a looker.
-Oh, yeah.
-Played by Diedrich Bader.
-Yeah.
Who is also a looker
as a matter of fact.
Okay, this is probably the weirdest
sequence in the whole movie.
Yeah, we admit it.
-And it's Jeff Ranjo's fault.
-Jeff Ranjo, it's all his fault.
Then Diedrich ran with it
and we encouraged it and all that.
But as strange as this is, you know,
we were questioning it...
..-you know,
is this just too out there?
Then I think about at the same time,
it was Super Bowl Sunday...
..and in this particular Super Bowl,
they had--
When you cut away
from the game...
.. they would cut to photographs
of the players...
.. posing with the trophy...
..and kissing the trophy
and hugging the trophy.
And we realize this is not so...
-... far out.
-This isn't weird.
You know, but we pushed it.
We make a little weirder.
We had a test screening
and this first version...
.. Slightly, sort of the same,
people didn't like.
We did a different version, edited it.
Nobody liked.
So we went back
to the original version.
-You know...
-l like the pretty--
Kids get it on one level.
Adults get it on another.
Well, one of the ideas
is that Cody was--
That's all Cody wanted to do,
was to win the trophy.
Epitomized winning. Well, we thought,
"What if our villain--?
That's what he's all about.
It's all about the trophy."
One of our best
documentary shots here.
Camera follows. It's still one shot.
Hey, who said you--
Turn the board around.
Get back here.
I think the water is--
Some of the best water
is when it's like that.
Not necessarily
when there's breaking waves.
I just love this scene.
-You wanna jump in.
-Yeah.
-Well, I'd like you to jump in there.
-Beautiful.
Jump off.
We never got tired of putting Cody
through the ringer.
He needed to be.
Well, it's a cocky--
A cocky character,
you don't mind seeing him....
That was the interesting thing
with him...
.. was keeping him sort of driven
and cocky and that--
-Likable?
-Likable.
-Gotta keep him likable.
-And believable, I guess.
-Mychael Danna's score.
-Oh, yeah.
-We gotta--
-Funny little ditty that he did here.
The guy was versatile
more than like--
-That's--
-He's amazing, amazing.
But he also wrote the SPEN theme,
the original, the opening theme.
And then the Boneyards.
-Incredible music at the end.
-Score.
Now, this X started off as a gag.
And it also showed...
.. you know, that Zeke was really
connected to the water.
He knew when the waves
were gonna break.
And it was kind of a one-off gag
at one point.
And we'd realize
we could use it later on.
Now, the precursor of that
Was a scene...
...that, [ think, Ed Gombert
had created.
A lovely scene.
Where Z was very much--
Kind of like...
.. he's doing transcendental meditation
on the beach.
Oh, right.
And he was counting down
the waves...
..and he knew exactly
when each wave would break.
With his eyes closed.
He didn't really need it.
That wasn't ultimately, what,
Cody needed to learn.
He didn't have to learn the technique
or the technical aspects of surfing.
He needed to learn
how to have fun.
We could have gone conventional
and said:
"Well, there's gonna be a big contest
in act three...
..and we need to have Cody,
like, training every day...
..in leading up to that.
We tried some versions.
Yeah, they just never--
It wasn't fun and it felt
like you had seen it before.
Now, Rob has hair kind of like that.
And by coincidence...
.. adolescent penguins grow
this crazy, brown feathery stuff...
..out of their head
when they're teenagers.
Not quite as much of a Chia Pet
as Rob became in this movie.
Okay, you gotta tell
our wonderful listeners...
.. about this one right here.
Well, Reed was talking about--
Actually, he loves, you know,
toy guns and stuff like that.
So l was asking him,
"What would you like on your gun?"
He said,
"I'd like grenade launcher."
So we took that out of context
and put it into the surfboard thing.
Those happy accidents.
-Oh, the Pen Guans.
-It's another happy accident.
How many cameramen did we lose
in the movie?
Now, we gotta give a nod
to Jason Lethcoe.
-Yes.
-He really--
Early on in production...
..he took the whole middle
of the movie...
..with Cody and Z...
..and worked out a through line
about making a board.
Now, he-- I think he told us
he was inspired by--
Being in the workshop...
.. With his granddad
when he was a kid.
And he tapped into something here
that's universal.
He really understood
the father-and-son dynamic...
..of these guys.
And in creating this scene,
it had echoes back...
..and into the end of the movie.
The movie, I think, really sort of
added those elements back in...
..to all aspects.
Again a lot of great improv
from Jeff and Shia.
Yeah, they were
in the room together.
I think it was their first time together,
like the second day.
We did three days in a row.
And they did four takes.
That was all we needed.
-Yeah.
-We wanted the overlaps.
We wanted the improv.
We wanted it to feel natural.
This scene could be so written...
..and really traditionally,
the information in this scene--
It could be over in a few seconds.
But to actually experience...
..this relationship developed
on-screen...
. this is kind of the core
of the movie in a way.
-Yeah.
-It is.
We were asked many times to cut it.
Trim it...
..way back.
We kept saying, "I don't know."
I think the whole gag works...
.. because of the tension that builds up
throughout the sequence.
The subtlety of these performances
is just staggering.
But they were cuing off too, I think...
..of the great performances
they were getting.
The very natural cadence
of the actors.
And those little eccentric...
.. you know, characteristics
that you don't normally get...
... because lines are, in other movies,
so delivered.
Very unusual to have two actors
in the same space...
.. acting out a scene
for an animated movie.
Normally, you would record
one actor at atime...
..and then a great deal of work goes
into trying to forge a connection...
.. between the performances.
And that seemed a little crazy to us,
quite honestly. We thought--
"If you want a natural performance,
put them together in the room."
And everyone was worried about them
overlapping dialogue...
..and how it would limit us
when we got back to editorial.
No, we embraced it.
We embraced to a large degree
the idea of spontaneity...
..and kind of being stuck with
what you get on film...
..or what you get on tape.
That's what documentary filmmakers
have to deal with.
It was important to keep that sense
of spontaneous reality in everything.
The camera moves, then obviously,
the character performances...
..the story events.
We wanted a sense of reality
unfolding in front of you...
.. not these sort of...
..preordained events
being locked down...
..in a kind of a formulaic way.
That can sometimes happen.
We had transcripts
of everything that these guys said...
..S0 we could go in and find just the
right things with our highlighters...
.. and try to cut it all together.
We had hours and hours of tape
to work with.
So that made it a lot easier
with the transcripts.
We have to thank
the blistered fingers...
-...of Jeannine. Yeah.
-Jeannine Marques, yes.
So those voices are really good
on those penguins.
-Who plays those guys?
-Why, that would be us.
Sped up.
Well, l have never--
Oh, it is just us.
Again, you know, like with the kids,
you added more kids...
..as the movie went on,
we added more Pen Guans.
-They're a very popular character.
-Yeah.
And John ad-libbed this scene here.
-We just said, "What--?"
-Yeah.
"How would Chicken Joe
take being put in a pot...
..a boiling pot of water...?"
l love the opening up
the pores and....
This is something that-- l remember
you bringing this idea into work, Chris.
The idea of going non-linear
with this sequence.
Going back and forth, yeah.
Cutting ahead.
We always had that struggle of trying
to keep the documentary alive...
.. because sometimes
it would just become too narrative.
We're trying to tell the story
and we forget that it's a documentary.
And we'd push ourselves
to keep that alive...
..and others would push us too.
So wherever we could,
we tried to keep those bits going.
And then the fun idea, too,
that came in late.
Not late. I mean, it's always there,
but I think we just kind of lost it...
..in the second act a bit.
So we tried to keep that alive
and it started here, I think.
Because this sequence
was a little more melancholy...
.. than we really wanted.
-Yeah, Z was too down.
-Yeah.
And we realized,
if he's gonna be the mentor...
.. he's gotta be the one who realizes,
"Wait, what are we doing? We're--
We should be having a great time."
And even Z hasn't been having a good
time and when he realizes that...
..then it's time for him to be
a great teacher to Cody.
And also, you know,
Cody, for Z, is a way of kind of...
.. reconciling with his past
because he's--
Cody is kind of like Z was as a kid.
Z is what Cody might be
if he goes down the wrong path...
.. where winning becomes
everything.
And if it's everything,
it's not gonna--
Being the champion,
you're not gonna be on top forever.
And what your life's like,
when your glory days are behind you?
-So--
-Right.
That was a strong hook in the movie,
I think, is that...
.. they're the same character
essentially separated by time.
This is a huge moment
for Lani in this sequence, I mean--
A little nod to Denise Koyama
who storyboarded...
..a lot of the Lani stuff.
You know, being guys,
we just didn't understand the girl.
And she brought a warmth
into this character...
..and the slight sense of romance
building between Cody and Lani.
I think it's a really lovely--
Ash, you rewrote
some of this stuff too.
-That's right.
-That kooky stuff she does.
Yeah, the waterfall stuff and all.
-That's great. That's good.
-Yeah.
What was the whole thing
with the lava tube?
Because we knew that we were really
pushing the rules of a documentary...
..in a camera following them
down here.
Well, there's a parallel track
through...
..the ride coming up.
-Yes.
-And that's how the camera followed.
Yeah.
Bravest cameraman
in the history of animation.
-We lost a few.
-Yeah.
All right!
But James Williams came up
with this idea of a parallel track.
-To make it more believable--
-How'd they get ahead of them there?
Yeah, how did they--? How are they
ahead of them?
-Where's the camera--?
-l track-- You know what?
-The guy's Welsh, I can't explain it.
-Yeah.
And by the way,
penguins didn't invent surfing.
-You're kidding.
-Yeah, I know it's surprising.
Man, all this time.
This idea came up--
I'm not sure where it originated.
We were well into production...
..and then somebody read about
how the Hawaiians were doing this...
..2000 years ago.
They called it lava sledding.
-Jerry had been to Hawaii.
-Yeah, yeah.
And glow worms really do exist.
-Yeah, it was--
-That really is their poop.
Yeah, the glowing stuff
is their poop.
Now, maybe they don't output
that much.
I don't think so. I hope not.
These guys are big eaters
on Pen Gu.
A little known fact that
that's actually radioactive.
We're kind of concerned
about Cody, I think.
Yeah, Ash, the stuff
coming up here.
You wrote this beautiful stuff
between Cody and Lani.
Look at that, look at the sentiment
of that. It's just--
I think that was Zooey-ism, right?
That stink-stink thing?
No, that was Ash.
That was an Ash-ism.
What happened is you--
You know, well, you'd--
You're with actors and you kind of
get to know their voices...
..and we could all go back.
We can all write.
Yeah. You're right because it's one
of the last scenes we did.
You just got to know
their voices after a while...
..and they talk to you in your head.
Oh, do they talk to you
in your head?
-You know, I never had that, Ash.
-Oh, okay.
We can cut that.
He's my uncle.
He's the only family I've got.
-There she is.
-Bucktoothed Lani.
-Even though penguins don't--
-Do they grow teeth?
I'm not sure.
No, I think that might have been
some kind of snack food...
.. that she was eating at that time.
It just looks like a tooth.
-It was a lucky photograph.
-Oh, it was a snack food.
Another great song
that came in from a band called--
-Dirty Heads.
Slow mo, we slowed that down,
didn't we?
Didn't we stretch it?
-Yeah.
-ls that what it's called?
We were down in the wire.
We had a shorter scene...
..and then we just--
We wanted to--
We wanted the music
to hit certain beats...
..and, you know, really swell here.
-So we open up a couple of the shots.
-Can we stretch it?
I think it was all carefully planned...
.. you guys are just
making this up now.
No, no. They have
a stretching machine.
There was the idea of that--
That curl of wood...
.. looking like the wave,
which is kind of nice little--
Oh, that's right. Yeah.
-Little thing that we threw in there.
-We tried.
It was out there.
That's pretty good
for a second board.
-Pretty good job.
-The ones that he damaged...
.. before we got to this state.
-No.
-Let's see here.
Don't try this at home, by the way.
Come on! Come on!
I think this is the most beautiful scene
in the movie.
I love this one.
We wanted to bring in the concept
of the tube as a--
Because we--
We went down to Trussels--
It's a surf spot near San Diego.
--and we interviewed real surfers.
They're the voices
that you hear coming up.
And we just started to realize that....
Yeah, surfing is competitive,
but there's also a real spiritual side.
Everybody kept talking about
what it's like to be inside the barrel.
And we just knew we had
to incorporate it into the movie...
..and it became--
Became the metaphor, I think,
or the theme, in a way.
Wait, wait, that's Toby, Cody.
It became the metaphor
of the symbol.
-Tobey, Tubey?
-This is Surf's Up...
.. not Spider-Man,
ladies and gentlemen.
Isn't it? I thought we were talking
about Spider-Man all this time.
No, it was Cody's thing.
It was Cody to be tubed.
Right, to get tubed.
-It's not what he wanted to--
-Be one with the wave.
--you know, necessarily do but--
Well, here, this moment right here
sums it all up...
.. for where Cody still is.
Yeah, "How many points
can I score for getting barreled?"
Didn't understand the spiritual
quality of being one with the water.
Now, Reggie Belafonte
is not a gopher.
-He is not a--
-Koala bear.
-Koala, hedgehog.
-We're here to tell you-- What is he?
-We're here to tell you.
-He is a sea otter.
-Sea otter.
-Okay.
-So chosen because--
-Look at the feet.
Is that his real hair, do you think?
-I don't know.
-Hard to say.
I've never seen a sea otter
like that personally, but, you know....
He's a sea otter because of--
He's a sort of a manipulative guy.
-And sea otters are very manipulative.
-They have hands.
-That's great.
-Oh, they have hands.
Did you ever go to...
..Monterey and watch how
they pick pockets and stuff.
I get it. You guys look hungry.
So Joe got away
from the natives.
We had to bring him back.
Now, the Pen Guan language
is similar to Hovitos.
Hukana matusa means, I think,
"kill him" in Hovitos...
..but in Pen Guan,
it means "tastes like chicken."
So there's no confusion.
Squids can actually
either be made into a snack food...
..or into a life preserver on Pen Gu,
by the way.
-What face?
-Oh, man.
They go pink when you cook them.
That was all improv to. Reed's...
It wasn't true.
It was the improv of--
Reese was actually--
-That 's right.
-Sitting at home recording that line...
-...and the cat--
-Oh, the cat.
The cat had a trouser cough
as we call it back in Wales.
Cat had too many
bean burritos that night.
And she responded to that.
Hey, Z! Come on!
-Where you going?
-l thought we were going to train.
Not in the water. Jeez.
What are you thinking?
And this all became--
Again, last minute thing.
All became about fun also.
-Yeah, originally--
-The training--
It was real nuts-and-bolts
training like--
Here's how you balance on a board
and here's how you turn.
There's a little leftover
with the rock thing, right?
Yeah.
But this was Ed again, right?
Ed Gombert had done a lot of stuff,
initially. 1 know that--
I think I actually brought
a lot of gags in here too...
.. but the pineapple slices
on the eyes was from--
Yeah, that came from the scene
you mentioned earlier.
That was a line improvved by Jeff.
Right, so we added that music back in
and sort of--
-That sitar.
-Sitar.
Okay, how did Jeff do that, guys?
He was talking about--
He wanted us to show him
doing this great wave...
..and he acted out this whole thing.
-How he would surf the wave.
-Surf the wave.
He was not--
He didn't think he was on mike, right?
-Yeah.
-He's just showing us, so it's all real.
These are the kind of tricks...
..we used to play on each other
in making a movie.
Pineapples on the eyes.
Yeah.
Can I take them off now?
Ash and I do the interviewers
throughout the movie...
..S0 those are our voices.
Whether you like them or not.
l love them.
You owe me 20 bucks for that.
Where's my wallet?
Now, this used to be a heck
of a lot more complicated.
And there's the X again.
-Show them that Cody has--
-Number two X.
--learned to read the waves.
And have fun.
Then, Cody...
And we took a lot longer for Z
getting back in the water...
..and we also
had this moment where--
-The tiptoeing in.
-Yes, but....
But Z, wouldn't he
have this spiritual moment...
..going back in the water?
At this point in the movie...
.. nobody cares.
It's like, let's just get into the water.
-That scene was much bigger.
-Yeah.
I just took forever to get Z
in the water.
We thought we had to make a big deal
about it...
..and he'd have to tiptoe
out there and--
Yup.
The idea was Z hadn't been
in the water for 10 years.
And so that was
such a big moment...
..and you had it be very serious.
He was, you know...
..considering whether to smack Cody
on the head...
..or go surfing and--
Just had him jump in the deep end.
-Yeah.
-Yup.
It came through Chad Stuart
animated that great shot...
.. where Z's upon the board
for the first time and he's tipsy.
It all came through right there.
We wanted to do--
Slow-mo photography...
is a big part
of surf documentaries.
The waves look so much better
if you're shooting at...
..200 fps rather than real time.
Again, Imageworks folks,
they pulled it off.
You're gonna see
a few shots coming up here...
. that's just couldn't be
more beautiful.
Thanks to Sugar Ray
for this fantastic song.
And for Liza for bringing it to us.
Now, in this sequence, originally...
. Cody was gonna get tubed.
He was gonna find out
what it's all about...
..and he was gonna unlearn
that lesson...
.. that was much too complex.
I think we felt that just to be able
to hold on to the experience...
..that's transformative for him.
Yeah, if you got tubed this early...
.. then it said that he'd gotten past
needing to win.
If he went back to wanting to win,
then he hadn't learned a thing.
-So it was confusing.
-So we just keep it.
He has a good time out here,
but he doesn't get tubed.
Yeah, it's more about just getting
his confidence back so that he can....
That he feels he can really ride
these waves...
..and maybe has what it takes
to go compete now.
Now, where did the cannon ball
come from?
-Was that in animation?
-[ don't remember.
Was it--? Was it lvan?
Oh, Ivan suggested it.
-lvan Bilancio.
-Great moment.
The water in that shot even when
they're not waves, the refraction--
I just wanna dive in.
So this is probably, I would say...
.. the most complex story sequence
of the movie.
Z having to reveal what happened.
It was not easy.
We had it earlier in the movie.
Or I don't know if it was earlier,
but it was in a different place.
How much to reveal?
How much to say?
We had one point when both
the characters were really angry.
-You kind of hated both of them.
-Yeah.
You really didn't care
what happened.
But somehow Z's journey
was about coming back to life...
..and returning to the beach
and to his--
His old friends and his family.
We let that fear of having lost
so many years ago...
..be the thing that keeps him
from being able to go to the contest...
..and support Cody
and be there for him, so....
-It was tough.
-Yup.
History revised,
we call this sequence.
And I think we revised this one about
1000 times.
It's such a delicate balance
on information in here...
..and tone for the movie.
Gets too deep and you start
to break the tone, the movie...
.. becomes more of a drama.
But there are some very big and
important things going on in this scene.
It turned out
to be the right moment...
.. for Z to reveal why he was
in hiding.
And that his fear of showing
his face again as a loser...
.. kept him from being able to go
and support Cody.
So they didn't pass.
God, it looks so easy now, guys.
We struggled....
Back to the archival footage.
Great grainy look.
Ash, you did some beautiful
versions of this...
..[ mean, going all the way back
to virtually the beginning of the movie.
-Well, we have--
-Yeah, it used to be in...
..in his tree, he revealed this,
didn't he?
Oh, really?
And even before that this is where
Geek revealed that he was Big Z.
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Oh, this is the exact
same scene, right?
-That we used earlier.
-Yeah.
There's this spot lit....
So if you go back
and look at that scene now--
Back when Cody
first arrives in the island.
--you'll see Z backing off the board
and disappearing in the white water.
Not wiping out.
thought it would be kind of nice
to have a Zapruder like moment.
I mean,
I think our hats are off to...
-...our actors on this.
-Oh, yeah.
Yeah, we put Shia
through the ringer on this.
But he committed totally.
Well, every session we'd come in,
we probably had a new version of it.
And they'd keep asking,
"What was wrong with the old one?"
-They were troupers.
-Yeah.
But kudos to Shia, man.
He can handle both, you know,
the comedy and the drama.
-He can handle anything.
-Just anything we threw at him.
He's been an amazing guy.
So this is Cody's lowest moment
in the movie.
In case you hadn't noticed.
Well, you struggle with that.
It has to be somewhere in here...
..but you're not exactly sure.
Yeah, you question, when to--
When to do an interview...
..and when just to let the moments
play out without the interview.
But we really felt
we needed to remind people...
.. that he's are not just there
to win a trophy.
That there's
something deeper going on.
What he's really missing is a dad.
And what was a joke in the one
of the first sequences of the movie...
..ends up being,
as we kind of knew it...
..then really, just a core emotion
for this guy.
I think Cody's really been looking
for a chicken all his life...
.. more than a dad.
Like many of us.
-Great.
-Yeah, I've been looking.
-l'm still looking.
-How's lunch coming?
We won't ask how far the beach is.
Of course, it's right there.
The jungle set and the beach set were
two completely different models...
..and there was no way to--
We couldn't move
the camera around to show--
Show that the beach was close.
Now, this whole competition day
was inspired by a location...
..up in Northern California
called Maverick's.
Where Cody got his last name,
right?
Yup, we were-- It was that--
That documentary we watched--
-Condition Black.
-Condition Black, yeah.
Surfers going out in Hawaii
after a hurricane or--
They were gonna cancel it, right?
And the promoter wanted
to keep doing it.
Yeah, that was back in '74.
The promoter pushed the surfers out
against their will...
.. because he had a big, live broadcast
all set up to go.
That's right.
Didn't wanna have it cancelled.
So Reggie was inspired by that.
And if he's watching right now,
we apologize.
We hope you learned your lesson.
Without you, we'd never have been
able to get story point.
So thanks.
I'm trying to think of all
the incarnations of this scene.
-l couldn't tell you.
-The whole--
Yeah, the fight Reggie and Lani
had about...
.. whether the contest
would proceed or not.
That's right. Man, I remember
this used to be like...
.. 15 minutes longer
to set up the contest rules and--
Oh, we had the rules
and the scoreboards and all that.
And we realize that...
.. you folks, out there don't really need
all that information.
You already know this stuff.
If a surfer falls, you probably lost.
If he stands up on the board,
rides it, he'll win.
Those were our rules,
we decided.
That's all people really care about.
Now, this scene kind of
really happened.
-With our animators--
-Surf day.
Surf day out at Zuma Beach.
Not quite that size a wave.
Watching 40 or 50 people...
.. taking the same wave.
Wiping out all at the same time.
Hey, you guys came up with this.
-Little flashbacks, they're great.
-Flashbacks, great.
Just needed to get inside his head.
Yeah, you were doing something
unimportant...
. like you were having a baby
at that point, I think, and--
Not me, I won't take credit.
Great shot here.
-l love this.
-Not sure if he's gonna make it or not.
I love the soundtrack.
It was a huge moment for Cody...
..and we had to watch the music
still swell but we didn't get too big...
.. because it's not the climax
of the whole sequence.
-There he is.
-That was a late addition.
Oh, we struggled. Should we bring
him back, should we not.
Really hats off to Ash
on that one, we....
We weren't sure.
We kept thinking we could
bring him back at the shrine.
But it's nice to bring him back earlier.
We used to have a really extended--
-We showed everybody--
-Two minutes of--
--rising up through the ranks.
It's called that, right?
-Rising through the ranks?
-Yeah.
Oh, nobody care.
I just told you what you already knew
was gonna happen.
Exactly.
-Joe was enjoying everything.
-We knew from the beginning...
-...we wanted Joe to win the contest.
-From the beginning.
Just didn't know how
it was gonna happen.
Joe's gotta win. Joe's the guy
who doesn't care about it.
As his character developed,
it made more sense though.
l love Chicken Joe's surfing style
and that scene too.
It's like holding on to the rails
with his talons.
-Joe, typical Joe.
-Yup.
Again this is all improvved, right?
Yeah, although they were
recorded separately, the kids, were.
Their agents and managers
would not let them work together.
So we had to record them
separately.
And the hiccup was real too.
The hiccup-- I think this is when
Jeff brought the DAT recorder...
.. back in the first day.
And his son was just hiccupping,
and we go, "We gotta have that."
This was a late little addition, too,
but it's a nice touch of Lani.
Instead of just supporting Cody,
actually hurt by the whole thing.
That he would choose
to compete over Lani and Z.
Well, I like that story point,
it just holds...
.. that energy back
for the end of the story too when...
.. everybody realizes
that Cody's triumphed.
I love that kind of decision.
One thing we never got
to make a point of...
...was that surf board of Joe's,
it's an ear of corn.
Some bit of old wood
that fell of a barn somewhere...
..and turned it into this corn board.
Remember there was a long dialogue
scene with Cody and Joe here?
Where Joe is talking about
the meaning of life.
It got a little preachy.
Yeah, it got a lot preachy.
Much better for Joe to be
talking about kittens in the cloud.
Yeah.
A reminder of Z.
That medallion came in
real useful.
It wasn't planned
that way, originally.
This used to go by so quickly
that-- A big moment--
-Tank wiping out, yeah.
-Weren't you guys saying:
"lL wish we could just replay it."
And we said, "We can, it's SPEN."
"It's animation. It's SPEN.
-We can do it."
-So here you go. So we did slow mo.
So anybody that missed
what's happening...
..we not only show them
we have Sal tell you.
But the energy that Sal
brings to this when you hear it.
It's great.
Well, Sal did a lot of improv.
We just showed this to him.
We showed him the scene
and he just did a few takes.
As if he was commentating
on a live event.
Doing it live.
And we hoped that the audience
would forget about Tank...
..and think that maybe...
.. you know, you misdirect to think--
Make everybody think....
The last wave is gonna be about Cody
having to ride against his best friend.
-Right.
-And we were struggling...
.. With all this in editorial.
Well, we struggled every day
in editorial.
And Ivan said, "You know what?"
We wanted Tank to come back into it.
And Ivan said, "Well, there's a
really tough move called the Airdrop...
.. where a surfer comes off the top
of a wave and drops straight down."
And then that spurred all
this, coming up.
Yeah, that was the signature sound
of the tube again.
So Cody's about to get tubed.
He has a choice to make.
Here he comes.
Joe's unfazed.
Even then, yeah, Joe doesn't go,
"Hey, wait."
He just-- He enjoys it.
Of course, Cody's
gonna do the right thing.
Boneyards was there from
the beginning, wasn't it?
Yeah, we had that.
It was gonna be our climax.
We had that thing where
Cody went back and saved Tank and--
Right.
But they were taking
Lani's job away from her.
It was getting convoluted so we said,
"Well, we gotta get Cody to Z.
That's where the story
picks up again."
We made some tough trims
in here that was really--
We'd animated some of them.
It was beautiful.
That wave-- That wave
is just staggering there.
-This whole Boneyard sequence.
-Just incredible.
And the mist that these guys
are put in there and...
l love these shots in here.
All the...
Yeah, Mychael Danna incorporated
some Hawaiian drums...
...into the score here,
especially coming up right here.
I just love this part.
Now, that was--
We saw something like that
on some documentary stuff.
It was a guy on a jet-ski
getting pushed up onto the rocks.
-Yeah.
-Trapped.
In, like, this area,
they couldn't get to him.
We poured over this moment
for hours...
..to get this last--
-Days, months.
-Weeks, months.
-Maybe you hours.
-It all blurs together now.
This is where we talked about
the X again so we'd play it off again.
Third X.
And Cody having to let go.
-Oh yeah, the third X.
-Stop fighting.
Fighting life, fighting everything.
This really does work
if you're in a situation like this.
-We tested it out.
-Well, we put Chris in--
-Yeah, he tested it out for us.
-Well, only needed--
l only need one leg to get around.
"Is he dead? Are they dead?"
Where's Cody?
Lani is an incredibly powerful
.
penguin.
The way she can maneuver
something like that.
And the Reggie character
that really cares.
There's more of Reggie
we had in the movie at one point.
-Just couldn't fit it all in.
-Yeah.
Love this scene.
Z hasn't yet decided
to go back on the beach.
But here he kind of admits he lost
and Cody lost and it's no big deal.
In fact, we had another take for Cody
where he was really down about it.
He said, "I lost."
And then you found
another one, of course, that...
-...wasn't so--
-He's just kind of tossed it aside.
That's right.
It's a great way
of bonding two guys...
.. who have gone through
the same thing in life.
Realize it's not that important.
It's so subtle.
It's not like you would normally do.
You really push for maybe
very sentimental lines...
.. but this is very natural.
Every time I've been on a surf board
in that situation--
-"Let's go, loser."
-Yeah.
"Don't touch his stuff,"
if you guys remember the line.
Oh, yeah.
When Z says,
"Don't touch my stuff, man."
-Okay, Doris and Sheila.
-There's Doris and Sheila right there.
-Yeah, Z's ex-girlfriends.
-Mindy Sterling.
-Jane Krakowski.
-We had to cut them out.
They gave such wonderful, wonderful,
wonderful stuff.
But those are not their voices.
Yeah, because they were trimmed out
of the movie.
We wanna save them
for another movie.
--l got lost for a little while.
But that kid there, Cody...
Okay, I'm a sucker,
but I love this moment here.
Yeah, we'd knew that Z's appearance
would overshadow Cody.
And that it would be great if Z could
take the spotlight back over to Cody.
-And then Mario takes it back.
-Yeah.
The animator did this little
touch here, Z...
.. rubbing Cody's head just like he did
back in Shiverpool, 10 years ago.
Nice touch.
The one piece-- The guy's
we never got together...
-...were James and Jeff.
-Oh, Yeah.
They never got to do
their scenes together.
The idea of dropping the boards
was that they were Reggie boards...
..and everyone was kind of--
-Done with Reggie.
-Yup.
Notice the fluorescent colors...
..as compared to the natural colors
of the other boards.
We used to have an extra long
wrap-up, then we just said, "Well..."
These two scenes with Kelly and Rob
were animated without their voices.
We didn't--
We couldn't get ahold of them.
They were always off in
the other side of the world...
.. Surfing some great breaks.
And we finally caught up with them
over the Internet basically...
-...and recorded in Hawaii and--
-Very last day of production.
Last day.
Yeah, within an hour their lines,
recorded in Australia and Hawaii...
.. were cut into the movie.
That's a nice touch.
-Look, that hair's not real.
-Hey.
Now, he looks like a sea otter.
Sponsors of the competition
were Reggie Belafonte's--
-Hair gel.
-Wood wax and hair gel.
That's right.
We had really wonderful help
in this movie.
There was a really--
It's quite a vision to carry out
for the second movie at a new studio.
But there were great people...
..we were lucky enough
to help us along the way.
-Incredible, incredible artists.
-Yeah.
Incredible voice talent, everyone.
We talked about this
being the ultimate--
It's Z's beach
but it's never looked better.
And everyone's back on,
it's full of life again.
How did they get that thing
out there, that pot?
We always ask that.
With that-- Who better to put, you know,
on the board than Mikey at the end.
We got Kelly and Rob surfing.
-Look at the lighting on this.
-Yeah.
Cody used to get tubed
a lot earlier in the movie.
And it seem like such a spiritual
thing that it's something that...
.. Maybe you shouldn't earn
until right at the end.
-Right.
-And he also went in by himself.
And then Chris said, "No.
That's how he started the movie.
He's alone, so why don't we get him...
-...in there with Z?"
-He's never had the dad.
We thought, "Oh, come on, we gotta--
The two of them together, finally.
Kelly Slater said after seeing
the movie...
.. that there were various
other times in the movie...
..he wanted us to go into the tube
and see inside there.
He was just, like, really eager to
see that and then he realized...
..at the end, to hold off and to-- To get
the experience of being in the tube.
He was happy, relieved.
A ring of fire there
with the golden light around there.
That's wonderful.
-Gives me goose bumps.
-Incredible.
Love it. Oh, but it's not over yet.
No, we're gonna have a really
long extended "Where are they now?"
And we're gonna check
with all the characters.
-Oh, that's right.
-But they were all kind of wrapped up.
-Yeah, except for these two.
-Yup.
We needed-- We had a lot of feedback
on what happened to Mom and Glen.
-Particularly Mom.
-Yeah.
There are suggestions
that they show up for the competition...
..and we just didn't want that
so this was--
And that Mom has a change of heart
right here.
-But not Glen.
-Never Glen.
So Mom's supporting Cody,
Glen never.
We tried a version
where Mom was a little more--
-Yeah, just like Glen.
-She's like--
-She didn't--
-"What do you mean he didn't win?
Why are you doing this?
You're embarrassing us?
-Get out of here," so....
-Yeah.
And then we went--
Others went, "Wait a minute."
They wanted to see Mom
change a bit.
-And so--
-She does.
We went-- Dana was right down
the hall, we recorded her.
And then we went through
the transcript of Brian Posehn...
..and found lines that worked,
you know.
That was the value of these transcripts
we had.
-Yes.
-Hours and hours of material that--
There's always a little nugget
that was right for a moment.
-Right.
-If you looked hard enough.
So those two did not record
those scenes together.
The fact that Cody's mom
comes back...
..and understands that
something good happened...
. this, I think--
Satisfied a lot of folks.
We also--
The scene that's at the very end...
.. with Glen, was pushed up here
when we thought:
"You know, let's just leave it
with those two."
And it was such a great out,
with, "This interview's over."
But the scene
was already animated...
..1 don't know if it was all lit yet.
But it was such a great scene and we
said, "We gotta put it somewhere."
So we decided to put it
at the very end.
So those are the people that stay
to the bitter end...
..get a little treat.
So yeah, it's a fun movie to do and--
It's a nice way to spend a few years
on the beach, in the water.
It's fantastic.
So it came out well.
-This is actually very fun. It's great.
-Yeah.
l haven't seen the movie in a while
and it's, you know, it's cool.
In a week.
Haven't seen the movie in a week.
That's a while.
l was watching it
probably five times a day, you know.
-So--
-You know what, these movies...
..these kind of movies,
they come along so rarely...
..and I just wanna say,
it's great working with you guys.
-Likewise.
-Where are the tissues?
And I'm looking up all the names
in the credits here and just--
-It's an incredible team.
-Yup.
-Couldn't have hoped for better.
-Very lucky, really.
And I think everybody
had a really good time on this.
Hope you guys
had a good time listening.
-Yeah, thank you.
-Hope-- A little insight to the movie.
Or at least we hope we helped you
take a nap if you were sleepy.
Maybe you're asleep right now.
We can make subliminal suggestions.
Buy more DVD's...
..or Blu-ray.
Thanks for listening, guys.
-Appreciate it.
-Thank you, guys.
Thanks for getting this little movie
for your home theater.
Get out there.
Get out there and surf.
-What do you doing watching TV?
-And if you live in Indiana...
..the lakes are going off today.
If you need a river, you can dam
the river then surf that.
Do you wanna follow a tanker?
Oil tankers are going down in
the gulf right now.
-Yeah.
-Pretty good ride.
And there's always snowboarding.
Hey, that's a thought.
Shakabrah.
-Over and out.
-See you, dudes.
Remember when we were talking
about you leaving? That was great.
Remember when
you were gonna go?
-We were gonna go--
-You should still go.
It's technical equipment.
I know what I'm doing. I can unplug
one of your little Hollywood devices.
The lighting thing,
whatever you call that...
..and then the microphone thing.
Go back to Hollywood.
Cody would never do this.