Pleas-s-se go to sleep
Please go to sleep
S-S-Sleep, little man cub
Rest in peace
Hup, two, three, four
Keep it up
Two, three, four
Hup, two, three, four
Keep it up two, three, four
Oh, the aim of our patrol
ls a question rather droll
For to march and drill
over field and hill
Is a military goal
Hup, two, three, four
Dress it up, two, three, four
By the ranks or single file
Over every jungle mile
Oh, we stamp and crush
through the underbrush
In the military style
Hup, two, three, four
Keep it up, two, three, four
Doo-bee, doo-bee
Doo-bee-dee-doo
Well, it's a-doo-bah-dee-doo
Yes, it's a-doo-bah-dee-doo
! mean, a-doo-bee, doo-bee
Doo-bee, doo-bee
Doo-bee-dee-doo
And with...
Look for the bare necessities
The simple bare necessities
Forget about your worries
and your strife
1 mean, the bare necessities
Are Mother Nature's recipes
That bring
the bare necessities of life
Wherever I wander
Wherever I roam
! couldn't be fonder
Of my big home
The bees are buzzin' in the tree
To make some honey just for me
When you look under
the rocks and plants
And take a glance at the fancy ants
Then maybe try a few
The bare necessities of life
will come to you
They'll come to you
Look for the bare necessities
The simple bare necessities
Forget about your worries
and your strife
1 mean, the bare necessities
That's why a bear can rest at ease
With just the bare necessities of life
Now, when you pick a pawpaw
Or a prickly pear
And you prick a raw paw
Well, next time beware
Don't pick the prickly pear
by the paw
When you pick a pear
try to use the claw
But you don't need
to use the claw
When you pick a pear
of the big pawpaw
Have I given you a clue?
The bare necessities of life
will come to you
They'll come to you
When you find out
you can live without it
And go along not thinkin’ about it
lil tell you somethin’ true
The bare necessities of life
will come to you
Look for the bare necessities
The simple bare necessities
Forget about your worries
and your strife
1 mean, the bare necessities
That's why a bear
can rest at ease
With just the bare necessities of life
Yeah, man
Doo-bee-doo
Aye-bee doogie-woogie doo
Dah dee-ding dah-ding-ding
Oh, lode diddly-ohh-zing-boing
Sca-bee-doo, hoo-bi-dee
Zee-boh-doh-zub
Diddly-ub-doo-dee-moy
! wanna be a man-man
Mon-mon, lorang
Orangutango-jango
Now, I'm the king
of the swingers, whoa
The jungle V.LP.
I've reached the top and had to stop
And that's what's been botherin' me
} wanna be a man, Man Cub
and stroll right into town
And be just like the other men
I'm tired of monkeyin' around
- Ooh-be-doo
- Oop-dee-wee
- l wanna be like you
- Hop-dee-doo-bee-do-bow
! wanna walk like you
Talk like you
- Too
- Wee-bee-dee-bee-dee-boo
- You see it's true
- Shoo-be-dee-doo
- An ape like me
- Scooby-doo-bee-doo-bee
Can learn to be
Human too
Now, don't try to kid me, Man Cub
1 made a deal with you
What I desire is man's red fire
To make my dream come true
Now give me the secret, Man Cub
Come on
Clue me what to do
Give me the power
of man's red flower
So can be like you
Hey, de-zop-ba-nonie
Hap-de-dee-ba-lat
Da-dat-dat-non
Hey, a-baby-dot-doo
Zaba-doo-doo-day-doo-bop
Doo-boo-doo-day, ze-bonz
Za-bop-bop-bobby
- Za-bah-doo-dee
- Well, a-ree-bah-naza
- He-beh-do-beh-doy
- Well, a-lah-bah-zini
- Wadahlabat-boodalabat
- Seebahlialat-dodie
- Oooh-ooh-ooh
- Well, a-ha ha ha
Gettin' mad, baby
- You-hoo-hoo
- Boop-dee-dweet
- l wanna be like you
- Bop-dee-ocobee-doobee
! wanna walk like you
Talk like you do-ooh-ooh
- You see it's true-ue-ue
- Shoo-be-dee-doo
- Someone like me
- Scooby-dooby-dooby
Can learn to be like someone like me
Take me home, daddy
Can learn to be like someone like you
One more time
Can learn to be like someone like me
Scooby-dooby-dooby
Dooby-doo
Look for the bare necessities
Some good ol' bare necessities
Forget about your worries
and your strife
1 mean, the bare necessities
That's why a bear can rest at ease
With just the bare necessities of life
I'll live here in the jungle
all my life
Hup, two, three, four
Keep it up, two, three, four
Oh, we march from here to there
And it doesn't matter where
You can hear us push
through the deepest bush
Hup, two, three, four
With a military air
We're a crackerjack brigade
On a pachyderm parade
But we'd rather strolf
to a water hole
Hup, two, three, four
For a furlough in the shade
Trust in me
Just in me
Shut your eyes
And trust in me
You can sleep
Safe and sound
Knowing!
Am around
Slip into silent slumber
Sail on a silver mist
Slowly and surely
Your senses will cease to resist
Trust in me
And just in me
Shut your eyes
And trust in me
Trust in me
We're your friends
We're your friends to the bitter end
The bitter end
When you're alone
Who comes around
To pluck you up
When you are down
And when you're outside looking in
Who's there to open the door?
That's
What
Friends are for
Who's always eager to extend
A friendly claw
That's what friends are for
And when you're lost
In dire need
Who's at your side
At lightning speed
We're friends with every creature
comin' down the pike
In fact, we've never met
an animal we didn't like
Didn't like
- So, you can see we're friends
- Friends in need
We're friends in need
and friends indeed
Friends indeed
Oh, friends indeed
We'll keep you safe in the jungle
Forevermore
That's what friends
Are for
My own home
Father's hunting in the forest
Mother's cooking in the home
! must go to fetch the water
Till the day that l am grown
Till 'm grown
! must go to fetch the water
Till the day that l am grown
Then I will have a handsome husband
And a daughter of my own
And I'll send her to fetch the water
I'l be cooking in the home
Then I'lf send her to fetch the water
I'l be cooking in my home
Look for the bare necessities
The simple bare necessities
Forget about your worries
and your strife
1 mean the bare necessities
Are Mother Nature's recipes
That bring the bare necessities of life