Tokuma Shoten, Studio Ghibli,
Nippon Television Network,
Buena Vista Home Entertainment,
Hakuhodo, Mitsubishi and Toho Present
lf you find yourself troubled
by something mysterious
or a problem that's hard to solve
there's a place you can go
a place where...
Oh no!
Haru, are you awake?
Just got up!
Good
Morning
Really...
Why bother to set
your alarm clock?
Bye
Aren't you having breakfast?
It's so delicious
Ooh, so delicious
Not fair
Bye
My shoe!
Excuse me
Oh no!
The Kingdom is now gone
Yet the mountains and rivers remain
The castle draped in the
Dense greens of spring
Miss Yoshioka
You don't have time to sneak in
just get to your seat
Yes sir
Caught again
The Cat Returns
l hate this
Late again and embarrassed
in front of the whole class
Machida was laughing at me too
He was laughing
Why?
What's wrong with me?
Well, this must be a sign
Something even worse
is about to begin
Thanks for the sympathy
That's an unusual cat
What's so great about Machida?
He's just so cool!
Have you told him that?
He seems to have a girlfriend
She's a freshman and
very good-looking
So you already know
In case you get dumped
I'm ready to console you
Thanks a lot
l think Tsuge is cool
Good, if he dumps you...
Had something in his mouth
Stolen goods?
Hmmm...
What's he doing?
Hey cat! Watch out!
Anyway, it's just a cat
Hey, that’s dangerous
Oh no. what's he doing?
Wait. Haru!
Good going Haru!
Hey! Stop that truck!
Cat...
Are you OK?
Thank you for saving me
from a dangerous situation
l hope you haven't injured yourself
Please excuse me, but
l really must be going now
Allow me to express
my gratitude later
Don't mention it
Haru!
Ah, you broke it
Never mind, a cat's life is
more important
Did you see that?
Huh?
The cat bowed to me
Haru...did you hit your head?
I'm home
Don't step on that!
Sorry. ] can't decide
which pattern to use
Honey, can you make dinner?
Mom
Can cats talk?
Well.. let's see
What !?
Come to think of it
you said so before
Really?
When you were very small
you used to say
“lL can talk with cats”
Did I?
Yes, don’t you remember?
What's wrong?
l see, you're hunery
Do you like fish?
OK, take these
You're so dirty...
Good?
OK. OK
More?
Good girl
Eat them all
No need to thank me
Haru
Oh. Mom!
What were you doing?
Talking with a cat
Remember asked you what did you
talk about with the cat?
Then you said. “she told me it's
tough to make a living in this world”
and I thought it was so funny
I guess that did happen
Anyway, I'll get up
early tomorrow
in time for breakfast
Uhm,..over here please
A little closer
Allow me to introduce
The King of the Kingdom of Cats
A King among Kings
The Cat King
That's me
The cat you saved today was
the son of the King, Prince Lune
Given the importance
of the matter,
the King himself has come to
show his gratitude
Uh... mmm...
Thank you
This is the program
From tomorrow,
countless joys will befall you
Thank you
See you
A dream?
You're saying...
it really wasn't you
who did this?
l have no idea
Then who did it?
Haru!
Haru, hurry up!
What is this!
Cattails!
Oh. I work too hard.
I'll ba in bed today
No!
Why?
Haru, it's this one, see?
Morning!
Sorry, got to run
What's she up to?
You think she has catnip?
Catnip? Why?
Don't know
Hey Yoshioka!
Leave your cats at home
They're not mine
What is this?
It wasn't a dream
It was those cats that did this
Was it a mistake to save a cat?
Haru
Wha...What is it?
Did you get rid of
the catnip smell?
Yeah, it seems OK
and the cats aren't after me
anymore
That's good
Yeah
Say, can l ask you a favor?
Can you take my turn
for clean-up?
Tsuge has a game today
and I can't make it if I don't
leave right now
Please!
Oh... sure...
Clean-up, right?
Thank you Haru!
Tsuge! Go for it!
Hurray Tsuge!
You're so cool!
Be careful of the step
Thanks
Ouch, that hurt
Oh no!
What a mess
Uh oh
What on earth am doing here?
There you are,
Miss Haru, Miss Haru
You cats! One thing after
another all morning
We're glad you're pleased
NOT!
Why is that!?
This project has been taken
on by the whole kingdom
to express our maximum gratitude!
What are you saying?
don't eat mice
] don't like cattails or catnip
Oh, is that so...
Excuse our ignorance
This is unexpected
How shall] report to the King?
Sorry, did l hurt you?
Maybe ! said too much
To tell the truth, a lot
happened to me recently
Such as?
Such as many things
l see, is that so?
Even a beautiful lady like
Miss Haru has troubles
Again...that's enough
No, it isn't enough
We can't stop now
We'll do our best to
make you satisfied
You have more?
Yes
Please come visit us in
the Kingdom of Cats
The Kingdom of Cats?
It's a nice place
Lots of natural scenery
and good food
The whole Kingdom will
welcome Miss Haru
And what's more
The King is expecting
Prince Lune, who you
saved yesterday,
to welcome Miss Haru
as his bride
No way! That's impossible
The Prince is a cat
What's the problem?
He is a cat but he’s cool!
Cool?
Well...
A Kingdom of Cats might be good
Just laying around all day
Exactly!
It might be heaven
Eat tons of great food
then have a nap,
forget all your troubles...
But a cat's bride...
that's going too far
Even if he is a prince, that's...
Huh?
Well then, we'll come
for you tonight
What do you mean?
Hey! Wait!
Ouch
That really hurts
Wait, give me time to think
That is to say...in a word...
What can I do?
I'm sure those cats will do it
They'll take me to
the Kingdom of Cats
They'll make me the cat's bride
No, no, no! Never!
Haru
Who is it?
Haru, the Cat Business Office
Find the Cat Business Office
Not this
Who is this?
What is the Cat Business Office
I'm sure they'll help you
A large white cat at the Crossroad
will show you the way
A large white cat...
Haru, go to the Crossroad
and find the Cat Business Office
Never heard of
the Cat Business Office
A large white cat...
But the voice was beautiful.
Might be a nice white cat
Oh, I'm tired
I'm taking a break
What? What is it?
What's this big fat cat
What are you doing here?
A large white cat!
Is this it?
Hey you. do you know
the Cat Business Office?
I need your help
I mistook you for a different person...
oops, a different cat
I'm sorry l sat on you
Follow me
You are the one
Hey, wait for me!
Hey, isn't there an easier way?
Is this revenge?
Because I said you're fat?
What a strange place
Where's the Cat Business Office?
Are you listening?
l have a big problem
These cats are taking me
to their kingdom!
Is... this...
Hey, Baron!
You got a visitor!
Cut the theatrics and just come out!
Welcome to the Cat Business Office!
Cool...
This place is in a dimension
a little differant from yours,
a world for beings who have souls
When people create something
with all their heart and hopes.
the creation is given a soul,
like me and him
Oh my gosh!
Ha is Toto, a gargoyle with a soul
Baron, it's quite rare for you
to have a visitor
Yes, and a quite charming one,
don't you think?
Baron...?
I'm Baron Humbert von Gikkingen
The person who created me named me so
So that's why you're called Baron
l heard your story
Trouble with some cats from
the Cat Kingdom?
That's right
l saved a cat from being run over
Now they're saying. in return.
they want to take me to their kingdom
In return?
Heh, it figures,
too kind for your own good
You shouldn't have bothered
Your mind is nasty as ever, Muta
You can't appreciate the kindness
which saved a cat
And she is in trouble for it, right?
Never mix in somebody else's business
Where did you meet this girl?
At the Crossroad place
She already knew about this place
Hmmm
Uh, I heard a voice,
though ] don't know who it was
A voice?
You listened to some strange voice!?
How naive can you get... Yeow!
What are you doing?
Why don't you hold your tongue!
You stay out of this... !!
Don't fight because of me...
You said your name was...?
Oh, it's Haru.
My name is Haru
Okay, Haru.
Plaase do come in
Don't worry about them
You lousy black bird!
Don't you even know I'm a crow?
Come out from the dark, you fowl!
Nobody can miss a giant
marshmallow like you!
You big hog of a cat!
Go get fried, chicken wings!
Shut up, moo shoo pork!
Pollo loco
I'm coming in
Oh... This place is gorgeous
Now, do come in and have a seat
Thank you
Any lemon or milk with your tea?
Milk, please
You have a beautiful office
Here you are
Thank you
Cute
It's my special bland
Can't guarantee the flavor though,
it's different each time
This is good!
This is really good
Then, you're lucky
How can you drink green leaves?
Too refined for your
tongue, I bet
Go catch a worm, bird
Muta...
Tell me about
the Kingdom of Cats again
That whole place is fake,
a place for
those who don't have
a mind of their own
Mind of their own...
One of the Cat King’s men said,
they want me to marry their Prince...
Why not?
A cat's bride?
What !?
Might not be so bad
This is going nowhere
Could be an interesting experience
l see
I did want to visit
the Kingdom of Cats once
This might be a good opportunity
How brave of you, Baron.
but think I'll give it a miss
You are coming with me
No thanks. It's not my territory
You're not taking her, are you?
That won't be wise
But I can't leave her here all alone
Babysitting isn't my thing either
Are you busy?
Not really
Um, 1 think I'll go home
I'm just making trouble for all of you
I started all this mess
l have to solve this myself
l see
I'm sorry
] couldn't be of any help
Okay, okay, I'll do it
I'll just hang around for a while
You're a good cat, Muta!
It's set then
Haru, you can come back now
But...
Muta complains a lot
but doesn't actually mean it
l see
He is actually nice then
That's right
I'm not listening
Thank you for your help,
Moota
Moota?
Did you say Moo!?
Are you saying ! am a fat cow!
No, you're just fat...oops!
Ha ha. This girl is not bad
No way I am going to halp!
Didn't we have some delicious
chiffon cake in the cupboard?
Where?
On the upper right shelf
Why didn't you say so
Let's have a piece before we start
I'll go get my special
mulberries then!
It seems like this is
going to be fun
Let me help too
Haru, you need to think about
how you can learn to be yourself
Then, you should have nothing to fear
Okay
Baron! Give me a hand. I'm putting
some whipped cream on top
We're really going full-scale
Of course we are
Maybe, I'll find something here
Yes
ls that Toto at the door?
Miss Haru, we have come for you
No!
What is this?
Not good
You promised to help me!
Baron, horde of cats headed this way
You're blind as a bat!
After them!
Owwwww...
Miss Haru. we looked
all over for you!
I'm going home
Careful!
Let me off! Take me back!
lam going back, this instant!
You must be having
pre-marriage blues
lam not!
Things got a bit out of hand
Owwwwww
Hey, you, wait, ouch, let go!
Muta, and Baron!
Let go, I'm telling you!
Toto, now!
Don't let go!
Why did we get out of the way!
No choice
I'm really mad now!
Yeay!
This is over the weight limit!
Toto!
I see it
Where are you going !?
Out-maneuvered
Go up
OK
Now what?
The wind. Follow the lights
OK!
Ooooh...
I landed on my back...
Why?
Where am I?
Muta? Did you get bigger?
No, you got smaller
Why?
Because we're here
This is the Kingdom of Cats?
This is it
Wow, cats really live here
Well, this is their kingdom.
you know
Hey, come on
Ahh, it's so nice and relaxing here
We should find a way out
and go back
Just a little longer
Let's get going
But...it feels so nice
No! You must go back at once
Hurry. Run away!
Hey, what a pretty cat
Even the cats are prettier here
Please, you have
no time to lose!
Haru, you are not meant
to be here
Why do you know my name?
Miss Haru!
It's that cat again
lam so relieved to find you
Seems we dropped you
when coming in
Your servant exceeded
our weight limit
Servant!?
No no, this is Muta
Shall we? A banquet is being
prepared in your honor
You are welcome to join us, Moota
Moota? Moo?
But ...
His Majesty is waiting
at the palace
Palace?
The palace is right over there
Oh, really
Yes, indeed
Hey, you're not thinking of...
Maybe it's rude not to
greet the King first
Are you out of your mind?
Let's go!
Please, this way
Wait
Can she come with us?
What is your name?
Yuki, sir. l serve at
the royal table
So you work at the palace
Miss Haru, you'll see her later
Okay, I'll see you again
Haru
What's that? Creepy!
There's my future daughter-in-law
Well, [ must go see her in person!
He's strangely familiar
Please change before
meeting the King
I need to change clothes?
Plaase wait in the next room
Why can't I go in with her?
Don't be gross
Gross?
We prepared refreshments for you
Okay, I'll wait
Not bad
The dress is very becoming on you
Prince Lune is the idol of all
female cats in this Kingdom
You'll be very happy with him
Really?
l mean, no, that's not why I'm here
You look lovely
You are the purrfect bride for Lune
Natoru, who is that cat?
A servant named Moota, I believe
Moota?
Never heard of him
No match for my stomach
Um, ! am sorry but
l can't really accept marriage to...
l thought you already said yes?
That was what I was told
Where is the Prince?
He is away at an official function
Anyway, I don't really know him
And the Prince, he is a cat, right?
I'm not a cat, so
l can't marry him
That, you don't need to
worry about
You already are a cat
Wow, real cat ears
I'm a CAT!!
Muta, where are you?
What happened to him?
He insisted on having
a bowl full and
dunked himself in catnip jelly
He didn't have to die like this!
Muta, how could you
do this to me?
...the banquet is ready to begin
No! 1 don't want to leave him
Then, he will come with us
Is this Miss Haru?
She has a perfect pair of ears!
Such full, attractive paws!
l was told you don't like mice,
so l have prepared
fresh fish for you
Miss Haru doesn't seam pleased
What do we have
for entertainment?
1 will bring them in
l want something more amusing
Next!
Can't you do anything better !?
shall amuse Miss Haru
What should we do?
Why not?
Shall we dance?
I can't dance meow
Oh no, I even sound like a cat!
... trust me
They dance well together
What is this...
I never felt like this before
Being a cat might
not be that bad
No, Haru. Don't lose yourself
You must learn to be yourself
I already told you that.
didn't I?
You are...
Stop this music!
You suspicious cat
Exactly who are you?
Apologies for my
belated introduction
There is nothing to fear
] am Humbert von Gikkingen
l have come for Haru
Baron!
Can this be?
What?
No way
Guards, get him!
] can't eat anymore
It's alive!
Yeay, Muta, you're alive
Uh oh
Stop, you scoundrel!
Take His Majesty
to a safe place!
Don't let him get away
Guests’ emergency exit this way
Out of my way!
Muta, you're strong!
I didn't start it
This way
You're the cat...
Baron, ! knew you would come
How do you know me?
I've heard about you
and your Office
If [ had listened to you,
this wouldn't have happened
If you leave before dawn,
you can still become human
Really?
A secret passage to the outside
This is convenient
What about Muta?
He'll be all right.
Haru, hurry
Yes
This is the back of the castle
Top of that tower leads to the exit
It's so tall!
You must go through the ruins
to the tower and then climb up
We'll make it
Good, Plaase take care of Haru
Wait
She is gone. ] haven't even
thanked her yet
Haru, this is just my guess
but isn't she the one
who led you to me?
Haru, the Cat Business Office
Yes, that beautiful voice was hers
But why?
Because of you, ! almost died
Must hurry now
Right
You guys, listen to me
Did they go in?
Yes, Your Majesty
Purrfect
That labyrinth was built with
our state-of-the-art technology
We'll enjoy the view from here
Tricky
The sun is still high, though
It's always daytime here
What? It is?
It's probably past
midnight outside
Then, we have to hurry!
This way? That way?
Which way should we go?
They are lost
It won't be easy to
get out of there
Right, Your Majesty?
Yes...we have nothing
to worry about
Where are the soldiers?
Over there
Let's go this way
We must keep trying.
one by one
Keep your eyes on the tower
You won't lose your way
Smart
Muta, you're cheating
Why get lost just ‘cause
it's a maze
There he is!
Why does it have to be me?
Let's hurry while he keeps
them busy
Right
Why do I have to be the bait!
Get back, Haru!
You're strong!
Your cane got bent?
I was going to buy
a new one anyway
Used is best
Nice shot!
It hit one of ours!
What?
Your Maiesty,
how could you?
Don't tell anyone, okay?
Excuse me, sir
Our men are all scattered
They are all lost
Where is Haru?
They already got that far!
Hi!
Welcome back
How's that way?
It's a dead end
Everything as planned
Is this another dead end?
It's getting more difficult
Something's wrong! There was
no wall here a minute ago
It must be your imagination
No, we walked through here
Are you saying that
walls have feet?
This is no wall
It's fake
See?
Good work, Haru!
What is all this?
] told them not to get in line!
They are getting away!
Your Majesty, wait!
Go ahead, I'll catch up with you
Show off!
No, Baron...
Don't worry!
Your Majesty, please,
it's dangerous
I can't let this happen!
l have soldiers waiting
in the tower, just in case
Brilliant move!
Good, good
I'm afraid the tower's
getting old...
This is not good at all!
We have no choice
but use THAT
What? No, not that!
If you do that. Your Majesty,
your image will go to shambles
Give me the button!
There is no such thing here
Here's the remote control
Yeay, we came out
to an opening
Just a bit more
Now!
What?
Hold on!
That was a great spectacle!
Let's go!
We're back on the ground
Let's see how things go
We have no choice
Come on, come on
Gikkingen. nice to see you again
Haru! We'll go back to
the castle right away
Being a cat is not so bad
Do I have to learn to like mice?
It's too early to give up
What's all this?
Father!
Lune, you're back already?
His Highness the Prince!
As you were!
Prince?
l hurried back thanks to Yuki
What is all this?
Haru
Oh, Yuki
I'm glad we made it
Err, ] just wanted to thank her
I thought you'd be happy
to have Haru as your bride
You don't need to
worry about me
Il want to marry Yuki
What !?
Looks like news to everyone
This Prince is not bad
Yuki, look
l went to your old
home to find this
Oh, could this be
what I think it is?
Those cookies...
used to love those
That's right
These are the fish cookies you gave
me when [ was an orphan kitten
That kitten, that was you!
You're so beautiful now that
I didn't recognize you
Yuki
Will you accept these as a token
of our life together from now on
That means
you two are getting married?
Oh. l am so happy
for you Yuki!
Thank you, Haru!
If l hadn't met you then,
l could have starved
on the streets
You also saved ma from danger
I didn't know you were the person
Yuki told me so much about
You saved both of our lives
How can we thank you?
I don't want anything
You two made me
so happy already
Saving a cat was a good thing
This is such a moving sight
So you already had a fiancée
I didn't know,
but that is all right
Haru, you must be disappointed
Not really
No need to be polite.
If you can't marry my son,
why don't you marry me?
You can eat all the cookies
and fishes you want
How about it?
Just put me back
to the way I was
That depends on your answer
Are you out of your mind!?
Of course ! don't want
to marry you
You pervert!
Why can't you...?
This is hilarious!
It's out of the question!
l admire a woman with
a mind of her own
You found yourself an ally
I, Renaldo Moon will
lend you a hand!
Renaldo?
Renaldo Moon?
That Renaldo Moon?
That's it!
Who?
Have you forgotten,
Your Majesty?
The worst, most notorious crime
in this Kingdom's history!
A cat suddenly came from nowhere
and devoured all the fish
in the lake and escaped
the criminal of the century,
Renaldo Moon!
Unbelievable...
He's a monster
Muta, you did this?
Disgraceful
I'll eat the whole castle this time!
Take His Majesty to a safe place!
No!
Men, protect Haru
Yes, sir
All forward!
Get that culprit!
Your Majesty!
Leave my father to me
Everybody, please run
But the tower has fallen
It's still connected to the other side
Strange...
Oh no, it's dawn
Leave it to me!
What? Are you...doing !?
Don't!
Haru, run!
We'll be right behind you!
Take care!
You too
Thanks, Yuki
l wasn't wrong
Saving a cat,
feeling lost and down,
that was all part of
finding out who ! am
You go ahead!
Thanks
Where is Father?
Up there
Father, you'll hurt yourself.
Plaase come down
What a rash thing to do
will bring His Majesty back down
We'll settle this with a duel!
My pleasure!
Baron!
Take care of Haru!
Right
I win, King
Orat!
I've heard about a statue of a cat
that doesn't mind his own business
Had no idea you were this good
I heard you were just a window
display standing in some back alley
You should have come to
my Kingdom and joined me
Unfortunately. I'm quite happy
with my present way of life
Where am 1!?
What did you do?
I didn't do a thing
With the tower collapsed this much,
[wouldn't be surprised if the exit
moved to a different point
I must go!
Miss Haru!
l should have foreseen this
But look! Haru is human again!
I think I'm going to fall
Oh no, I'm falling
I'm going down!
Haru!
Muta, please don't say I'm heavy
Hang on...but next time...
lose some weight!
] can't hold on!
Haru!
I'm going to die!
You're not dead yet!
Open your eyes!
Baron?
Straighten up
and look down!
l can't!
Trust me!
Are we...still alive?
Yes!
I think so!
You know what?
Wea look fantastic!
What is this?
There are so many of them
We're saved
Hey, Muta!
How is it, being saved by birds?
Toto!
Oh, it's lousy black bird
Thanks for saving us, Toto
Glad ! had my friends
waiting up here
Doesn't it hurt walking on them?
You're light as a feather, Haru
Really?
disagree
Look, Haru!
It's my school!
I'm home. I was able to
come back!
Everybody, thank you so much!
Yes! They made it!
Hooray, Miss Haru!
I'm relieved
Take care, Haru!
Your Majesty!
Natori
My time on the throne is over
Then must resign with you
Toto, thank you
My heart is still pounding
Of course
But it was a bit fun
Yeah, right
Haru has to go to school,
so she'd better go home and rest
Yeah
Is this going to be goodbye?
Must do one last thing
Baron, I might have
a crush on you
! admire your sincerity, Haru
Haru, when you really need us,
our doors will open to you again
Until then, goodbye!
Goodbye
Thank you!
Baron! Toto!
You too, Muta!
What do you mean, me too?
Me too?
Oh no, better get up
Morning
Why are you up so early?
Today is Sunday
I'm going to the movies
with Hiromi
Going early before
it gets crowded
l better get going
l made eggs and salad for you
What?
l already ate so please
help yourself
There is also English tea
in the pot
And about the tea
That's Haru's special blend
It's a bit different each time,
so no guarantees about the flavor
l see...
Hey, smells good
Haru! News from a reliable source!
What's the big fuss about?
Machida, he broke up!
Oh, he did, huh?
What kind of reaction is that?
What?
Don't you have more
to say than that?
No
It doesn't matter anymore
Did something happen, Haru?
No
You're lying
No, honestly
How about you, Hiromi?
What?
How is it going with
you and Tsuge?
Err, no, nothing at all
Voices
Chizuru IKEWAKI
Yoshihiko HAKAMADA
Aki MAEDA
Takayuki YAMADA
Hitomi SATO
Kumiko OKAE
Tetsuro TANBA
Project concept by
Hayao MIYAZAKI
Original graphic novel by
Aoi HIIRAGI
Screenplay written by
Reiko YOSHIDA
Music by
Yuji NOMI
Theme song sung by
Ayano TSUJI
English translation by
Rieko IZUTSU-VAJIRASARN,
Nao AMISAKI and Steve ALPERT
English subtitles by
AURA and Nippon Cine Arts
Production
Studio Ghibli
General Producer
Toshio SUZUKI
Director
Hiroyuki MORITA