Jt
ey’ [Woman Vocalizing ]
- [ Baby Cooing ]
- gf [ Vocalizing Continues ]
@ Youare my world J
My darling »
@ What a wonderful world
lsee f
You are the song
I’m singing f
You're my beautiful
Melody -
@ Darling
we'd better be going J
Look at her
Isn’t she glowing
@ She looks divine
and you look exquisite J
- { But look at the time p
- {Couldn't be Is it f
@ The crew
is awaiting your orders
Were sailing away
from our borders ,*
- J Steady, boy, steady J
- Ahoy there! They're coming!
Trumpeters ready!
Drummers, start drumming!
ey [ Trumpets: Fanfare ]
Down to the sea
we go}
Down to a world
l know f
@ There’s never been
not ever before .
@Achild born
of sea and shore J
[ Crew ]
¢ Down to the sea we go f
-* Down to the world
below,?
A journey to bless
a princess-to-be
o* Under the sun,
. And under the sea,
Ariel’s coming J
Ariel’s coming?
- Ariel’s coming?
- J Ariel’s coming S
- J Ariel’s coming
Ariel’s coming S
-,*Ariel’s coming
Ariel’s coming
@ What’s all
the big commotion »
é That’s spreading
through the ocean J
@ From sea to shining sea J
[ Laughs ]
@ Dere is no hesitating J
Today
we celebrating .
@ Ariel’s Melody J
eOhhy
Today when Triton’s daughter
comes back here to de water J
2 We gonna have a spree
Ha!
@ De boat is nearer now J
@! think I hear her now
Ariel’s Melody J
{Chorus ]
. La-da, da-da, di-da-da
-[ Chorus ] $ La-da, da-da, di-da-da ,°
- }Ohh-oh f
-, La-da-di-daaah
-fYeah Sf
-, La, la-da, di-da-da
- f Lala-la yp
-, La-da, di-da-da
- f La-la-la
La-la, la-la §
[ Merpeople ]
@ Up from the sea we rise J
Up to the world
of skies J
@ There’s never been
not ever before .
@Achild born
of sea and shore J
@ Up from the sea
-
we rise ,*
@ Up to the world
of skies ¥°
. Forever to be
together as one ,*
@ Under the sea J
And under the sun J
é This is your world
my darling S
@ One world
The land and sea
My hope for you
for always J
@ (s that your heart
will hold part of me J
¢ Down to the sea we go f
- J Up from the sea J
-,’ Down to the world below,
[All]
¢ Together we come
forever to be f
@ Under one sun
@ The land and the sea
- Congratulations!
-[ Whistling, Cheering ]
[ Cooing ]
Wonderful!
My precious Melody,
I’m giving you
this locket...
so that you will never forget
that part of your heart...
will always
belong to the sea.
eet [ Music Box ]
[ Cooing Continues ]
Melody!
[ Cackling ]
A party!
Aaah!
Ursula’s crazy sister!
I didn’t miss the cake
and ice cream, did 1? [ Laughing ]
Morgana!
Surrender the baby,
or I’Il--
Ah-ah-ah.
Ursula would have simply
loved to have come,
but something came up.
N-Now, what was it?
Oh, yes.
-[Gasps ]
- You all shish-kebabbed her!
One minute you're on top,
the next you're sushi.
Now, is that fair, Gramps?
l ask you.
But then, whoever said
we had to play fair?
[ Cackles ]
Oh, Undertow!
Make way,
little mershrimp!
I’m comin’ through!
-[Gasps ]
-[ Melody Cooing ]
Hand over the trident,
or your precious granddaughter
will be shark chow!
You can have
anything you want.
Just don’t harm
little Melody.
Well, well.
I get the trident,
avenge poor,
unfortunate Ursula,
and gain all the powers
of the ocean,
and it’s not even 10:00.
Not a bad morning.
- Hit the deck!
- [Groans ]
Aaah! Ohhh!
-[ Both Scream ]
- [ Cooing Continues ]
Yiii!
Melody!
What have you done to me?
Look at me!
I’m an anchovy!
Aah!
This isn’t the end, Triton!
It’s just the beginning!
- After her!
- [ Morgana Cackling ]
[ Cackling Continues ]
You'll never find me!
But I'l find you...
and your precious
granddaughter!
We shall not rest
until that madwoman is vanquished!
Find her!
I’m sorry. There is no sign of her.
She’s vanished.
- [Triton ] We'll keep trying.
- Sweetie, no.
We've got to keep Melody
away from her.
Until Morgana is found,
Melody can’t go in the sea.
And neither will I.
- But, Ariel--
- I’m sorry, Flounder.
But if Morgana is anything like Ursula,
she'll never give up.
This is the only way.
Melody can’t know about
merpeople or Atlantica...
or even you, Daddy.
[Sighs ]
Very well, Ariel.
You're right.
Sebastian,
you will watch over her.
Me? Aww!
[Ariel]
Melody?
[ People Chattering ]
Oh, Carlotta,
have you seen Melody?
Not since this morning,
Your Majesty.
- gf [Humming ]
- Louis, Melody’s not in here, is she?
No, Your Highness,
but her birthday cake is.
Twelve petite candles.
Cest magnifique!
[ Makes Kissing Sound ]
Whoa-ohhh!
[ Chuckles ]
Whoo-eee! This is gonna be
some kind of shindig.
Yes, sir, a real swanky soiree,
as they say.
There’s just one thing missing--
the guest of honor!
"Sebastian, you watch
over her," he said.
[Grunts ]
I’m too old for this!
A crab my age should be retired,
getting a tan,
playing sea golf,
sipping a tuna colada!
Not baby-sitting
another teenager.
Oh. Hmm.
[ Gasps ]
Melody!
[Sighs ]
Hey, Scuttle. Hey, Sebastian.
What’s kickin’?
Uh, what’s kickin’?
Hmm. L-Let me see.
Don’t rush me.
Ha! You know perfectly well
what’s kicking.
Now, come along.
You gonna be late for the--
- [Splashing ]
-[ Coughing ]
[ Giggling ]
Sorry, Sebastian.
Melody, child,
how many times do! have to tell you?
[ Together ] It is expressly forbidden
for you to be swimming...
beyond the safety
of the sea wall.
Any such swimming
is a reckless disregard of "da" rules,
don’t you know?
- Stop dat.
- [Giggles ]
Oh, Sebastian,
I can’t help it.
I just love the sea!
Hey! [ Coughing ]
Come back here!
You're just like--
like your mother.
[ Chortling ]
Hi, Melody.
[Thunder ]
[laughing]
Trust me!
This time I’m sure
I’ve got it right.
Yeah, that’s what you said last time,
and I was sore for a week.
Oh, stop your carping
and stand still.
Oh, this is gonna hurt.
Yes. Yes. Yes#
Uh-oh.
[Sighs ]
Hmmph!
Aww!
- [Groans ]
- [Snickering ]
Oh, it’s just no use.
The power of the trident
is just too strong for me to overcome.
I bet Ursula
coulda done it.
What... was that...
you said?
Nothin’.
I’m just sayin’--
Stop criticizing me!
That’s all my mother ever did
was criticize me.
It was always Ursula this
or Ursula that...
or, "Morgana, why can’t you be
more like your sister...
Ursula!”
Welt it isn’t Ursula’s fault
! got miniaturized.
- It’s yours!
-Is not!
Your fault that we had to hide out here
for 12 frostbitten years.
-Is not!
- Your fault that we can
never show our faces...
in polite society again!
You're really pushing it,
small fry.
- [ Morgana Gasps ]
-[ Together ] It’s the locket!
Oooh-ha-ha!
This is just the kind of break
in the ice we’ve been waiting for.
When Ariel’s
innocent little daughter...
uncovers the secret
of that locket,
she’s going to have
lots of questions.
And who'll be right there
with all the answers?
-[ Chuckles ] We will.
- Exactly!
She'll be the perfect tool
for Triton’s undoing.
And I'll get to be
big again.
Finally I’ll succeed at the one thing
my sister never could.
Really, really big again!
Total domination
of the seas!
-[Cackling ]
- [ Laughing ] I'll be huge!
[ Cackling, Laughing Continue ]
Melody, please.
If your mother ever found out
you’d been swimming out here--
I know, I know.
She’d flip.
I had a thought here.
Now, where’d it go? Hmm.
Hey, Sebastian, what’s my mom
got against the ocean anyway?
{ mean, how could there
be anything wrong with something so...
wonderful?
[Giggling]
You know what?
Sometimes
I even pretend...
I have fins.
[ Sighs ] l wish I could tell my mom
how I feel.
But she’d never understand.
I can talk to crabs, but...
not to her.
Wait a minute.
[ Groans ]
It just hit me.
How ’bout
you tell Ariel...
how you really feel?
Oh, yes,
by all means.
Just waltz right in
and tell her you been out here...
swimming in the ocean!
We could all just have
a big party.
[ Gasps ]
The party!
Say, that reminds me
of somethin’.
[Max Barking ]
[Barking Continues ]
- Whoa!
- Oh, Your-- Your Highness.
Sorry. My fault.
I-l gotta go.
Can't go the party without shoes.
[ Giggles ]
If you ask me,
she’s a little strange.
I heard she actually
talks to fish.
- [All Laughing ]
- You're kidding.
[Boy] It should make for
an interesting party.
[Girl ] Yes! 1 should say!
[laughing]
[Max Barking ]
[ Continues Barking ]
[ Sniffing, Panting ]
- [ Seagulls Calling ]
- [Sighs ]
miss you, Daddy.
I wish you could be here
with us.
[Sighs ]
- Mother?
-[Gasps ]
- What are you doing?
- Uh, nothing.
-[ Both Sigh]
- [Ariel ]1'lf be right up!
Melody?
[ Gasps ]
[ Sputters ]
I’m ready.
Here. Let me help.
- {Door Opens ]
- So, we’re having a bad hair day.
If we were, you wouldn’t be helping,
would you?
I’m just here to let you know there are
a lot of people downstairs--
We'll be right down.
Give us two minutes.
[ Chuckling ] Right, two--
Where have I heard that before?
Mom, put down the brush.
It’s hopeless.
Ohh.
You look beautiful.
Do I have to do this?
Everybody thinks I’m...
weird.
Oh, honey, everyone has trouble
fitting in at your age.
I know I did.
I was a regular
fish out of water.
You? No way.
I’m just so afraid...
I’m gonna make
a total fool of myself.
Melody, this isn’t just
about the party, is it?
Is there something
you want to talk about?
You know you can always
tell me anything.
Well, okay.
I mean,
it’s kinda crazy and...
sort of impossible.
Now, don’t freak,
but what I dream about more
than anything in the whole world--
- [ Tapping On Glass ]
- How’s it coming?
Oh, Melody.
Is that you?
- You look beautiful.
- [Giggles ]
He’s right.
Now, we'll talk later.
You're going to have a wonderful time
tonight. Trust me.
Jt
ee [ Finishes ]
May t present
Her Royal Highness,
Princess Melody.
[Applause Continues ]
Oh, yeah. Mom’s right.
I can do this.
[ Muffled Shouts ]
Um, hi.
W-Would you like to dance?
[ Whispers ]
Goon.
Sure. Okay.
[ Muffled Shouts Continue ]
eet [ Waltz]
[ Shrieks, Groans ]
[ Muffled Shouts Continue ]
[ Gasps ]
-{Crunch]
- Yeow!
[ Gasps ]
- [Yelling ]
- Huh?
- [Yelling Continues ]
- Aaaaah!
Yaaaaah!
ee [Humming ]
- [Loud Splat ]
-Hmm.
[Guests Laughing, Murmuring ]
- Oh, no!
- That’s it.
I’m booking meself
.
ona cruise.
- I’m so sorry.
- Well, I should say!
- Are you okay, Sebastian?
- So.
Who is she talking to?
[ Laughing ]
She’s talking to a crab!
[Guests Laughing ]
[ Gasps ] You!
[ Gasps ]
- [Shrieks ]
- Saboteur!
You're going
in ze bouillabaisse!
Oh, no! No, Louis!
You don’t wanna do this, man!
I’m old!
I’m not tender anymore!
- Louis!
- [Growls ]
Aaah! Huh?
Melody!
[Growls ]
Death to the crab!
[ Sputters ]
Oh, Louis!
[ Sobbing ]
[ Sobbing Continues ]
[Door Opens, Closes ]
Oh, sweetheart,
I’m so sorry.
What’s wrong with me?
Oh, nothing’s wrong
with you.
Mom, I’m the princess
of disaster.
Being a teenager is hard,
and, uh,
all kids your age feel...
a-awkward.
- And, um--
- Melody?
What is this?
My name’s on here.
-[Gasps ]
- ff [ Music Box ]
-Lt
- That song. Where have I heard it?
- [Melody ] It’s Atlantica.
Jt
-Lt
- With merpeople and everything.
- Mother, you always said it
was just an old fish tale.
- df [ Stops ]
Where did you get this?
I-- 1 found it.
You went over the wall,
didn’t you?
Actually, l went under it.
I hate that stupid wall.
- Melody, you know you’re
not allowed in the sea.
- But why?
- And why does that necklace
have my name on it?
- Melody, listen to me.
You're hiding something
from me.
Y-You deliberately
disobeyed me!
‘ never want you going out there again!
it’s dangerous in the sea!
How would you know?
You've never even been in it!
- [ Resumes Sobbing ]
- Melody, I--
- Uh--
- [Sighs ] Oh, no.
Ariel, darling,
we knew this day
would come.
Oh, Eric.
You're right.
It’s time I trusted her with the truth.
Oh, now, child,
it’s gonna be okay.
You know,
when I was a teenager...
you couldn’t get me
out of my shell for nothin’.
I had this
high, squeaky voice...
and these itty-bitty
little pincers.
And then one day, boom!
I sound like Caruso...
and these whoppers
pop out!
Young lady, just where
do you think you’re going?
- I’ve gotta figure this out.
- [Whimpers ]
This necklace
means something,
and if no one’s
gonna tell me,
I’m gonna find out myself.
Aaaah!
[ Gasping ]
Melody, please!
You’re making a big mistake!
[ Chuckles ]
Oh, this is delicious.
This is divine!
- Let’s go, flatsos.
- [Morgana Continues Chuckling ]
Hurry, Undertow.
There’s a little girl out there
who needs our help.
All right, Sebastian,
you must remain calm.
This is not your fault.
All you have to do is go in there
and calmly explain...
that Melody has run away.
No reason
to lose your head.
Whatever you do,
you "absitively,"
"positutely”...
must not panic.
- Melody!
-[Gasps ]
- Melody’s gone, Melody’s gone!
- Sebastian? What are you doing here?
All my fault!
I tried to stop her!
I don’t deserve to live!
[ Sobbing ]
Gone? Gone where?
Out... out...
to the sea.
[ Blows Nose]
What do you mean?
Where could she be going?
To Morgana’s.
And she can tell me what this locket
means, why it has my name on it?
[ Chuckling ]
Oh, sure, kid.
Morgana’s the best.
She'll help ya.
Okay.
Then let’s go.
[ Sinister Chuckling ]
[ Snickering ]
Angel face,
meet the one and only...
Morgana.
Oh, welcome, my precious.
Oh, don’t be shy.
Come in.
Come in out of the cold.
Sit, sit.
Put your feet up.
Hungry?
Afraid all I have is a cold plate.
[ Chuckles ]
Smelt-cicle?
Kelp chip?
Hush guppy?
Uh, no, thank you.
! was hoping you could
telf me about this pendant,
why it has
my name on it.
My mother
wouldn’t tell me.
[Sighs ]
She just doesn’t understand.
Oh, you’re not the only one with
a mother who doesn’t understand you.
Believe me,
I know just how you feel.
Dear child,
did you ever consider...
that it has
your name on it...
because it has
your destiny in it?
Oh, deep down you know
you weren’t meant to be...
a lowly human.
What you are is something
far more enchanting.
A mermaid?
But it’s not possible.
[ Chuckling ]
Darling, anything’s possible.
You can turn me
into a mermaid?
Piece of fish cake,
honey.
[ Mutters ]
Huh! Lotsa luck.
Doo-de-doo-doo
doo-dum-dee
Ah.
Ursula’s magic?
Where'd you get that?
I’ve been saving it
for a special occasion.
[ Chuckles ] One drop of this and,
bada-bing, bada-boom!
You're in fin city!
Whee!
- Really?
- Come, my darling.
Your destiny awaits you.
[ Cackling ]
[ Continues Cackling ]
I don’t believe it!
I’m amermaid.
Say it loud, say it proud!
[ Cackling ]
[ Laughing ]
I’m a mermaid!
You had this all along.
You coulda changed me back.
Why, I oughta--
Keep your scales on,
small fry.
I’m still reeling her in.
[Ariel]
Oh, Daddy, I'm so worried.
Everything’s going to be
all right, Ariel.
We have search parties
scouring the ocean.
I’m going to join them now myself.
Ariel, maybe you
should go with him.
- But, Eric--
-l need to stay here
and lead the search on land.
But you know these waters,
and you know
our daughter.
You have to go.
It may be dangerous.
Eric’s right, Daddy.
I should’ve known I couldn’t keep Melody
from the sea. It’s a part of her.
Anda part of me.
I have to go.
Bring her home.
What a totally cool
feeling!
[ Giggling ]
Whee!
-[Gasps ]
- [Whimpers ]
Oh, excuse me.
I’m so sorry, ma’am.
e Okay, get a grip
Get the hang of this flipper »
It’s like slipping two feet
Into one big, huge slipper ,*
é This way is left
Which way is right ¢
Oh, now I’ll be circling
in circles all night p
Oh, so this is forward.
No problem.
l can’t believe
I can do this and more
# Toswim in the sea
like l walk on the shore J
Out of my shell
Not closed up likeaclam J
@ Look out, sea
This is me J
eHerelam y
@ Foramoment
allofme Jf
@ ls alive and at home
in the sea}
em swirling and twirling
So graceful and grand ¢
Not stubbing my toes
Getting stuck in the sand ¢
@ Foramoment
life is cool J
e!masplash
in the world’s biggest pool J
é This is more than my thoughts
ever thought it could be J
@ Foramoment
Justa moment J
e Lucky me J
[ Giggling ]
e 'fonly for one moment J
! had shared with you
alll know J
@ The sea wouldn’t be
amystery S
Oh, why did you
have to go
e Everything’s newer
and brighter and bluer J
And truer to life
than before $
of Watch me soar?
@ Foramoment
I canshine J
@ Gota grin
and a fin that works fine
e My fingers are wrinkly
and I really don’t care J
e lfall of my curls
have curled out of my hair ¢
@ Foramoment
I can feel »
All the dreams
I’ve been dreaming are real S
@ Wish my mother
could hear it $
@ The sea is my song f
@ Foramoment
Justa moment J
¢! belong s
é! will find you
my darling S
# And the moment that I do
ell hold you close
my Melody J
And sing
the song of the sea
¢ With yous
- Sing the song of the sea J
- { Fora moment Just a moment J
-,* With you $
- fl belong fy
Oh, thank you!
Thank you so much!
Oh! [ Sniffling ]
- What’s the matter?
- Oh, I knew this would happen.
One taste,
and you’re hooked.
Oh, Undertow,
1m such a failure, such a--
[ Honk]
Oh, my precious,
there wasn’t enough potion
for this to be a forever spell.
Please, I don’t want
to go back to being an ordinary girl.
Isn’t there some way
I can stay a mermaid?
Oh, I’m afraid there’s
absolutely no possible way.
Well, there is one way.
No. What am I thinking?
It’s far too dangerous.
What?
What’s too dangerous?
Well, could make
the spell last longer...
if had
my magic trident.
Oh, but it was stolen
years ago...
by a deranged
kleptomaniac,
and there’s no one
to get it back for me.
Maybe I could
get it back for you.
You would do that for me?
If did, would you
make me a mermaid forever?
Even longer, if you like.
[ Chuckles ]
Now, here is where
the scoundrel lives.
Atlantica? You mean it’s not just
an old fish tale?
It really exists?
Of course it exists, dear.
Whoever told you otherwise?
My... mother.
Well, I’m sure she didn’t mean
to be cruel and deceitful.
Okay, ’ll bring back
your trident.
You can count on me!
Be careful, dear.
Enjoy those fins!
While you can.
[ Sinister Chuckling ]
Hmm, let’s see.
South to Two Circles Pass,
then, uh, north to--
No, no, um, east...
to, uh, hmm--
Ahh--
Ahhh--
- Ah-choo!
- Whoa!
[ Groans ]
[Sighs ]
My map. It’s ruined.
Now how am gonna
find my way to Atlantica?
Help! Someone, please!
Help! Oh! Oh, hold on, sweetie!
We'll save you!
Help! Mama!
Hurry!
- I can’t reach her.
- [All Grunting, Murmuring ]
Oh! Oh!
Somebody help us!
Da-da-da
da-da-da-da!
Mightier than a hurricane!
Braver than a killer whale!
Faster than
a moray eel!
It’s the fearless
adventurers--
Slash-explorers.
Titanic Tip
and his trusty sidekick Dash!
- Oh, no.
- Not them.
Hee-hee-hee!
This is it, Dash. Redemption.
No, not the walrus.
- Sorry. Excuse me.
- Ow!
Oh, was that your face?
We're finally gonna be
heroes for real.
Yeah, they're not gonna
laugh at us anymore.
- Heh. This is too easy.
-[Grunting ]
And a-one, and a-two,
and a shark--
- Shark? Aaah!
- Shark!
- Shark, shark, shark!
- Comin’ through!
- Goin’ up, goin’ up, goin’ up!
- Goin’ down.
Aaaah!
Oh! Mmm! Mmm.
- [All Grunting ]
- [Tip] Get offme!
[All Screaming ]
Well, that wasn’t so bad.
Ohh!
- Mama!
-Mmm!
Another plan
perfectly executed.
What did you think
you were doing?
We were just trying
to be heroes.
You call abandoning my baby
heroic?
You two boys
almost got us all killed.
Of, yeah,
some fearless heroes.
- More like zeroes!
- [All Laughing ]
-[ Laughing Continues ]
- [Penguin ] That's a good one!
Go ahead.
Laugh your
stinkin’ tuxedos off.
[Laughing Continues ]
We'll show you...
someday.
- Excuse me.
- Aaah!
Ohh! Oooh!
You don’t have to be scared of me.
I won’t hurt you.
Scared? Who said anything
about bein’ scared?
Don’t you know an evasive maneuver
when you see one?
[ Giggles ]
Hi. ’m Melody.
This here’s Tip,
and I’m Dash.
Excuse me, Mr. Spill My Guts
To Total Strangers.
- You just blew our cover.
- l was just trying to be friendly.
Uh, guys, I really
need to get going,
so if you could just
tell me--
Aw, see? Now she’s gonna leave,
and it’s all your fault.
My fault?
[ Sputters ]
- Guys--
- She’s probably allergic to blubber.
Oh, yeah?
Well, maybe she doesn’t like
birds that can’t fly!
-[Gasps ]
- Guys--
Well,
you can’t fly either.
And you walk funny.
- Guys!
- Oh, yeah?
Well...
you can’t fly either!
Guys!
Do either of you know how to get
to Atlantica? I don’t have much time.
Why do you want to go
to Atlantica?
I have to get something
that was stolen from a friend.
Ifl don’t,
I'll turn back into--
A what?
Turn back into a what?
-A human.
-[Gasps ]
I knew there was something
unfishy about you.
Tough break, sister.
Drop us a line.
Let us know
how it all turns out.
- We'll take you.
- You will?
- We will?
- She’s a damsel in distress.
It’s our big chance.
Whew. Hoo-boy.
I can’t believe I’m doing this.
Somebody stop me.
All right, then,
we're in.
On to Atlantica!
Aha!
@ Taming the tides J
@ Swarming the seas
Beware, barracudas
Drop to your knees J
Aaah!
«* Defending our friends
and anemones ,*
- J As big as awhale S
- Hey!
With a much smaller
tail f
@ Facing the foe
with our fearless flukes
@ Daring the dastards
to put up their dukes
Great globs of gore
We'll storm the shore J
And seek the unknown
Then can we go home?
Titanic Tip
and Daring Dash
Adventurers-slash-explorers J
é Titanic Tip
and Daring Dash »
Adventurers-slash-explorers J
Our gallant quest
to do our best J
@ And smile
for our adorers J
- J We'll save the day J
- g And make a splash J
é Titanic Tip
and Daring Dash »
We'll clobber those crabs
with their clammy claws
@ We'll shatter those sharks
with their savage jaws J
- { The battle is fierce p
- g And mercifully brief J
The conquering heroes return
as kings of the reef .
e We'll dine
with the best .
o Dressed with a flair
e Climb every mountain,”
@ Because it’s there p
Come on, follow me
We'll make history J
« To courage
TOUS,”
- {The trident J
- fOr bust p
é Titanic Tip
and Daring Dash »
Adventurers-slash-explorers J
é Titanic Tip
and Daring Dash »
Adventurers-slash-explorers J
- J We'll save the day J
- g And make a splash J
- § Melody J
-DTipsS
- And Daring Dash J
All for three
and three for one J
@ Atlantica
@ Here we come J
[ Melody]
I knew it! It’s real!
- Atlantica.
-{ Morgana Chuckles ]
That’s right,
Princess.
Just a little further.
Cloak! Dagger!
Go make sure that no one interferes
with her return, hmm?
Have you heard anything,
Daddy?
I’ve been searching everywhere,
but I’d-- Flounder!
Daddy!
Now what?
- Sorry.
- Ariel?
- Flounder?
- Ariel!
Oh, I’ve missed you!
[ Giggles ]
Boy, you’re sure not
a guppy anymore.
-[ Chuckles ] You can say that again.
-{ Chattering ]
- Over here!
- Throw it to me!
- Yeah!
-fwant it!
Oww!
Children,
what did I say...
about playing Kick the Clam
on the reef?
- Sorry, Dad.
- Kids. [ Chuckles ]
I’m sorry about Melody.
Flounder,
I really need your help.
Wild sea horses
couldn’t stop me.
[ Chattering, Laughing ]
- Oh, boy!
- Follow me!
Come on!
[Sighs ]
It’s so beautiful.
- Whoa!
- Sorry. My...
- Sorry. My fault.
- fault.
-Hi.
Uh-- Uh--
I don’t think I’ve seen you around here.
What’s your name?
I’m... Mel-- Mel--
Hey, guys!
Meet Mel-Mel.
-Hi.
- Hey, you wanna hang out with us?
All right, all right.
Break it up. Break it up!
There’s nothing to see here.
Move along.
Come on,
Miss Popularity.
We have a previous engagement.
Remember?
Maybe I'll
catch you later.
[Sighs ]
This is what happens...
when you bring a country fish
to the big city.
Was that a penguin?
Wow!
[Dash] Nice crib.
Come on.
Follow me.
[Melody Gasps ]
That must be him.
He looks sad.
- He doesn’t look like a thief.
- They never do.
Look!
There it is!
A fork? We're risking our tails
for a fork?
We haven't time for this.
I want every available
merman searching!
Find her!
-[Rattling]
-Hmm.
Dash, if--
if this is the end,
I just want you
to know, pal,
I’m sorry I said that thing
about the blubber.
- Well, I’m sorry about the fish breath.
- Yeah--
- You didn’t say anything about that.
- But I was thinkin’ it.
[ Both Whimpering ]
King Triton,
your daughter has returned.
- Ooh, that was close.
- Whew!
Oh, sure, that’s it. Take your time.
Kick back. Relax.
Let’s all just
linger here and die!
I’m sure
she’ll turn up soon.
He’s coming back!
[Melody Gasps ]
My necklace!
Ah, don’t worry, Ariel.
We'll find her.
Daddy! The trident!
But that’s not possible.
Nobody can remove the trident
from the stand except you, sire.
You or one of your descendants.
Melody.
Who I was supposed
to be watching.
Go ahead, crack me open.
Make a crab cake out of me, sire.
But how could she
have gotten here?
Morgana. If she gets her hands
on my trident--
Double the search parties!
-[ want every creature
in the ocean on patrol!
- Yes, sire!
[Ariel]
Wait a minute.
I Know those two.
It’s all my fault.
Ifl had just paid
a little more attention...
instead of blabbering
on and on and on...
..and on and on.
From now on, Your Majesty,
nothing gets past--
Hmm?
me.
Whoo-hoo!
Yeah!
We did it!
Uh-huh!
Uh-- Hmm?
All this time Atlantica was never
that far away from home.
This is your home?
It used to be.
Whoa, what a pad.
Talk about your curb appeal.
But what’s with the wall?
I know good fences make good neighbors,
but isn’t that a bit much?
- What you tryin’ to keep out?
- It wasn’t built keep something out.
It was built
to keep mein.
Come on. Let’s go.
- Whoa-ho-ho!
- Whoo-hoo!
[Tip ] You know, kid, the three of us,
we make a pretty good team.
[Dash ] Once you're a permanent
mermaid, we'll be friends forever.
- We'll be inseparable.
- Nothing will ever come between us.
- Shark! Run! Run!
- Shark! Aaaaaah!
- No, wait!
- [Screaming Continues ]
It’s just--
[ Laughs ]
Leavin’ so soon, boys?
What can I say?
When you got it, you got it.
Hey! You got it!
Sweetheart,
you're my new hero.
Let’s go.
It’s time for some magic.
But-- But my friends--
Ha! You mean you call those two
yellow-bellied sea slugs your friends?
Come on!
You wanna be a mermaid,
or what?
We got the power.
[ Grunting ]
We got the power!
[ Gasps ]
So there it is.
Swim back as fast as you can and tell
my father. I'll try to find Melody.
But if that old sea witch is in there,
and then there’s that mean little shark,
and then those manta rays come, and then
she takes those creepy tentacles...
so suction cups stick to your face,
and, and--
[ Sighs ] Uh-uh. No way you’re
going in there alone.
But, Flounder,
if we both go,
who’s going to tell Daddy
where Morgana’s lair is?
What's all the whispering about?
1s Melody around here?
- Did you find her yet? If she’s--
- Scuttle!
[ Whispers ]
Get down and be quiet.
Wait a minute.
Scuttle can get help.
Scuttle, l need you
to pay very close attention.
We're doomed.
Oh, there you are,
darling!
Oh, I was so worried
about you,
And look!
You brought back my trident.
- Clever girl.
- Give it to her! Give it to her!
Hey!
Forgive him, dear.
He’s got a little size issue.
Now, ifyou'll just
hand over the--
- Melody, don’t! Don’t listen to her!
- Mom!
[ Simultaneously ]
You're a mermaid?
Ariel, how nice of you to come.
And you brought Flopper
with you.
The name’s Flounder.
- Grrrt
-"Grrr" yourself, pipsqueak.
Get that thing
and hit me.
One bite,
and he’s shrimp toast.
Sweetheart,
hand me my trident now.
All this time,
and you never told me?
Kept the most important secret
In her whole life from her own daughter.
Please, give it to me, Melody.
No, hand it to me.
- It’s for your own good.
- She’s lying!
I’ve given you
what you’ve always wanted.
She’s the one who lied to you
all these years.
-[ was trying to protect you.
- By fencing me in?
You knew how much
loved the sea.
Why did you
keep the truth from me?
Melody, listen to me.
If there was one thing in my
life that 1 could do over, I--
Too late, Mom.
Melody, no!
[ Cackling ]
All the power of the seven seas
at my command!
[ Continues Cackling ]
Hello!
Can we get with the program?
It’s still
a small world down here!
Mom!
Your mommy was only trying
to protect you from mov!
What she did,
she did out of...
[ Sniffs ]
love.
Little Melody’s been
avery naughty girl,
stealing from
her own grandfather.
My-- My grandfather?
King Triton,
ruler of Atlantica,
commander in chief
of all of the oceans!
Or at least he was,
until a certain little thief came along.
- You tricked me.
- You've got no one to blame
but yourself.
Tell me, Melody.
Is being a mermaid
everything you dreamed?
Was it worth it?
[ Cackling ]
[ Gasps ] Oh!
- [Groans ]
- Melody!
Oh, and by the way,
your time as a mermaid
has just about expired.
Catch you later.
I’ve got bigger fish
to fry!
Bigger fish!
Now, there’s an idea!
-[Grunting, Panting ]
- We gotta keep trying.
It’s no use. It’s too thick.
[ Sobbing ]
Oh, Flounder.
I’ve ruined everything.
We're guppies, man.
Jellyfish.
The great Tip and Dash.
Cowards-slash-losers.
Well, at least we’re alive.
Yeah, if you wanna
call this living.
Okay, on the one hand...
we can live
a long, healthy life,
albeit as disgusting,
pathetic, cowardly--
- Worms.
- That’s good. Good.
Cowardly worms.
On the other hand, we could gather
our courage, if we had any,
and storm the fortress
and be heroes.
Yeah, until they hack us up
into fish bait.
- You're right.
- {Thunder ]
-[Gasps ]
- [Thunder Continues ]
Melody’s in there.
She could be in big trouble.
She may really need our help!
So what’s it gonna be?
A lifetime as worms,
or two minutes as heroes?
{Thunder Continues ]
All hail Queen Morgana!
I’m hailin’!
Hold on, sweetie!
The cavalry is comin’!
[ Gasps ] Ariel!
Af! Prince Eric.
Come to join the party?
We're having a blast!
- Aaaaah!
-[ Crew Yelling ]
[ Grunting, Yelling ]
Oh, how dear Ursula
would have adored this.
Morgana!
King Triton?
Oh, please!
Is that the best you can do?
Release my daughter,
surrender my granddaughter...
and I shall spare you.
Oooh! What you gonna do?
Throw the crab at me?
-[Cackling ]
- Hmph!
[ Laughing ]
Face it, Triton.
You're all washed up!
- Uh-oh!
- Ha ha!
’m gonna be teachin’ you
some marmers!
Look at me.
I’m bait!
[ Gasps ]
[ Sebastian Shrieks ]
Oh, yeah! Ha ha!
Look out!
Where’s Melody?
What have you done with her?
You want to join your daughter?
think that can be arranged.
- Aaah!
- [ Barking ]
Eric!
[ Eric Yelling, Muffled ]
You are a very bad lady!
[ Scuttle Grunting ]
Very bad.
[ Both Yelling ]
Goin’ somewhere, boys?
Um, we’re just lookin’ for
the little penguin’s room.
[ Weak Chuckle ]
Well, it’s been nice
knowin’ ya.
Yaaaaah!
Now, that is one brave
hunk of blubber.
I-P’Il hold him!
You go find Melody!
[Dash Groaning ]
Hurry!
[ Groans ]
Aah!
[ Panting ]
What’s-- What’s happening?
Oh, no! Ohh--
[ Gurgling ]
-[ thought you were gonna hold him!
- 1 am holding him!
Nice fishy.
Ooh. Big fishy.
Hold on, Melody!
{Grunts ]
I’m gonna bust us out of here...
[Grunts ]
ifit’s
the last thing I...
[Grunts ]
d-do.
Oh, Tip! Help!
Another plan
perfectly executed.
[Flounder ] Melody!
[Tip ] Uh-oh.
Aaaaah!
Ha!
[ Groaning ]
Fools!
have the trident now.
And all the creatures
of the sea are in my power!
[Cackling ]
I’m the queen of the sea,
and you wilf bow down
before me!
- Oh, this can’t be good
for the lower back!
- Pathetic fools!
- Watch and see how
utterly powerful I can be!
- [Melody] Mom!
The end begins...
for alf of you
with fins!
[Cackling ]
Ha ha ha!
That’s it, Triton.
Bow down!
Bow down before me!
No, Your Majesty.
You mustn't.
I’m sorry, Sebastian.
[Grunts ]
I have no choice.
Oh! Wishes do come true.
See that, Ma?
Who’s your favorite now?
[ Laughing ]
It’s over, Triton.
I sentence you...
to oblivion!
You!
Just what do you think
you're going to do...
with that?
Stay back!
Ha ha ha!
Wrong end, sweetheart.
[ Gasps, Groans ]
Aaah!
- Yaah!
- Grandfather?
I think this
belongs to you.
No!
[Screams ]
[Grunts ]
Never again...
will you or yours
threaten my family.
There will be no escape
for you...
ever!
[Screams ]
[ Whimpers ]
Mommy.
[ Moans ]
Dad?
Oh, Melody,
I was so afraid we'd lost you.
I’m sorry, Mother.
Oh, no, sweetie.
We're sorry.
We should have
told you the truth.
I didn’t mean
to hurt anyone.
I just hoped
I'd be a better mermaid than a girl.
Oh, Melody, sweetie, it doesn’t matter
Ifyou have fins or feet.
We love you for who you are
on the inside--
our very brave
little girl.
Just like your mother.
Oh, Grandfather!
Melody, don’t blame you...
for wanting to join
us merfolk.
And because you're
my granddaughter,
I’m giving you
a most precious gift--
a choice: you can come
to Atlantica with me...
or you can return
to your home on land.
it’s up to you.
I have a better idea.
[Melody Giggting ]
Now we can all be together!
Oooh!
@! feel the music playing
It’s swinging and it’s swaying f
@ Life is a rhapsody,”
Whoo!
«* Today we're so delighted
Today we're alf united $
«* Here on the land and sea,
Oh-hoo!
e (see the sails are sailing
Even the whales are whaling ,*
-,* We're swimming fancy free
- [Grunts ]
e Were feeling better now
We sing together now
here on the land and sea?
La-dee-da
Pick up the beat
e Move your fins
and move your feet ,*
o Life is sweet
Life is grand $
« Blowing bubbles
with the bass brat’s band *
- [ Sebastian ] Everybody now!
- Come on in!
There’s plenty of water
for everyone!
- [All Laughing ]
- Look out!
-  There’s no more stormy weather J.
- § Now we can sing together J
(In perfect harmony J
¢ We're feeling better now
We sing together now
here on the land and sea
- § Those on land sing J
- { Ladee dah doh ys
- § Those below sing J
- { Lo dee doh doh
[Sebastian ]
' Life is sweet as sweet can be,*
@* On the land
and on the sea,*
-,* Everybody sing
- Come on, Grimsby, join us.
The water’s great!
I think not, sir.
The very idea seems rather absur--
e Were feeling better now
We sing together now,
e* Here on the land
and sea,
- Whoa!
- Sorry.
- Oh, hi.
-Hi.
¢ We're feeling better now
We sing together now f
@ Here on the land J
eAndsea SS
[Melody Giggtes ]