So I get this phone call, July 30th, 2005,
from Steven Spielberg.
He calls me up in
his jovial self and he says,
"Michael, I want you to direct
this movie called Transformers."
I'm like, "Okay, Steven,
well, that sounds great.
"Let me think about it,
and I'll get back to you.”
I hung up the phone
and in the 30 seconds everything
that goes through your brain.
"Is that that little robot toy movie?"
"Is that like a Small Soldiers movie?"
"That was just Steven Spielberg
calling me up. Oh, my God!"
"This is one of my idols,
wants me to direct a movie
"that he wants to
be involved in."
So I thought about it.
I called Adam Goodman, president
of the studio at DreamWorks.
l said, "Adam, so what is
this Transformers movie?"
He goes,
"Why don't you think about it?"
Adam convinced me to
go to Transformer school,
which is in Hasbro
in Rhode Island.
And I'm like, "Okay,
well, let's make the trek.”
So the next morning
we went into Hasbro.
You pass this hallway of all
the famous toys we all grew up with.
We sat in this
big conference room.
I mean, they must have
had 25 people in there,
all trying to convince
me to do Transformers,
and they started with
Transformer school
which is, they basically take you
through the entire lore of Transformers.
Now, I have been offered a lot of
comic book, superhero movies
in my short film career.
And I have always said no because
it really hasn't appealed to me.
But one thing I did spark to recently
was Japanese anime movies.
I just love their visuals. It's just a
really unique type of cartoon.
And I'm sitting in this Transformer,
I guess, like, lecture.
I kept looking at this artwork
of just a multitude of images
and there was something
from this Japanese artist.
He had some amazingly dark,
cool images that...
That just right there
in the room inspired me.
I kept thinking to myself,
"I need to make this very real.
"I need to make this cool.”
I kept thinking about cars
transforming at 80 miles an hour.
Action images would just
kind of come to my mind,
of, like, "Why would I be
interested in doing this movie?"
I did like the lore
of Transformers.
It's very noble, it's got good
morals, it's interesting.
But it's like, how do
you make Transformers
understandable to an adult
who has no knowledge
of what Transformer toys are?
We broadened the story in terms
of bringing in the American military.
It's this big story, but it kind of comes
down to this little story on Earth,
which is all about Sam
and having these glasses.
This is kind of how the birth
of Transformers happened.
l have always had the lucky fortune
of working with military equipment
before anybody else, such as
these Ospreys right here.
They have never
been used in a movie,
and I don't think many people
have shot that Stealth 117 either.
So I've got this hotline
to the Pentagon.
I've got this relationship with
the film liaison, Phil Strub,
who helped me on Armageddon
where we worked with the Air Force.
And Pearl Harbor, where we worked
with the Navy and all the branches.
And I called Phil up and I said, "Phil,
I'm gonna be doing this movie.
"It's a fantasy movie called
Transformers."
And he goes,
"Oh, the kids’ toy, huh?"
He said, "Well, Mike, you know,
if we did have alien robots on Earth,
"[ think the American military
would be involved.
"And we will bring the fight
anywhere we have to.
"So let me read the script.
I'm excited to read it."
And I guess the rest is history.
He loved it.
And then it's a matter of me
going to different bases
and trying to convince bases
to be...Imitate Qatar,
which is the forward command
for the whole Middle East.
And we found Holloman
Air Force Base in New Mexico,
which kind of has these
white sands
which are test missile ranges
for, I think, the Army.
Right here, this was done at
Edwards. These are two F-22s,
which are the brand-new planes
that are costing $130 million each.
They can take out six F-16s before
they can even be spotted.
They are just deadly lethal,
and of course, I was the
first to use those as well.
Why does the military
let me use this stuff?
Because they look good at
what they do in my movies.
And working with these
men and women...
You know, I have done many years
of working with them, in movies,
and, you know, they are
really great people.
And they're really dedicated.
And I really admire them for
the service they do for the country.
And, you know, they don't
work for a great wage,
but they're just so dedicated
to the country and...
You know, so, like, just diligent
and just, you know...
I find many of them so intelligent,
and it's always been a great experience
when I've worked on these bases.
And I really have fond memories
of it.
And very much, they're impressed
with our film industry
because we work very much
like the military works,
in terms of the different hierarchy
and how it works on our sets and crews.
And they are always very sceptical
when we show up,
because they think we're going
to be a bunch of Hollywood...
But they always come away with,
I'm sure, with a great respect.
And they tell us that,
that they come away with a great
respect for what we do,
because they see it so
similar to the military.
So this was our first
transformation here.
And the transformation was...
"How are we gonna do this, basically?"
l had my animators do
tough versions of it.
But when we had
this first version up...
That was the very first version
l ever saw of that transformation.
And it was done by
an artist named Keiji.
He's Japanese.
He speaks like no English.
He is the absolute Rubik's Cube
genius to figure those things out,
of how those parts actually
move and come together.
I met Keiji in a very odd meeting
at Industrial Light and Magic.
I had about 30 ILM artists
sitting in a kind of hi-def room
where we are looking
at the artwork
that my illustrators had
worked for months,
I mean we're talking
eight months, on.
And then I saw Optimus Prime's
face in his first 3-D kind of,
I guess, iteration of him.
He looked terrible.
He had this fat, ugly face.
And I'm like, "You guys
got to be kidding me.
"This is awful. What
happened to Optimus?"
And all of a sudden, in this small room,
this guy pops up in the back,
and he goes, "That Optimus Prime is
an insult to the Japanese people.
"That is an insult to the Japanese,
l want to do Optimus Prime.”
But you can tell someone else
was obviously modelling
Optimus Prime's fat, ugly
face and Keiji knew this.
And so I said, "Keiji, first of all, this
is the most bizarre meeting
"Il have ever been to, the biggest,
funniest outbreak I have ever seen,
"and you know what,
just because of that,
"I'm gonna let you work
on Optimus Prime."
So not only did Keiji do Optimus
Prime in terms of the 3-D modelling,
but he did the amazing
Rubik's Cube
of how we were going to
transform these robots.
What the military is very concerned
of when they do movies
is that they just want things
to be accurate.
They are very into, like,
those uniforms.
If they are not Qatar-issue uniforms,
we just can't use them.
Right here, I shot this
in the Tank Graveyard.
These are old tanks, some are
just kind of shells of other tanks,
where they actually put
them out in the field,
in this white sand, and they
use them as target-practise.
We actually started the shoot,
the very first day was...
I shot this little, I guess,
Mars rover. I shot that.
I got it assembled because
I had this idea for a teaser
that was the very first teaser
that came out the summer
where we just began to start...
We just started shooting.
I just wanted to mark our date of
July 4th and to say we were real.
The very first day of
pre-production photography,
I shot in the Tank Graveyard.
My first days really never
suck, but this one really sucked.
I get to the set,
I'm all excited,
and I'm walking around with
my viewfinder, ready to go.
And I get on set
an hour before call
and the hour passes and then
I'm waiting, "Okay, where's my crew?"
I'm like, "This isn't good."
My crew apparently was
just eating dinner.
And normally when you
get to set, you show up,
you either eat dinner before...
So my cameraman, Mitchell Amundsen,
my operators, everyone's eating.
And I'm like, "Okay." And that pissed me
off, the first night.
So I'm like,
"Mitch, this is a big movie,
"and you're not going to be
eating your burritos any more
"when I show up to set and
I'm ready to work."
So I think that kind of shook the
ground of everyone, the first night.
Because I got to tell you,
when I come on the set
I'm like, ! come in...
They joke on the set,
"Bay's coming in hot."
It means I like to work.
I don't like to fart around,
and everyone knows that
I do a lot of set-ups every day.
An average on a movie is 19 to 25.
I do 50, 60, sometimes 75.
And these are real set-ups.
And I shot a lot of this movie
very, kind of, suburbia.
But I didn't kind of sex it up
in terms of making this slick.
This is a classroom that we all
know about, we have all been to.
And it's something that makes it
more accessible, I think, to everybody.
And like, I have never in my life
ever shot in a Burger King.
But you know what? We all eat at
Burger King or McDonald's or whatever,
and it just makes it
more everyday life.
And I kind of like this,
kind of, sci-fi movie
coupled with this suburbia life.
I thought it was a good mix.
And casting Shia...
l actually started to
look for kids and I had...
My casting ladies scoured the Earth for
the best 16, 17, 18, 19, 20-year-old kid
that can play a 16-year-old
out there.
And we looked from London to
Australia to Canada,
and lan Bryce was the first to
mention to me Shia LaBeouf.
Or "LaBoof." I call him
"Shia LeBuff.”
I said, "Well, saw him
in Constantine,
"and I have never seen
the movie Holes,
"but in Constantine he was playing
a cab driver. He looked a little old."
So the kid came in, and
he was kind of skinny
and, like, a little goofy and
way over-excited.
I'm like, "Dude, you
got to calm down here,
"you're just auditioning with
me at my office.”
And he goes, "Wow, I just...l want to be
an action guy and I want to be a...
"It's just like, wow, I love your movies and
I can't believe I'm meeting you."
I'm like, "All right, calm down,
let's just do the audition."
And I just instantly liked his
energy in the audition.
You know, we had some of our early,
early written pages,
where the dialogue really needed
to be tweaked and made more real.
And sometimes it's actually good to
read with some clunky dialogue,
and you see how actors
could fare through,
because a good actor can
make any line sound good.
And Spielberg will even
tell you that.
That's the art of acting,
.
In a way.
But I started throwing some
stuff to Shia,
like improv-ing with him a bit
in the audition.
My thing is I love finding actors
that can improv
because a lot of my film-making,
.
we Improv as we go.
I mean, we have the basis
of the scene.
I mean, I kind of learned this on working
with Martin and Will on Bad Boys.
Shia just had this great thing.
And, you know, I called Steven,
and I said, "I met with Shia.”
And Steven goes, "I love Shia."
So he was all excited about that.
And I said, "Well, I really want
to show you this tape."
l went downstairs and because I had
auditioned a couple of other kids
and he just was heads and tails
above every other kid that came in.
And I asked the girls
in the office,
my assistants who are
very blunt, I said,
"So what do you think
of him?"
I said, "Just watch the DVD,
watch his video."
They saw and they go like,
"Oh, my God, he's great, he's great.
"He's so funny, he's so charming,
he's so funny."
So I sent the audition to
Steven,
and then I called Shia back.
And meanwhile I had to
make this movie for a price.
And I actually do some of
my own actor deals
because when I make a movie
for a price, 1 make it for a price.
So I have to play a tough guy and
I say, "Basically, if you want the part,
"you got 24 hours to decide. This is
what we are going to pay you.
"Yes or no, give me an
answer in 24 hours."
So sometimes that's the
only way to get a deal done.
I must say, I'm very proud
of the fact
that we made this movie
for $150,000,000.
But I'll go into that later, okay?
But Shia, I guess he was
my first snag on the cast.
And from there it followed
to Jon Voight
and then the amazing John Turturro, who
l had always wanted to work with.
I originally thought of Steve Buscemi,
but Steve was busy directing something,
because I love working with Steve and
Turturro is someone I've always loved.
Me being such a huge Coen
Brothers fan.
It's like, anyone who can bowl
and have a rose in their bowling ball,
I got to work with that guy.
From there we kind of went
on to get our female,
and I looked at a lot of females.
It was a very hard role to cast
and Megan Fox is someone
we auditioned for a movie
I produced for Platinum Dunes
for Amityville Horror.
And I remembered her and
my casting ladies brought her in.
said I wanted to see her
because I really liked her look.
And in person she's very, kind of,
timid and shy. She's from Tennessee.
She had a sweetness about her,
and I knew I had to make her tough.
And she was very new at acting.
But I just liked something
about her.
There was something that
was more exciting to work
with an actress who is fresh
and not done a lot of movies.
And so I had Shia come in
and work with her.
And we did several
auditions with her
and working with Megan, she
was so timid in the beginning,
just being on this big, massive set.
But there was a good kind of
chemistry between her and Shia.
Shia was able to really
lighten her up,
and there were times I really
had to make her tough.
And every actor has a button
you got to push once in a while,
and you got to figure out what
that button is when you're directing them.
And her button was...Because I
couldn't get her to emote tough enough
when she was, like, cutting that
little robot in half with a saw.
And it just was looking way
too girly, way un-tough.
And I'm like, "Megan, remember
I told you when you got this part,
"you had to be tough.”
And she told me she would hang out
with mechanics or whatever
to get this movie part.
Finally, her button was, I said, "Megan,
we have so much money on this movie,
"we will stay here all night long
to get this one shot.
"l don't care if we stay here 15 hours,
we're gonna shoot it all night long.
"Because you will hate this
shot right now.
"Come here, look at the monitor."
And all of a sudden that would
get her angry. It would get her pissed.
And that was her button where she
was able to really give me...
Like emote, and whatnot.
So anyway, I just thought she had
a good thing with her and Shia.
And Shia was able to really throw
a lot of things at her.
And, you know, her problem was
with his improv,
she just kept laughing through
the takes. So that wasn't good.
Many of the times we had to CG
her face out when she was laughing.
No, I'm kidding, we didn't.
Mojo, the dog, was kind of like
an idea...
I just love dogs and like...
You know what, a dog addicted
to pain pills with a cast,
that's just funny.
So I said to the writers, I said,
"Let's put a dog named Mojo."
So I auditioned a bunch of
Chihuahuas.
And this one was, I guess,
by far the best one.
Then I thought, what better
than having a Chihuahua
that's stoned eating pain pills,
that hobbles up on his
little penthouse of a birdhouse.
So you can imagine when
I'm telling the art department,
"l want to build this little
silly, little doghouse,
"but it's elevated."
Well, this gives the movie
audience a laugh,
because that's just funny.
Right here, the dad right here,
this is my best friend,
Robert Offer, who's my lawyer,
who I have known since nursery school.
He has a problem with his kids.
He doesn't let his kids walk
on his grass.
And I have always...I save things up
that I learn in life for movies.
And I'm like, "What neurotic dad
"doesn't let their kids walk
on his own grass?"
Well, this is Robert
Offer right now.
And this right here is complete
improve, where...
This is an example of how
we were playing around with
Kevin Dunn and Julie White,
this amazing mom who just actually
won a Tony. A Tony award.
At this time, we can't confirm
whether there were any survivors.
Oh, my God.
Our bases worldwide are,
as of now, at DEFCON Delta,
our highest readiness level.
We're dealing with
a very effective weapons system
that we have not come across before.
But our prayers are with the
families of the brave men and women...
Honey, Daddy's gonna be okay.
I've never seen
a weapons system like this.
The thermal shows this weird aura
around the exoskeleton
like it's cloaked by some
kind of invisible force field.
That's impossible. There's no
such thing as invisible force fields
except in, like, comic book stuff, right?
-Man, I don't know.
-What is that?
My mama, she had the gift, you know?
She saw things. I got the gene, too,
and that thing that attacked us?
I got a feeling it ain't over.
How about you
use those magic voodoo powers
and get us the hell out of here, huh?
When I took that picture,
I think it saw me.
It looked right at me.
All right, we got to get this thing
back to the Pentagon right away.
They got to know
what we're dealing with here.
My radio's fried.
-1 got no communication with aerial.
-Hey, Mahfouz.
-How far do you live from here?
-Not far. Just up that mountain.
-Do they have a phone?
-Yes.
All right, let's hit it.
Dude, are you sure
we're invited to this party?
Of course, Miles.
It's a lake. Public property.
This is a scene where for
Shia, you know, our character Sam...
This is an experience where
every guy has had this experience,
where the tough guy comes up
and kind of tries to embarrass you
in front of his friends.
This moment right here is
the moment where
I think every guy first of all
identifies with him.
But you like him instantly because he's
able to come back with comedy and wit.
This guy, John, right here,
he jumps up on this tree
and I'm like, "Wait a minute,
that's great, that's funny.
" mean, what kind of kooky-ass
friend would hang on a tree
"and make this kid embarrassed?"
So I wasn't gonna
make this kid the geek,
because I didn't want the geek.
l wanted the geek who
was sharp, who was witty
but was able to come
back with humour.
And right here with this whole
"colouring book" thing,
this is, I think, where you kind
of fall in love with this kid.
No, it's a good book.
Your friends'll love it.
You know, it's got mazes in it and,
you know, little colouring areas,
sections, pop-up pictures.
It's a lot of fun.
That's funny.
People were very worried
about the tone of this movie,
where it was very
edgy and hard
and then it had these funny
kind of suburbia touches.
And, you know, that's the thing
that everyone talks about,
the tone of the movie.
They love the tone of the movie,
and that's what, around the world,
when I did press for this movie,
everyone talks about the tone
and how funny it is.
And, you know, that's just
kind of what I like doing.
It's my thing.
God, I can't even tell you
how much I'm not your little bunny.
Okay.
You'll call me.
Who's gonna
drive you home, tonight?
Hey, man,
what's wrong with your radio?
-I'm gonna drive her home tonight.
-What?
She's an evil jock concubine, man.
Let her hitchhike.
She lives 10 miles from here, okay?
It's my only chance.
You got to be
understanding here, all right?
All right. We'll put her
in the back. I'll be quiet.
-Did you say, "Put her in the back"?
-I called shotgun.
I'm not putting her in the back.
You got to get out of my car.
-That's a party foul.
-What rules?
Bros before hos.
Miles, I'm begging you
to get out of my car. Okay?
You can't do this to me.
You got to
get out of my car right now.
So when I signed on
to do this movie,
God, there was a lot of talk
on the Internet about,
"Michael Bay will wreck this movie,
he won't know how to do this movie.
"He doesn't know anything
about Transformers."
You know, stuff like, "Michael Bay is
wrecking my childhood.”
"Death to Michael Bay." Boy, I had a lot
of death threats, I must say.
They even actually protested
at one of my offices,
but it was an office 1 had moved
out of two years prior,
so, you know, I guess they weren't that
smart, to figure out where to protest.
But I remember listening to
stuff on the Internet.
I would listen to some of their ideas
that they would talk about,
because fan support
is very important,
and I wanted them to be
happy with Transformers.
But I was trying to introduce
a world of people
that have never seen
Transformers to this movie.
And, I think, in a way, it was better
that l wasn't a Transformer fan,
because I was able to make
this movie more accessible
to the non-fan, I guess.
So I must say right now,
lam a true Transformer fan.
l have probably thought
about robots
more than anybody
in the past year and a half.
And probably...
I thought about robots
more than anybody else on
Earth for the past year and a half.
We would have artwork
that would leak.
I mean, it was truly one of
the most sought-after movies
and talked about on the Internet than
l can remember in a very long time.
Our art server had 39,000
attempted hacks
in the month of January,
in the year 2006.
And we had to literally get, like,
almost Pentagon-type quality encryption.
And they actually personally hacked
into my personal computer.
And they were able to steal
one script.
We know who stole it, and
l was able to get the script back.
But luckily it only
got out once.
So there were so many leaks that I
decided to actually keep the script...
Just literally, had the only original
script in my computer.
And certain actors had
ones that were older
and everyone had coded scripts.
And we collected all
the scripts from the crew.
We gave them out
and they gave it back
and all those
different measures.
And there was one script,
a very old script
that got out on the Internet
that everyone read,
and everyone kept
commenting on, and...
But it was so old,
scripts can change.
In a month you can change
so much in a script.
And theirs was, like,
probably five months
older than what the script
was in the movie.
I mean, we had...
In case the script got out,
we had names of our robots,
a. k. a. names.
But there were many characters
that I tried to create.
Like, let me give you an example.
We were working on this movie,
budgeting this movie and
they have to make these toys,
like moulds and like the idea
of these type of moulds,
a year and a half out.
We didn't even have a script
and lan Bryce came to
me and says,
"Hasbro needs to know
what Transformer vehicles
"and what are you using
for the Decepticons?
"Autobots and Decepticons.
What kind of cars?"
And I'm, like, literally had to
come to a choice with, like,
"Okay, I think, maybe a tank.
"l don't know if we can get that
amazing bomb-searching Buffalo truck,
"that's brand new, that
they are sending to Iraq,
"if we can maybe do that one.
"I definitely, if l can get an F-22,
but I don't know if we can get an F-22."
So that's how we kind of had to decide.
We had to decide very quickly.
There it is.
l had fun. So, you know,
thanks for listening.
-Oh, yeah, yeah.
-You... You think I'm shallow?
I think you're...
No, no, no. I think...
I think there's a lot more than
meets the eye with you.
Okay.
Yeah.
All right, I'll see you at school.
All right.
That's stupid.
That was a stupid line.
"There's a lot more than
meets the eye with you." Stupid.
Oh, God.
Oh, my God. I love my car.
Hey, guys, I think the other team
figured it out. Terrorists.
Come on, man. This is way
too smart for their scientists.
-Think about it.
-What do you think, kid?
No way. This is nothing like
what they are using.
This is Air Force One.
Level of flight, level three-three-zero.
We will hunt down this enemy.
And when we do,
we'll know
just what to do with them.
-Thank you.
-You're welcome.
l also wanted to make other characters,
like in the boom box on Air Force One.
l like this kind of character,
and I think, if we do
Transformers 2,
we're gonna have a lot more
unique characters,
like this but also bigger.
And just, you can imagine
where the mind can go here.
I mean, I designed some...
With the artists, some
amazingly huge characters
who just got to be too big, too
costly, too expensive, whatever.
And it was Steven who said,
"You know what? We should
probably just keep this kind of like
"six against five or something,
where it's a little bit more manageable."
And I think he's right
that we keep it smaller
to kind of try to introduce
what's going on here.
Steven says I saved 30 grand right there
by doing that little one camera move.
We had a guy grab the boom box.
He's right. So I saved an effect.
Then right in here, this is our actually
full-scale puppet of this...Frenzy here.
Frenzy was animated by
a French artist
at ILM.
I liked this very quirky
kind of movement.
And when I was
directing the animation,
because I would actually
every single day,
I would work with animators
where they would send me
down what they are working on
so that I can actually
direct them,
you know, after these shots that...
We have done these plate shots
and try to direct their acting.
I got to tell these characters
so well
that I knew that when another artist
was working on this Frenzy character,
he wasn't the French guy.
I'm like, "Well, did you guys have
a different animator working on this?"
They are like... You hear them kind of over
the conference call, "Yeah."
So I'm like, "You got to put
the French guy back on,
"because it's a total
different character."
You know, and he says, "He's on
another movie, he's working on Pirates."
I said, "Well, you got to get
the French guy back.
"Whatever you got to do,
you got to get the French guy back."
Someone!
They're hacking into Air Force One!
We need a senior analyst.
-I think they're planting a virus.
-A virus?
-It's streaming right now.
-They are planting a virus
and stealing a whole lot of data
from your system at the same time.
Code Red. We have a breach.
Air Force One, someone onboard
has breached the military network.
I'm in the cargo hold. Clear. Clear.
-You got to cut the hard lines.
-What?
-Whatever they want, they are getting it.
-Sir?
Permission to take down
the Defence Network.
-Cut all server hard lines now.
My theory on effects, well,
it all comes down to lighting.
And I feel everyone
in their brain
has something that we
don't really know that's there,
but we can tell when
something is not lit right.
We don't know why it's there,
but we just know there's
something wrong with the shot,
and it's all coming down
to lighting.
Because we are used
to looking at the world
the way we see it
through our eyes.
After I did Pearl Harbor,
Dennis Muren said to me...
He says,
"You raised the bar on effects."
And I'm like,
"What did he mean by that?"
And he goes, "You have just
made effects more realistic."
And the first time I went to ILM,
or used them, was on Pearl Harbor.
And I had a big meeting
up there where I just felt
that Lucas’ stuff is awesome,
but it's very pastel.
In terms of their light,
it doesn't look real,
the shadows aren't
dark enough,
it doesn't have enough contrast.
It doesn't have the right
tipple reflections on metal.
So that was one of
the big achievements
I think we worked with
on Pearl Harbor,
in terms of shooting a movie
at 12:00 noon,
and making it, not disguising it
in night and showing it in broad daylight.
And making the planes as real
as possible and all these other ships.
And so I think that's what
Dennis was talking about.
Well, you know this, we had to
take it to a brand new level,
in terms of trying to
make reality here.
So we spent a tremendous
amount of time
and software and just
trying to invent new tricks
on how to light these robots.
They use this process
called ray tracing.
When you look at a car,
you go out on a parking lot...
I've shot a lot of
car commercials, so...
I was trying to explain, you can't just
have one quality of light
.
on a car, on a plece
of sheet metal.
It will reflect soft light,
hard light
it will have pings,
it will have long lines.
Cars are, like,
a nightmare to light,
in terms of if you're actually doing
a total digital model of a car.
So you probably couldn't
have done this movie,
I guess, as of two years ago.
That's my car!
No!
No, no, no, no.
So in terms of our effects,
we had Industrial Light and Magic
that were heading up Transformers,
and we had Digital Domain,
which is an effects company
that I recently purchased with
a couple of other partners.
Those are the ones that did...
Both companies did
the work for this movie.
ILM did three-quarters and Digital
Domain did the last quarter.
ILM came down
and they talked to me
about something that
was used in Star Wars Ill.
It was a digital model
of a character
that was kind of like a robot,
and it was so uncomplicated.
I'm like, "Guys, we have to go
so much farther than this."
General Grievous was ILM's most
complicated digital model at the time
and it was, if you look at it, it's so simple
compared to the complexity that we
needed to do our models.
They talked about these models which
finally, when they were done,
Optimus Prime is made of 10,108 parts
that all have to move,
not intersect,
and it's just an immensely
complicated digital model.
They say they're the most complicated
digital models ever made.
My name is Sam Witwicky.
Whoever finds this,
my car is alive, okay?
So this is actually Shia's first night, and
you can see his nappy hair right now.
I just kept looking at his
hair, I said,
"Dude, we gotta do
something with your hair."
And he says, "Mike,
what's the matter with my hair?"
I said, "It just looks nappy.
We gotta make it cooler."
l wasn't allowed to cut it because
he was still shooting Disturbia.
And this is his first
scene for the movie,
and those dogs chasing him
are actually killer police dogs.
And Shia's running,
and there's a man in a big dog
suit who stands behind him,
and he was there with a whip,
and he was calling the dogs.
Well, they actually missed
the guy with the big dog suit
where they're supposed to
chomp on the arm,
and they kept going after Shia.
Shia was almost killed that night,
lam not kidding you.
Thank God he was fast.
It wasn't good when the guy with
the whip, he says, "Uh-oh, uh-oh."
The whole crew started
chasing after the dogs
with the big chains on their necks,
so we were able to tackle them.
-Good, you're here.
-Let me see your hands!
-No, no, no! It's not me!
-Let me see your hands.
-The guy's inside.
-Shut up! Walk towards the car.
Put your head on the hood.
If you have military assistance, you
have to have advisors on the set
that are from the Pentagon
that make sure
that we're doing things correctly.
They won't tell us, like, what lines we
have to say and what we can't say,
but it's just gotta be accurate.
When Rachael here had
to go into this room,
l was just gonna have
her slip into the room,
but we had to have this other
guy knock on the window.
That was the only way they were
gonna let me do this shot,
because they would say there would
be no way in the Pentagon for her
to slip into a private
room like this.
So you gotta make these little
concessions here and there.
And I said to the guy, "Are you sure
that would never happen?"
"No way, that would be impossible. "
"Are you sure?"
"No, that's impossible."
So, okay, I'm, like, "All right, this is
the way we gotta block this scene."
shows them doubling
its naval activity.
Maybe it's a precaution,
because isn't that what we're doing?
The signal pattern is learning.
It's evolving on its own.
And you need to
move past Fourier transfers
and start
considering quantum mechanics.
There is nothing
on Earth that complex.
What about an organism?
A living organism?
Maybe some kind of
DNA-based computer?
-And I know that that sounds crazy...
-That's enough. That's enough.
We have six floors of
analysts working on this thing.
Now, if you can find proof
to back up your theory,
I'm gonna be happy to listen to you.
But if you don't get a filter
on that brain-mouth thing, you're
gonna be off the team. You understand?
Look, I can't be any clearer
than how crystal clear am being.
-It just stood up.
Wow. That's really neat.
Okay, chiefie.
Time to fill her up.
And no drippy-drippy.
What are you rolling?
Whippets? Goofballs?
A little wowie sauce with the boys?
-No, I'm not on any drugs.
-What's these?
Found it in your pocket. "Mojo."
Is that what the kids are doing now?
Little bit of Mojo?
-Those are my dog's pain pills.
-You know, a Chihuahua. A little...
What was that?
You eyeballing my piece, 50 Cent?
You wanna go?
Make something happen. Do it.
‘Cause I promise you I will bust you up.
Are you on drugs?
This was actually the very first day of
official shooting right here.
New Mexico, White Sands.
Let's hope this telephone line works.
Hey, heads up!
Heads up! Hey! Heads up!
What the heck was that?
English, dude. English.
The way we made
the Skorponoks work
was I remembered something
we did in Armageddon
where we did these primer cord
explosions that...
Primer cord's like a very stable
kind of explosive device.
It's like rope.
And we put like 150 of
these in a row,
and they had a computer
that was able
to fire milliseconds apart from each
other so it made a ripple effect.
And that's how we did this shot right
here with this ripple shooting up
and the thing jumping
out right behind them.
l remember doing
the animatic for that shot.
Il said, "You know what?
That shot's a trailer shot."
And that was Tyrese's second day
where the guys actually had to
run over a carpet of explosives
as the stuff was fired
behind them.
I'm, like,
"Guys, do not stop, do not trip,
"and we're gonna fire
these things off,
"and this stand's gonna go,
because it will really hurt your foot."
So that look is, I guess,
one of fear and real terror, there.
A lot of these guys, these rangers
here, are the real deal.
Many of them were very decorated
United States SEALs and Rangers.
Hey, I need a mag! Give me a mag!
-Cell phone!
-I don't know how to thank you.
Fire!
This scene right here with Josh
was something that I remember
a real SEAL telling me.
It happened down in Grenada where
they were trapped in a house.
They lost all their coms,
and they had a cell phone where
they had to call to the Pentagon
and literally had to get a credit
card to get out of the country
and link up with an operator at the
Pentagon to get an air strike to come in.
And they had to vecto
in their position.
So something I always held in my
ideas of wanting to get into a movie,
and so this was
an idea of making it
kind of fun and serious
at the same time.
I just like the whole
chain of events
and how fast you can see
this air strike come in.
It's called an Air Force Combat Controller.
That's what Tyrese plays.
An Air Force Combat Controller is a job
that a guy can use a gun.
He can help them in battle,
but he's a very important tool
in terms of getting very deadly
air support,
which is what they call
"danger close,”
which is where they'll
shoot missiles,
and they give a precise position
where the friends are,
and they will give a precise position
where the foes are.
And these missiles will sometimes
come in 50 feet, 20 feet,
that's why they call it
"danger close" there.
You know, sometimes you think
we're "movie-ising” this thing up
where the guys are
coming in with,
I guess, those laser-sighting
things on their guns.
That's called marking a target.
Hey! Make way!
-What is that?
-I don't know.
We need air support
and we need it now.
Roll in strike package
Bravo on unknown target.
l authenticate Tango Whiskey
at time 0300 Zulu.
Attention, all aircraft.
This will be a danger close-fire mission.
These guys on the AWACS, that
was done on Edwards Air Force Base.
I told these guys on the AWACS...
These are all the real guys.
I said to the guy in charge of
the AWACS, I said,
"How would you run this mission?
"This is what's going down
on the ground.
"This is what's happening.”
And literally within three minutes,
these guys were talking.
I did not add one line here.
This is exactly how they talked.
That's as fast as they talk.
And, literally, we were capturing it
like a documentary.
It's amazing how fast everyone's
talking over each other.
And a multitude of things
.
going on.
And what's going on,
Josh, right now
is laser-designating for these missiles
coming in right now,
and that's actually how it's done.
These Warthogs are, ! must
say, very, kind of, scary
‘cause they've got a very
low, kind of, sound to them
and they get very low to
the ground,
and they're slow enough
where you can see them
and they just got this evil whine to it,
and they're just so deadly, these things.
No frigging way
that thing's still not down.
Spooky Three Two,
use 105 shells. Bring the rain.
Be advised, ground team
is requesting 105 sabot rounds.
Skorponok was our first
scene that we shot
and it was one of the first scenes
that was kind of digitally completed.
And that was kind of, I guess, the basis of how
these Transformers should look.
I started showing some of my friends this
scene and everyone kept saying,
"Well, what is it, an animation?
What is it?"
And then I'd show them
this scene
and then instantly,
this is a scene they go,
"I get it. l understand
the movie now."
"You're doing this kind of
in a real-life way."
And it's got fun, and,
you know, it's kind of sci-fi.
So I guess this is when we started
convincing a lot of people.
Like even the Japanese came
in, the Toho distributors.
I had to do a lot of dog-and-pony
shows for a lot of people
because we were, I guess, one of
the very few non-sequels of the summer,
and we had to kind of
position ourselves.
And a lot of theatre owners,
"Well, what is Transformers?
I don't get it."
So we did this little compilation
reel of 20 minutes,
and it's something that we started
showing around to theatre owners
and to try to get people on board,
to understand what we have here.
Because everyone
thought this is, kind of,
"What is it, silly?" "Is it
animation?"
Is it this, is it that?
We started showing people this.
Like, for example, Toho,
which is the biggest movie
distributor ownership in Japan,
which is a gigantic market.
They came into my trailer, I
showed them 20 minutes of stuff,
and, literally,
you just heard the word...
And I guess that meant
"Good" in Japanese.
They upped our estimate,
they doubled our estimate
of what we're gonna make in Japan,
and they gave us
the number one house...
Toho, I guess,
chain in Japan.
But that reel was a way to really
get people on board with this movie,
you know, ‘cause I kind of knew
what we had early on,
and I remember going in to
see my very first fight in Vegas.
A live fight.
It was Oscar de la Hoya.
And I walked in and there was
Peter Chernin, who I'm friendly with,
and, you know, good jovial fun,
he's walking in with his friend.
And he goes,
"So, [ hear you got Transformers."
And I said,
"So, l hear you got Die Hard!"
And I'm, like, "Yeah,
they're the same date.”
And I just kind of said, "Yeah,
but you'll move, don't worry."
And, of course, they moved.
You know, it's kind of a game
of chicken.
I think they saw our
second teaser.
We wanted it to be a hard-edged teaser,
‘cause we wanted to show the fans
that we're gonna do a serious,
cool Transformer movie
and we weren't making
it too kiddy,
and it was going to appeal to
the 30-year-old guy and girl
that, you know,
grew up with Transformers,
as well as the younger kids
that are just getting into it.
Looks like there's a message embedded
in the signal. Let me work my magic.
"Project Iceman"?
-What's Sector Seven?
-Who is Captain Witwicky?
Are you playing
those video games again?
You can tell right here, 1 mean
this guy, Omar, right there,
he wasn't in the script,
but I always add weird stuff like this
tight here...Going through glass.
Why are we doing that? I don't know,
it's funny, all right?
That's just my humour.
So this is where the studio goes,
"What are you doing?
Is this director out of his mind?"
But in every single movie theatre,
I've seen it around the world,
they all laugh.
You know, what can I tell you?
We're not told where they're going.
Morning, Mo.
The government has been very quiet
about what's going on but in our...
-Mojo. Mojo.
-They were headed directly
towards secret targets.
Stop with the barking, Mojo.
It's too early. Please?
We had $145 million to
make this movie.
It doesn't sound like a lot.
I mean, it sounds like a lot,
but it's really not.
When you look at some of these
movies like Pirates, which is $350
and Spider-Man which is $325,
I don't even know how you spend
that much money on a movie.
I'm really proud of the fact
that we did this movie
for ultimately $151
at the end of the day.
We were very judicious about
where we used the effects.
And I must say a lot of that is
attributed to Steven,
‘cause Steven would put
the reins on me.
I mean, literally, Steven is very,
very tough about budget.
He wanted me to think really hard
about how many effects I used
and to use them and
choose them wisely.
He would say, like, "Listen,
when I did Jurassic Park,
"it was only 50-something effects,
and we all remember it as more.
"When I did War of the Worlds,
it was only 117 effects."
I kind of thought, "Are you kidding?
would think it'd be more than that."
So he really got me to thinking
how to use my effects wisely
‘cause they can get very pricey
and that's why the budget
can just balloon.
So I literally animaticked the whole
movie, in terms of every scene
where we were gonna
do big effects.
Literally, a lot of these effects in the movie
are exactly how we did them
in our little MILE files in my office.
I started to get excited about potentially
what I can visually show.
Like this shot right here of Shia
going in, this whole scene.
A kid on his stupid mom's bike that is
now gonna confront a monster.
I kept thinking this could
be a movie...
Every kid has to have a
movie that they own, you know.
With me growing up,
it was like E. T.
and really, like, Raiders of
the Lost Ark and Star Wars.
Those were two movies
that kind of...
There are seminal moments in
my childhood of cool movies I saw,
and that's what I wanted
this movie to be for kids.
You know, it's something new and
different that they can discover.
It's not a repeat of something.
You know, I can't tell you how
many kids have come up to me
saying, "It's my favourite movie
I've ever seen!
"l love Transformers! I can't wait
to see Transformers 2!"
You know, this is why you do movies,
and I think people responded to it
because it was kind of
new and different.
And, well, what I'm really
surprised about
is the massive age range
this movie had,
from 50, 60-year-olds to,
I mean, young four-year-olds.
I don't get that. I don't see how
four-year-olds can see this movie
and not think it's too scary
or whatnot.
I don't know if I really believe in parents
bringing their kids to a movie like this
when they're that young.
I think what really inspired me to do this
movie were not only animatics
but the illustrations.
The movie started to become more real,
and there's a charm about the movie.
I like this whole magic of these two kids
kind of discovering these things.
And, you know, my favourite scene,
I think, in this movie is...
It's kind of ironic. Thinking back, it's
like all my movies, like, first hour in,
there was always one
montage. That kind of...
You can kind of see this in
all my movies like The Rock.
Sean Connery and Nic Cage
breaking in into the Rock,
and then Armageddon,
the astronauts lifting off
or Pearl Harbor, the Japanese
kind of getting ready to attack
or the asteroids coming in and landing
and the kids meeting the Autobots.
I kind of have a theme,
I guess, in my movies.
I do these montages
that really inspire me,
and they always seem
to happen an hour in.
But that's kind of
my favourite scene,
when we see Optimus kind of
transform in front of the kids.
Oh, God! We're gonna die!
We're gonna die!
No, we're not.
No, we're not gonna die.
-Oh, my God!
-Trust me. He's a kick-ass driver!
So when we're
doing scenes like this,
I'm sometimes, often times,
in the car with Shia and Megan,
and we're driving with
the stunt driver,
and we're driving very
fast and controlled,
but it really gets your
adrenalin going, ! must say.
We're locked in.
The car won't start.
At least we ditched the monster, right?
Okay.
Shia always says I'm the director
that will put my knee pads on,
I'll be right next to the actors.
When I do action...Oh, God,
you hear these rumours.
It's the kind they love
to just get onto the...
"Michael yells."
"Michael's a screamer." Blah, blah, blah.
No, Michael's like
a tough-ass basketball coach
that is in your face, especially
when you're doing action.
For one, because of safety,
two, because I'm trying to
get your adrenalin level
where I think it needs to
be for that scene.
How many action
scenes do you see
where it seems like actors are
just kind of walking through it?
I really want that adrenalin to be real,
and I want you to look energised.
So that's kind of how I work, you know?
So the screaming only comes,
I guess, when I'm doing tough action,
and I want you to get to that
energy level, you know.
And it's also, a lot of these times,
I'm very safety-conscious,
and I take it personally,
and I'm like my own A. D.
on my sets.
l work with an A. D. ,
l worked with Simon this time,
but I move my sets forward
for myself,
and I want everyone to know
what I'm thinking and I'm vocal about it.
Like, "We're moving over here!
We're coming over here!"
And so I've got a good projecting
voice that, you know, like,
"Let's get our day done,
and let's, like, do it."
Granted, I like to laugh just
like the next guy, and I tease.
lam a professional teaser
with my crew.
And it's funny when you see
new crew members come on.
They're day players,
whatever, and I'm teasing,
‘cause I'll act it like
I really mean it.
I'm totally screwing
around with people,
but my crew that's
been with me for 16 years,
they all know that I'm
screwing around with you.
But I like picking on people,
and I like being picked on, too,
just as long as you're good at
picking on people. It's fun.
But I do like to have
a good environment on the set
and especially work with people
that I really like being around
that look at it as a career,
not as a job.
Because, let me tell you,
I know everyone's job on this set.
I've been doing this
since I'm 24,
and I will be the first to point out to you
when you're not doing a good job.
But you know what?
A director's only
as good as his or her crew,
and the studio wanted to ship me
off to Australia, then to Canada.
We went to check out Canada.
I felt Australia was too far away.
And we went up to Canada and
I just, like, "Oh, my God..."
I was trying to make it work,
trying to make it work.
Looking around, scouting, and I
realised this will be a waste of money.
It'll just be...
There's no way the crew can do
the serious kind of stunt work
that we really do on our sets,
‘cause they just don't have a lot of
great stunt work up there,
and you gotta ship in too many people,
and it just would be a lost cause.
And so the studio gave me
some grief for not going up there.
So I ended up giving 30% of my fees so
l can shoot with my crew in America,
and that's because I'm loyal to my crew,
and they're just, I think, the best.
Visitors from heaven? What...
What are you, like,
an alien or something?
The sound work was done
by Ethan Van der Ryn and Mike Hopkins
who did the sound work for
Lord of the Rings and King Kong.
Mike is from New Zealand,
Ethan was trained up at Lucasfilm.
And I must say, awesome sound.
When you listen on this DVD,
it is just awesome sound.
My mixers, Kevin O'Connell
and Greg Russell...
Kevin, by the way, is the biggest Academy
loser in Academy history.
He's lost, I think, 20 times.
He's done some amazing movies.
He's an amazing mixer.
As a team, they're amazing mixers.
And Kevin and Greg said to me,
in all their time on mixing,
they felt this was the most inventive
sound work they've ever worked with.
And, meanwhile, they feel it's
one of their finest sound designs
and mixing efforts that
they've done as of yet.
We had to invent so many
different sounds here,
and it just gives these robots
such personality,
and it's really just a launching pad for
where we can go on number two.
-Yeah, all right.
-Right?
-Yeah.
-Okay.
There, see? That's better.
You know, that seat belt thing
was a pretty smooth move.
Thank you.
You know what I don't understand?
Why, if he's supposed to be,
like, this super-advanced robot,
does he transform back
into this piece-of-crap Camaro?
I have no idea why this scene
right here,
and I've seen this movie from Korea to
Australia, all over Europe,
America, just why
tight here in the movie,
they applaud when this
yellow car comes up.
Oh, that shot. Let me tell you
about that shot right there.
That was the most patient
I've ever been
for doing a stunt in
the history of my career.
That took exactly three and half hours
for that guy to go up on two wheels.
Why was he on two wheels?
Well, he was on two wheels
because, I don't know,
l wanted the guy up
on two wheels
and, you know, wanted to go old
school with the stunt there.
That Camaro was
a prototype that I saw
when I was looking through
all these car companies,
new kind of prototypes
that were coming out.
Then I saw this
at the skunk works at GM,
this little, kind of secret
building in California
where they do kind of
these concept cars,
and I kind of knew right away
that was the car.
That was gonna be Bumblebee,
and the fans were gonna give me grief
because it wasn't a Volkswagen,
but there's just no way I could do
this movie if this was a VW bug.
And so I just felt that
was the car.
So there's a scene with
this little girl in her bed.
And, you know,
this girl was five,
and I actually hired two of them
for the exact same scene,
and I shot one shot with one and another
one literally with the other girl,
and we were like flipping back
and forth, ‘cause I knew...
The studio teacher
that comes with the kid
is a kind of a social worker
that watches the kids.
She said, "I've never seen
a director in my 20 years
"ever hire two girls
for the same role."
I said, "Well, at 11:30 at night,
"when we have 20 minutes
left on our time,
"where you have to take the kids,
we're doing the most important shot
"with this robot getting
out of the pool,
"and I guarantee you,
one of them will crap out."
And sure enough, by the time we got to
the pool, one of them had crapped out.
And so we used
the little blond girl.
This was a fun night for
the crew, I must say,
because we're up there at this
house, it's 8:00 at night,
and I said to the guy,
"So what crane do we have?"
And everyone kind of looked at
me. It was like the silent look.
"Crane?"
"Well, guys, you saw the animatic,
what we need to do, right?
"We have to move this, like,
long move, and whatever."
Well, let me tell you, they called
every place around Hollywood.
I don't know how they
manufactured this weird-ass crane,
but anyway,
we got to do this shot.
And this was our very
first take with the girl.
Now it's very hard, 'cause she has to
follow this pole above her six times
and right there when she does that
little stutter step, I just loved it,
‘cause she tripped and
it just looked more real.
And ILM said, "Whoa!
Let's use the other shot
"cause she looks
like she screwed up."
I said, "That's what it's about. It's about
a kid screwing up. That's what it is."
Now the concept car, 'cause
we only had one in the world,
we had to actually build it.
And once we got the
CAD files and the okay...
It's very hard to get CAD
files from a car company
because of thievery or
whatever they call it.
This shot right here with
Optimus transforming,
this is one of the shots we made
very early on in the animatic process
that got me excited about
the movie.
This is almost verbatim to our animatic
that we created in my office.
I think this moment right here when
I finally heard all the sounds
with Peter Cullen's
. .
amazing voice.
Thank God the fans
actually...
I kept listening to fans,
and they were right.
You guys were right
all the way through.
But I just wanted to have an open mind
of who can play these robots, so...
You know you can't
fault me for that.
But that was Optimus Prime.
When he speaks, let me tell you...
But when Ethan and Mike added
those sounds to Optimus,
it just made it
come to life.
You know when you look at these effects
tight here, it's just so real
in terms of the reflections of
the metal and how they fit in.
-What's cracking, little bitches?
-My first lieutenant. Designation, Jazz.
This looks like a cool place to kick it.
What is that?
How did he learn to talk like that?
We've learned Earth's languages
through the World Wide Web.
My weapons specialist, Ironhide.
-You feeling lucky, punk?
-Easy, Ironhide.
Just kidding. I just wanted
to show him my cannons.
You know, there's the whole thing about
Transformers about mass-shifting,
and to me, that was just
always a complex thing.
It was very hard to get across
in movie-making,
and I wanted to keep
the idea of the robots.
If you're coming from a vehicle,
you've gotta kind of stay that same size
of whatever that vehicle you
could possibly stretch it out to.
So, yeah, I got some
flak about
changing Optimus from
a flat-nose to a long-nose,
and the long-nose just made
him so he can be 28 feet
instead of the 20 feet that he
would've been with a flat-nose truck.
And, you know,
I got a lot of flak for that.
And then I got more flak for
putting flames on Optimus.
Boy, I mean, it was literally...
Death threats all started over again,
and the "Damn you, Michael Bay!"
And whatever the hell it was.
I mean it's just, you know,
l wanted flames.
I mean, if you want
a pink house,
l want a green house.
What's the difference?
I'm the director, and, it's just,
that's what I wanted.
And I knew the flames
were barely visible
when you saw him
when he was transformed,
and it kind of gave
the impression that he had ribs.
And it was a picture of a truck
that saw, and I wanted to copy it.
And I must say,
l went to my teamster captain,
and I said... They're in charge of
painting vehicles, and I said,
"I'm telling you, a white guy is not
allowed to paint those flames, okay?
"l want, what we call in LA,
l want a cholo.
"l want a guy
who is an artist
"who knows how to do
these amazing kind of cholo cars.
"It's art. Find him, all right?"
And so the funniest picture
I got in this entire movie was our guy.
He's from Mexico. He had a cup of
coffee with his hat backwards.
He's sitting in the art kitchen.
They took a picture of him and said,
"Here he is.
This is your guy.
"He doesn't speak any English.
We're gonna use an interpreter.
"But he does amazing flames."
And I gotta tell you, they were
the most beautiful flames I've ever seen.
He accidentally activated his
navigation system.
The coordinates to the Cube's location
on Earth were imprinted on his glasses.
How'd you know about his glasses?
I must say, I did audition
Peter Cullen twice.
They wanted me to go with
Frank Welker for Megatron.
To me, Frank Welker, great voice artist,
but it just sounded too cartoon to me,
and I don't think I could really tell
Frank to change it for this movie.
It just wouldn't feel right.
So early on in the process
when I picked certain actors
to be what I would interpret
that character to be...
Like, let me give you an idea.
Liam Neeson was Optimus Prime,
Michael J. Fox was Bumblebee,
Hugo Weaving was Megatron.
And, you know,
just in terms of movies
that I wanted the artist to
look at, to kind of emulate,
not the way they move,
but just how regal,
like, Liam Neeson is, to,
you know, Hugo Weaving.
And it's just his voice, Hugo's voice
just kept sticking in my head for Megatron.
One of my producers,
Lorenzo di Bonaventura,
who used to run Warner Brothers,
he did the Matrix movies.
And he called Hugo and
got him into doing this,
and Hugo was down in Australia and I
was directing him from here via iChat
and they had the movie
down there,
and it was amazing how I was
able to direct him so far away
in modern technology.
But he just has an awesome
voice for Megatron.
She did it! She did it!
She's the one you want! All right?
l was just sitting at home
watching cartoons,
playing video games with my cousin,
and she came in there.
-And then...
-Glen, you freak.
Hey! 1 am not going to jail
for you or anybody else!
l have done nothing bad my entire life!
Hey, man, I'm still a virgin.
Okay, so what?
I've downloaded a couple of
thousand songs off the Internet.
Who hasn't? Who hasn't?
-I promise!
-Glen, shut up!
No, you shut up! Don't talk to me!
Don't talk to me, criminal!
So I never get sick
when I shoot.
You just kind of have
this adrenalin that carries you
for a full year-and-a-half,
two years through a movie.
But one day I had a little
vacation down in Cabo,
‘cause I guess there
was a union break we had,
and I leaned down in the elevator
of Air Force One, I'm like, "Uh-oh!
"Maybe we got a little Cabo-VWabo
something going on there."
And within an hour,
I just got violently sick with the flu,
and I'm sitting in my chair,
and I'm shaking and I'm sweating,
and I'm like, "I'm okay,
can direct. I'm okay, I'm okay.”
And you know how you
get when you get fluey.
So I went outside of the trailer,
and I had to lie down on the asphalt
‘cause I was so cold.
I'm shivering.
And my producer, lan Bryce, is standing there
and says, "Buddy, you gotta go.”
I said, "No, no, I've never gone
home ever, ever in my career,
"ever gone home sick.
No, I'm not going home.”
And then we had some gigantic
days like, literally, two days away,
we had to shoot downtown
at the cost of, like, $375 each,
and it's a big deal to shut
all that stuff downtown.
And then the set doctor
came by and she says,
"You got 102-and-a-half.
You gotta go home," so...
Anyway, I kicked it kind of, sort of,
like the next day, or whatever,
but I was sick and kind
of whatever,
and I had to direct in my trailer, s
o they had a microphone.
And I was kind of like Coppola in the
Silverfish where he would direct,
but he had a Jacuzzi in his.
But I was trying to direct my crew
and they were so slow
without me on the set.
We went from 50-something set-ups
a day to 15, and I'm on a microphone,
and it was just like, "Guys, you are
so slow. What's going on?"
It was pretty funny.
One more thing, huh?
All right, I love you!
Sleep good, handsome man!
What are you doing?
No, watch the path! Watch the path!
Watch the...Please, please, please.
No, no, wait. No, no, no! Oh, no!
-Sorry. My bad.
-Oh, I... You couldn't...
You couldn't wait for five...
You couldn't wait for five minutes?
I told you to just stay!
Just stay! God!
-I told you to watch them. I told you.
-Okay, you know what?
-They seem to be in a little bit of a rush.
-Oh, this is bad. No!
Mojo, Mojo! Off the robot! God!
-Oh, wet.
-No, no, no, no, no! Easy! Easy!
Hold on! Hold! This is Mojo.
This is Mojo. He's a pet of mine.
He's a pet. Okay? That's all.
If you could just put the guns away...
-Put the...Put them away. Please.
-You have a rodent infestation.
-A what?
-Shall 1 terminate?
No, no, no, no. He's not a rodent,
he's a Chihuahua.
This is my...This is my Chihuahua.
We love Chihuahuas! Don't we?
So, you know, working
on these scenes,
they are looking at literally window
washer poles with different heights.
And those arms we had two window washer
poles with tennis balls on them
so that they can actually kind of
have an eye line to watch.
It makes it kind of hard
when you're trying to do camera
moves without things there
and trying to imagine
what fits in.
That's why the animatics were huge
helps for the actor to see.
There are times like this, this is
a shot I made up on the fly,
just having Optimus look in.
-You didn't even ground him.
-Almost, almost.
Where are they? No, no, no, no, no.
Come on, come on.
What? What is this?
l always do these crazy things,
like, this should've been a set,
but I like shooting in a real house
where I have the access to the outside.
The houses are always way too small,
locations are small.
Sometimes locations
just feel better to me.
And even though this is a minuscule
toom we're shooting in
with a crew.
It's sometimes ridiculous.
Right there,
she grabbed that box.
That was kind of an improve
thing. And he ran over.
I mean, that's got to be his porn box,
l would think, you know.
Every boy's got that
somewhere in the room,
and guess we all understand that,
don't we?
I'm already stressed out enough.
Okay. What now?
No. No, no. No, no, no.
This isn't hiding. This isn't hiding.
This is my backyard, not a truck stop.
Oh, God. Oh!
Okay, I saw it. The UFO landed
tight here and now it's gone.
My moped's under there, man!
Who's gonna pay for that?
Sam? Sam, Sam, Sam, Sam.
-He's back here.
-I can't deal with this. I can't...
What? Oh, no, no, no.
-This is my mother's flower...
-Oops.
Okay, listen. You got to listen to me.
If my parents come out here and see you,
they're gonna freak out.
My mother's got a temper, okay?
We must have the glasses.
I know you need the glasses.
I've been looking everywhere.
They're not here.
They're definitely not here.
Keep searching.
The way we'd get facial emotions
like this from Optimus, I'd actually...
The animators up north
or down here at DD
would kind of imitate something,
video themselves or whatnot,
and then they'd kind of animate
how that would work.
Or we'd actually use actors
to do certain things.
We wouldn't use motion
capture like you would here...
He wants us to be quiet.
Earthquake! Move, move, move,
move, move! Earthquake!
Judy! Judy, get under the table!
Move it! Duck and cover right now!
How did you
get over there so fast?
Wow! That was tingly!
-You got to try that!
-Yeah, that looks fun.
-Sam?
-Sammy?
-What the hell is that?
-I don't know.
-Sam?
-That's weird.
-Sam!
-Ratchet, point the light.
-Come on, hurry.
-Listen, we got a major issue in here.
What's with the light?
You gotta stop the light.
What's going on? Turn it off.
You gotta tell him to shut it off.
-Shut it off.
-Sam, are you in there?
How come the door's locked?
You know the rules.
No doors locked in my house!
You know he'll start counting
-if you don't open the door!
-One more chance. Five...
Oh, dear.
-Four. It's coming off the hinges, pal.
-He's counting!
-Sam, just open the door.
-Three.
-Oh, my.
-Two.
-He's counting.
-Stand back.
-What's up? What's with the bat?
-Who were you talking to?
-I'm talking to you.
-Why are you so sweaty and filthy?
I'm a child.
You know, I'm a teenager.
We heard voices and noises
and we thought maybe you were...
It doesn't matter what we thought.
What was that light?
No, what light? What?
There's no light, Dad! There's no light!
You got two lights in your hand!
That's what it is.
-Maybe it bounced...
-There was light under the door.
First time I showed
this scene to Steven,
I said, "Steven,
l want you to...
"I'm almost done with my rough cut.
I want you to see some scenes."
He goes, "No, no, no. I want to see
the movie when it's all done.”
Il go, "Come on, Steven,
l want you to see this scene."
So he was watching
this scene particularly,
around the house,
with the robots around the house.
And it was hysterical
because he kept hitting me
on the leg and laughing like a kid.
And I'm like,
"What are you doing?"
And he goes,
"l have never seen robots do this."
It was a funny moment
because, considering I filed his
Raiders of the Lost Ark storyboards...
And now this guy is slapping me
on the leg saying he's never seen robots.
And I'm like, "You're the dude
that's invented dinosaurs,
"and you've seen everything."
And he goes, "But I've never seen this."
So that was kind of a fun moment.
Also a funny moment,
when we saw the first cut
at my house in my screening room,
he kept giving me high fives
when he was watching the movie.
Spielberg giving me high fives
when he's watching the movie.
When a good scene
would come on,
you'd see his arm go up,
"Bam!" Another high five.
But, you know, when I do scenes,
I actually...
When I'm doing the illustration
and the animatic process...
Like, a shot like this.
This was like a seminal shot
you base these scenes around.
And so this shot was created
very early on
in the animatic process.
Those are the scenes
I kind of hang my hat on.
Or those are what the charm
of the movie is.
Ironhide, you know
we don't harm humans.
What is with you?
Well, I'm just saying
we could. It's an option.
We heard you talking to somebody, Sam.
-We wanna know who.
-Mom, I told...
Hi. I'm Mikaela.
I'm a...I'm a friend of Sam's.
Gosh, you're gorgeous.
Isn't that the prettiest girl?
-She can hear you talking, Mom.
-Thank you.
Oh, my goodness. I'm sorry you had to
hear our little family discussion about...
-Sorry that we're bugging you.
-Do you have my backpack?
-Come on, hon. Let's go.
-Oh, it's in the kitchen.
John Turturro in his character study,
he kept saying
he was trying to imitate me.
Now, I don't understand
how his character
is even the slightest bit imitating me
because that's not who I am.
But according to him, that's what I am.
See, I would never do that.
John's character, we kind of felt
that he was a Sector Seven Agent,
that his great-great-grandfather was
a Sector Seven Agent.
He's been doing it for generations.
It was actually in the movie,
in some of the dialogue,
and we actually cut it out,
made it pretty funny
for his character.
He thinks he still lives with
his mom and whatnot.
He was questioning his sexuality
in this movie.
I just didn't think that was
really necessary.
John, I don't think we have to
really go there.
I think you're a guy, okay?
So just let's keep it at that,
all right?
He was a great delight to
work with.
He has the best Scorsese imitation
you have ever seen.
I think we must have that.
We must have that somewhere
in the making of.
-Yeah.
-Well, I need you to come with us.
Whoa, way out of line.
Sir, l am asking politely. Back off.
-You're not taking my son.
-Really?
You gonna try to get rough with us?
No, but I'm gonna call the cops
because there's something
fishy going on around here.
Yeah. There's something
a little fishy about you, your son,
your little Taco Bell dog and
this whole operation you got going on here.
-What operation?
-That is what we are gonna find out.
I think direct contact.
-Son?
-Yeah.
-Step forward, please.
-Just stand?
Fourteen rads.
Bingo! Tag them and bag them!
If you hurt my dog,
I'll kick your ass!
I don't know where we found this
little dog stick,
but I just thought that was
a funny moment.
"Put that thing around the dog,
please."
Mom walks out and she says,
"T'll kick your ass."
Judy's a funny woman.
So,
LadiesMan217.
That is your eBay username, right?
Yeah, but, you know,
it was a typo and I ran with it.
What do you make of this?
My name is Sam Witwicky, okay? And my...
Is that you?
Yeah, that sounds like LadiesMan.
Last night at the station,
you told the officer your car transformed.
-Enlighten me.
-Well, here's what I said, okay?
‘Cause this is a total misunderstanding
that my car had been stolen...
-Really?
-...from me, from my home,
but it's fine now
because it's back! It came back!
-Well, not by itself.
-Well, no.
Because cars don't do that
because that would be crazy.
That's funny. That is so funny.
So what do you kids
know about aliens, huh?
Oh, you mean, like a Martian?
Like what, E. T. ? No.
-It's an urban legend.
-Yeah.
You see this?
This is an l-can-do-whatever-l-want
and-get-away-with-it badge.
-Right.
-I'm gonna lock you up forever.
Oh, God. You know what?
Don't listen to him.
He's just pissy 'cause
he's got to get back to guarding the mall.
You, in the training bra, do not test me.
Especially with
your daddy's parole coming up.
What? Parole?
-It's nothing.
-Oh, grand theft auto, that ain't nothing?
You know those cars
my dad used to teach me to fix?
Well, they... They weren't always his.
You stole cars?
Well, we couldn't
always afford a babysitter,
so sometimes he had to take me along.
She's got her
own juvie record to prove it!
She's a criminal. Criminals are hot.
That'd be a real shame if he had to rot
in jail the rest of his natural life.
It is time to talk!
Big! It's big!
We actually hung these actors
on this little contraption
that would spin them around.
I got on the car with the operators,
and it's quite fun.
I got to tell you, this stunt, where we
strapped cameras, right there, bam,
that looked like it hurt.
You A-holes are in trouble now.
Gentlemen, I want to introduce you
to my friend, Optimus Prime.
Taking the children was a bad move.
The scene where we pull
the guns out,
look at the driver in the car
with John Turturro.
We had little Jazz here. He uses
his magnetic gun right there.
If you freeze it, watch as the gun...
Watch the guns fly up past the guys.
l want you to go back in that DVD and
freeze it.
Because I told the driver, I said,
"No, you will not get hurt.
"They're rubber guns and they're on
bungee cords and they're gonna pull."
If you freeze it, you'll see it hit
him kind of on the temple.
He goes, "I thought you said it
wasn't gonna hurt.” Well, I'm sorry.
Look, there are
S-Seven protocols, okay?
I'm not authorised
to communicate with you
except to tell you
Il can't communicate with you.
-Get out of the car.
-All right.
I don't know, I was kind of crazy
when I told the writers,
I said, "I really want to have Bumblebee
piss on John Turturro."
Call me crazy, but you know what?
At least the audiences laughed.
You know, doing Transformers,
I got to tell you,
a bunch of adults running around
the set the first couple of days
and saying the word "Bumblebee"
and "Megatron"...
l remember the first couple of days,
literally about 50 airmen,
military extras
at Holloman Air Force Base
and I said, "I know, guys,
this sounds really stupid,
"but you're gonna have this big robot
fly in, transform, land right here."
And the guys were in their 20s, 30s,
they go, "Would that be Starscream?"
I'm like... You know, it was...
I honestly did not think
there were that many fans
around the world for this thing.
And how much it meant to
people that are now in their 30s...
Being told but seeing in
your life is a different thing.
But for Hasbro to say, "This is
the largest-selling toy around the world.
"It's the top-five largest selling toy
around the world for 20 years."
I think that's a big accomplishment.
But I just didn't realise
the depth
of how many fans
there were around the world.
And, you know, right now,
you just kind of...
As we were getting ready
to release the movie,
the trailers were always, like,
in Yahoo,
like, the number-one downloaded,
most watched, consistently
from when they came out Christmas
till almost the day of the release.
Like, Pirates would come up there,
and they would fall back down,
but we were always one and two
for the entire time.
And that kind of told me something.
It actually became one of
the most downloaded trailers in history,
according to Yahoo that
tracks this stuff.
So all those kind of signs were
telling me something.
And when it opened and it became
the largest non-sequel opening of all time,
I guess I was...
I just honestly did not think it could
do as well as it's done so far.
I mean, it's gonna pass 300-plus
million here.
And it's right up there with
the Spider-Man and Pirates 3,
these gigantic franchises.
And internationally,
it's gonna...
Right now we're already
at 260-something,
and it'll probably go to 350, 400,
I don't know.
Anyway, I guess it was a good
gamble for the studio on this.
Okay, I'm tracking him. I've got him.
Got him going down the street.
A lot of people would've done that
helicopter shot right there digitally,
but not me, for some reason.
That was a real helicopter
very close to that bus.
I just like things real.
As much real as I can get, I'm gonna do.
It seems to be like a dying art
with a lot of directors now
where you do your own stunts,
you do a lot of stunts and stuff like that.
Doing these gigantic moves
on this special Akela crane,
which is like 75 feet tall,
we're able to do these big drops.
This was kind of a chaotic scene
because we had four helicopters,
one airship,
and it was quite noisy
in this river of...
I don't know if that's...
I don't know what's in that river.
That polluted river right there.
We actually saved a guy's life
in the river that night.
We just so happened to be there
when a guy in a hospital uniform
was floating by.
And literally, there's no
getting out of that thing
because that channel travels
very quickly.
And it's all algae, there's no stopping,
it goes all the way to the ocean.
One of our electricians just threw out
a piece of cable and saved this guy,
who was like an escapee from
some hospital.
-Take the shot, get him.
-Take the shot.
No!
I've never worked on a movie
where obviously I've had to do
so much digital animation,
character animation.
It was really one of the most
fascinating things about this movie,
is actually directing these
kind of creatures
and ultimately making them feel
like you've got a soul inside of them
when you see these things.
And I think it's done through
sound and facial stuff.
You just start to feel for this thing
that doesn't even exist.
I think that's kind of
the accomplishment of the movie.
Stop hurting him!
Don't let him move!
Right there, right there,
that's the mock-up of Bumblebee
we actually built for 200 grand.
Really complicated to build.
You couldn't really shoot it that closely.
Like you're gonna see
tight there,
it's the mock-up which saves
money on digital shots.
And then there again
you see the mock-up,
and then we go back to
a digital shot.
So if you use it sparingly,
tight there,
the five, six, seven shots with that
mock-up just saved a lot of money.
We only had mock-up pieces of like,
Optimus Prime,
and certain head sections but
nothing that detailed.
We built Megatron's legs in the
chamber where he's being held.
We built about 30 feet of his legs,
which cost us half a million dollars,
but when we use it through those shots
it actually saves you on effect shots.
Because every one of those pieces...
Reason why it's so expensive,
you've got to carve it out of foam,
and then it's got to be on a steel
kind of frame to hold it up.
This shot right here, I call it
"the jungle gym Optimus.”
I just hated the blocking of it,
but we were just kind of stuck
with the shot that we had shot.
Often times the animators
had to squeeze in where
we could fit our robots.
We got to be very good at
shooting robots after a while.
We used a special tool.
It's a Porsche Cayenne with
a special crane on it where we were able
to move at a high rate of
speed on a car
and we can do these amazing
crane moves.
It was actually a robot-cam
where we could spin around.
Right there walking through
National Military Command,
that was a room that I'd been to,
it's in the basement of the Pentagon,
that's where they run wars and whatnot.
And the thing that I always remember
was going down there,
they have these two Lucite doors
that are like bullet-proof and blast-proof
and you have to go through these doors.
The chamber that we take this
conversation that comes up
is called the Vault in the Pentagon,
actually.
It's this soundproof room that
has this vault door
and it has five seats
for the Secretary of Defence and
the four different branches of military,
with a direct link to the President.
They feel that this room is like,
the fewer people that know
about what's going on,
the better a secret could be kept.
We kind of designed it exactly
the way I saw the room
from my memory, I guess,
when I was down at the Pentagon.
They actually took me into the room
where the two guys are there
to launch nuclear weapons.
They sit in their own vault.
It was kind of an odd experience.
l was down at the Pentagon
when I was doing Pearl Harbor,
the tap dance.
I met with every branch of the military
because of the cooperation we needed.
Actually, Transformers, since
Black Hawk Down and Pearl Harbor...
This has been the largest military
cooperation
that they've done thus far
since those two movies.
Beagle 2 transmitted 13 seconds.
This was classified above top secret.
This is actually
the very first stuff
we ever shot for Transformers
tight here, the Mars rover here.
It was part of our teaser.
I've always been fascinated,
what if the Mars rover found
something that was of human origin?
So it's something I always
saved for a movie.
More than just
a pile of Martian rocks.
This is the image from Mars.
Here's the image your
Special Ops team was able to retrieve
from the base attack.
We believe they are
of the same exoskeletal type,
and obviously not human beings.
Are we talking about an invasion?
We intercepted the message
from your Special Ops team.
These things can be hurt
by our weapons and now they know it.
That's why the virus shut us down,
so we can't coordinate
against their next attack,
which I would bet my ridiculous
government salary is coming soon.
Get word to our fleet commanders
over the National Guard frequency.
It's a shortwave radio channel.
It might be still working.
Tell them to turn their ships around
and come home. ASAP!
And inform all commands
to prepare for imminent attack.
Josh Duhamel is someone
I met
in one of my Platinum Dunes meetings,
for a movie,
and I just liked his energy.
He just was a great guy.
And he's got those movie star
looks.
Just thought he would be
a good fit in this movie.
Jon Voight's one of the elder statesmen.
He's just...
Actors love hanging around him.
He's a really fun guy.
He's just such a good actor.
And it was nice to see
all these young actors around him.
He's really such a leader
among these actors.
Steven wanted me to cast this movie
where I wasn't using movie stars,
like he would do a lot of
his movies.
Because, you know,
the movie was the star.
The Transformers were the star.
I think right now you've got
this Shia LaBeouf,
who's just gonna explode
off the screen.
He's now in Indiana Jones.
The guy is, you know,
he's like the young Tom Hanks.
He's just one of those kids that
really has exploded off the screen.
I'm proud to have worked with him.
He's been a lot of fun to work with,
actually. Great energy.
Please, let this work.
Fire it up, Optimus.
The code.
The code on these glasses indicates
the All Spark is 230 miles from here.
Il sense the Decepticons
are getting ready to mobilize.
They must know it's here, as well.
What about Bumblebee?
We can't just leave him to die
and become some human experiment!
He'll die in vain if
we don't accomplish our mission.
Bumblebee is a brave soldier.
This is what he would want.
This is the Los Angeles Observatory,
and it's been under renovation
for five years.
And California becomes
a very tough place to shoot,
where they just make
it tough to shoot.
And that's been closed...
And when you have a big movie,
you have a lot more clout.
So going to City Hall
and convincing them
that we're bringing
this gigantic movie here,
and we're keeping it here
in America and in California
where things are running away,
moving out of state.
And we demanded certain things,
like to shoot at this observatory.
I think the only way I got into this
observatory, from what I heard,
because it's run by this doctor,
he knows someone who is
married into my family
called Leonard Nimoy.
You know, Spock,
who's a big giver of the...
Susan Bay and Leonard Nimoy
are big givers to the Observatory.
Right here this is the Hoover Dam.
And that's its actual wall.
They don't touch it because
it's kind of a landmark, obviously,
and they don't put rails
around it and whatnot.
They told me I wasn't allowed to
do anything that exploded by it,
because they're worried about
a terrorist blowing up the dam.
Now, let me tell you something.
I think you need a nuclear
bomb to blow that thing up
because it's seven football
fields thick of concrete.
It was made in three years.
It was a constant pour. Actually it was
made in four...1 think, four years.
A constant pour,
where they poured one piece
of concrete for four years.
When I did this movie,
I mean, certain people
in California look at this movie,
like, "Is this director stupid?
"Because they go from Nevada
all the way to Los Angeles.
"How did they go so fast?"
Ultimately, most people don't
know where this dam is,
which is in Nevada.
Half of it's in Nevada, half is
in Arizona, by the way.
And I tried to shoot Los Angeles
not as Los Angeles
but Anytown, USA.
That shot you just saw there,
that crane shot by the dam,
we had to keep our crane very
low because of possible arcing,
where it would arc from the gigantic
power lines onto the crane,
just because of metals too
close to these power lines
that could jump and
kill my crew members.
It's very scary,
I must say.
This was shot down
at the Spruce Goose,
where we built this entire set.
We did some digital extensions here.
We used some of
the actual Spruce Goose walls.
It just gave me a lot more
production value.
Right there,
you're seeing that's all real,
everything there is built,
those feet are real.
It even says "Bay Foundry"
tight there on that little plaque
tight there if you zoom in.
My grandfather actually helped
build that platform...No, I'm kidding.
My grandfather was in
the stonewashing business.
Like you need to know that.
He actually never thought
I would make it in the film industry.
He always thought I would
be stonewashing jeans.
Thank God I wasn't doing that.
NBE One. That's what we call it.
And you didn't think
the United States military might need to know
that you're keeping a
hostile alien robot frozen in the basement?
Until these events,
we had no credible threat to national security.
Well, you got one now.
So why Earth?
Right here, that was a real
structure as well.
We built part of the hands.
We walk into this next scene.
l had a very funny speech
for John Turturro.
He actually...John kind of
sparked off something I said,
and he made up this very
funny speech
which is in kind of the added extras,
extra scenes.
Right here,
that was an all-digital shot.
For some reason,
I just wanted pictures of the First Seven.
I don't know what it means.
I think these are the guys that helped
discover this Cube long before,
and then they built the dam
over this Cube.
President Hoover had the dam built around it.
Four football fields thick of concrete.
A perfect way to hide its energy
from being detected by anyone
or any alien species on the outside.
So when we had to shoot
by the F-22 on the ground,
it was a totally secured area.
And they wouldn't allow
Simon Warnock,
who was my assistant director, near the
plane because he was a foreigner.
And I didn't want him near the plane
because he's clumsy.
It's $130 million plane made out of
composite material and whatnot.
They wouldn't allow your cell phones
near the plane.
I think they were worried about radio
interference or something,
I'm not sure.
That Blackout pilot was
actually the helicopter pilot of
that very helicopter,
and when we hired Moustache Man,
the guy actually flying,
I said, "My God, you look just like
the Moustache Man I'd imagined."
And Steven Spielberg
called me up
and goes, "That's exactly how
I pictured Moustache Man.”
So, we actually had him delay
his wedding and his honeymoon
so that we can come and shoot
Transformers
and thus make more money
for his future babies.
So we helped in the cause.
-Right? That's Wolverine!
-That's very funny.
Anybody have any mechanical devices?
BlackBerry? Key alarm? Cell phone?
I got a phone.
Originally when we did this scene,
I really wanted to have a little iPod,
but Steve Jobs wouldn't allow it.
So we ended up using some,
I guess, Nokia phone or whatnot.
On that sign behind John Turturro
it says, "The last accident
happened here 322 days ago,”
because that meant that 323 days ago
someone was killed in that very facility,
as you saw the scratches
in the wall and whatnot.
l actually ended up cutting
it out just for time.
I think when we do
Transformers 2,
I think this is a start of something
where we can branch off
what can really go on,
happen in our world.
That is, if I'm gonna do Transformers 2,
still haven't made the deal yet.
Listen, 1 gambled my fee
on this movie.
That means I put my cojones
on the line
where I gambled my entire fee
that this movie would make money.
So that's why when I go to Vegas
with my friends I don't gamble.
‘Cause I gamble on
$150 million movies.
I don't need to be gambling
on $20 slot machines
or, you know, $5 hands of blackjack.
I gamble on big-ass movies,
that's what I do.
Go! Go! Go!
Move!
Gentlemen, they know the Cube is here.
Banachek. What's going on?
Well, the NBE One hangar has lost power...
-What?
-...and the backup generator
-is just not gonna cut it.
-Do you have an arms room?
That was Kenny Bates and lan Bryce.
Kenny Bates is my stunt coordinator,
who I've worked with since Bad Boys.
He's like my older brother.
He's like the Rain Man of stunts.
Sometimes you can't understand
what he's saying,
but he's brilliant in his physics
and whatnot.
He's gonna kill me for saying that,
but that's the truth.
There's so much physics
when you do stunts
in what can go wrong and trying
to predict what can go wrong.
That's why we've had such
an amazing safety record together.
Because we do very
dangerous stuff,
but we've just been incredibly
safe about it.
Forty millimetre sabot rounds on that table!
That's good. Get all the ammo you got.
Everything you can carry. Bring it.
You got to take me to my car.
You have to take me to my car.
He's gonna know what to do with the Cube.
-Your car? It's confiscated.
-Then unconfiscate it.
We do not know what will happen
if we let it near this thing!
-You don't know.
-Maybe you know, but I don't know.
You just wanna sit here
and wait and see what happens?
l have people's lives
at stake here, young man.
Take him to his car!
Drop it.
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
Drop your weapon, soldier.
There's an alien war going on
and you're gonna shoot me?
You know, we didn't ask to be here.
I'm ordering you under
S-Seven executive jurisdiction.
S-Seven don't exist.
Right. And we don't take orders
from people that don't exist.
-I'm gonna count to five. Okay.
-Well, I'm gonna count to three.
-Simmons?
-Yes, sit?
I'd do what he says.
Losing's really not an option for these guys.
All right. Okay.
Hey, you want to lay the fate of the world
on the kid's Camaro? That's cool.
No, no!
Stop! You got to stop!
Stop! Stop! Stop!
No, no, stop, stop, stop!
Let him go! Let him go!
Are you okay?
They didn't hurt you, right?
Listen to me. The Cube is here and
the Decepticons are coming.
No, no, don't worry about them.
They're okay. Right?
They're not gonna hurt you.
Just back up a little bit.
He's friendly. He's fine.
Okay, come on. Put the guns down.
They're not gonna hurt you.
Here, come with me.
I'm gonna take you to the All Spark.
Steve Jablonsky did our music.
He is Hans Zimmer's protégé.
Hans helped a little
on the movie, as well.
It was very hard to get that theme,
that heroic theme I wanted for
Transformers.
And just one day, I said,
"Steve, that's the theme."
I played it for Steven and Steven goes,
"I love that, it's very memorable."
Because it sounds like a Western.
It's just got that great tragic hero.
Which I liked. It's just so powerful
how to get the right mood
through music.
That's why I really feel that sound
in movies is 50% of a movie.
What you try to do with music is
you try to set up different themes.
You've got the heroic theme
for the Optimus.
You've got Sam's theme
which is kind of by the lake.
You've got the Decepticon theme
which is kind of, we found this...
There's this church choir in London
that's got this very dark-sounding
church they record in,
and we gave them operatic kind
of words that they sang.
And it was just this chilling kind of
Decepticon music.
-Will it work?
-Anything's possible!
-Did you see that...
-All right, Sam, get it in the car!
Mr Secretary! Get our birds in the air.
You saw that Camaro transform
tight there.
That was officially the lamest shot
of the entire movie.
That's why we cut it down.
You always have turkey shots.
And that was, let me tell you,
a turkey.
I'm gonna tell you another shot
when we get there.
Steven actually wanted to
pay for it.
It's where Optimus’ nose unfolds
and you see his face
after he slides around the Camaro.
I never ended up putting it in the movie.
I left it off.
lam Megatron!
Right here, that thing flying,
I didn't like that thing flying.
That flew a little farther than
l wanted for comfort.
We had stuntmen down below,
but no one was hurt.
-The Cube's okay?
-Yeah, it's fine.
Well, put the seat belt on.
Pour it on him!
That one sound when you see
Starscream on the top of that dam,
and he's vibrating, that's my favourite
sound in the entire movie.
When you hear his body shudder,
tight there.
What I'm gonna do in Transformers
2 is I'm gonna focus more on the faces.
I guess, because of the limited number
of effects shots, I limited myself
on how close I went into
these faces
so that I can, I guess,
do more with less.
Give me a minute. Give me a minute.
Come to me, Maxwell, come to me.
Plugged in there.
-We're hot! We're live!
-Where are the mikes?
Mikes?
This doesn't work without mikes, Simmons.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no!
This is called our Alien Archive room,
that I thought was fun.
It's got books going 40 feet
tall up into the stacks.
This holds all the Sector Seven stuff
that's been there through history
of anything alien, having to do
with our world here.
Simmons, I need a screwdriver!
There's Optimus.
That shot where we're tracking
behind Optimus,
I'm actually in the Porsche Cayenne.
We're going 55 miles an hour,
as an entire semi locks up,
and we are right behind.
I mean, I gotta tell you,
that's a little scary.
We shot that scene where
they're driving in the Valley of Fire.
We actually blew a roadblock
because the sun was going down.
Which means we passed a cop
roadblock, and we kept shooting
on this road, and they
were so pissed.
They hauled lan Bryce, my producer,
and he had to kiss a bunch of hands
in Vegas or they were gonna shut
us down at the Hoover Dam.
So thank God to lan, but I had to
get this shot. And you know what?
I'll run any police roadblock
I have to if the sun's going down,
and I got a beautiful shot.
See, I'm never really good
at taking no for an answer.
I don't know, "Whoops,
I didn't see it, sorry."
"This is Defence Secretary Keller.
Get me NORTHCOM commander."
-Whoa!
What was that?
Authenticate emergency action.
Blackbird 1195...
Sir, have an authenticated
air strike order from Sec Def.
Doing this highway scene, we shot
it on a freeway, near Riverside.
I've done a lot of car stuff in
my day. We did this in two days.
We're actually launching cars
off a car carrier that are dropping
onto the ground and the Bay Buster
is actually ramming into these cars.
It's a special thing that I built on
Bad Boys 2. Go see that disc,
and then you'll learn all about it.
So on this freeway, you can see
all those people standing up there?
They heard that Transformers
was shooting
in the neighbourhood. So those are
real fans actually watching us shoot.
Right here, this is done with a special
go-cart and then we transition
to the Porsche Cayenne camera and
we tilt down and we pull away.
Two different moves and we
seamlessly blend it in together.
So I wanted Bonecrusher,
tight here, as he slaps through,
I wanted him to look like a hockey player.
So I had the...
Right here, this looks like
a hockey player
and then we go to
a football tackle, right there.
That was my favourite shot
in the whole movie, right there.
This was over a freeway and
we had the bigger moving crane.
We blocked this doing plates
and whatnot.
What I realised in the animation is
the animators are not fight choreographers.
Fight choreographers have been working
20 years and been doing this.
So they spent forever on this stuff
tight here, you're seeing right now,
and they were never getting
it right.
So what we did is,
once I got these plates, these shots,
l actually used real fighters
that had different abilities,
different fighting skills,
and I would videotape them
by a pole or whatnot,
and kind of imitate these angles.
And we actually had humans
fighting this out at the same beat,
at the same time as these plates.
And it wasn't motion-capture,
but they were able to copy
what these fighters were doing
in the time they were doing it.
So that became a very effective way
for us to work.
The voice of this little Frenzy guy,
he's just got the most
amazing human voice,
and we were able to overlay
some mechanical sounds over it.
It's amazing that humans can
actually talk like this.
But it makes it quite funny.
If you listen really closely,
he's saying the word "Tutankhamen."
He keeps saying "Tutankhamen,"
I don't know, it's just a funny thing,
if you listen to it.
Sucker, burn!
Oh, shit!
Yes! They're sending F-22s to the city!
Raptors, let's scramble, scramble, scramble.
Here we are
at Edwards Air Force Base,
where they're actually
going into real F-22s,
unlike Die Hard,
where they had to use fake F-22s,
because, I don't know,
they just don't have the juice.
But we got real stuff.
That's because I got the phone
number to the Pentagon.
-Come on, let's go! Mount up!
-Move out! Move out! Go! Go!
Here, I got shortwave radios.
Wait. What am I supposed
to do with these?
Well, use them! It's all we got!
This is like RadioShack
dinosaur radios or something, man.
Doing this downtown stuff,
I gotta tell you,
is one of the harder things
that I've done
in terms of keeping all these
different storylines going simultaneously.
And unfortunately, what made it
harder for me is was not able to shoot
on one block consecutively.
I literally had to be shoved around LA
to different blocks, and so I had to
use basically three different blocks.
One in Detroit, two in LA...Actually four.
One on the Universal back lot.
And blend them all together
as if they're one.
So some of the geography shots,
I don't really have,
because I was never able to do it.
Because they were different blocks,
and it would give things away.
So it made it very tough on me
to figure out some of the stuff.
But one of the helps was
we had to shoot on the weekends,
so l was able to assemble
what we were shooting,
so I can keep track of everything.
You know, it's just...
It's really hard when you've
got multiple stories going on.
Especially this is like a 25-minute
ending action scene.
This is one of my
favourite moments, here.
This was shot on the Universal back lot,
this shot.
With a real truck,
we moved it on cue.
Right there, we kind of shake it
because I'm counting it out.
We kind of walk it out for Shia,
how fast Bumblebee will be moving.
It's just beautiful animation right here,
and how he's straining, right there.
See that arm going down and
the head shaking, right here.
You can really get into the fine detail
with these animators.
That was Universal back lot,
tight here and then the shot with Josh
in the close up, that was downtown.
So it's just...
You gotta remember exactly what piece you
shot that you need in another place.
Army Black Hawk
inbound to your location. Over.
Alpha 273 degrees, 10 miles.
November Victor, 1.2 clicks north.
That's the Universal back lot,
tight there.
And again, Universal back lot.
DreamWorks kept having meetings
on the Universal back lot,
they kept hearing explosions.
Now we come down to downtown.
And now we're in the back lot.
See how you can go back and forth.
You really can't tell. That's the back lot,
and now we're downtown.
Let's go! Move!
I'm not gonna leave you.
Coming up here, these are some
of my favourite shots, right here.
This just takes it to a whole new level.
l wanted these robots not to be,
what I call "Clunky, fat, f-ing robots."
That was the lingo
on the animator's desk.
So we looked at a lot of ninja movies,
karate movies, samurai,
things like Gladiator.
We just wanted them to be warriors
that can jump and spin.
If you look at this scene, right here,
coming up, where he's shooting,
there's gonna be something right
here on the roof, right there,
it says "Takara Sushi."
There's actually a whole
bunch of things.
If you actually pause at certain cars,
random cars, you'll see things
on licence plates. You'll see Easter
eggs all over this movie.
You'll see different shop signs
that say certain things.
You'll even see my address
to my house on one of these things.
I'm not telling you where it is.
Got the tail number to my plane,
it's 4500 XRAY.
We needed a tail number,
so why not use mine? Sounds good, too.
Fall back!
Get our guys out of the way!
Get out of here! Go!
Get them out of the buggy! Move out!
We need air cover down here now!
Sam, help me with this.
-That all you got, Megatron?
-Come here, little cretin.
You want a piece of me?
You want a piece?
No! I want two!
What's going on?
Sir! That tank thing's getting back up.
Oh, these things just don't die.
Oh, we're so dead.
-Wrap it around the head.
-Sam!
Where's the Cube?
-Right there.
-Okay.
And take that and wrap it around
the base and then put it around his neck.
-Okay?
-Epps, get those Black Hawks here!
That building.
-Okay.
-What?
All right, 1 can't leave my guys back there,
so here, take this flare.
Okay, there's a tall,
white building with statues on top.
-Go to the roof. Set the flare.
-No.
-Signal the chopper and set the flare.
-No, no. I can't do this!
Listen to me! You're a soldier now!
All right? I need you to take this Cube.
Get it into military hands
while we hold them off,
or a lot of people are gonna die.
-You got to go. You got to go.
-No, I'm not leaving.
-You need to go. Go.
-No, I'm not leaving
till l get Bumblebee
out of here, okay?
You always want to
te-do things in movies
and that prop of
the Cube is kind of lame.
You know?
It's just...
It's just not what it should be.
But you can't catch everything
because you've got so
many millions of parts moving on.
Those Black Hawks that are
flying through downtown,
it was the only time in my life
I've wanted a religious service
to end quickly,
because we were not allowed to
fly them close to downtown
while this religious service was going on,
tight where Shia is running towards.
Il was even thinking of
offering donations
so that we could continue shooting.
They didn't wanna buy that.
Watch out!
-Girl, get that tow truck out of here!
-I'm going! I'm going!
Get out of here now!
When you watch this movie,
tight here, when you see this,
you're actually rooting for a truck.
I mean, isn't it silly? But it works.
And this we did digitally, with
the Porsche Cayenne coming around.
Kind of like that shot that I did on Bad Boys
where I spun around the guys.
And I've done it subsequently
in The Rock and Armageddon
and why not do
it with Optimus Prime here?
Now, Megatron was not a big gun
because I just didn't know
how I would explain him
being a big gun.
Just doesn't make sense.
Shooting that hotel thing,
we shot it with a little, tiny little helicopter.
With, like a lawnmower engine,
it can take a tiny little camera up
and two guys with remote
controls control it.
We got a lot of flak
for the face of Megatron.
He was a little uglier
than he is now.
And the fans, rightly so,
complained about it.
And we kind of fixed the face.
I think he's pretty cool.
He looks menacing.
This was done down in Detroit
and then smashing into a real set
here with stuntmen diving out.
But shooting the deli shot,
it was very complicated because we had to
shoot it against a bluescreen.
We had to rip up the car, violently,
and we had to throw it,
once it ripped up,
into the window.
So we shoot it, first with
people inside the deli,
then we have Shia run past
the deli window, several times.
Then we rip up the car and
we pull it into the window, right here.
Then we marry them all together
to make it look very dangerous.
This shot with Starscream landing,
those are real cars
that are getting flipped violently.
Simultaneously, they're being pulled
by giant cranes on these canister rigs
that are just extremely violent
when they pull things.
So imagine no robots there
and just figuring out timing
of how long that plane's supposed
to transform to it flying out.
I mean, you really,
as you're operating camera,
it's a little bit of guesswork
trying to fit it in.
There's Ron, you just
saw him there,
the African-American
sitting in the chair.
Ron is homeless and
a very intelligent homeless man.
We offer him money, he doesn't want it.
But he is a huge fan of movies.
And what he does, he knows everything
about the film industry.
He knows so many people
in the business,
and he literally becomes
a mascot of the set.
He followed us wherever we went.
He actually rented a car,
or hitched a way, got a bus ticket,
and he made it to Detroit.
And we were all surprised
to see him there.
And I told lan, "We gotta get
him a hotel room."
And he didn't want it,
but we forced him to take it.
But Ron's gonna be in all my movies
from now on. He's a great guy.
That was the train station
down in Detroit.
It's now gonna be, I think, destroyed,
so this is the last movie to be shot there.
So we're doing this scene with
these gigantic metal prongs
that are off the tow truck,
and we're actually backing up
that tow truck and the driver is Cory
who is dressed as a girl.
He's got a little, cute pink top on.
He looked frightening as a girl.
This isn't going well!
Shoot! Shoot!
And that shot, where we're flipping
the cars up, we have these car flippers
and it gets as close to possible and
it triggers the car flippers
as the car comes up.
Nice shot.
-That tank is definitely dead now.
-All right, let's go! We got business!
Now this scene,
where we did downtown on this rooftop,
it's about 20 storeys tall.
Shia is escaping from Megatron,
and he climbs on one of these statues
and lan Bryce, my producer, goes
"Well, you gonna do this bluescreen,
tight?"
I said, "No, 1 wanna do it as real as
possible, let's do it real."
Let's hang Shia out there,
let's hang him by a wire.
This is a Black Hawk, actually,
hovering right over an LA building.
It's kind of an interesting sight having
Black Hawks flying through Los Angeles
at such low altitude.
Right there, that's the real tail
of a helicopter mock-up
that comes past Shia.
It's safe because
Shia's ducking down,
but that thing is actually busting plaster,
concrete and whatnot.
But those are the type of shots that
I like to involve the actor in.
‘Cause it just gives more intensity
and realism to the scene.
I said to Shia, I said, "Shia,
I'm gonna hang you out on this building.
"And there's not a lot of foot room up there,
but you're safe with wires."
And he says, "Okay, all right,
I'm cool, I'll do it, I'll do it.”
Well, literally the moment before
he was supposed to go up and get on
this very secured statue and
totally safe wire,
even though you can't see it,
it's on either side of his hip.
He goes, "Mike, come here.
I can't do this."
I said, "Are you kidding me, Shia?
You're gonna embarrass yourself
"in front of the whole crew."
Now, mind you, in my own mind,
I would never go out there.
But I'm a director so I can tell
people to do things like that.
With all the machismo and whatnot.
"Dude, you're gonna go out there,
and you're gonna like it.
"You get paid way more money than
those kids on Fear Factor.
"So get the hell out there."
So of course he did it.
It was an awesome shot,
because it's totally real.
And three minutes into doing it,
Shia just loved it.
l was actually supposed to
be hanging out of a Mercedes,
grabbed by Megatron, and climb
out of the sun roof, which I did.
And they had me wired by a cable
where they pulled my ankle up,
and he was supposed to yank me.
But in light of not doing that shot,
Il was the guy that got flicked by
Megatron and goes into the cab.
So that is me.
Sam?
You risked your life to protect the Cube.
No sacrifice,
-no victory.
-If cannot defeat Megatron,
you must push the Cube into my chest.
I will sacrifice myself to destroy it.
Get behind me.
It's you and me, Megatron.
No, it's just me, Prime.
At the end of this day,
one shall stand, one shall fall.
You still fight for the weak!
That is why you lose!
Fighter jets in 60 seconds.
We got friendlies mixed with bad guys.
Targets will be marked.
Hey.
Bring the rain. All right?
All right, let's kill these things.
-Move, move, move!
-Remember, aim low.
Armour's weak under the chest.
Target marked. Still waiting.
Time on target, 20 seconds.
F-22s, we're still waiting.
Move out!
Incoming!
Weapons armed. Status green.
Run! Move!
Second wave's on approach.
What is that? Break off!
-Copy.
-It's either a massive amount of...
Doing the aerial shots, basically
I'm having my helicopter pilot
fly with a VistaVision,
which is a much wider negative,
larger, so you can move it around a bit.
And he's flying as fast as he can go
through these buildings and around.
It's kind of, very much
how we did some of our Pearl Harbor stuff.
And I had actually some of the same plane
animators that worked on Pearl
work on this.
When I went to test screen
this movie with the studio,
we did it in Arizona,
and we were doing a family theatre
where it was a bunch of kids at 5:00,
with parents.
And then we were doing
an adult screening with adults
at about 8:00,
and they were both 500-person houses.
So they're very large.
What I do when I put my movies together
is 1 actually will put a small group
. .
In a screening room.
Different-aged kids, where they'll watch
a very rough cut, give me some ideas.
It's very good to just have to show
your movie up on a bigger screen
so you can see it and put it
in front of people.
You can see where they get confused,
what they're liking, what's not working.
So I did that twice.
First started with nine-year-olds to 16.
And then I went
from 16 to 25-year-olds.
And it prepared me
for my studio screening.
Even being a final cut director,
it's still intense.
Because they come there
with 30 people from Paramount
and DreamWorks.
Everyone is nervous.
They determine what
they're gonna spend on advertising.
That very moment, you get numbers.
So we watched it with the families.
It went well, they were laughing
at the different jokes,
they were not laughing
at some of the adult jokes.
There were several applause
through the screening.
And I'm like, "That's kind
of fun, but odd.
"They're applauding three or four times
during the screening.”
Then I quickly ran over
to the adult theatre.
So I saw the adult one start up,
then I ran back to the kids one
where we did a focus group,
26 people.
Guy stands up saying,
"l have nothing to do with this movie.
"How would you rate this movie?"
Excellent, blah blah blah,
very good, poor, good, whatever.
All 26 hands raised at "Excellent."
And I'm like, "Well, okay, it's a fluke,
"it's a family thing, whatever."
Then I ran back to the adult screening.
And I sat next to this guy, I was just
sitting in some random aisle seat
where I had a little sound box
where I got to control the volume
because the volume is not really
precise because it's not fully mixed sound.
It's a little abrasive at times.
And the guy knew I was a director
because I told him,
‘cause he asked what that box was.
Halfway through the movie,
the people are really enjoying it,
you can see the adults are laughing.
And I asked this guy, he was about 30,
I said, "So do you like
this kind of movie?"
And he looked at me and goes,
"Yeah, not really my thing, not really."
So I'm thinking, "This movie sucks.
It's just going to be a kids' movie.
"All right, fine. It'll be a kids' movie."
Every emotion goes through your body
when you're a director
sitting there and watching
500 people at a time
.
see your movie.
And they don't care who you are,
what you are, nothing.
They'll tell you,
they'll be frank as...
It can be a brutalizing experience,
because they will tell you
how bad or good your movie is.
Then we did a focus group
with the adults and we had
a huge round of applause
at the end of the movie.
And I'm like, "That's kind of odd.
"These are adults.
This is a robot movie.
"What are they applauding for?
I thought that this was a kids' movie."
So we go to this focus group.
And this woman who is, I gotta
tell you, she was like 40.
And she says...And this was
after they raised their hands,
which out of 26 people, 24 of them raised
at "Excellent" and 2, "Very good."
And I'm thinking,
"Well, that's kind of odd,
‘cause that just never happens."
That's a lot of people
saying "Excellent."
And this woman raised
her hand.
She says, "I was dragged to this movie.
I didn't want to see this movie."
And she goes, "But you know what?
"This movie,
it reinvents the superheroes."
She goes, "I'm tired of the capes
and the suits and all that stuff,
"and this totally is something new and
different that I've never seen before."
And that's when it kind of hit me.
And then we got the numbers
from the kids' audience
which was a 94. That's a huge score.
I've never had that score in my life.
I mean, that's a massive number.
Then we got the adult score.
It was the exact same, 94.
So obviously the studio
is doing cartwheels.
I guess it was a good experience
as far as movie testing goes.
The parents here were something
that the audience,
they all felt, what happened to them?
So this is an additional scene I shot
just to let people into
what happened to them
and that they're keeping
this conspiracy going.
Likewise, they also wanted to
know what happened to Starscream.
So I added it again, where you
see him go back into space.
What they told me in that test
was I had to fix this ending.
And a lot of times, if they don't
like the ending, an audience,
they'll actually be harder
on the grading of the movie.
But somehow, there was so much
goodwill to this movie, that they...
They still gave it a very high score.
I had to fix some issues
with the Cube.
I had to show...It was very vague
for them to understand
what Sam had to do by pushing
the Cube into his chest.
So we had to do something
about the observatory
with Optimus showing the spark.
And talking about,
he'll put it into his own chest.
And then we had to do a few more shots
with Sam pushing it into
Megatron's chest,
just to clarify the ending.
It's been a bizarre experience
travelling with this movie
to so many different countries.
And even Japan, where I just saw
a screening with 4,500 people.
In Japan, it's funny, they'll tell you,
"The movie's so funny, it's so funny."
But you watch it, and you wanna
kill yourself.
Because you got 4,500 people
sitting there, not emoting at all
because it's impolite to laugh in
Japan when you're watching a movie.
But then they gave it huge
applause at the end,
which is something that
they don't do as well.
And Japanese theatre people
that are distributors there, they were
just saying, "That's a very good sign."
So it opens in Japan...1 guess
when you get this DVD
it will have already opened in Japan,
but this is a week before it opens.
In the Asian countries,
it's just been phenomenal.
I mean, Korea, it's the number
one movie of all time,
at $50-million something.
Malaysia, it's the number
one movie of all time.
It's the biggest opening in China
of all time. It's just crazy.
Transformers was the most fun experience
I've had directing a movie.
It was definitely challenging, but a lot of
my movies have been challenging.
It was a new experience for me
in that working almost like
on an animation movie
with live action.
I can't wait to get started on 2.
The experience of it coming out
and the way it's been accepted around
the world has been staggering to me.
The fans have...
The death threats stopped.
I'm very glad, you know?
I think I've made a lot of
the fans very happy.
I mean, I know I have.
They've told me.
So many have said, "Thanks for making
my childhood dreams come true.”
It's like they've all dreamed
of this movie.
So that's a really nice feeling. But it's an even
nicer feeling to see older people
that knew nothing of Transformers to actually
really enjoy this movie.
And I'm just proud to have worked
with the people I've worked with.
And I can't wait to do it again.
It was a delight to work
with the writers.
Kurtzman and Orci, I don't know
if they're going to write 2,
because they don't know
if there's any magic left.
They've gotta be wrong
with that, you know?
So I'm about to hear many,
many pitches.
But I know that Transformers 2,
if I do it,
I definitely want to take it to
a whole other visual level.
I think this movie has definitely raised
the bar of visual effects.
In terms of realistic visual effects
and what can be done.
It's almost anything what a director thinks
can be done, nowadays.
It's amazing how effects jump
every single year.
I'll look forward to doing it again.
So thanks for listening to me.
Some of it, hope I'm not blabbing.
It's hard to sit in a dark room, right here,
with a microphone in front of you
and talk for three hours.
Till next time, see you.